<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H4611BA7D18E54A6185FDE8C43F036B42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 167 EH: Community Reclamation Partnerships Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 167</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to authorize partnerships between States and nongovernmental entities for the purpose of reclaiming and restoring land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining activities before August 3, 1977, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9D94FA1960E94AF0ADC14EAE2D635EC5" style="OLC"><pagebreak/> 
<section id="HE03B5D1FFD904C7DBBF64085F8286235" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Reclamation Partnerships Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H48366C4177D0406887BD77AB76176E1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reference</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided, whenever in this Act an amendment is expressed in terms of an amendment to a provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a provision of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="HC185E64B28634B39B0AC88CBD52E73C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>State memoranda of understanding for certain remediation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 405 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1235">30 U.S.C. 1235</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (l) the following: </text> <quoted-block id="H005BB0A6E1C04C26AEFFC7579A44DCE0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3E11180B815849B4B5D63094F9DC7087"><enum>(m)</enum><header>State memoranda of understanding for remediation of mine drainage</header> <paragraph id="H67B59A41671B4B84B3A2E534C5C17F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State with a State program approved under subsection (d) may enter into a memorandum of understanding with relevant Federal or State agencies (or both) to remediate mine drainage on abandoned mine land and water impacted by abandoned mines within the State. The memorandum may be updated as necessary and resubmitted for approval under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC460E598FD084D0E847E0A20D20C5F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Memoranda requirements</header><text>Such memorandum shall establish a strategy satisfactory to the State and Federal agencies that are parties to the memorandum, to address water pollution resulting from mine drainage at sites eligible for reclamation and mine drainage abatement expenditures under section 404, including specific procedures for—</text> <subparagraph id="H34D18F9973234BABA2312255FED56E5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring that activities carried out to address mine drainage will result in improved water quality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18675241A10E42549A20E158AAF6F698"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitoring, sampling, and the reporting of collected information as necessary to achieve the condition required under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42FE169C04CF423DBE192E73A6F7BC77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operation and maintenance of treatment systems as necessary to achieve the condition required under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA76D688325924F8294BDEAE0C66072B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other purposes, as considered necessary by the State or Federal agencies, to achieve the condition required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C5FC10486594B42AAD84E90A1EBF36A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public review and comment</header> <subparagraph id="H097175709CBC4A75BAE8391A6766940E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before submitting a memorandum to the Secretary and the Administrator for approval, a State shall—</text> 
<clause id="H77865360369442EEACA89BC594A82DEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>invite interested members of the public to comment on the memorandum; and</text></clause> <clause id="H308CB48604CE46DAAC1B5442494E123E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hold at least one public meeting concerning the memorandum in a location or locations reasonably accessible to persons who may be affected by implementation of the memorandum.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09A8167A96754AA5B7E49E33E4A632E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice of meeting</header><text>The State shall publish notice of each meeting not less than 15 days before the date of the meeting, in local newspapers of general circulation, on the Internet, and by any other means considered necessary or desirable by the Secretary and the Administrator.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2F62797CEA14427AB0F07F4C429D0EC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Response to public comment</header><text>The memorandum shall include responses to substantive concerns raised by the public in comments and during public meetings if received within 30 days of such meetings and opportunity to comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6E979EF61234A60B1AA25B22C34BAFB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission and Approval</header><text>The State shall submit the memorandum to the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for approval. The Secretary and the Administrator shall approve or disapprove the memorandum within 120 days after the date of its submission if the Secretary and Administrator find that the memorandum will facilitate additional activities under the State Reclamation Plan under subsection (e) that improve water quality.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DFC29F08CA741D9A4B3413B3EDA367C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment as part of state plan</header><text>A memorandum of a State that is approved by the Secretary and the Administrator under this subsection shall be considered part of the approved abandoned mine reclamation plan of the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA96A467071E14CD1B0EEFAAF6B5BF3E3"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Community Reclaimer partnerships</header> 
<paragraph id="HB3A32405D04B4155BCE2FCA3E82E65B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Project Approval</header><text>Within 120 days after receiving such a submission, the Secretary shall approve a Community Reclaimer project to remediate abandoned mine lands if the Secretary finds that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5985BC738FFC45C79C81E6CA0919FC5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed project will be conducted by a Community Reclaimer as defined in this subsection or approved subcontractors of the Community Reclaimer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73901387085C4AC49160B541174B63D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for any proposed project that remediates mine drainage, the proposed project is consistent with an approved State memorandum of understanding under subsection (m);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8FEFEF6F60C421C8E9880148DADABF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed project will be conducted on a site or sites inventoried under section 403(c);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F0EC2A0F8774DDB92B068E40784FAE6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the proposed project meets all submission criteria under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE36F753A5A4470E8DB2DE9639B65579"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the relevant State has entered into an agreement with the Community Reclaimer under which the State shall assume all responsibility with respect to the project for any costs or damages resulting from any action or inaction on the part of the Community Reclaimer in carrying out the project, except for costs or damages resulting from gross negligence or intentional misconduct by the Community Reclaimer, on behalf of—</text> 
<clause id="H320F8E53C56C4CAD92646BD4A3E971FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Community Reclaimer; and</text></clause> <clause id="H884FB4D638594C1085DD155F8851953E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the owner of the proposed project site, if such Community Reclaimer or owner, respectively, did not participate in any way in the creation of site conditions at the proposed project site or activities that caused any lands or waters to become eligible for reclamation or drainage abatement expenditures under section 404;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29C1CD48FFAD48DA92848DD6688D17F5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the State has the necessary legal authority to conduct the project and will obtain all legally required authorizations, permits, licenses, and other approvals to ensure completion of the project;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H752A49A28C114A7BA60A4584DEE5445E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the State has sufficient financial resources to ensure completion of the project, including any necessary operation and maintenance costs (including costs associated with emergency actions covered by a contingency plan under paragraph (2)(K)); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36787D5CB82A407986E410F5B856E10D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the proposed project is not in a category of projects that would require a permit under title V.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37204D5ABAE7496D950BA4E56FB965E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project submission</header><text>The State shall submit a request for approval to the Secretary that shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEC33B9C624A44818B5F580AE413019AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the proposed project, including any engineering plans that must bear the seal of a professional engineer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDE964148D3F4FACAB1D66F0BE5EC3DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the proposed project site or sites, including, if relevant, the nature and extent of pollution resulting from mine drainage;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB5CDBE27DF446BD8553750486CF621E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of the past and current owners and operators of the proposed project site;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5307FC7E0C746C2A88573019B789B26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the agreement or contract between the relevant State and the Community Reclaimer to carry out the project;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02E196F1E0DD4B9C8835BBC40768B71F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a determination that the project will facilitate the activities of the State reclamation plan under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABB822998BCE4EE795E49A57EEDFDDEF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>sufficient information to determine whether the Community Reclaimer has the technical capability and expertise to successfully conduct the proposed project;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEACD78A2F7724150BEB045E371290210"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a cost estimate for the project and evidence that the Community Reclaimer has sufficient financial resources to ensure the successful completion of the proposed project (including any operation or maintenance costs);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B9D073A61CF4766A6D6FB9C2153F032"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a schedule for completion of the project;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38B208E9DCC64D808023A292861B2FE7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an agreement between the Community Reclaimer and the current owner of the site governing access to the site;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF94CA7880C404A48A73FBFA13B973D95"><enum>(J)</enum><text>sufficient information to ensure that the Community Reclaimer meets the definition under paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4815AB4B2D124CCF8FDB8B1F3E581649"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a contingency plan designed to be used in response to unplanned adverse events that includes emergency actions, response, and notifications;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DE6424D30D347A19882F9C862DB0703"><enum>(L)</enum><text>detailed plans for any proposed recycling or reprocessing of historic mine residue to be conducted by the Community Reclaimer (including a description of how all proposed recycling or reprocessing activities contribute to the remediation of the abandoned mine site); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EBE76CD0DDB4E24846AD13DE07A516E"><enum>(M)</enum><text>a requirement that the State provide notice to adjacent and downstream landowners and the public and hold a public meeting near the proposed project site before the project is initiated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA37A2206C89426FA72DE4FD08BE1DA1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reprocessing of materials</header><text>A Community Reclaimer may reprocess materials recovered during the implementation of a remediation plan only if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBD4132DABD2547AAA6459A10CEFCC92F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable land management agency has signed a decision document approving reprocessing as part of the approved abandoned mine reclamation plan of the State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC824E6229E36457BA9366E7AAAF5242A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proceeds from the sale or use of the materials are used—</text> 
<clause id="H2ABE404ADE2547F6A20ECC23B5F89E61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to defray the costs of the remediation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H80C5DFB4C1E54AEE9ABABFDFAA57A06E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to reimburse the Administrator or the head of a Federal land management agency for the purpose of carrying out this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E8EDC54996649CFB48189B2E605329E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the materials only include historic mine residue.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6A8561E28B24BDF837CCC2159FE748E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Community Reclaimer defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>Community Reclaimer</term> means any person who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55C602EF9949465D83C346D58161BA2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seeks to voluntarily assist a State with a reclamation project under this section, which may include companies that currently hold reclamation liability elsewhere from the proposed site or active mine sites that require a performance bond;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C44969CD5124E08B22EB7F900DFD7E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>did not participate in any way in the creation of site conditions at the proposed project site or activities that caused any lands or waters at the proposed project site to become eligible for reclamation or drainage abatement expenditures under section 404; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90A2EFD0822A45589D8A3DB7B3F02FFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not subject to outstanding violations listed pursuant to section 510(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HCE98B9C1040B4496B0A59D5D0610A71E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarifying State liability for mine drainage projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 413(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1242">30 U.S.C. 1242(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>unless such control or treatment will be conducted in accordance with a State memorandum of understanding approved under section 405(m) of this Act</quote> after <quote>under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7993F54D861D49948E2857797B9C1A82"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 405(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1235">30 U.S.C. 1235(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H472C74BE1A004760A8C05D2774CF1751"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon in paragraph (6);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E5935FFA86146459F91E1ACB93A640F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (7) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDE9E09223914734811EE5162F8B2125"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD5163A965F974F42BFD3582EDB3A6976" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H957FC1E06B4F4E83AF1C06F0E92379DF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a list of projects proposed under subsection (n).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H69F95CD8235245E19F5577F9B753B402"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall be in effect until September 30, 2032.</text></section> 
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250513" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 13, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


