<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61FB6D9CAFFF4B4ABB3755337CFD803F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 591 IH: A resolution congratulating the members of the 509th and 131st Bomb Wings for successfully completing Operation Midnight Hammer.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution congratulating the members of the 509th and 131st Bomb Wings for successfully completing Operation Midnight Hammer.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the 509th Bomb Wing has an illustrious history of carrying out among the most critical, dangerous, and important missions of the United States Armed Forces, including the bombing of Hiroshima and Nagasaki and the conduct of the first strikes in Afghanistan following the terrorist attacks against the United States on September 11, 2001;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 131st Bomb Wing began as an observation squadron using biplanes and has grown into the most lethal bomb wing of the Air National Guard, partaking in historic flights such as the Charles Lindbergh <quote>Spirit of St. Louis</quote> flight as well as in combat actions against enemies of the United States spanning decades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian regime refused to allow international observers to conduct proper oversight of nuclear facilities in Iran and continued to illicitly enrich nuclear weapon-grade uranium;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when the President required the most lethal and capable bomb wings to deliver a decisive blow for international peace through Operation Midnight Hammer, the President called upon the members of the Armed Forces stationed at Whiteman Air Force Base in Johnston County, Missouri;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, because such members train at, operate at, and maintain the highest level of proficiency, such members were able to successfully complete Operation Midnight Hammer on extremely short notice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in conducting Operation Midnight Hammer, the 509th and 131st Bomb Wings departed from Knob Nobster, Missouri, in secrecy and delivered the tip of the spear to the heart of an illegal nuclear weapons program;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in conducting Operation Midnight Hammer, the brave B–2 pilots of the 509th and 131st Bomb Wings flew for 36 hours, refueled mid-air on dozens of occasions, and still performed with incredible precision in delivering payloads; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the deployment of 125 different aircraft and outstanding coordination with the Department of the Navy and the Marine Corps enabled the success of Operation Midnight Hammer, landing a critical blow to the illicit nuclear weapons program of Iran: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAE1DECEFD069442EBEF1B1481DBE95B2"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HABCBEAF8DB2E4822AEE527477291C7BE"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H7386A3D59DF8431399D8EAA4803326E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congratulates the 509th and 131st Bomb Wings for their incredible service in Operation Midnight Hammer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43F10C4EC00A4173BA18F47C72CB3ECB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the critical nature of ensuring soldiers, sailors, marines, airmen, and coast guardsmen remain always ready to answer the call of the American people.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

