<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25490-DNG-3D-HW3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S1011 IS: Belt and Road Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1011</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250312">March 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the position of Country China Officer in the Department of State to monitor and counter financing projects around the world that are backed by the People's Republic of China.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H42F7F22534CF4734B47C3CD1953EF5A7"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Belt and Road Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5428ee368d504d9e80457703ebc76bab"><enum>2.</enum><header>Country China Officer</header><subsection id="id239086d7a2d64f75ab14ce12a217f9f9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall direct all Chiefs of Mission to designate 1 Foreign Service Officer in a United States embassy or other diplomatic post in each country with whom the United States has diplomatic relations as Country China Officer. </text></subsection><subsection id="id6B458EC0E59248F2A2F66507158C5BF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each Country China Officer shall monitor and report on the activity of the People’s Republic of China in his or her country of responsibility, including capital investment in critical infrastructure and other projects associated with the People's Republic of China, including the Belt and Road Initiative.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6639F1449116499492D783DD50CB6735"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The requirement to designate Country China Officers under subsection (a) shall expire on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idd61fc9a86cf64c0bbd2c8b8cd5d3633c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive review of Belt and Road Initiative projects</header><subsection id="id592e7d7732514e64bc1adc7411953e0d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall direct all United States embassies, working through the designated Country China Officer, to prepare a report that details assets within their respective country of operation that are controlled or financed by the Government of the People's Republic of China or a state-owned enterprise in the People's Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="idFD52C31790A94A1EA70D414DF32A74A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="id989077c61569417796709ee3a08fcdc1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the respective country’s debt obligations to the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6559a98bac6a4c88b1599b7f9fe31893"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of known infrastructure projects in the respective country that are financed from capital provided by—</text><subparagraph id="id4324fc40566b494598bf73cad6762497"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the banking system of the People’s Republic of China, including—</text><clause id="id8639928022f4498f81129477e514fba9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policy banks, including—</text><subclause id="idbb92e465bee745d4988fbd60a89e1e50"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the China Development Bank;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd6e85181ce9246139646b0c40f808c1b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Export-Import Bank of China; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8ca25d23d931487c912228e5342ecf14"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Agricultural Development Bank of China;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id784f4f1ec9774a93baa9fceb3fa9f085"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>state-owned commercial banks, including—</text><subclause id="id43438b6f5cfa4f0293cba410a44db901"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China;</text></subclause><subclause id="id291f360415d64f1fb1b90fb397be664e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Agricultural Bank of China;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd24b6ee05d764dbbaaf261d94cd34a71"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the China Construction Bank;</text></subclause><subclause id="id01205b41b54b492b9067699e5e388e50"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Bank of Communications Limited; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id675e059751394654a4c9140279553b3f"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Bank of China;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id66181c3ab09a4c90957efdd13444dac8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sovereign wealth funds, including—</text><subclause id="id29f04ec1edaf41f58a8f704b69ddb786"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the China Investment Corporation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2a6fd04312bd46219d4e609d9035a6a1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>China Life Insurance Company;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6a5030a9649342849463e7fd766211e2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the China National Social Security Fund; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id79d176c6204e47bcaa989264c92ed819"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Silk Road Fund; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="id94ca80645ec145b6ac29a692c3abe094"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>urban commercial banks; and</text></clause><clause id="id6530e62fbfcf4aa39abcb43e7bbb815b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>rural financial institutions; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83f1cc2ed24445d2a7fa522b9bba275d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>international financing institutions, including—</text><clause id="id2d5122289ec4419899b35ac2bdadaa40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank; and</text></clause><clause id="id4a8c8dd33cbf46e697f325178d6ca248"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the New Development Bank; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02320a1d036249569ec7413a0f8611f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other financial institution or entity otherwise controlled, overseen, or managed by the Government of the People's Republic of China;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d531dc7e0584a4da684aa3187946391"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the identification of the infrastructure projects referred to in paragraph (2) that are projects under the Belt and Road Initiative;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4f24200139f4f058cc302c2d389c085"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of projects that have caused the country to incur significant debt that has the potential to harm its economic prosperity and national sovereignty; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaaea4dc573ef4b08824d71953a5dd195"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a list of the known or speculated collateral listed by the respective country for the debts incurred by Belt and Road Initiative projects referred to in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id195133a6ed8d4f11a03fe260cae23ab7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a list of the known assets owned by the Government of the People's Republic of China or state-owned enterprises in the People's Republic of China, including telecommunications and critical infrastructure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id337e71fa0008404f967f9a55168598f3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a list of known activities at research institutions or institutions of higher education controlled or financed by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or state-owned enterprises in the People’s Republic of China. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida7d4bc7192f547a7838e0de5f936dffa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission and distribution of report</header><paragraph id="id5B8587753B8B4486BEE3400EFF663625"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial submission</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of State issues the directive described in subsection (a), the Chief of Mission in each country shall submit the report required under subsection (a) to the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14ECC2D589B94B70ABE679D4FEADC666"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall prepare and distribute a report that includes all of the information from the individual country reports received pursuant to paragraph (1) to—</text><subparagraph id="id9CF337ADC062470C87E594B79D4F2D2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the heads of other bureaus and agencies of the Department of State, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA409DB5C48054B9A8D748C00BCD6216A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58153B2621304FAAA6F3AA646AEA90F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idECA66EB60DC84F98BDB435910B2DEA92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB1CE306AEB84459E9CD40B77961B75B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id285B20B6E44C4DB6B6A3700EB2EC852B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09C91C0541BB4617A7F0F9EAC5C2EB37"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF0871075090046559F95FC554BAFBFB4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB90D95FBE72A45939BB2C38793C6B78A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD92A8525219F4C85B3FDBBEAE23D2F22"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfdaa39bc3ec446f2b3604ed4380e8ed7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification of future Belt and Road Initiative projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">After the preparation and submission of the reports required under section 3(a), the Secretary of State shall require the respective embassy and the China Desk at the Department of State to inform the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs of any project described in section 3(b)(2) not later than 30 days after the date on which the Country China Officer is informed of such project.</text></section><section id="idb2ff9e2d9a38421799ea199b2ca6e3c7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual comprehensive report of Belt and Road Initiative projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall submit an annual report to Congress that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id496206f3e5d748ad93f65d9e119a5d04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains all findings relating to projects controlled or financed by the Government of the People's Republic of China or state-owned enterprises in the People’s Republic of China submitted by Country China Officers through the process described in sections 3 and 4 during the 12-month reporting period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4bbf32dfbc64855bf2206e8d2f7fa85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes updated findings and analyses related to paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of section 3(b).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7ad8c8484ef040bb982a97ca5851cd41"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual Strategy to Counter PRC Influence</header><subsection id="id03b3031b26014fd691ce5c086d32b3dd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Country China Officer at each respective embassy, in consultation with the Chief of Mission for the respective country, shall develop a comprehensive, country-specific strategy to counter the influence of the People's Republic of China, including a plan to counter anti-American messaging by the People's Republic of China, within their country of responsibility. </text></subsection><subsection id="id4E2C5831F9DA460CBFA491A04E3E4F3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of strategy</header><text>The strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be used to equip all personnel across all embassies, consulates, and other diplomatic posts in the respective country of responsibility with the tools needed to effectively counter the influence of the People's Republic of China in their respective context and country of responsibility.</text></subsection><subsection id="id81d0b77fdfc84a0e9c150986fb368e96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>During the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, each Chief of Mission shall submit an annual report to the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs that—</text><paragraph id="id4C2686F473274829A6EAB36CC434D962"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the implementation of the strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a) during the reporting period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9C992424B1554CCC9B41425A2E682EF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses specific challenges and opportunities relating to the People's Republic of China in the respective country of responsibility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idED3DBC9D9C8F473ABE8C485DBA1B4994"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall submit an annual report that summarizes the information contained in the reports received pursuant to subsection (c) to the heads of the bureaus of the Department of State, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdddbbf2356d496b83f8ffdfbc5cdd4d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Countries with limited or no investments by the Government of the People's Republic of China shall be excluded from the strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id6835ada472354e5bbfe76d471f5e14be"><enum>7.</enum><header>Procurement projections</header><subsection id="id355C89D25FC14E149C370DE30A9607C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>During the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Country China Officer at each respective embassy, in consultation with other embassy personnel, shall submit an annual report to the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs that—</text><paragraph id="idABB05B1ED65E4192B410763A9EEDBE75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the procurement and infrastructure needs of their respective country of responsibility; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCCF2533CF1754068A4436CC7AA8772FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses specific challenges and opportunities relating to potential financing by the People's Republic of China for procurement and infrastructure projects to meet such needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id854B3BC4D4D24F39AAFD9DE40D2C19F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall submit an annual report summarizing the information contained in the reports received pursuant to subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph id="id12360373488C45A89364D5AE45C41AEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of the bureaus of the Department of State, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9AD2AF069B4B4104BA54221282866466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other instrumentalities of the Federal Government, including the United States International Development Finance Corporation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida304c99f4c5a4893a5c53aa69292e5a4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding development finance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, as the People’s Republic of China's influence grows through infrastructure (particularly infrastructure that can easily be shifted from economic to military uses), the United States International Development Finance Corporation should prioritize providing alternative financing opportunities that increase port and air field capacity of countries that—</text><paragraph id="idD07EE76A511E41F3BB013BB1EC045A49"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet the investment criteria set forth in title II of the BUILD Act of 2018 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9621">22 U.S.C. 9621 et seq.</external-xref>); and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBEA04AB7AAD6443696A756EC53643342"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are targets of the predatory infrastructure development scheme of the People’s Republic of China commonly known as the Belt and Road Initiative. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

