<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25124-9JR-50-G7V"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S364 IS: Hearing Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 364</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20250203">February 3, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to remove silencers from the definition of firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H534BFCFADCB94B81B6BA59ADFD1BE93B"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H06E37161A62D4A92ABB09AA0BC8FD2F9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hearing Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2C68C59279AA467F81CC65F27B9220CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equal treatment of silencers and firearms</header> <subsection id="HA7E4AA4B5A6E417EAAFC7F912BD504D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5845">Section 5845(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>(7) any silencer</quote> and all that follows through <quote>; and (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>and (7)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H750853A46240430CBE77FBAFF7F07E2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to calendar quarters beginning more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4727ABDA17E643F5A82F960DD8092789"><enum>3.</enum><header>Treatment of certain silencers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5841">Section 5841</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAB07DA727A1F4B1D80CC6310F1CB255F"> 
<subsection id="H6E62C54EF5984D508751FEB3211B55F7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Firearm silencers</header><text>A person acquiring or possessing a firearm silencer in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, shall be treated as meeting any registration and licensing requirements of the National Firearms Act with respect to such silencer.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H384F75E691CD450D8993A99DEDEB3638"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preemption of certain State laws in relation to firearm silencers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 927 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a law of a State or a political subdivision of a State that imposes a tax, other than a generally applicable sales or use tax, on making, transferring, using, possessing, or transporting a firearm silencer in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, or imposes a marking, recordkeeping, or registration requirement with respect to such a firearm silencer, shall have no force or effect.</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA332792C0A6342B58D6261A91DD785CF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Destruction of records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall destroy any registration of a silencer maintained in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5841">section 5841</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, any application to transfer filed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5812">section 5812</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that identifies the transferee of a silencer, and any application to make filed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5822">section 5822</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that identifies the maker of a silencer.</text></section> <section id="H38B4691B39954D9490B8D6C559801E4A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amendments to title 18, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H834C21EBE1694A969E6C6FD7D8733FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 921(a), by striking paragraph (25) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA3ABC0C060D4C4F99622CF07B83B212"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB0360717AD1B49E4B1012EBB8127FBE4" indent="up1"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The terms <quote>firearm silencer</quote> and <quote>firearm muffler</quote> mean—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H07EF0EAB97C448459FE67313184FFFFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any device designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HBC24B58896224D56BE3DDE68C8E4BECD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to silence, muffle, or diminish the auditory report of a portable firearm; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H7780B2DDD313409685E6A5E8F68C8E83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be attached to a portable firearm, directly or through a mount, adaptor, or other device that is not a firearm silencer or firearm muffler; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD0A90CCBD9340D88A6745C59774A0AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outer tube or other single part of any device that—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HE44B2DEDCADC48CCBB8609E964DE29EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides the primary housing or is the primary structure for internal sound-reduction components designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to silence, muffle, or diminish the auditory report of a portable firearm; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H03396C7625E348EFAEED57E3AE13C61F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attaches to a portable firearm, directly or through a mount, adaptor, or other device that is not a firearm silencer or firearm muffler.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8F6440C9EFE4C329B3B80BC7D3FD0C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 922(b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F0CE13190554CBF830FB2EE6C20F823"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>shotgun or rifle</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>shotgun, rifle, firearm silencer, or firearm muffler</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFC1179996304E22B36B111E362BFDA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>rifle or shotgun</quote> and inserting <quote>shotgun, rifle, firearm silencer, or firearm muffler</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1CF9C34B8554A999EE3373BEA05D89C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 923(i)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H96B2FB7AB038470C81715C2EC315B91E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Licensed</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>(1) In the case of a firearm other than a firearm silencer or firearm muffler, licensed</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72236BB132DC4D6C97CD8C6E1092DDC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H57337A293F4E43718E0E18693B4C2C2F"> 
<paragraph id="HA2CED9D9D7024B928167075121DD9629" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a firearm silencer or firearm muffler, licensed importers and licensed manufacturers shall identify by means of a serial number engraved or cast on the outer tube or other single part that provides the primary housing or primary structure of the firearm silencer or firearm muffler, in such manner as the Attorney General shall by regulations prescribe, each firearm silencer or firearm muffler imported or manufactured by such importer or manufacturer, except that, if marking the outer tube or other single part that provides the primary housing or primary structure is impractical, licensed importers or licensed manufacturers shall submit a request for a marking variance to the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall grant such a request except on showing good cause that marking the firearm silencer or firearm muffler as requested would not further the purposes of this chapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H5AE7F8F568A64A1BBDAAADD9A368762E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Imposition of tax on firearm silencers or firearm mufflers</header> <subsection id="H4FB0B552B43548AEA15E8EA608D92F5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4181">Section 4181</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end of the list relating to <quote>Articles taxable at 10 percent</quote> the following:</text> <list list-type="none" level="subsection"><list-item><quote>Firearm silencers or firearm mufflers.</quote></list-item></list></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D02130DD6074B7584902AE14F035152"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Firearm silencers; firearm mufflers</header><text>Section 4181 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE42F65CC1CA64DFD90EBE3AF5257CF02"> <subsection id="H79013ECB8D1446308E4460B5AF59327B"><enum></enum><text>For purposes of this part, the terms <term>firearm silencer</term> and <term>firearm muffler</term> mean any device for silencing, muffling, or diminishing the report of a portable firearm.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C7C29E4E4E749658F46FD9ACE809826"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H76F4A706F9744D25A544BA6B66029EB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 4181 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>other than pistols and revolvers</quote> and inserting <quote>other than articles taxable at 10 percent under this section</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4C652FC04AC438A9768033798F5DE75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 4182(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>firearms, pistols, revolvers, shells, and cartridges</quote> and inserting <quote>articles described in section 4181 and</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8AC417E7AD414D6AA6B3E4B48595F29E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 4182(c)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or firearm</quote> and inserting <quote>firearm, firearm silencer, or firearm muffler,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3FF555920BBF4E7DBA33D34B9F954371"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to articles sold by the manufacturer, producer, or importer in any calendar quarter beginning more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


