<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82B4D5CEDAD24D3B98F4565B4839C0BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 735 IH: United States Reciprocal Trade Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 735</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250124">January 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to take certain actions relating to reciprocal trade, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H973A24BF2D6E49A7A37A287374F6B031" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H53879FE92F39412AA860991BB1FCC6AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Reciprocal Trade Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB903EDB47F4A406BA2D405A119297EA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD11B3D5A85A74D4BAB975BAAA7D4CAD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States maintains an open market for goods, with relatively low tariffs, and has long encouraged trading partners, both bilaterally and in multilateral fora, to liberalize their markets.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14B05F80D7284A09A18AE6C2E870B3D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States is the world’s largest importer of goods.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADC84AF50BF143ADBD3FEF2DCE20EE14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Trading partners of the United States in many instances impose significantly higher tariffs on United States goods than the United States imposes on the same or similar goods imported from those same countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26EDE15C679B4557BFF8385DEC640C2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Europeans have continued to protect their auto markets from United States automotive companies through high tariffs while dumping cheap European cars into the United States, undermining our automotive industry.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H557A3F121EAD4795B630C1910478632C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canadian and Mexican authorities have flooded American markets with cheap goods while simultaneously allowing for illegal migrants and poisonous fentanyl to pour into the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H846DD37096D7429EA70E0DC67BE68B77"><enum>(6)</enum><text>United States trading partners in many instances impose significant nontariff barriers that greatly undermine the value of negotiated tariff concessions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H857FC44AC0B3416487F9321F2D636D96"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The lack of reciprocity in tariff levels and disproportionate use of nontariff barriers by United States trading partners facilitates foreign imports, discourages United States exports, and puts United States producers, farmers, and workers at a competitive disadvantage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87AF976301DF4CB0B29C4A07A6816525"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The lack of reciprocity in tariff levels and nontariff barriers contributes to the large and growing United States trade deficit in goods, which is a drag on economic growth and undermines economic prosperity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1960EC5EFC584D8AB786462DC6B88E54"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tariffs under the Trump presidency substantially shrank the trade deficit with China.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9B8840A664940E0871E0FBBF3651C3C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The President must be able to levy tariffs on our global competitors. Preferential treatment of adversaries, such as China’s Most Favored Nation trading status, undermines American national security interests domestically and around the world.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD08FC7B62F39408FA56EFD477B8DA6A3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To date a number of United States trading partners have been unwilling, including in multilateral negotiations, to reduce tariffs and eliminate nontariff barriers applied to United States exports.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAF0AAD56C564D0A8B7B2C31FD7E9B80"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States should seek action by United States trading partners to lower tariffs and eliminate nontariff barriers, to promote efficiency in those markets and enhance opportunities for United States producers, farmers, and workers.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2FCAC7F683B644439E2DC9EA11CF8683"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the United States to maintain its economic dominance globally, the President must have the authority to levy reciprocal tariffs against unfair trading partners.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D06EDF3187F49C7A7C963D402B3A1B0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The President should have a wide array of tools to open the markets of United States trading partners and encourage participation in negotiations to liberalize trade in goods on a fair and reciprocal basis, including the authority to adjust tariff rates to reciprocal levels.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H33118E8A627D41A79F9756E7AD443F3E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to take certain actions relating to reciprocal trade</header> 
<subsection id="H05A334A3946F4B6B84713F3F6FB0511E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President determines that—</text> <paragraph id="H868005408B654B2CA48D59BC5846AF1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate of duty imposed by a foreign country with respect to a particular good, when imported from the United States, is significantly higher than the rate of duty imposed by the United States on that good, when imported from that country, or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCC49334887D4A9BABF97899C39EFC14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nontariff barriers applied by a foreign country with respect to a particular good, when imported from the United States, impose significantly higher burdens, alone or in combination with any tariffs imposed by that country on that good, than the burdens of the nontariff barriers applied by the United States with respect to that good, alone or in combination with any tariffs imposed by the United States on that good, when imported from that country,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the President may take one or more of the actions authorized under subsection (b).</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CB7644ACFF44ADB9F4801F77855E870"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions authorized</header><text>The actions authorized under this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE420FA69BA84457DADFD7DD2E08EDFE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To negotiate and seek to enter into an agreement with the foreign country that commits the country to reduce the rate of duty or reduce or eliminate nontariff barriers on the good that is the subject of the determination under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF35AFE2A47A04B4F8E6F027F960A0F48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To impose a rate of duty on imports of the good that is equal to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F9BB2E002164E50A689655DD885A3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of duty imposed by the foreign country with respect to the good, in the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(1); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D19F46DD4D641BA8D22F04D96A6E3F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effective rate of duty of the nontariff barriers applied by the foreign country with respect to the good, alone or in combination with any tariffs imposed by that country on that good, in the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35C1646DD34D47C594F03E818E26DD27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In taking an action authorized under subsection (b), the President shall consider the following factors:</text> <paragraph id="H3F347C9FAB6F48BF81B84DA1EFD1E6D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tariff classification of the good by the United States and the tariff classification of the good by the foreign country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2520B86C949345B9A1D5736BF9E47053"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rate of duty applied by the United States with respect to the good and the rate of duty applied by the foreign country with respect to the good.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF7566F2472C4097A386888DC9EEB099"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The physical characteristics of the good.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45FDCE2ADCD44396B2BC084138047248"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The end uses and existence of a competitive relationship between the good—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F3FA02E8B4742EA91DCB834ABDC2634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as exported from the United States to the foreign country; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD033E3F6039A4E7C85976195EC3D22AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as imported from the country to the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8423935C5AB945BC8BDB29E38478DC58"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The level of exports of the good by the country to the United States and to other countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32D3E88346CA40C588B67E837BB4C3AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(1), the extent to which the rate of duty applied by the foreign country with respect to the good is impeding or distorting trade.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A3CD508F44146779460C27731389772"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H437D70A258724CA1AEEF7BA94F5ADCF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent of the nontariff barriers applied by the foreign country with respect to the good and the extent of the nontariff barriers applied by the United States with respect to the good;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CE161BBA19B4513AA0A226DEA437A3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which the nontariff barriers applied by the country with respect to the good, alone or in combination with any tariffs imposed by that country on that good, are impeding or distorting trade;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H636B79FE6FBF4F95B4C8ABD801D85F59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the identified purpose of the nontariff barriers applied by the country with respect to the good, if any, and the extent to which the nontariff barriers are more restrictive than necessary to meet that purpose; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72AB18771D6E46F18FB2D555F58CC52B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the degree of transparency of the process by which the country adopted the nontariff barriers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DAA9FC9996C4C66894608791272467B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Other factors, as the President determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9F0FDF6F1A5A467A98617FE0479391F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Role of USTR</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall advise the President in determining the effective rate of duty imposed by the nontariff barriers applied by a foreign country with respect to a good, alone or in combination with any tariffs imposed by that country on that good, in the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E8CFAE408A34C72B29A71CA3CAF0A86"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Lower rate of duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country that is lower than the rate of duty described in subsection (b)(2)(A) or lower than the effective rate of duty described in subsection (b)(2)(B), as the case may be, if the President determines that application of such lower rate of duty is necessary and appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H37B16A720E344BF49BB9E7B6A0228C09"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Higher rate of duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President imposes a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country under subsection (b)(2), and the country further increases its rate of duty on imports of the good from the United States, the President may further increase the rate of duty on imports of the good from the country to a rate that is equal to the rate of duty applied by that country.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HEDD8103600084DB192FAAFD557D6DD58"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall terminate the imposition of any increase in the rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country under subsection (b)(2) effective on the date on which the President determines that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H864AEBC3B0D84B489886ADF6879B2CF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the foreign country is no longer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD5101ECF7CC9403B8CF058B126B241A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imposing a rate of duty with respect to the good, as described in subsection (a)(1); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E2E4ED459B4444AACFA000A10822C1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applying nontariff barriers with respect to the good, as described in subsection (a)(2); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HEE6B200432FA4C2D8682337750EAFB7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continued imposition of the increased rate of duty on imports of the good from the foreign country is not in the economic or public interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H09E060F32E564C2997D4D95F24AF43FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notice and consultation</header> <subsection id="HA2949EA8B8AB4897BC28036B9D71E3B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before taking any action authorized under section 3(b)(1), the President shall provide notice to and consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate regarding the proposed action.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52B6847A3A244848B519392DC1788E5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before taking any action authorized under section 3(b)(2), the President shall—</text> <paragraph id="H97DFFB2E4E18427680E6F92C8DBD9691"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 30 days before the date on which imposition of an increased rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country is to take effect, publish notice in the Federal Register of, and allow for public comment on, the proposed imposition and level of such increased rate of duty; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81F3D908720C43AA87BF851D6FFA6C36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek advice regarding the proposed action from the advisory committees established under section 135 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2155">19 U.S.C. 2155</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H408C86D06F124E488B9F46EE36A712FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional notice</header><text>The President shall promptly publish in the Federal Register notice of any action taken pursuant to section 3(f) or 3(g).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H01E4BF6AED78478FB0300FF4636CCEC8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Congressional disapproval of Presidential imposition of rates of duty on imports of goods from foreign countries under section <enum-in-header>3(b)(2)</enum-in-header>; disapproval resolution</header> 
<subsection id="H129F54021FE44FC881AA6887581FB0DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action taken by the President under section 3(b)(2) to impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country shall cease to have force and effect upon the enactment of a disapproval resolution, provided for in subsection (b), relating to that action.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE74EE3D301984C63BED5F90261798724"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional rulemaking power; disapproval resolution</header> <paragraph id="H37C3EC5D92DF4666B19B1E4AFC9F3D24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section is enacted by the Congress—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H73405AA6F9CD4F85BAD8CA8D0372DB4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedures to be followed in that House in the case of disapproval resolutions and such procedures supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0272A8670D7449C79C0960EAFA798175"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD985F0D990C46448A199B448339725F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disapproval resolution</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>disapproval resolution</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That the Congress disapproves the action taken under section 3(b)(2) of the United States Reciprocal Trade Act with respect to the imposition of a rate of duty on imports of __ from __ under such section 3(b)(2).</quote>, the first blank space being filled with a description of the good with respect to which the duty is imposed under section 3(b)(2) and the second blank being filled with the name of the foreign country from which the good is imported into the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H476614C16A1D41CF972F5632A88B285E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header> <subparagraph id="H98AEF8A59D7E40A2B8385FCB8EA0E3F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>All disapproval resolutions introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means and all disapproval resolutions introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2AFF1F8358904DA6834E04ECC1CA3315"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amendments prohibited; motions to suspend application of this subparagraph prohibited</header><text>No amendment to a disapproval resolution shall be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate, and no motion to suspend the application of this subparagraph shall be in order in either House nor shall it be in order in either House for the Presiding Officer to entertain a request to suspend the application of this subparagraph by unanimous consent.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39AA6A9722004C86AFF2620FBCAA7F18"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Majority required for adoption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disapproval resolution considered under this subsection shall require an affirmative vote of two-thirds of the Members, duly chosen and sworn, for adoption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4805D46217F84326BE24C2EA07278A44"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before entering into an agreement with a foreign country under section 3(b)(1), the United States Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that describes—</text> <paragraph id="HA3FE3F900DAA4B008AACE99767A8F243"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of the agreement, including how it is consistent with and does not materially differ from or otherwise affect Federal or State laws or regulations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H795F0B23795940F08077ECDAFDDBAAB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact on the competitiveness of United States businesses; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC193F7FC080C48DFB940702BFE82FC11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact on United States consumers.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H989276755B464D7D83EC4427DC3B720B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset of Presidential imposition of rates of duty on imports of goods from foreign countries under section <enum-in-header>3(b)(2)</enum-in-header> by disapproval resolution</header> 
<subsection id="H6E3D89E1C14947DE83CCC0BBE3EA4BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authority of the President to take an action under section 3(b)(2) to impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country—</text> <paragraph id="H7FFB2212D6734153AD541C78A0E11180"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be effective for the period ending on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39F7F7D29C0E4D38851A6E971DA10F88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be extended for an additional period of three years if (and only if)—</text> <subparagraph id="H24FA28E453AA4512B3C8D6E946C078ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President requests such extension under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB354FECCA99044D0AAED024E7D3E0D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a disapproval resolution is not enacted into law as provided for under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A93647EDEDD4CEC927EC06F7A9388DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President is of the opinion that the authority of the President to take an action under section 3(b)(2) to impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country should be extended for the additional period described in subsection (a)(2), the President shall submit to Congress, not later than the date that is three months before the end of the period described in subsection (a)(1), a written report that contains a request for such extension, together with a description of all actions taken under section 3(b)(2) to date.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1087D2BEA76483CA6008D55AD40CF9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disapproval resolution</header> 
<paragraph id="HEEA306D437534B6BB00DA2804BB4BFC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional rulemaking power</header><text>This section is enacted by the Congress—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D8FCD9C5E1D4F448D24DD4A110FE7A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedures to be followed in that House in the case of disapproval resolutions and such procedures supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7949496D6E9F4835A25C0F518B2FF9FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H874D4AC05A4E4AD5A2AECCF93BFAEC83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disapproval resolution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>disapproval resolution</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That the Congress disapproves the request of the President for the extension, under section 7(a)(2)(A) of the United States Reciprocal Trade Act, of the authority of the President to take an action under section 3(b)(2) of such Act to impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country after the period ending on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of such Act.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3635D73EE7B74112A9011CB242D34953"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Introduction; referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disapproval resolution—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA1ED7953B3C4260BC07C262081F91D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be introduced in either House of Congress by any member of such House; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC32D6DAE88941CF8BE952FFE0B92871"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be referred, in the House of Representatives, to the Committee on Ways and Means and, in addition, to the Committee on Rules.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6BD2F43E4DA4B6584283AD81396ABE6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (d) and (e) of section 152 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2192">19 U.S.C. 2192</external-xref>) (relating to the floor consideration of certain resolutions in the House and Senate) apply to a disapproval resolution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD896D30B293946FEB9C753FF156C5F8C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations on consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is not in order for—</text> <subparagraph id="HE23FA823371841ACA7F466775B232F07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the House of Representatives to consider any disapproval resolution not reported by the Committee on Ways and Means and, in addition, by the Committee on Rules;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6F4CEF1D3874720B5C3A29385594661"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Senate to consider any disapproval resolution not reported by the Committee on Finance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B54618214A94CE8861C85D134A2E2A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either House of Congress to consider a disapproval resolution after the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B6D812D5A824E418CAFE5F0D8CF221D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> 
<paragraph id="HBCAD552B7761478BA2672EAFBB2107EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action authorized under section 3(b)(2) to impose a rate of duty on imports of a good from a foreign country that is taken before the end of the period described in subsection (a)(1) or the end of the period described in subsection (a)(2) shall remain in effect after the end of such respective period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ABB87C8B88D4D9E93DED1C160E6B1AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise the authorities of subsections (e), (f), and (g) of section 3 with respect to an action described in paragraph (1) after the end of the period described in such paragraph that is applicable to such action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5492428125004545A476610824E43A92"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HCC1E40640C234AEA8AA32D56155980B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees and leadership</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees and leadership</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H54C05A1539E744769204D2F3424E3523"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65BD6512B2B54AB280223A5A9B4511D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the majority leader of the Senate, and the minority leader of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26F57C3084644E73B1BDD5FFDB13CBA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nontariff barrier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nontariff barrier</term> includes any government-imposed measure or policy, other than a customs duty, that restricts, prevents, or impedes international trade in goods, including import policies, sanitary and phytosanitary measures, technical barriers to trade, government procurement, export subsidies, lack of intellectual property protection, digital trade barriers, and government-tolerated anticompetitive conduct of state-owned or private firms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD36BAFDBABA144449F2FC8CEEE2EA132"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rate of duty</header><text>The term <term>rate of duty</term> means the rate of customs duty applied on imports of a good, but does not include an antidumping or countervailing duty or a duty applied under a preferential tariff arrangement.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

