<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E292F7F606B461888278A96C7DB69A8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 236 IH: Expressing support for the goals of a “NICU Baby’s Bill of Rights”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 236</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the goals of a <quote>NICU Baby&#8217;s Bill of Rights</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States continues to experience high rates of infant prematurity, with over 380,000 babies born preterm each year and thousands more full-term medically complex babies admitted to the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the preterm birth rate of Black babies is 50 percent higher than that of White babies in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas preterm birth is the leading cause of death among children under the age of 1 year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a baby born preterm or full-term with medical complications is a significant driver of comorbidities, including necrotizing enterocolitis, bronchopulmonary dysplasia, cerebral palsy, brain injury, and retinopathy of prematurity, often resulting in lifelong complications or death;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas babies born prematurely or with severe medical complications are most often cared for in neonatal intensive care units (referred to in this resolution as <quote>NICUs</quote>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas having a baby born preterm or full-term with medical complexities is a traumatic experience, and NICU families are often overwhelmed by their circumstances, leaving them at high risk for a variety of mental health concerns, including perinatal mood and anxiety disorders;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas NICU parents are often separated from their critically ill babies, bonding is interrupted, and this may have significant negative impacts on the cognitive development of the baby and the emotional and mental well-being of the parents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas critically ill babies and their parents and family caregivers benefit from skin-to-skin contact in terms of increased breastfeeding rates, higher rates of emotional attachment, enhanced neurodevelopmental outcomes, and promotes confidence in caregiving;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, when NICU families are supported, outcomes improve for babies and their families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas all families deserve family-centered care that is developmentally appropriate and supportive;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas all NICU families deserve access to the individualized support, education, and resources they need to thrive during and after their NICU stay;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas NICU families are often not fully informed or consulted on questions of substance regarding their child’s care, including treatment plans, the true health status of their baby, and infant nutrition;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, although studies have shown that human milk-based nutrition is preferable, many families report being unaware of the nutrition options available to their babies including donor human milk and human milk-based nutrition; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas all NICU families have the right to informed consent regarding all aspects of their child’s care: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8AA4318D53B94DA5B9B676608450D74E"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2EB7D0FC5E73477498D0DAD576B4D053"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HF2CE7556F7034518B85F43FFABC2BD6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the goals of a <quote>NICU Baby’s Bill of Rights</quote> supporting the needs of neonatal intensive care unit families and their babies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9375C081C8764FB7BBE1243BC7F876E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on health providers and other stakeholders to promote a family-centered approach to neonatal intensive care unit care, including the needs of babies as well as families to make the decisions that are right for them, including encouraging parents to be integrated into the daily care of their babies as much as possible;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AA697F2F7224E37B4CA157D6A3FC9F8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">understands that parents are a neonatal intensive care unit baby’s best advocate, and asks hospitals to establish clear policies that prioritize parental or primary caregiver presence, integration, and collaboration, and involve family advocacy partners in the creation and development of such policies from the beginning of these discussions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA64CE0D51D4842599360D83094047E48"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages hospitals to embrace an informed consent model for important care decisions for all neonatal intensive care unit babies, including treatment care plans and infant nutrition for all neonatal intensive care unit babies, ensuring families are fully informed of the risks and benefits of all care options available, and empowering parents to make informed decisions on behalf of their child;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4CBE3F5C95D41A69AAE8C8FB1F78A6E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>emphasizes the importance of a comprehensive discharge planning process that includes family participation, ensuring the plan is tailored to the needs of each individual baby and family; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H293DC05976B747018533F5BC0F024986"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">underscores the importance of mental health support for parents and family caregivers of neonatal intensive care unit babies, including connecting them to peer-to-peer support programs, support groups, and counseling, whether in person or virtual, to reduce the impact of perinatal mood and anxiety disorders.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

