<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H444CA968656240969AA975E417C4FB57" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1379 IH: Trafficking Survivors Relief Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250214">February 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the vacating of certain convictions and expungement of certain arrests of victims of human trafficking.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H499CC1860552476380B300B1777AFC59" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4C54CDC07B614BBCA5ECE00647BCA7A3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trafficking Survivors Relief Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H07C834569DA947C0BA51D1F496728B11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal expungement for victims of trafficking</header><subsection id="H5800D2D41B2B46B0A1A36B667C6E673E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/237">Chapter 237</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91B5E7E99D3045A5B394E0014FCB4551"><section id="H7D65E66A99B041FD9B99A7D2CD7C3FB0"><enum>3771A.</enum><header>Motion to vacate; expungement; mitigating factors</header><subsection id="H540C33EBFAE84970B6A4240D8DEE2C54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H4B24A7338B514D39BDF657F4102DFA97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64EE1090766846888E62FADD218A5CB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered prisoner</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H317130D96847448A8437169CFE559605"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was convicted of a level A offense or level B offense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H826F7D64360A4A789750500B4399FA86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was sentenced to a term of imprisonment for the offense described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H175FB0697B9F48A4819C6842673F6844"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is imprisoned under such term of imprisonment;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB44387E4A98D4A3ABBC20F7F50676032"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the terms <term>employee</term> and <term>officer</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 2105 of title 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H331AD6A58B544B65828B827EDFF58AE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal offense</term> means an offense that is punishable under Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D8643C31E2C41CFAAD4765B508DD57B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>level A offense</term> means a Federal offense that is not a violent crime;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF422F7BC36784379A0A15A8522DA5ACE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>level B offense</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H03F5CEBC87EB40708D9394D9A2050B96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a Federal offense that is a violent crime; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A73E187EC7D4D849C5F70788D2B490C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a Federal offense that is a violent crime of which a child was a victim;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1619B9CD38A4F0399474A3FD7CA9B55"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>level C offense</term> means any Federal offense that is not a level A offense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62C9E4EF7E5040D2BA91DA765EC5DAC1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>victim of trafficking</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A509DE57B2549AFAAB838D3D8CA9929"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>violent crime</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11103">34 U.S.C. 11103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H100FDB7268F74423909A3EABBDF60A83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Motions To vacate convictions or expunge arrests</header><paragraph id="H48379603B52C4251A32396A0C93A6164"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H06787C69B5434C36948D18C36F975562"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Convictions of level A offenses</header><text>A person convicted of any level A offense (or an attorney representing such a person) may move the court that imposed the sentence for the level A offense to vacate the judgment of conviction if the level A offense was committed as a direct result of the person having been a victim of trafficking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3925E0C814074C8CAC667FA6014CA84C"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Arrests for level A offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person arrested for any level A offense (or an attorney representing such a person) may move the district court of the United States for the district and division embracing the place where the person was arrested to expunge all records of the arrest if the conduct or alleged conduct of the person that resulted in the arrest was directly related to the person having been a victim of trafficking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36CC0F8F719D4CBD8BBE31AB178B7833"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Arrests for level C offenses</header><text>A person arrested for any level C offense (or an attorney representing such a person) may move the district court of the United States for the district and division embracing the place where the person was arrested to expunge all records of the arrest if—</text><clause id="H991C9AFA47FB437EA28B11FF24A539DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the conduct or alleged conduct of the movant that resulted in the arrest was directly related to the movant having been a victim of trafficking; and</text></clause><clause id="H9EA37D46F5D74AB2926761204CA5D3F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA611FEB2772641CF8E0EE005885817D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the movant was acquitted of the level C offense;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H28747808A06F46639B5C55B1E23A52EB" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Government did not pursue, or the Government moved to dismiss, criminal charges against the movant for the level C offense; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF21D8070B3842E393BCAD745178939D" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8A4342AE6E184D0DB934FE85CC126EAE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the charges against the movant for the level C offense were reduced to an offense that is a level A offense; and</text></item><item id="H96583B92DE88414A8C3AFEF5E89D944A" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the movant was acquitted of the level A offense, the Government did not pursue, or the Government moved to dismiss, criminal charges against the movant for the level A offense, or any subsequent conviction of the level A offense was vacated.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H247EC49848B444D79EF6E601B1AFBF4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of motion</header><text>A motion described in paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5DF7F7F037D244AA977AA583CF2BBAB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be in writing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73FABE1D9B2F429D846CF1B698065013"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe any supporting evidence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16831C57BA349A1B9ACAB0F99045CDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>state the offense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E2BCE581F3D4FB2B3A8B1E1BFBA02FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include copies of any documents showing that the movant is entitled to relief under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE41690B1B1439AAC80FC2F69648BE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hearing</header><subparagraph id="H725A0630678F458894D424CEA1C134CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mandatory hearing</header><clause id="H0E623C29084B4C4AA12FE925D93F4947"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Motion in opposition</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a motion is filed under paragraph (1), the Government may file a motion in opposition of the motion filed under paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="H93FF45C76E154A7FA50B3286BB406969"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mandatory hearing</header><text>If the Government files a motion described in clause (i), not later than 15 days after the date on which the motion is filed, the court shall hold a hearing on the motion.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B78A51C4FF422585A106AC0CB9046D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discretionary hearing</header><text>If the Government does not file a motion described in subparagraph (A)(i), the court may hold a hearing on the motion not later than 45 days after the date on which a motion is filed under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H741349E8639E427EBE2291D74240C5EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Factors</header><subparagraph id="H4889D980503C4B988B29567322EF8060"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Vacating convictions of level A offenses</header><text>The court may grant a motion under paragraph (1)(A) if, after notice to the Government and an opportunity to be heard, the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence, that—</text><clause id="H17380F235A2440319CCF1C47B1C8DFCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the movant was convicted of a level A offense; and</text></clause><clause id="HD6E981F131E94B229CD867B5A0E2373E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the participation in the level A offense by the movant was a direct result of the movant having been a victim of trafficking.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10F5072DEE3F4591A855896B58972406"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expunging arrests for level A offenses</header><text>The court may grant a motion under paragraph (1)(B) if, after notice to the Government and an opportunity to be heard, the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence, that—</text><clause id="HB36314EC582B48C5AF44F7705643493C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the movant was arrested for a level A offense; and</text></clause><clause id="H881F24766DCC4262A3CF05F67742A01C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the conduct or alleged conduct that resulted in the arrest was directly related to the movant having been a victim of trafficking.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70B411BD791B404DBE49EFE35AFFA78B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expunging arrests for level C offenses</header><text>The court may grant a motion under paragraph (1)(C) if, after notice to the Government and an opportunity to be heard, the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence, that—</text><clause id="H5883640762AD49F9A8BC01093568010C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the movant was arrested for a level C offense and the conduct or alleged conduct that resulted in the arrest was directly related to the movant having been a victim of trafficking; and</text></clause><clause id="HA668D65CCC984AA6921FE570A6C92F64"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E2947E0E4AB451892AA8F17DD14C12A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the movant was acquitted of the level C offense;</text></subclause><subclause id="H97C8EE3D4C9F402A80992406AD9E3918" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government did not pursue, or the Government moved to dismiss, criminal charges against the movant for the level C offense; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H46696D69D9CF408A926AA46472CADC12" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H430CED5CA4FA409BB3B740C0E4F3D4E3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the charges against the movant for the level C offense were reduced to a level A offense; and</text></item><item id="HA2EF2724AA65432EAB110545BE637DFB" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the movant was acquitted of the level A offense, the Government did not pursue, or the Government moved to dismiss, criminal charges against the movant for the level A offense, or any subsequent conviction of that level A offense was vacated.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E22A36FCCC44C10BA3EB7D56B27FD31"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supporting evidence</header><subparagraph id="H275E6BE2AF93467BBBF482ED908F9CE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, in determining whether the movant is a victim of trafficking, the court shall consider an affidavit or sworn testimony of a licensed anti-human trafficking service provider or clinician. The court may consider any supporting evidence the court determines is of sufficient credibility and probative value, including sworn testimony from a law enforcement officer detailing the role of the movant in coercing other victims into committing Federal offenses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FCC86FCEC8F4F07B609825672F3F963"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Affidavit or sworn testimony sufficient evidence</header><text>The affidavit or sworn testimony described in subparagraph (A) shall be sufficient evidence to vacate a conviction or expunge an arrest under this section if the court determines that—</text><clause id="HC77CAD4961374ADFA6E3C92800C48CD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the affidavit or sworn testimony is credible; and</text></clause><clause id="HA8E4D672E18E41C29AEF53D9BE78E303"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no other evidence is readily available.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF40D06FDF04C7BBD47A2B053FCA44D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Conviction or arrest of other persons not required</header><text>It shall not be necessary that any person other than the movant be convicted of or arrested for an offense before the movant may file a motion under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67D5552796704A9D82423B8EED345F21"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Denial of motion</header><subparagraph id="HDE0F7216034D4B7AACC7F039CD439671"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court denies a motion filed under paragraph (1), the denial shall be final, subject to the discovery of any new and compelling evidence or information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F766DD13DE4136BCEF51E333CBB0A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reasons for denial</header><text>If the court denies a motion filed under paragraph (1), the court shall state the reasons for the denial in writing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H407F14BE603D42DA9758F45A595AEA35"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reasonable time to cure deficiencies in motion</header><text>If the motion was denied due to a curable deficiency in the motion, the court shall allow the movant sufficient time to cure the deficiency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC7BC88A9AE41D6B0DC1E36467FDFA6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>An order granting or denying a motion under this section may be appealed in accordance with section 1291 of title 28.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1DCC47E7B3A41779E72418C110D8127"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vacatur of convictions</header><paragraph id="HD865D9569C85467790D6E7AEC4E5FC2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the court grants a motion to vacate a conviction of a level A offense under subsection (b), the court shall immediately—</text><subparagraph id="H3090F9AFABEB4C988631E9ABACCF2C93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>vacate the conviction for cause;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2581CB5CDDE94AAAAD3BF73E7462DCAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>set aside the verdict and enter a judgment of acquittal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5B170AA73C04ED4B3F8286A6172D56C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enter an expungement order that directs that there be expunged from all official records all references to—</text><clause id="H586E376624C2405395E29AFE894EA0C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the arrest of the movant for the level A offense;</text></clause><clause id="H3C401F678147426E87E67F0B190059BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the institution of criminal proceedings against the movant relating to the level A offense; and</text></clause><clause id="H1939D28CB24944E1924CA6035DB822B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the results of the proceedings.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB74ADCC322734CC490D2FCF95760CD69" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this subsection requires a court to amend, impose, or remove any fine or restitution order in a criminal or civil proceeding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9DC150F013D4C6EB5F90CCC1B6CBF03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>If a conviction is vacated under an order entered under paragraph (1) the conviction shall not be regarded as a conviction under Federal law and the movant for whom the conviction was vacated shall be considered to have the status occupied by the movant before the arrest or the institution of the criminal proceedings related to such conviction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C130FD2C379461BA73FE8E0A02F6042"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expungement of arrests</header><paragraph id="H111D91FFBF3D488489DDE6D3CA4C5767"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the court grants a motion to expunge all records of an arrest for an offense under subsection (b), the court shall immediately enter an expungement order that directs that there be expunged from all official records all references to—</text><subparagraph id="H5AC8C3C182E24C2EA4EA0CD7C5B263BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the arrest of the movant for the offense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H966510A351E941309A55648435BF82CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the institution of any criminal proceedings against the movant relating to the offense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B06C3DF59BB4BFDB52444D5A2223E7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the results of the proceedings, if any.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B4A792EAA842528B8BFC8999EF3C24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>If an arrest is expunged under an order entered under paragraph (1) the arrest shall not be regarded as an arrest under Federal law and the movant for whom the arrest is expunged shall be considered to have the status occupied by the movant before the arrest or the institution of the criminal proceedings related to such arrest, if any.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DBE8923FCD440999DAAE2F9DBE2DE1B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mitigating factors</header><paragraph id="H4DA243D602B24026AD6E6530570B74A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The court that imposed sentence for a level A offense or level B offense upon a covered prisoner may reduce the term of imprisonment for the offense—</text><subparagraph id="H3F0F020DD0644FE09CF9874A5858CD64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upon—</text><clause id="H61A4161AB4AF40A6AC1F72AE486758BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>motion by the covered prisoner or the Director of the Bureau of Prisons; or</text></clause><clause id="HF814F4EC6FE749559E5EE87F61B06BDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the court's own motion;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8637EA0074EF44EAB4D08B24EC086664"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after notice to the Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7D76F710B44488798D4419C56D9BA49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after considering—</text><clause id="H934E82F6E1EB4F7DAFDF67DB70DA7877"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the factors set forth in section 3553(a);</text></clause><clause id="H38CECD5B6B4448D4ACFA8A959F5CB5B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the nature and seriousness of the danger to any person, if applicable; and</text></clause><clause id="HAF7E9F548DA246158BAF3DEE1B1CDE5F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the community, or any crime victims; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB430001E62D54025A77861D6F4E79AB8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the covered prisoner committed the offense as a direct result of the covered prisoner having been a victim of trafficking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACD011995160425AB7A11117F5F13D66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any proceeding under this subsection shall be subject to section 3771.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE66D6CCBEDA42F09C6BA8D4833F3F88"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Particularized inquiry</header><text>For any motion under paragraph (1), the Government shall conduct a particularized inquiry of the facts and circumstances of the original sentencing of the covered prisoner in order to assess whether a reduction in sentence would be consistent with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2030BB252B8740FDA7D17178BACB884A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional actions by court</header><text>The court shall, upon granting a motion under this section, take any additional action necessary to grant the movant full relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="H45E1053D517A408BA67BE352B16C39E8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No fees</header><text>A person may not be required to pay a filing fee, service charge, copay fee, processing fee, or any other charge for filing a motion under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5986C0C40FA4A0292EC58367B026264"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Confidentiality of movant</header><paragraph id="H02D6254A4AF349128D71D9B382B5498E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A motion under this section and any documents, pleadings, or orders relating to the motion shall be filed under seal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6567AF86A89947C982810BA3D7C5F252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information not available for public inspection</header><text>An officer or employee may not make available for public inspection any report, paper, picture, photograph, court file, or other document, in the custody or possession of the officer or employee, that identifies the movant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF744104D06948CCA73E19D879E013DB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to any conviction or arrest occurring before, on, or after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1FFDFD65C85B42DDA4052B20994E0C3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/237">chapter 237</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDBFF3543AC034B55BBCD64D865F35F8F"><toc><toc-entry idref="H7D65E66A99B041FD9B99A7D2CD7C3FB0" level="section">3771A. Motion to vacate; expungement; mitigating factors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HAA5703E545034259A459FC452E444FBF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H2A83E3AA527948BFB0A19C4B6AFE4EFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States Attorney motions for vacatur or expungement</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, each United States attorney shall submit to the Attorney General a report that details—</text><paragraph id="HFFAF6948ABB54E9090D93DDB24E1F274"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of motions for vacatur or expungement filed under section 3771A of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 2, in the district of the United States attorney; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABCAE329BE9343EBA1A1C3E3346D1233"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each motion described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HFB3D80AE0BFB486785A0803A90310684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the underlying offense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB0B8FDE630476392A9C3AE02D4461C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the response of the United States attorney to the motion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9955598118846C8BBF6E3BE94769F03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the final determination of the court with respect to the motion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7E43C9EDBBE4B32AC999A690C9E8617"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United States attorney training on human trafficking indicators</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report that details all professional training received by United States attorneys on indicators of human trafficking during the preceding 12-month period.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDCE36F66D6C144F89DFACC91327435C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="HA8065F0D1DC94DA79844B773868CE733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the impact of the enactment of section 3771A of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 2; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCA87F7190584C278143DD93BB855CDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes—</text><subparagraph id="H754360C731EF40B989ADBF746EACC3A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of human trafficking survivors who have filed motions for vacatur or expungement under such section 3771A;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C700AA1CFB4EF5B357D3C2E7A7C589"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the final determination of each court that adjudicated a motion described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84AA947792AE49F6A472F2909E8C8FA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to increase access to post-conviction relief for human trafficking survivors with Federal criminal records; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC33084374C042809B9A372D978A2AAC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the implementation and tracking of professional training of United States attorneys on indicators of human trafficking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFF9E11C7D680493FB110A931C63F516A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of grants for post-conviction relief representation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office of Justice Programs or the Office on Violence Against Women, in awarding a grant that may be used for legal representation, may not prohibit a recipient from using the grant for legal representation for post-conviction relief.</text></section><section id="H2C300F7FC1994B20B077E4B10203F55D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HD623CB490E724A6A9AF49AD0FE5EBE80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act is a first step to address the changing tactics of human traffickers, who are using forced criminality as a form of force, fraud, and coercion in their human trafficking enterprises; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EB1A162B1C7422B84B9CDA5BF31B409"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress is committed to continuing to find solutions as needed to thwart human traffickers and protect survivors of human trafficking.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC3C3C052EE7C45D19B9849F9104E571C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Human trafficking defense</header><subsection id="HE0477BB6A5574AF98A9E9F4C67B195C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43B5F81E7A9E48BC91716FDFCF28681D"><section id="HF8BE8E46165E4B62A13101B040939B2E"><enum>28.</enum><header>Human trafficking defense</header><subsection id="H9E03CEC6A9A449B094AAB28406A24BD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered Federal offense</term> means a level A offense or level B offense, as those terms are defined in section 3771A.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B1D06CC0DD3452E838E222C8CD56369"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption of duress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a prosecution for a covered Federal offense, a defendant who establishes by clear and convincing evidence that the defendant was a victim of trafficking at the time at which the defendant committed the offense shall create a rebuttable presumption that the offense was induced by duress.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC52349BE5B1E46C7933E281910BEBF9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Record or proceeding under seal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any proceeding in which a defense under subsection (b) is raised, any record or part of the proceeding related to the defense shall, on motion, be placed under seal until such time as a conviction is entered for the offense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5ACCB7FDF7E44EC198F8E459B7E4AEEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Post-Conviction relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failure to assert, or failed assertion of, a defense under subsection (b) by an individual who is convicted of a covered Federal offense may not preclude the individual from asserting as a mitigating factor, at sentencing or in a proceeding for any post-conviction relief, that at the time of the commission of the offense, the defendant was a victim of trafficking and committed the offense under duress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H233D1724CF7B489EB22DB9F50D2CF80D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal aid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failure to assert, or failed assertion of, a defense under subsection (b) by an individual who is convicted of a covered Federal offense may not be used for the purpose of disqualifying the individual from participating in any federally funded program that aids victims of human trafficking.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H13D52E4A6A4D41169AE7E302B51A474C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF44B8A0D1BF4598A0B1EDB1708620B5"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">28. Human trafficking defense.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H57308B5071C54399A57254D68952E667"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to conflict with any of the crime victims’ rights described in section 3771 of title 18, United States Code.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

