<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25078-VJ5-0L-8G5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 30 IS: Honoring Mississippi's Gestational Age Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 30</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Mississippi's Gestational Age Act.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 15, 2018, Mississippi State Representative Becky Currie of Brookhaven, Mississippi introduced the Gestational Age Act to protect unborn children from elective abortion after 15 weeks gestation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 19, 2018, the Gestational Age Act was passed by the Mississippi State Legislature, approved by Mississippi Governor Phil Bryant, and enacted into law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in May 2021, the United States Supreme Court agreed to review Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health, 597 U.S. 215 (2022), a challenge to the constitutionality of the Gestational Age Act, where the question before the Court was whether all pre-viability prohibitions on elective abortion are unconstitutional; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 24, 2022, the United States Supreme Court issued its historical decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health, holding that <quote>the Constitution does not confer a right to abortion. Roe and Casey must be overruled, and the authority to regulate abortion must be returned to the people and their elected representatives.</quote>: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7eea697e0dd34ea08b91841a6e68d17c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses profound gratitude to Mississippi State Representative Becky Currie for introducing the catalyst that ultimately brought about the historical victory of overturning Roe v. Wade, 410 U.S. 113 (1973) and Planned Parenthood v. Casey, 503 U.S. 833 (1992); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87ea63aeaecd40538394c27c66ac6fc2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors life-affirming States across the country that have enacted laws aimed to value and protect the inherent dignity of every mother and unborn child.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

