<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00419C33867545C3B6F2ADF2B0437C28" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 655 IH: Expressing support for the designation of August 17, 2025, as “Marcus Garvey Recognition Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 655</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of August 17, 2025, as <quote>Marcus Garvey Recognition Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey was the father of the largest African-American movement of all time, a movement which attracted millions of followers from around the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey’s legacy is deeply rooted in many North American and Caribbean communities, and his memory is highly regarded by many in the United States and his native Jamaica;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Marcus Garvey was able to enlist the support of more than 1,500,000 members of the Universal Negro Improvement Association to purchase shares in the Black Star Line, a cargo shipping line developed to increase the economic independence of African Americans;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the ultimate goal of Garvey’s philosophy was for the Black community to achieve economic independence through free enterprise, entrepreneurship, and political self-help; and</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Marcus Mosiah Garvey was granted a Presidential posthumous pardon in 2025, and it is therefore fitting and appropriate at this time to recognize his contributions to Black history: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H58183B92A7BA48EEA5F6CFAAABCD7689"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H35D0604A7BC34D26B48EFD3146D1492F"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Marcus Garvey Recognition Day</quote> and the President issuing a proclamation calling upon the people of the United States to observe that day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

