<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B0C732EE6DD4294A1BF6649626E7C1A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3265 IH: Protecting our Students in Schools Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3265</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of corporal punishment in schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB2721D1A74D741ABA4A4D7F0277D4EA7" style="OLC"><section id="H88C553E87F39470FABC55D9C059AC2D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HDA571D16399445E187539B9A9948CFFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting our Students in Schools Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8691833E3F3845CAB2992304273D5186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act are as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H88C553E87F39470FABC55D9C059AC2D0" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0700460660A340F3B11D71EAA8279ED9" level="section">Sec. 2. Purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4458C3B201074C55875777B133D3D9BC" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6D9BAE5DB9014BBFA45A29A0F2C9BDF0" level="title">Title I—Prohibition of Corporal Punishment</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBAB1C59652C14D6DB11354DD608F7B0C" level="section">Sec. 101. Prohibition of corporal punishment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5B629405718D4CC9AA8C77B665EF97A4" level="section">Sec. 102. Civil actions by the Attorney General.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H818E2F470BB643C5997B1D4CBED36067" level="section">Sec. 103. Enforcement by the Office for Civil Rights.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H459E51025D4F4388B1EFA4C71A864C02" level="section">Sec. 104. Parent notification and protection and advocacy systems.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H81B3508500FE4946A66AFA958F416062" level="title">Title II—State Activities and Grant Program</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H330EB2A49EB544E2AA344BE0BA8BCFD7" level="section">Sec. 201. State plan and enforcement.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H209380541EE24D00B32FFC4DCA94CDC7" level="section">Sec. 202. Grant authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6FB574B14E014AD3A35DE6B86C79B8D6" level="title">Title III—Additional Provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEE67F286777740C4ADA60EC9ACDB3E63" level="section">Sec. 301. Federal regulations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA8200C6FDD0442D7AF62DD04FD98D560" level="section">Sec. 302. Other schools.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCCFA483CE0AD46EDA9472E5E6A2F03AF" level="section">Sec. 303. Limitation of authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1CABB8A04287473086B0C53866DA956C" level="section">Sec. 304. Applicability to private schools and home schools.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE163C698D0194A3EAF02569BABF8BF0F" level="section">Sec. 305. Severability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7094121CA65445538D454E7CDFEF742B" level="section">Sec. 306. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H0700460660A340F3B11D71EAA8279ED9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="H7799F43532EA4F99B5FD1C735A69A51F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>eliminate the use of corporal punishment in schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F7180E9C22C4255B716CB02E73D8045"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure, regardless of sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, sex, race, color, national origin, disability, or religion, the health and safety of all students and program personnel in schools and promote a positive school climate and culture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6650AA76CCE045F3BF9BD31F09756790"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist States, local educational agencies, and schools in improving school climate and culture by implementing positive behavioral interventions and supports, and other models (including models such as restorative justice interventions, trauma-informed care, multi-tiered system of supports, crisis and de-escalation interventions, implicit bias training, and culturally responsive teaching), to address student behavior and work to eliminate the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H934ADF98A3134941A7A7B4961BA0101F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure all program personnel have the supports and training necessary to implement positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to address student behavior and improve school climate and culture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H488DC97A563D42E0BB473A1C0C9F2B2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>collect and analyze data on exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in schools.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4458C3B201074C55875777B133D3D9BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE3153CE94D19422A91B731D839C970BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corporal punishment</header><text>The term <term>corporal punishment</term> means, with respect to a student, a deliberate act which causes the student to feel physical pain for the purpose of discipline, including an act of physical force, such as striking, spanking, or paddling, inflicted on a student’s body, requiring a student to assume a painful physical position, or the use of chemical sprays, electroshock weapons, or stun guns on a student’s body.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA33C571103CF424D8B3D3BD99580209B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>evidence-based</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>outlying area</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, <term>State</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3FB4A70F36F46F0B7521D0A77470CA9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusionary discipline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>exclusionary discipline</term> means any type of disciplinary action that removes or excludes a student from the student’s usual educational setting, or from access to education services, including such disciplinary actions as in-school suspensions, out-of-school suspensions, expulsions, or any other removal, however labeled, that results in lost instructional time for the student.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0F633AA64F045F6BD691E647DBFE4B4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Model</header><text>The term <term>model</term> means an activity, strategy, framework, or intervention that is evidence-based, to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F604ACB58CA4CDEA322ED52E502125C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Positive behavioral interventions and supports</header><text>The term <term>positive behavioral interventions and supports</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H834057063377424B8F7F343389EDF5D3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a schoolwide, systematic approach that embeds evidence-based practices and data-driven decision making to improve school climate and culture in order to achieve improved academic and social outcomes and increase learning for all students (including students with the most complex and intensive behavioral needs); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D40ABB8B512468E862C0DC3EF7D9A4C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encompasses a range of systemic and individualized positive strategies to teach and reinforce school-expected behaviors, while discouraging and diminishing undesirable behaviors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC93DB24A092848798C36312926F257BA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9B90F1ED0CEF4921B74D9D5138698170"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all of the operations of a local educational agency, system of vocational education, or other school system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CBFC5160FD642D9BDD841AD5F34D4DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a program that serves children who receive services for which financial assistance is provided in accordance with the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA415155D4CDF4194876B98E895547168"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an elementary school or secondary school that is not a public school that enrolls a student who receives special education and related services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE03052CEB0F468A800137C67FBE82B3" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program personnel</header><subparagraph id="H9CCD0E5DEE00482DAF23E04CBCBF819A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>program personnel</term> means any agent of a program, including an individual who is employed by a program, or who performs services for a program on a contractual basis, including—</text><clause id="H09ABC6CAF96141F48095CD1EE586B0A8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>school leaders;</text></clause><clause id="HAA0CF08B4ED74A19BB669933AE39BEF5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>teachers;</text></clause><clause id="HD3529CEAF6CE4B9B9F466834A742F564" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specialized instructional support personnel;</text></clause><clause id="H91BDF893346B4CE7AA79D47EEC4929FC" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>paraprofessionals; or</text></clause><clause id="HA41F7E3988054BBD973884D4CF5D3595" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other staff.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C3B5F3D992A42628BAFC3E99C0E067B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), program personnel shall not include a law enforcement officer or a school security guard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F7FC9003D9F48E2ABDC5C9ABD32BDEB" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Protection and advocacy system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>protection and advocacy system</term> means a protection and advocacy system established under section 143 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15043">42 U.S.C. 15043</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DBE09216A0747B4AADF34B0FF74F153" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H2D9D4FA7934646E1B632AFB00A8B0437" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any person who—</text><clause id="H10F4399223984B9198C2A1973C4A6845" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a State, Tribal, or local law enforcement officer (as defined in section 1204 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284</external-xref>)); and</text></clause><clause id="H967C662884DE475193A1CD14D301CBDC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is assigned by the employing law enforcement agency to a program, who is contracting with a program, or who is employed by a program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62344758323F4682A04F9E7B4D9E5C39" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes an individual referred to as a <quote>school resource officer</quote> if that individual meets the definition in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F77568B5D2B4556BB84D66AD90A6EA5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>School security guard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school security guard</term> means an individual who is not a sworn law enforcement officer and who is responsible for addressing one or more of the following safety and crime prevention activities in and around a program:</text><subparagraph id="H8B7355970BE64222AC58116CE7997492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Assisting program personnel in safety incidents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81A710C1B4E04170B25339CBAAF0A11F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Educating students in crime and illegal drug use prevention and safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B851A5506784D8F83462993523A0F66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Developing or expanding community justice initiatives for students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H333A95A9EB3B4807B8E5A88BB1E9F924"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Training students in conflict resolution and supporting restorative justice programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49CF87E09EC46EDB4D8659AD13CE329"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Serving as a liaison between the program and outside agencies, including other law enforcement agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H106537883EB340AB9FCEE8E17E963B62"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Screening students or visitors to the program for prohibited items.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE57A70B183A540B0994068D7A62B35DD" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student</term> means an individual enrolled in a program.</text></paragraph></section><title id="H6D9BAE5DB9014BBFA45A29A0F2C9BDF0"><enum>I</enum><header>Prohibition of Corporal Punishment</header><section id="HBAB1C59652C14D6DB11354DD608F7B0C" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum><header>Prohibition of corporal punishment</header><subsection id="HFC96A97123C14C6EBD7AA815F18BD9BD" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No student shall be subjected to corporal punishment by program personnel, a law enforcement officer, or a school security guard under any program which receives Federal financial assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC72BDF785770418481259FA441335C36" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A student who has been subjected to corporal punishment by program personnel, a law enforcement officer, or a school security guard in violation of subsection (a), or the parent of such student, may file a civil action in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction against the program under which the violation is alleged to have occurred for attorneys’ fees, expert fees, injunctive relief, and compensatory damages.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5B629405718D4CC9AA8C77B665EF97A4" commented="no"><enum>102.</enum><header>Civil actions by the Attorney General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whenever the Attorney General receives a complaint in writing signed by a parent (including a legal guardian) or a group of parents (including legal guardians) to the effect that the minor children of such a parent or parents are being deprived by a program of the right under this Act to not be subject to corporal punishment by program personnel, law enforcement officers, or school security guards and the Attorney General believes the complaint is meritorious, the Attorney General is authorized, after giving notice of such complaint to the appropriate program and after certifying that the Attorney General is satisfied that such program has had a reasonable time to adjust the conditions alleged in such complaint, to institute for or in the name of the United States a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States against such parties and for such relief as may be appropriate, and such court shall have and shall exercise jurisdiction of proceedings instituted pursuant to this section. The Attorney General may implead as defendants such additional parties as are or become necessary to the grant of effective relief hereunder.<italic></italic></text></section><section id="H818E2F470BB643C5997B1D4CBED36067"><enum>103.</enum><header>Enforcement by the Office for Civil Rights</header><subsection id="HB9ADE61CA5604E37B9B6C8EAA400817B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Referral to Office for Civil Rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall refer any complaint alleging a violation of section 101(a) to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education for an investigation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H58F54C97DF5C47AA83677E388FA37B2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for referral</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and implement a procedure for receiving a complaint alleging a violation of section 101(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HFF088CF33E1646FB8C855AE6EBA8F72D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Failure To comply</header><text>In the event that a program has failed to comply with section 101(a), the Secretary shall carry out at least one of the following:</text><paragraph id="H4D334372C1ED4529829798CE138FD000"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Withhold from such program, in whole or in part, further payments (including payments for administrative costs) under an applicable program (as such term is defined in section 400(c) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221(c)</external-xref>)) in accordance with section 455 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234d">20 U.S.C. 1234d</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD82F88AC48954B2DB87A64CE4D0F7000"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enter into a compliance agreement in accordance with section 457 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234f">20 U.S.C. 1234f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40CE8D8B80624AEEA5B986DBEEF1348E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Issue a complaint to compel compliance of such program through a cease and desist order, in the same manner the Secretary is authorized to take such action under section 456 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234c">20 U.S.C. 1234c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23B8BF884FE54C0E9F09772285325B2C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cessation of withholding of funds</header><text>If the Secretary determines (whether by certification or other appropriate evidence) that a program that is subject to the withholding of payments under subsection (c)(1) of this section has cured the failure providing the basis for the withholding of payments on a date that is within one year from the date on which such payments were first withheld, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H0D4E4F694F324A52AA8E64A8639C62E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cease the withholding of payments with respect to that program under such subsection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCF386F10FBF4E9BAFA216F32668373D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reimburse all the withheld payments under such subsection to such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84A7A28139274D07BDDE3D8750C682EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withheld funds</header><text>The funds appropriated or made available for the payments that were withheld under subsection (c)(1) shall be available for expenditure to that program pursuant to this subsection for up to one year from the date upon which the determination in subsection (d) was made.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2810BC2114484E259CE03CA9287D5200"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the Secretary’s authority under the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H459E51025D4F4388B1EFA4C71A864C02" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>104.</enum><header>Parent notification and protection and advocacy systems</header><subsection id="H4D5B4F37AD524C8D92D809FEDA2F9D69" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a student is subject to corporal punishment committed by program personnel, a law enforcement officer, or a school security guard at a program, the program serving such student shall notify, in writing, not later than 24 hours after such use of force occurs, the facts of such use of force to—</text><paragraph id="H1B9B31F434124BB19AB09DF9BF4A53C2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the parent or parents of such student;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2F0DC31C2D4004875D2FA6D77B9C23" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State educational agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBF9AC0E8E94211ACDE7069282A2560"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the local law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H761E5D6615C44190BF2B8C53BA595106" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification for students with disabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a student described in subsection (a) who is an individual with a disability (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)) the program serving such student shall—</text><paragraph id="H66614E8AE0114FBE88304E78F3243C59" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in addition to the notification described in such subsection, notify, in writing, not later than 24 hours after the use of force described in such subsection occurs, the facts of such use of force to the relevant protection and advocacy system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A2644776AF947C89169EE1CA177DD69" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide any information to the relevant protection and advocacy system that the protection and advocacy system may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29746EC6F38E482BA3388BDAAFA3DFBE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restatement of authority</header><text>Protection and advocacy systems shall have the same authorities and rights provided under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15041">42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to protections provided for students under this Act when such students are otherwise eligible to be clients of the protection and advocacy system, including investigating, monitoring, and enforcing such protections.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H81B3508500FE4946A66AFA958F416062"><enum>II</enum><header>State Activities and Grant Program</header><section id="H330EB2A49EB544E2AA344BE0BA8BCFD7"><enum>201.</enum><header>State plan and enforcement</header><subsection id="HF54C70446CA84F3D92C18B15E0A26889" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State requirements</header><text>In accordance with the schedule specified in subsection (c), each State educational agency that receives Federal financial assistance shall provide to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H34B1348C201E4614AA647D112951D8E1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State that did not prohibit corporal punishment in schools before the date of enactment of this Act, a written assurance that—</text><subparagraph id="H118EBAC35F5F4FF79D5E827FA7CC594F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all programs located in such State have been notified of the requirements of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF8415050400441E88854304AF9970A8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all program personnel of such State educational agency have received training with respect to such requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB50C831AC836456F9C263C80D5599189" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>parents of students served by such State educational agency have been notified of the requirements, rights, and remedies available under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3D71595E80D4851BB0E53DA505091A8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the notification required under subparagraph (C) is publicly available on the website of the State educational agency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AFA2CCCF4044DC5862A7BAB3CB3A4B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State that prohibited corporal punishment in schools before the date of enactment of this Act, a written assurance that all programs located in such State have been notified of the requirements of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E82E40CA3BB4422BAA5BF6331230649" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a school climate report that includes a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H6711DFBBDCAB4C9AA318D8F8D5B79F41" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the policies and procedures of the State educational agency with respect to exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in such schools;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF31B412ECE3C49CDB6B1823EE20BDB71" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the State educational agency plans to implement, is implementing, or has implemented positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to address student behavior and reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in the public elementary and secondary schools of such State as required under section 1111(g)(1)(C) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(g)(1)(C)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B86DBDF69CF461691662F514D5A3C75" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>efforts of the State educational agency to ensure program personnel receive the supports and training necessary to implement the interventions, supports, and other models described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51B27DBC6ED54C7BA82C0088AE89FED6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local educational agency requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the schedule specified in subsection (c), each local educational agency shall submit to the State educational agency a report that includes the information the State educational agency determines necessary to comply with the requirements of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H47CF9D61C8DC47E19D9AD425484AA95A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local educational agencies shall make the submissions required under subsections (a) and (b) as follows:</text><paragraph id="HAAE32D8499E24B268C616E54D82E288E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The initial submissions shall be made not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act and on an annual basis during each of the 3 years following the year of the first submission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F0B819E6DA641AF84E4F71B36202C94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>After the expiration of the 3-year period described in paragraph (1), subsequent submissions shall be made not less frequently than once every two years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06FB6FE0039149BE95FB7AD7930DFD54" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year in which the Secretary receives submissions from States in accordance with the schedule specified in subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H4B379BEA8921451A88A0AA01BDD180FB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report summarizing the findings of the school climate reports received from States for such year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACFEAD1D289442FDAB67EC7A897BE662" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the school climate reports publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC502E9554A74603BD478D04B6513D59"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H256220B1FC8D49D5B1BB9E2568F9E5F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HDBFB78F6BB8D4797A03F58C8672593C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of remedies</header><text>If a State educational agency fails to comply with subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out at least one of the following:</text><clause id="H3021FC2A792248568D090A168E4F6B05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Withhold, in whole or in part, further payments under an applicable program (as such term is defined in section 400(c) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221(c)</external-xref>)) in accordance with section 455 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234d">20 U.S.C. 1234d</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H9F9E79DB08FE47CA8348271DF3BC1D38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Enter into a compliance agreement in accordance with section 457 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234f">20 U.S.C. 1234f</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H910EF741456C4DA0A841EA403262CFCC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Issue a complaint to compel compliance of the State educational agency through a cease and desist order, in the same manner the Secretary is authorized to take such action under section 456 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234e">20 U.S.C. 1234e</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80090B6800074ADEB07F9F970A086A31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cessation of withholding of funds</header><text>If the Secretary determines (whether by certification or other appropriate evidence) that a State educational agency that is subject to the withholding of payments under subparagraph (A)(i) has cured the failure providing the basis for the withholding of payments within one year from the date on which such payments were first withheld, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H4AE7F2BEB07047D795DEEFC8B6A9C92D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cease the withholding of payments with respect to the State educational agency under such subparagraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H2E672E78904B4B26A1178C8EB89DE249"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reimburse all the withheld payments under such subparagraph to such State educational agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3A0734F2274FF3BCD55EC00B53EF30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withheld funds</header><text>The funds appropriated or made available for the payments that were withheld under paragraph (1)(A)(i) shall be available for expenditure to that program pursuant to this paragraph for up to one year from the date upon which the determination in paragraph (1)(B) was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C1C8418A1584F6AA4DBD590E062CB88"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the Secretary’s authority under the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H209380541EE24D00B32FFC4DCA94CDC7"><enum>202.</enum><header>Grant authority</header><subsection id="H77F5C1C94B6A48E58AA97BDADE617827"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount appropriated under section 306, the Secretary may award grants to State educational agencies to improve school climate and culture by implementing positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to address student behavior and reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</text></subsection><subsection id="H54B38AD8F8894520B972815398765797"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of grant</header><paragraph id="H9490401C38DC4E12A110648680546D1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded to a State educational agency for a three-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F657B9F39994C68A432A8208BE11C79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reapplication</header><text>At the end of a grant period described in paragraph (1), a State educational agency desiring a subsequent grant under this section may be eligible for such grant if such State educational agency—</text><subparagraph id="HD1275706D8544660AAA5403938734292"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submits an application under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AC39BBE72E04C95B60264D37A8E5301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates—</text><clause id="H3E76AE90C27645AE902A34BC89F88F25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that such State educational agency effectively used grant funds to carry out the required activities under subsection (e) during the previous grant period; and</text></clause><clause id="HC30FEFCF1D9D4C27858544F2C6A7F46A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to such State educational agency, a decrease in at least one of the following:</text><subclause id="H7D4A9B3E052740EFAB077C3ADCA79267"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions, including in-school suspensions, out-of-school suspensions, and expulsions.</text></subclause><subclause id="HB4CB0963B98D42708271612B153B2571"><enum>(II)</enum><text>School-related arrests.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8D8C16111E9F4A1D8192B8958FB8CE2E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Referrals of students to law enforcement.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD3796E96404D96B92B4C7A6881E6CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency shall, with respect to the data used under paragraph (2)(B)(ii)—</text><subparagraph id="H8A0D70B766E04DCBB9B119E856C954A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cross-tabulate such data and disaggregate by race, gender, disability, and English learner status; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88E7CA96BD784847ABDA59FDA0D85018"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redact all personally identifiable information from such data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE35AE6CCD6814369967D104B9AB93ABC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HB192A63104E24B8687178F17902F9C74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State educational agency desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5AE582A9D1094CE48D685007FA8A852F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on how the State educational agency will carry out the required activities specified in subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9965629C490C49828D68E31AA40A934F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the State educational agency will improve school climate and culture by reducing the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86E10F66E35472EA5BCFA76426A3D8D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the State educational agency will implement positive behavioral interventions and supports, and other models (including models such as restorative justice interventions, trauma-informed care, multi-tiered system of supports, crisis and de-escalation interventions, implicit bias training, and culturally responsive teaching), to address student behavior and work to eliminate the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AB14FBBE02B4EF09D0BAAB5362D430F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the State educational agency will develop and implement high-quality training for program personnel designed to improve school climate and culture and increase the use of positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to address student behavior and reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8DE6E791794D279C810B83A30792AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to State educational agencies—</text><subparagraph id="H3244789FA0D74FC0B5A86D4F1A593EF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a high percentage of in-school suspensions, out-of-school suspensions, expulsions, school-related arrests, and referrals of students to law enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F526F4C98574687BEF6076FBE927895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that lack positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to improve school climate and culture; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCED72ACE88184DE096D26766C869A191"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are in most need of assistance relating to improving school climate and culture by reducing the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97A1D0F7FDC84E5680DBF2933BE671D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To make subgrants</header><paragraph id="H00899C349D4F42F9B8F8A1E89151DDB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State educational agency receiving a grant under this section may use such grant funds to award subgrants, on a competitive basis in accordance with subsection (e)(2), to local educational agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9FC214110E345F691F5720860F28417"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the applicable State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require, including the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (c)(1) with respect to the local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H914857AB8D324D3E98672D1CB19B37E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Required activities</header><paragraph id="H722A42F0A8AC4B4BB3141AF1330D750C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency receiving a grant, or a local educational agency receiving a subgrant, under this section shall use such grant or subgrant funds to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9996C8C30B2A47688583BC4777B13C45" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing and implementing high-quality training for program personnel designed to—</text><clause id="H3638D8466FAE471ABEDBF52CA3DB70A9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve school climate and culture;</text></clause><clause id="H32FF8E7742B94972B2B8E2A29D87C0D5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase use of positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to address student behavior; and</text></clause><clause id="HC806B778B89441BB854F4A437C5E28AB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions and the discriminatory and disproportionate impact such practices have on students based on their race, ethnicity, gender, or disability.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F1D647EECB04242B1F227D5DEC7CC85" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing technical assistance to improve school climate and culture by implementing positive behavioral interventions and supports, and other models (including models such as restorative justice interventions, trauma-informed care, multi-tiered system of supports, crisis and de-escalation interventions, implicit bias training, and culturally responsive teaching), to address student behavior and work to eliminate the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E5CE3206F1410E8D96A1C68646A8A8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Researching, developing, implementing, and evaluating models, policies, and procedures to reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF645D1F414A45CCB3737FCAC0D3EB30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>A State educational agency or local educational agency shall prioritize carrying out the activities specified in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (1) in public elementary schools and secondary schools—</text><subparagraph id="HFECBCECEABD64738A44B3C346BA5063D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which a disproportionately high percentage of students who have been subjected to disciplinary proceedings or have otherwise experienced the application of such a school’s discipline policies, practices, and procedures, relative to such school’s total student population, are students of color or students with disabilities (as defined in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9851943FA1034BFAA43A0192B816433C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with a high percentage of in-school suspensions, out-of-school suspensions, expulsions, school-related arrests, and referrals of students to law enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E044FE460B94BBFAC1612CA811391B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that lack positive behavioral interventions and supports and other models to improve school climate and culture; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50AE555E208142CF9491D64ABAD2D3E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that have demonstrated meaningful community engagement in selecting models to improve school climate and culture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10B388B5FCC64A16AD42B01C7352DC85" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header><paragraph id="H2472BE014D7A40F186E32D9E07973AA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency receiving a subgrant under this section shall, at the end of the grant period for such subgrant, prepare and submit to the State educational agency a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H1144769E957346DC919B818A8C026860"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluates the progress of the local educational agency toward carrying out the required activities under subsection (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF81031713FB54E42B6534AB20F3CC704"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any additional information the State educational agency determines necessary to complete the report required under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F798A51660B4A66A1F0520E50EBDA5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State educational agency reports</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving a grant under this section shall, at the end of the three-year grant period for such grant, prepare and submit to the Secretary a report that—</text><subparagraph id="HAE6B587BCBDC4717B79266FAAEBB9D2E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluates the State’s progress toward carrying out the required activities under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF6625279E0492292B21C12723B99FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes data on the impact of the grant program on school climate and culture during such grant period, including, with respect to the State educational agency, data on the prevalence of, and increase or decrease in—</text><clause id="H746C29A02C91419F877EDB3971453C6F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions, including in-school suspensions, out-of-school suspensions, and expulsions;</text></clause><clause id="HE263BDE2F62E4862AE34EDC55F8DCCDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>school-related arrests; and</text></clause><clause id="H54EC91C12CAD408C924BECEAC57F3B6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>student referrals to law enforcement;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF3FCF4FA8664710A4FFDD30CDB068FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the number of high-quality school climate and culture trainings conducted for program personnel during such grant period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9BC02C018CC4AAAA4A17EE246D39BAC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>describes the models implemented to improve school climate and culture during such grant period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E6CC581027940A1BA9489179FA12444"><enum>(E)</enum><text>specifies the number of subgrants made under subsection (d) and the local educational agencies that were awarded such subgrants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B57952A6DF54985BB2F9F9383BB75A3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>includes such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C1082679C5496AA5764C0BB3AAA5E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency shall, with respect to the data described in paragraph (2)(B)—</text><subparagraph id="H7D04869253A64539B45501F52589DE5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cross-tabulate and disaggregate the data in the same manner as under subsection (b)(3)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17955E420307475685FE77A005A9E033"><enum>(B)</enum><text>redact all personally identifiable information from such data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB75CA27C31A45DE91C4825A75F66B2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after receiving a report under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall make the report publicly available on the website of the Department of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CF5AAD47A19457D8770237E36AE3332"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funds available for the Department of the Interior</header><text>From the amount appropriated under section 306, the Secretary shall allocate—</text><paragraph id="HD7324C3711C64FD9B66416F5CE1D75ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>0.5 percent of such funds to the Secretary of the Interior for activities under this section with respect to schools operated or funded by the Department of the Interior, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8C3F2B1B03470893BBD1D30616F1E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>0.5 percent of such funds for activities under this section with respect to schools operated in the outlying areas, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H6FB574B14E014AD3A35DE6B86C79B8D6"><enum>III</enum><header>Additional Provisions</header><section id="HEE67F286777740C4ADA60EC9ACDB3E63"><enum>301.</enum><header>Federal regulations</header><subsection id="H25823C9FB30644A3A26BBD26525752A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to reasonably ensure compliance with this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3988E5A2646F4D77ACF6B608CE182CE4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking process</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall use a negotiated rulemaking process described in section 1601 and section 1602 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6571">20 U.S.C. 6571</external-xref>; 6572) except subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(3) of such section 1601 shall apply by substituting <quote>establish a negotiated rulemaking process;</quote> for the text of such subparagraph.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA8200C6FDD0442D7AF62DD04FD98D560"><enum>302.</enum><header>Other schools</header><subsection id="H87986C72E9614D8C9662C32C1845FD3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that schools operated or funded by the Department of Defense Education Activity or otherwise operated or funded by the Department of Defense for the education of military-connected dependents comply with the regulations promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDAF0D121C09043E4B3C27A732697292B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Interior</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that schools operated or funded by the Department of the Interior comply with the regulations promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCCFA483CE0AD46EDA9472E5E6A2F03AF"><enum>303.</enum><header>Limitation of authority</header><subsection id="H9FD78732E9FE490F85D445BEBFB34D87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="HC55A64A5A6154384AD717518F0357A83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to restrict or limit, or allow the Secretary to restrict or limit, any other rights or remedies otherwise available to students or parents under Federal, State, or local law or regulation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H580E5ACC81E24FB79AD3B5658C5C318E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to restrict or limit Federal, State, or local laws, regulations, or polices that provide for more stringent prohibitions or limitations on the use of corporal punishment than the prohibitions or limitations that are provided for in this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70AA3A2B18DE499FBBA0900EAFAA3555" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent a sworn law enforcement officer from carrying out the lawful duties of the officer under otherwise applicable law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE44AC309E0664706967D8B1250F1DFDB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction on enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the enforcement of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), or the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>) and their enforcing regulations.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1CABB8A04287473086B0C53866DA956C" commented="no"><enum>304.</enum><header>Applicability to private schools and home schools</header><subsection id="H5BAA9E251FA4400D81E7849C9E55612D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private schools</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect any private school that does not receive, or does not serve students who receive, support in any form from any program or activity supported, in whole or in part, with Federal funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCA31C88A3A4549E7B82FDDDF140CB337" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Home schools</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H9B783FD583AC4158906B1632B9A51165" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affect a home school, whether or not a home school is treated as a private school or home school under State law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA51FCB797DC4F2B917547CF0DE9239D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider parents who are schooling a child at home as program personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE163C698D0194A3EAF02569BABF8BF0F"><enum>305.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remaining provisions of this Act and the application of such provisions to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section><section id="H7094121CA65445538D454E7CDFEF742B"><enum>306.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

