<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25424-2KK-50-KVG">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2250 IS: Restoring the Armed Career Criminal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2250</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, relating to sentencing of armed
            career criminals.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring the Armed Career Criminal Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id0c20df8edf104c48b57e76b51f68d77c">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Amendments to the armed career criminal act</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 924 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="idc70305c2338647dc89ed154f48e36539">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>(a)(6), (g), (h), (i), (j), or (o) of section 922</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(6), (d), (h), (i), (j), or (o) of section 922, or, except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, subsection (g) of section 922</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idea7181e253d34006b1ef6c4c15a5e819">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fc86e5208b34f1dbd4ee1a23eb5c60f"> <subsection id="id7a38af86c0424e19bf1dcfee86ce39f5"> <enum>(e)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1c97ef8d039a4af78ba86aa1bc8caa18"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Whoever knowingly violates section 922(g) and has 3 or more previous serious felony convictions for offenses committed on occasions different from one another shall be fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 15 years and not more than 30 years, and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall not suspend the sentence of, or grant a probationary sentence to, such person with respect to the conviction under section 922(g).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id076a453843bc46ac91b7da5206f022ad" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="idba00add292e14215a1505dcb0db1b3d0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the term <term>offense punishable by imprisonment for a statutory maximum term of not less than 10 years</term> includes an offense (without regard to the application of any sentencing guideline, statutory criterion, or judgment that may provide for a shorter period of imprisonment within the statutory sentencing range) for which the statute provides for a range in the period of imprisonment that may be imposed at sentencing the maximum term of which is not less than 10 years; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="iddf38449a40204fb8918cbf6415236cd8">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the term <term>serious felony conviction</term> means—</text> <clause id="idd2e9592438bd4eb098bb73d797e9fc6c"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>any conviction by a court that, at the time of sentencing, was a felony offense punishable by imprisonment for a statutory maximum term of not less than 10 years; or </text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id421ca8463b394975aee87e5a006c3769">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any group of convictions for which a court imposed in the same proceeding or in consolidated proceedings a total term of imprisonment of not less than 10 years, regardless of how many years of that total term the defendant served in custody.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id4107b26745484c458afb84735ba1f4df">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Applicability</header>
            <subsection id="id4eeec43381004515b9c8d33f17e346c2">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to any offense committed after the date of enactment of this Act by an individual who, on the date on which the offense is committed, has 3 or more previous serious felony convictions, as defined in subsection (e) of section 924 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id635dc5f0d7c34cb7ba2d6eca84986dc2">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall not be construed to create any right to challenge a sentence imposed under subsection (e) of section 924 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

