<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42FB7FD88AB64E5C97AB7C3B4FB1BBC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3045 IH: West Bank Violence Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3045</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent violence in the West Bank and authorize the imposition of sanctions with respect to any foreign person endangering United States national security and undermining prospects for a two-state solution by committing illegal violent acts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H348FB17FD7AD4513945B5D064CED9B31" style="OLC"><section id="H1A21097E4A1D45D78A40F0BF47A67393" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>West Bank Violence Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7124EBC335B7459A9807244E06E9FC25"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H27DE1C183E90457C8A71CBAD173D2619"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The situation in the West Bank—in particular high levels of extremist settler violence, forced displacement of people and villages, and property destruction—has reached intolerable levels and constitutes a serious threat to the peace, security, and stability of the West Bank and Gaza, Israel, and the broader Middle East region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB8EF918A3044AF3B2992300430BD3AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These actions undermine the foreign policy objectives of the United States, including the viability of a two-state solution and ensuring Israelis and Palestinians can attain equal measures of security, prosperity, and freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DE6D99B12F14197A84208A9886ECA47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>They also undermine the security of Israel and have the potential to lead to broader regional destabilization across the Middle East, threatening United States personnel and interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13B8F5986A4F412CB87BE9FCD515125C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These actions constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H32AB7558C7924B69A6CA8BB9FADE7E56"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subsection id="H10C3C24465AF4B00AAB5F2C2072A66D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person determined by the President to meet any of the following:</text><paragraph id="HB0819C0005A44810A73501F8C1C7D255"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged or attempted to engage in any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA3C463720431409985068CB99F32DD1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Actions, including directing, enacting, implementing, enforcing, or failing to enforce policies, that threaten the peace, security, or stability of the West Bank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25C6A4CA3DB14D269B11147534215B44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Planning, ordering, otherwise directing, or participating in any of the following actions affecting the West Bank:</text><clause id="H1C141999B7434FE9AB25D671B2EC8FE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An act of violence or threat of violence targeting civilians.</text></clause><clause id="H161F3FEEB44D4C79B1B16C3EBAA7D73B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Efforts to place civilians in reasonable fear of violence with the purpose or effect of necessitating a change of residence to avoid such violence.</text></clause><clause id="H723B0FAE7F1F4439AF67E633EA6ADABF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Property destruction.</text></clause><clause id="HF67DB79050C346B18140088B88E39BDA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Seizure or dispossession of property by private actors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF09629956A401BB4251B5F839771FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To be or have been a leader or official of—</text><subparagraph id="H7D54655C5C1049398979E3AB8763456E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity, including any government entity, that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in paragraph (1), (5), or (6) related to the leader’s or official’s tenure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFF57DCB2D3F46D2AC01FB59566B0C80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity whose property and interests in property are blocked under this Act as a result of activities relating to the leader’s or official’s tenure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D297E95E1DA4A1D91BD1596FA93B035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person blocked under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C572BD6CA647EEB77B354B1F80BE34" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C92050EB7034D4597E8187A54AE5996"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To have committed or have attempted to commit, to pose a significant risk of committing, or to have participated in training to commit acts of terrorism affecting the West Bank.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3BFF49E0658415EB23AA51A7DC0B21C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To be a leader or official of an entity sanctioned pursuant to paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8241D9B4873E498188F3192B9108463A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H3FABCB9A7574495FB1F8EF5816955411"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><subparagraph id="H7A0A89DCE53643B9842D648C5A5EB036"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President shall exercise all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any foreign person described in subsection (a) of this section, if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person, including any foreign branch.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25929CF18CA34175AE33A0C4FB4AE348" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The prohibitions in subparagraph (A) include—</text><clause id="HCC8C3D2E19AE422DA028677C26B11189" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="HDBDABBBA39624AAA835301F623236CC9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD8BFEF3960941688103285EF77E6B20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="H03B705D8DA53481B888E81D762BB18FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="HE5F95291B84443669FF7DF22A8B9DF13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HF7228D37200145D1A686D5C7ECF848A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H244DF53681DF4C118F20BA38CCB5E0A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE192830124944E59B889FE04AE7A4B97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H5F4955DCA7B44A32A9D2B65A253344A0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause><clause id="H3F8CC341449A4D7ABA5662CD6DF3B4FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H3B655EBDE1E0495199EE4CDC61385BF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCAFF633CA44A4E78A41077BB58A7C453"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08B1B582C86E4BB0BBF4052EBC156BE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H1628850CEA894384B885F4C683E2BF61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3630593EC132461BB8D6D1CE73119935"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to law enforcement objectives</header><text>Sanctions under section (b)(2) may not be imposed if the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, so determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the person’s entry would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09B71B4B95664E519ED6C7FD74B2F518"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waivers</header><paragraph id="H41CD18CD39EF4E259F873AD2556C072B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the imposition of sanctions under section (b)(2) if the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines that the person’s entry would not be contrary to the interests of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72090106237446D3B360AE545266BD03" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior notice inapplicable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, may, due to the threat to national security risks individuals sanctioned under this section and their actions pose and because of the ability to transfer funds and other assets instantaneously, waive prior notice to such persons of measures to be taken pursuant to this section as such notice would render those measures ineffectual, including for those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked or affected by this section who might have a constitutional presence in the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3D834419F0294AE3BAF4474B0CEE19A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of this Act, including the names of any persons sanctioned by this Act.</text></section><section id="H3F41CDB147454400909AB8F0CE6667C0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H0E3DD25CC93947DE9145159AE7C2620D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H717983C8A6A54AB6B1D422705007E6F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H172BF0ACB3C042358168F3D3A6C26518"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB0B6EF8DDD74F23A12CA25D720131BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>entity</term> means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF5C4677A114E208D294DDF88BC1A80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3494E7940430444BA95FCF2820038819"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H5E28080EF1F0471AA77D81ACC33999A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2490AF389DF749B894EA23674E6006EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a permanent resident alien of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF3A489B32834438BA32D5B5063C5CB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A53FFCC11554A3789C0B5376CACF7E8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a person in the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B12E3A4487B42BA9F69901E9CED115A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>terrorism</term> means an activity that—</text><subparagraph id="H4642F34BA27A494CB5EB027A0D46F2C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involves a violent act or an act dangerous to human life, property, or infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84BC0A05CAE64C3AAEE1C2860835479A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appears to be intended—</text><clause id="H7E2AE84F91994E3A85DEE59409283CFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intimidate or coerce a civilian population;</text></clause><clause id="H4D877629CEE6472C8BE7FA9BEECBEFF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or</text></clause><clause id="HBF388990E5E34EAE9013620EC91C73DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, kidnapping, or hostage-taking.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

