<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9133BE8E94BC4F628C7821BA004B30E2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 716 IH: Supporting the designation of the week of September 15 through September 19, 2025, as “National Clean Energy Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 716</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the week of September 15 through September 19, 2025, as <quote>National Clean Energy Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, across the United States, clean and readily abundant forms of energy are powering more homes and businesses than ever before;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas clean energy generation is readily available from zero- and low-emissions sources;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the clean energy sector is a growing part of the economy and has been a key driver of economic growth in the United States in recent years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas technological innovation can further reduce costs, enhance reliability, and increase deployment of clean energy sources;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the report of the Department of Energy entitled <quote>U.S. Energy &amp; Employment Report 2025</quote> found that, at the end of 2024, the energy and energy efficiency sectors in the United States employed approximately 8,500,000 individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the scaling of affordable and exportable clean energy is essential to reducing global emissions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas clean energy jobs are inherently local, contribute to the growth of local economies, and cannot be outsourced due to the onsite nature of construction, installation, and maintenance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas innovative clean energy solutions and clean energy jobs are part of the energy future of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September 15 through September 19, 2025, should be considered <quote>National Clean Energy Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H566F84BCAB3D4F13B27386733A05FD3E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCD94CD2ED2A14CCB873C7CCFA51B7D31"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="H02768DAFE04F45F3AB3E1B22E104E75A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Clean Energy Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0935EF576A7846A7A5B18EFEB53CE4A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages individuals and organizations across the United States to support commonsense solutions that address the economic, environmental, and energy needs of the United States in the 21st century;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6F32E48BFE4F8DBE5DF27B1CBC6CC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds the work of the Department of Energy National Laboratories in Idaho, Washington, Oregon, California, Nevada, New Mexico, Colorado, Iowa, Illinois, Tennessee, Hawaii, Alaska, South Carolina, Virginia, Washington DC, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and New York;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF6360FEC6074D8893982E6E0455D5D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the Federal Government, States, municipalities, and individuals to invest in affordable, clean, and low-emitting energy technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H057DF641732F4D6E8379068971B13816"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports reliable and affordable energy for Americans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D22A470754D4182832BB1CC09340AED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the role of entrepreneurs and small businesses in ensuring the energy leadership of the United States in the global marketplace and supporting low-cost, clean, and reliable energy in the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

