<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2EE8CF9363CE4D0ABDD68774CF377009" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 382 IH: Exported Carbon Emissions Report Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 382</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to collect, calculate, and publish information regarding emissions of carbon dioxide and methane outside the boundaries of the United States that are associated with exports of fossil fuels, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA41083240ADE4C7AA8EDF7FE89B1093B" style="OLC"><section id="HBD0B13C66DA24836A006EA33C34AB621" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Exported Carbon Emissions Report Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HA6D4A5F802944F3682EC76A4D20FEDED" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comparison of trends in domestic and exported carbon emissions</header><subsection id="H932E5EC7EB3B4FFF84CE3EA8AE097834" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall collect, calculate, and publish information, for each of the previous ten calendar years, on—</text><paragraph id="H7E8D347C642C413F9584BC82B1303326" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total emissions of carbon dioxide and methane that are released within the boundaries of the United States (including the territories of the United States) that are the result of the extraction, processing, transportation, combustion, and other use of fossil fuels; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F3549F522E546AC97F08FCFF1B7EC36" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total emissions of carbon dioxide and methane that are released outside the boundaries of the United States (including the territories of the United States) that are the result of leakage and combustion of fossil fuels produced or refined in the United States and subsequently exported from the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8A639BA61554C34BEAE437187BA5302" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information</header><text>In collecting and calculating information under this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H462A15DC973F4FDFA9B53897ACFD90E3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use the best available scientific information, including, where available—</text><subparagraph id="HAEE65D45274B4D8C8F3B8008A12D71CC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information collected through direct monitoring and measurement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1980C4FFF3D24561A3DB11D43DCD94EF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclosures of carbon dioxide and methane emissions by other national and subnational governments; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H763843ED99AD43A4B1A6C74E470C5E0C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be informed by the established international standards for accounting for greenhouse gas emissions, including the protocols established under the Greenhouse Gas Protocol of the World Business Council for Sustainable Development and the World Resources Institute.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFF6A913CA1A44B7891706EB292D875E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H5B17D916ACEC46EBBF8DBFC0F869A040" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8C92642D68141CD9997A9E27263F0F9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the executive director of the International Energy Agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA38211ADF974865B15543549A5143F2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall make the information collected and calculated pursuant to this section widely available to the public, including by publishing such information on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC3047EE8071042AD88D7D0209653A34E" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of fossil fuel</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fossil fuel</term> means carbon-containing material formed in the Earth’s crust from the remains of prehistoric organisms, including coal, oil, and natural gas.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

