<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-KEL25693-H7X-MC-0F5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 78 IS: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to the authority of Congress and the States to regulate contributions and expenditures intended to affect elections and to enact public financing systems for political campaigns.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 78</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to the authority of Congress and the States to regulate contributions and expenditures intended to affect elections and to enact public financing systems for political campaigns.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="H9FAB20D7533D46A988BEF08ED140FCD4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HFDB6C315618C4A1F9AE9BF18D325AE8D"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification: </text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4096DBDBF5524F60A226D88998A97F5B"><constitution-article id="H78F7F394DB3947DA822FAF83BF4F98CC"><enum> —</enum><section section-type="section-one" id="H49A2BBC2A1334E669CD3D18E4899A0DD"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress and the States may regulate and impose reasonable viewpoint-neutral limitations on the raising and spending of money by candidates and others to influence elections.</text></section><section section-type="section-one" id="HBAD1885D8E4D4884827F4950E5BF5644"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress and the States may regulate and enact systems of public campaign financing, including those designed to restrict the influence of private wealth by offsetting the raising and spending of money by candidates and others to influence elections with increased public funding.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HB03C688913DB425C8A729415D5E1BC04"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress and the States shall have power to implement and enforce this article by appropriate legislation, and may distinguish between natural persons and corporations or other artificial entities created by law, including by prohibiting such entities from spending money to influence elections.</text></section><section section-type="section-one" id="H27552A589ABA4419AEF8C33822E66F47"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this article shall be construed to grant Congress or the States the power to abridge the freedom of the press.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

