<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF1C8916C480446189AB59AC8BE81D1D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 356 IH: District of Columbia Prosecutor Home Rule Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 356</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assign the responsibility for conducting prosecutions for violations of the laws of the District of Columbia to the head of a local prosecutor’s office designated under local law of the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB77F498722084A7C8046002D795A73DF" style="OLC"><section id="H4B88E5437EDF4184B2DFA2FF6DF85EC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Prosecutor Home Rule Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB9B7DB2B75C341B89DE5CB638285F3CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibility of local prosecutor’s office for conduct of all District of Columbia prosecutions</header><subsection id="HE7D14F36C37948538DB8DF42018555D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 23–101, D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking subsections (a) through (f) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7A71E979E0754015964CE23805F46147"><subsection id="HD9BD90582F7943A1AC7D77105912BA7E"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Prosecutions for violations of all police or municipal ordinances or regulations of the District of Columbia and for violations of all penal statutes of the District of Columbia in the nature of police or municipal regulations shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia by the head of the local prosecutor’s office or the assistants of the head of such office, except as may otherwise be provided in any such ordinance, regulation, or statute of the District of Columbia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF74C071A6C244FD0B7D729C64B14A3C3"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In this section, the <quote>local prosecutor’s office</quote> is the office designated under local law of the District of Columbia as the office responsible for conducting prosecutions under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H61B912E8174A4B409E2CB2DAF4E11358"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the authority of the Attorney General of the United States or the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia to exercise jurisdiction concerning violations of the laws of the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEDF69C2E3DE7462781330BB4BB15247F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to violations of District of Columbia ordinances, regulations, and statutes which occur after the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date on which a local law of the District of Columbia which designates the local prosecutor’s office for purposes of section 23–101(b), D.C. Official Code (as amended by subsection (a)), takes effect.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F4C8DA401964943B607FF6E9B17669F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Retention of federal benefits by continuing employees</header><text>With respect to any individual who is an employee of the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia as of the day before the date described in subsection (b) and continues to be employed by the local prosecutor’s office designated for purposes of section 23–101(b), D.C. Official Code (as amended by subsection (a))—</text><paragraph id="HF09486543F8E4D87BCF59E4D8E8D8B59" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual shall continue to be treated as an employee of the Federal Government for purposes of receiving benefits under any chapter of subpart G of part III of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C54311DE66B446B8100544E112A14FE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such designated local prosecutor’s office shall be treated as the employing agency of the individual with respect to such benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

