<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25A72-80W-14-S4S">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2453 IS: Partnership for Indo-Pacific Industrial Resilience Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2453</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to establish and maintain a security
            cooperation initiative to strengthen cooperation among the defense industrial bases of
            the United States and allied and partner countries in the Indo-Pacific region, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnership for Indo-Pacific Industrial Resilience Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="ida58f2058a8df483a946df577328d4eea">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Bolstering industrial resilience with allies in Indo-Pacific region</header>
            <subsection id="id3eb344e1c914454c862989b2febbe27e">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall establish and maintain a security cooperation initiative (referred to in this section as the <quote>Partnership</quote>) to strengthen cooperation among the defense industrial bases of the United States and allied and partner countries in the Indo-Pacific region.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id9eba5042a2934698808ce5d083ee1084">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Objectives</header>
 <text>The objectives of the Partnership shall be the following:</text> <paragraph id="id5ce742bd3c4143f29b1c8e07bffb7015"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>To enable the production and supply of the material necessary for equipping the Armed Forces of the United States and the military forces of allied and partner countries to achieve—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idbeb8ccdb95054b4a8000048537b0c038">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the objectives set forth in the most recent national security strategy report submitted to Congress by the President pursuant to section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</external-xref>);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id04e49bb054d94c01acb8f004b361fae3">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the policy guidance of the Secretary of Defense provided pursuant to section 113(g) of title 10, United States Code; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id1063f4c9991f47729c1aca105b4c19a9">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the future-years defense program submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 221 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id663189e5963a4f3f9eeef8ec0c47360e">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>To strengthen the collective defense industrial base by expanding industrial base capability, capacity, and workforce, including with respect to enhanced supply chain security, interoperability, and resilience among participating countries.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1ff669b3a4d54f0cbe827ddb66ba4bf7">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>To identify and mitigate industrial base vulnerabilities across partner countries.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id39b8fa6d5fcc4df6bc4d2fcd7e46845a">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>To advance research and development activities to provide the Armed Forces of the United States and the military forces of allied and partner countries with systems capable of ensuring technological superiority over potential adversaries.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id643657b78d274994ab6807268b5d7439">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>To promote co-development, co-production, and procurement collaboration in key defense sectors.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id10f349791c7d4c52a904f21ecb896a41">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>To promote defense innovation, improve information sharing, encourage standardization, reduce barriers to cooperation, and otherwise mitigate potential vulnerabilities and facilitate collaboration.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id139d9272d7f84b4cbe3c287470b3f0a4">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Any other matter the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idb15fa9d1f8734921af429a076469d65a"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Designation of senior official</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1de094ae1cd443038b0d4dac032a313c"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior civilian official of the Department of Defense at the Assistant Secretary level or above to lead relevant efforts of the Partnership, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd77d09c4422c48e3863f37946550dad3">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Notification</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense makes or changes a designation under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) a notification of such designation or change.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2d2664141b1d4074970e817c3a2cbf31">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Participation</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall establish a process to determine which allies and partners of the United States (including Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, India, the Philippines, and New Zealand) shall be invited to participate as member countries of the Partnership.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0cfe77a20c0542469388b0a013981204">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Authorities</header>
 <text>To carry out this section, the Secretary of Defense may do the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="ide9bab2c02c034591b4046200c05f7e0c">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Enter into agreements and memoranda of understanding with appropriate counterparts from participating countries.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id51df2c2aa4c94d18a1e6da2733352ad1">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Establish working groups and technical exchanges.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idad6b54b162974361b29bc0d93bf02cec"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Provide technical assistance and capacity-building support to partner countries using authorities available to the Secretary under title 10, United States Code.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida45b4bb7450e44c2b340c16a25018949">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Use funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for international cooperation programs, industrial base resilience, or other relevant purposes.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idbe040b41cff84509a25a22dc215efe9d">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Engage with industry, capital providers, academia, and any other stakeholders necessary to advance the objectives described in subsection (b).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id4b0b086da1094efc8b5593d1c44918d8">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Report and briefing</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2e7204ac6544cd9920ba3ca52727b6e">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Report</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70400f4556b24457a3895b57bcf00666">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2027, and annually thereafter through 2031, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) a report on the status and progress of the Partnership.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id33970826cb1643e597145c65db51f0a7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Elements</header>
 <text>Each report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text>
                        <clause id="idaa05a965b6844380b25a95549b8d6164">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>An assessment of shared industrial base vulnerabilities.</text> </clause> <clause id="id1192080c301c4c8c881572b364350d13"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>An overview of efforts among participating countries to enhance supply chain integrity and resilience.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idfcaa9ca4c8fe4268a75407016702145a">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>A description of any joint defense production or co-development initiative, including any such initiative involving sensitive or classified technologies.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id9da6fc4ab9264b7fb0ef97570d9a34fc">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>An articulation of priority initiatives for the upcoming fiscal year.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idf238f0b775924906b8d38fa31e990bb9">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Recommendations for legislative, regulatory, policy, or resourcing changes to achieve the objectives described in subsection (b).</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id3bb4d823a8bc4e1882088a024ace4fa2">
                            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>Any other matter the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idefd8b529526a4a60b6eefd61af775b71">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Briefing</header>
 <text>Not later than December 1, 2026, and annually thereafter through 2030, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the congressional defense committees with a briefing on the progress made toward achieving the objectives described in subsection (b).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id24d92b533d4c4bb78ef92e34ed0a03e0">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Termination</header>
 <text>The authority under this section shall terminate on December 31, 2030.</text> </subsection> </section> </legis-body> </bill>

