<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25545-0T9-HH-V64">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1694 IS: DHS Restrictions on Confucius Institutes and Chinese Entities of Concern Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1694</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security
                    and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To establish Department of Homeland Security funding restrictions on
            institutions of higher education that have a relationship with Confucius Institutes, and
            for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3EE26509653548B29252805562295EDC">
        <section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="H21F60A318CF34060ADCC3DD51703EAFC">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Restrictions on Confucius Institutes and Chinese Entities of Concern Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H1FE5796FF58743698BE754EB8B7497AE">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Limitations on Confucius Institutes’ host schools</header>
            <subsection id="H600B818E92AF4BE78ED6558BFBAF26DE">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HCABD12FB14684A5DB5E9738491D1C58A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Chinese entity of concern</header> <text>The term <term>Chinese entity of concern</term> means any university or college in the People’s Republic of China that—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HB88C4D621A8346FABE2E983AAE5063C8">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is involved in the implementation of military-civil fusion;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFCDF046FA18460BB4D14943E53CF8DC"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>participates in the Chinese defense industrial base;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2A1DADD29F744C948D965374779DF963">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>is affiliated with the Chinese State Administration for Science, Technology, and Industry for the National Defense;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H29139EC3850C4C01A846807A6108462A">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>receives funding from any organization subordinate to the Central Military Commission of the Chinese Communist Party; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5C199A7C49BF488C8466D4037EA13000">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>provides support to any security, defense, police, or intelligence organization of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H92411322684A42A3954CF5DF1ED8B3FE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Confucius Institute</header>
 <text>The term <term>Confucius Institute</term> means a cultural institute funded by the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD1112C149ECE4C20B7AA276FA1F18A61">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Institution of higher education</header>
 <text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H344263A80570430F8AB37A3037517A65">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Relationship</header>
 <text>The term <term>relationship</term> means, with respect to an institution of higher education, any contract awarded, or agreement entered into, as well as any in-kind donation or gift, received from a Confucius Institute or Chinese entity of concern.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H81922EBA8C4C4F0CA801E924CB703209">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Restrictions on institutions of higher education</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8218b23a0ac540779b56331b0329d033">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the first fiscal year that begins after the date that is 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that an institution of higher education that has a relationship with a Confucius Institute or Chinese entity of concern is ineligible to receive any funds from the Department of Homeland Security, unless the institution of higher education terminates the relationship between the institution of higher education and such Confucius Institute or Chinese entity of concern, as the case may be.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefd1c4aca0e14d969f765db9402c7c3d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Termination</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the termination of a relationship described in paragraph (1), the institution of higher education at issue shall be eligible to receive funds from the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

