<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H29E5245289A44830A44E86D52A90FB8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2510 IH: American-Hellenic-Israeli Eastern Mediterranean Counterterrorism and Maritime Security Partnership Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2510</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance counterterrorism and maritime security cooperation and training within the <quote>3+1</quote> structure between the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H73E7039755944C95B6EB03782A6EE15A" style="OLC"><section id="H6EDC7A1D3AD24F2A999D90F384CC84C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American-Hellenic-Israeli Eastern Mediterranean Counterterrorism and Maritime Security Partnership Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H54DC75ED9BED42ADB2F51B4CA9983A65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to enhance counterterrorism and maritime security cooperation and training within the <quote>3+1</quote> structure between the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></section><section id="HAE36BB0D62B94430ABE990FD2BE3CDBB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7B2D977FA5E442EEA336E70BF4957596"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Israel has been designated as a Major Non-NATO Ally under U.S. law since 1987 and its partnership with the U.S. is critical to the protection of U.S. interests in the Eastern Mediterranean and the surrounding regions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4FF829006A34B8488F2FB868835672E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of State describes Israel as <quote>a great partner to the United States</quote> with an <quote>unbreakable bond</quote> that <quote>has never been stronger.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D081A915DEC48E0A8A7ABA321D04772"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The longstanding strength of the relationship between the U.S. and Israel is demonstrated by the historic significance of the United States being the first country to officially recognize Israel as a state in 1948 and being the first country to recognize Jerusalem as its capital in 2017.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9653E9EA07D643F781C4AA174AAF19A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States remains in solidarity with Israel following the October 7, 2023, terrorist attack committed by Hamas, described by the Department of State as <quote>the deadliest terrorist attack in its 75-year history</quote> which included the deaths of more than forty-four Americans, the most killed in a terrorist attack since the events of September 11, 2001, and the capture of twelve other Americans as hostages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0955ACB17F6B4086B28AB061170A5C5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of State holds that <quote>support for Israel’s security has been a cornerstone of American foreign policy,</quote> as demonstrated by the longstanding support provided to Israel by the U.S.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D89736B29D94EAFA69DDD45A2327501"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States and Israel have defense cooperation agreements including a Mutual Defense Assistance Agreement (1952); a General Security of Information Agreement (1982); a Mutual Logistics Support Agreement (1991); and a Status of Forces Agreement (1994).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD3E24D7EA4419FB5760F672076A807"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States has participated in military exercises with Israel, including Juniper Oak and Juniper Falcon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF39D1C60548747BEB0EB841CBC722993"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States and Israel have engaged in strategic dialogue involving counterterrorism coordination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H055859FF0AC744F99D8886E084C847D9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Greece is a North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Ally that consistently exceeds its obligation of spending 2% of its gross domestic product (GDP) on defense annually. In 2021, Greece spent a higher percentage of its real GDP on defense than any other NATO country. In 2024, Greece spent 3.08% of its real GDP on defense and accordingly continues to rank amongst the highest of all NATO countries. Its significant contributions to the Alliance, including hosting the NATO Missile Firing Installation (NAMFI), the NATO Maritime Interdiction Operations Training Center (NMIOTC), the NATO Integrated Air and Missile Defense (NATO IAMD) Centre of Excellence, have led to it being designated as a <quote>key NATO Ally</quote> by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FB39A90FA324C4F8A472E7BB6F0155D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Greece continues to support U.S. maritime security through hosting the U.S. Navy installation Naval Support Activity Souda Bay on the island of Crete, and Souda Bay provides the only deep-water port in the Mediterranean able to service the largest types of aircraft carriers operated by the U.S.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H788414DF8EA84A4E870CF630B25972C5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Department of State describes Greece as <quote>a leader in the region</quote> and <quote>an important partner to the United States in promoting regional security, stability</quote> with a significant <quote>location at the crossroads of the Western Balkans, North Africa, the Middle East, and NATO’s southeastern flank,</quote> making <quote>Greece a particularly important strategic ally.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H007305D7CB4D4DA88FE385F6616E19A6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Department of State has declared that Greece <quote>shares a deep and abiding security partnership</quote> with the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D055A23A3BF4F8EB8AD8B8B5743AEE9"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States and Greece have defense cooperation agreements including The General Security of Military Information Agreement (GSOMIA) of 1986; the Defense Industrial Cooperation Agreement (DICA) of 1986; the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) of 1951; the Comprehensive Technical Agreement (CTA) of 2001; and the Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement (MDCA) of 1990 (updated in 2019 and in 2021).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1398C1345844A889299169803C80ED5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Greece has participated in multiple bilateral and multilateral military exercises with the United States, including Thracian Cooperation, Stolen Cerberus, Trojan Footprint, Poseidon’s Rage, Orion, Iniochos, Defender Europe, and Alexander the Great. According to the Department of State, each year the Armed Forces of the United States and Greece jointly participate in more than 15 major military exercises.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF082469C00234C949EF567BD84298EAB"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The United States and Greece have engaged in strategic dialogue involving counterterrorism coordination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC1F866DFC344BE83B7487A8D01631C"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Republic of Cyprus (ROC) has been described by the Department of State <quote>as an important partner for regional stability, security, and prosperity</quote> to the United States, with an important <quote>geostrategic position.</quote> In 2025, the Department of State declared that <quote>Cooperation between the United States and the ROC is at a historic high.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89FC50D602F64B5986D5D36812F2866E"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Department of State declared that the United States <quote>works closely with the ROC to advance shared security priorities in the Eastern Mediterranean region.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC66F07AA09AC4B568D9C7C292DD0A5A3"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The United States and the Republic of Cyprus have agreed to a Statement of Intent on bilateral security cooperation in 2018 and a Defense Cooperation Roadmap for 2024–2029 <quote>directed towards promoting stability, security, and prosperity in the region.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE3B93F94FA4C9496DF540D85B16792"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The United States and the Republic of Cyprus have engaged in strategic dialogue involving counterterrorism coordination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B7F98AB0464DB38AA4926DE8D77A06"><enum>(20)</enum><text>In addition to the strong bilateral relationships between the United States and Israel, the United States and Greece, and the United States and the Republic of Cyprus, all four countries share a multilateral relationship under the <quote>3+1</quote> structure established through Eastern Mediterranean Security and Energy Partnership Act of 2019 section of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2020 and the United States-Greece Defense and Interparliamentary Partnership Act of 2021 section of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E6B1DDF0F242478607C372134C1353"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Together, the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus share the mutual goal of ensuring the Eastern Mediterranean is protected from threats of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3153E4449772422FB0C5299E66E363DC"><enum>(22)</enum><text>The United States and Israel have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation. The Department of State has described Israel as <quote>a committed counterterrorism partner, closely coordinating with the United States on a range of counterterrorism initiatives.</quote> This includes previous annual meetings of the Joint Counterterrorism Group between the two countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC05A07D16FBB4C39A22E2C2E7E8D34BC"><enum>(23)</enum><text>The United States and Greece have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation. The Department of State has described Greece as <quote>a steadfast and reliable counterterrorism partner.</quote> This has been demonstrated recently through <quote>improved information exchanges and CT cooperation with the United States through the Joint Security Program pilot.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E5E86A6A6CB41349AE3E915E049BC32"><enum>(24)</enum><text>The United States and the Republic of Cyprus have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation. The Department of State has described the Republic of Cyprus as a partner that has <quote>collaborated closely with the United States bilaterally and as a member of the EU, as well as with other countries on international counterterrorism efforts.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53967F644BBC4429B787CAD2F6DB95A3"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The Department of State reported that <quote>ROC authorities have taken enhanced security measures to prevent terrorist actions following Hamas’s October 7 attack on Israel. The Cyprus National Police conducted increased patrols at airports, harbors, marinas, and ports; assessed high-threat targets—mostly of Israeli and U.S. interests—and provided frequent patrols; provided a police presence at all synagogues in Larnaca, Limassol, and Paphos; increased police coverage at the Israeli Embassy.</quote> Additionally, the Republic of Cyprus has been threatened by Iran-backed terrorist organizations, including Hezbollah.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45E43A727C974ACDAFACF007BF017A43"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Israel and Greece have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation and participate <quote>in regional and multinational counterterrorism exercises</quote> between the two countries, as described by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H080C718FF0154930BE31EB022E76AD3F"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Israel and the Republic of Cyprus have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation and participate <quote>in regional and multinational counterterrorism exercises</quote> between the two countries, as described by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H267042542C1D49D8AA1B5E31C3509CC0"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Greece and the Republic of Cyprus have a history of strong counterterrorism cooperation and participate <quote>in regional and multinational counterterrorism exercises</quote> between the two countries, as described by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69E7D64E0225435786B46DFA91BA3824"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus have a history of strong trilateral counterterrorism cooperation reflected through multiple types of engagement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36FB0B71E764F63A0039E9457CF1B57"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The foreign ministers of Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus, and the United States Secretary of State, have collectively met multiple times to discuss multilateral security issues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE7BA4EF0FBB4C45B0247B7734D25E6C"><enum>(31)</enum><text>The Cyprus Center for Land, Open-seas, and Port Security (C.Y.C.L.O.P.S.), initially funded by the United States State Department’s Export Control and Related Border Security (EXBS) program through a Memorandum of Understanding between the Republic of Cyprus and the USA, signed on September 12, 2020, has served as an important training center for the United States. The United States has conducted multiple security cooperation initiatives utilizing C.Y.C.L.O.P.S. including the U.S. Department of State’s Office of Weapons of Mass Destruction Terrorism <quote>Saharan Fox</quote> workshop.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A84CAC00EC147F0863F735A3D6BB2DB"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Together, the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus share the mutual goal of ensuring the Eastern Mediterranean is protected from breaches of maritime security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89178AE0BBE64D658811AE631FB0BDA3"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Souda Bay, Crete, has served as an important location for the United States to conduct maritime security initiatives since 1969 and has long been considered the most essential location for supporting U.S. naval activity in the Mediterranean. In addition to providing the only port in the region able to sustain the largest aircraft carriers operated by the United Sates, it’s location at the junction between Europe, Africa, and Asia make it a location of great geostrategic value.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF170B83D3DB3498A89F4D770EBA1DD6F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HD6E3E754B5A149169750472EE05B0592"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish a security subcomponent of the <quote>3+1</quote> structure between the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC8F185103C407F94CB97D370847B29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to expand official strategic engagement with Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus regarding counterterrorism and maritime security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE228EE7ADB4043EE83C601A4DE7D361F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase support for joint counterterrorism and maritime security exercises among Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE4EF3504A8844CF926C91A06B8C0C3F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to increase participation in multilateral dialogues on counterterrorism and maritime security conducted among the United States, Israel, Greece and the Republic of Cyprus;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA13DD4C0491349108335273673E3E05E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to increase support for the participation of Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus in the Combating Terrorism Fellowship Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B3C25E993544BE29776E9F88B8160BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to expand United States support for counterterrorism initiatives at C.Y.C.L.O.P.S. (Cyprus Center for Land, Open-seas, and Port Security) in the Republic of Cyprus and develop deeper cooperation with the latter regarding counterterrorism and maritime security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F2D62A2AC45496B8E338138EDE08A61"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to expand United States support for maritime security initiatives at the Greek Souda Naval Base in Greece and develop deeper cooperation with the latter regarding counterterrorism and maritime security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B91CAB43FA43EC83455D100B881197"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to further support a robust International Military Education and Training (IMET) programming with Israel, Greece and the Republic of Cyprus, which will increase interoperability with the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22FA3B5DC13A434B82C7D6CD19D635F2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to encourage counterterrorism, border and maritime security investments in Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F17437C86214546878581B474629E61"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to increase counterterrorism intelligence sharing and maritime domain awareness cooperation with Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4B46CFA81075437689EA9E3F1F1842D5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Elimination of scheduled termination of Cyprus, Greece, Israel, and the United States 3+1 Interparliamentary Group</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1316 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 is amended by striking subsection (e).</text></section><section id="H691A20E79BCE466C925D5770B3003710"><enum>6.</enum><header>Israel, Greece, Cyprus, and the United States Interparliamentary Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group</header><subsection id="HEC47E3B3716F4E8486FEB6D06F00336B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a group, to be known as the <quote>Israel, Greece, Cyprus, and the United States Interparliamentary Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group</quote> to serve as a security focused legislative subcomponent to the 3+1 interparliamentary group established in Section 1316 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA862BDCA0D442CA9BF8D89A6D6C88D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The group established under subsection (a) shall include a group of not more than 6 Members of the United States Senate and 6 Members of the United States House of Representatives, who shall be appointed jointly by the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate and the speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives, respectively. Membership shall include 2 Members of Congress who serve on an appropriate congressional committee. </text></subsection><subsection id="HBB4371F49F2D42CABF448564BE26517D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Not less frequently than twice each year, the United States Interparliamentary Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group shall meet with Israeli, Cypriot, and Greek parliamentary counterpart members to discuss issues on the agenda of the legislative branch of the Governments of Israel, Greece, the Republic of Cyprus, and the United States regarding counterterrorism and maritime security.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA3D283F311DA423B91324891FC81AEA9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Israel, Greece, Cyprus, and United States Interexecutive Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group</header><subsection id="H3F02B69AD2864C2099844D5CC6FD2230"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a group, to be known as the <quote>Israel, Greece, Cyprus, and United States Interexecutive Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group</quote> to serve as a security focused executive component to the <quote>3+1</quote> structure.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7852738415924C4481D66A6FF6DE8713"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Israel, Greece, Cyprus, and the United States Interexecutive Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group shall include a designated officer from:</text><paragraph id="H5B0871A12F954AFB8438CFAA1F8A6A55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Department of State, appointed by the United States Secretary of State.</text><subparagraph id="H4829F4A303A14E90B332E95F3F9D3AAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The responsibilities of this designated officer as established in Sec. 7. may be assigned to an existing officer within the Department of State to fulfil the requirements of Sec. 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H515390E2181941D484D2B29F6EF9E17A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States Department of Defense, appointed by the United States Secretary of Defense.</text><subparagraph id="H89740AD01DE246D7ADD73E071E1B3758"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The responsibilities of this designated officer as established in Sec. 7. may be assigned to an existing officer within the Department of Defense to fulfil the requirements of Sec. 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31EBC45020D245519F283C39AF51F044"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States Department of Homeland Security, appointed by the United States Secretary of Homeland Security.</text><subparagraph id="H057E8DBB6AD74B49BEB25F6C0F0940DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The responsibilities of this designated officer as established in Sec. 7. may be assigned to an existing officer within the Department of Homeland Security to fulfil the requirements of Sec. 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2F6C708EDBE40CE84D5CD41B93552D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Not less frequently than twice each year, the United States Interexecutive Eastern Mediterranean Security Cooperation Group shall meet with Israeli, Cypriot, and Greek executive counterpart members to discuss issues on the agenda of the executive branch of the Governments of Israel, Greece, the Republic of Cyprus, and the United States regarding counterterrorism and maritime security.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3CE12E20FF304F5DA4B68FE8CF79FCCF"><enum>8.</enum><header>3+1 counterterrorism cooperation training structure</header><subsection id="H48B1BD63256C40CAA13D5E230DC5126F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall establish a counterterrorism training program, to be known as the <quote>Counterterrorism Education for Readiness Building in the East-Mediterranean Region to Unify Security Program</quote> or <quote>CERBERUS</quote>, which shall—</text><paragraph id="H8AB28B82DA1E43CDB0E85552F588D0B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be used at the Cyprus Center for Land, Open-seas, and Port Security, provided that the Government of the Republic of Cyprus agrees so, with the purpose of increasing counterterrorism cooperation and interoperability between the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C7E7E203E14EF68627319D1132A574"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be available to ministry, agency, and headquarters level organizations for such countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF89718D577D4FF39945D00D8CCE74FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional required elements of training</header><text>The training program established under subsection (a) shall promote respect for legitimate civilian authority within the country to which the assistance is provided.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1F6A44862954905B47711B78F83E343"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports and briefings</header><paragraph id="HEA69C676181548DBB21B8F69FECDAD88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of the creation and implementation of the training program established under subsection (a) until the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines the training has been established and made available to the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B167A6BDE3A42679AD234FF784A97A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training structure report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines such training program has been established and made available to the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus, they shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the training structure they have created.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC140CF4A6AE943C9AD697B8F88D435AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training briefing</header><text>Following the submission of the report required by paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees an annual briefing on the results of such training program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H10B75A80CEE641638F68DC1E76C6A838"><enum>9.</enum><header>Establishing a 3+1 maritime security cooperation training structure</header><subsection id="HC7425B53FB7F42B99A92AF11D43FFE15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall—</text><paragraph id="H49BC28CAC2114002B68D868BBEAAC840"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create a training program to be used at the Greek Souda Naval Base, provided that the Government of Greece agrees, with the purpose of increasing maritime security cooperation and interoperability between the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3328CA6F36294790969ABBCC6424AA41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make available such training to ministry, agency, and headquarters level organizations for such countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA05A1DBA10A34CF5AA2A5F93BDFE5838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The provision of assistance and training under this section may be referred to as <quote>Training and Readiness Initiative for Regional East-Mediterranean Maritime-Security Enforcement</quote> or <quote>TRIREME</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H06AC4B388E8E403597BC69C762DF7E0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required elements of training</header><text>Training provided under subsection (b) shall include elements that promote respect for legitimate civilian authority within the country to which the assistance is provided.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40C83FA76BBD4368B54605CECC7F6B9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports and briefings</header><paragraph id="H044A5029EAF842BEA41DCB73B76E2B0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the status of the creation and implementation of the training established in Sec. 9. until the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines the training has been established and made available to the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EA36DBDEED344B4BD5DA2F036E3C1D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training structure report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after which the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines the training has been established and made available to the United States, Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus, they shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the training structure they have created.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BA8D75EB306477EA848036C1F6F0EB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training briefing</header><text>Following the submission of the report required by Sec. 9(5)(A)(i), on an annual basis the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit provide a briefing on the results of the training established through Sec. 9. to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4CB75FADF814411B84A9496BAD40495"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="HC484471F50074EE5A65F93AB1260216B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy on counterterroism cooperation in the 3+1 structure</header><paragraph id="HDE5995ED0FEF4417987DFEF4BE2AAA72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy on enhanced counterterrorism cooperation with Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7842D1F6B71F46B3A3A58BC79D826E21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF075BFB200164F858E88D11A69547D45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy on maritime security cooperation in the 3+1 structure</header><paragraph id="HC818D8D2F08844A6AFAB30D5A85FAD0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy on enhanced maritime security cooperation with Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFECC5B4A36D6472489E93979BF4F624E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD7AEA9D998BF43FDB7E11C6AD0A0A69B"><enum>11.</enum><header>Eliminating certain limitations and exclusions regarding defense articles and requirements regarding security assistance and sales with respect to the Republic of Cyprus</header><subsection id="H1B7C17B58E6A4B2D9DCB87A9E288AD0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination of limitations and exclusions regarding defense articles</header><text>Section 1250A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2373">22 U.S.C. 2373</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H58E5BC7513B44E8DA238251B43723FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Repeal of prohibition on</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Sense of Congress regarding</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACA829956EAD49488CE5CCA503FF7A68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Sense of Congress</header-in-text>.—It is the sense of Congress that</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>It is the sense of Congress that—</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C44BC9B048141E391927EB9DCDEAFD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b), (c), and (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H446AF00FA88C485081B969489343559B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of requirements regarding security assistance and certain sales</header><text>Section 620C of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2373">22 U.S.C. 2373</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (d) and (e).</text></subsection></section><section id="H599EC7A0728445E9AC962DF64E284283"><enum>12.</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header><subsection id="HCB07773174094DDBBBADC8BAC1C77288"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><paragraph id="H97DD5BFBB15E49A7A515E681C10F6757"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $5,000,000 to create new facilities at, and acquire new equipment for, the Cyprus Center for Land, Open-seas, and Port Security, in coordination with Minister of Defence of the Republic of Cyprus, for the purposes of counterterrorism cooperation training which can be used to carry out the requirements of section (9).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC8FCEE9EEE4587BDA96B46021A5957"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Following the creation of facilities and acquisition of equipment by the Department of Defense for the purposes specified in paragraph (1), such facilities and equipment is authorized to be made available to the Government of the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD7013D44FBE4EB68222FD6984428B69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There are authorized to be made available to the Government of the Republic of Cyprus $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 for annual general support of the Cyprus Center for Land, Open-seas, and Port Security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D17AB5532694547A57302689C867B31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 for the creation and implementation of the training program in section (8).</text></subsection><subsection id="H06F25CEE433148548A54CB5DB7B3AFFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 for the creation and implementation of the training program in section (9).</text></subsection><subsection id="H58A38ECF1DE64E5D8DD96DA94E78A45C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>IMET cooperation with Israel, Greece, and the Republic of Cyprus</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, to enhance interoperability and capabilities for joint operations and for counterterrorism and maritime security education—</text><paragraph id="H326B2B73A1EA4E86ABF1E13CE9CDBBDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for International Military Education and Training (IMET) assistance for Israel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2B86D66E5B4643A7306C31F847C00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$250,000 for International Military Education and Training (IMET) assistance for Greece; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H473EEE98168648C2A897B50CF1026504"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$250,000 for International Military Education and Training (IMET) assistance for the Republic of Cyprus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H985B3AE74F964F48BB7A57C2FCB315DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expanding maritime security training functions of the Greek Souda navy base</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $5,000,000 to create new facilities at, and acquire new equipment for, the Greek Souda Naval Base, in coordination with Minister of Defence of Greece, for the purposes of maritime security training which can be used to carry out section (9).</text><paragraph id="HED38A1E97A314C7EA13895BF53842DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Following the creation of facilities and acquisition of equipment by the Department of Defense for the purposes specified in Sec 11 (1) (A), such facilities and equipment is authorized to be made available to the Government of Greece.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H425ED98AFD2A4D20BE75EBF72E63C159"><enum>(f)</enum><header>General support</header><text>There is authorized to be made available to the Government of Greece $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 for annual general support of the facilities created through section (10).</text></subsection></section><section id="HBCF5B8AF3A4A49699D8BBB6894953147"><enum>13.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committee</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HC11C2FE2B475446DBEC998C463A52E67"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCE50494EEA043C1A6AC88DCA2336FA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

