<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0732DB59062F45868D58C572CB5BE146" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1164 IH: Fair Disaster Assistance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1164</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250210">February 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to ensure that certain applicants for assistance after a declared major disaster do not receive a notice of denial while the applicant has a pending insurance claim for disaster-related losses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H44B9C73FA0EA43BE847DEE983721B229" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8EA8EEB84293400AA25818E0CFA39D72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Disaster Assistance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H50A86D007F0E4984BD0D80E171010087"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on denial of assistance notification before insurance claim determination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue such regulations as are necessary to ensure that an applicant for assistance under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) that has indicated ownership of an insurance policy for a home or facility damaged by a major disaster declared under section 401 of such Act that is owned by such applicant does not receive a notice that indicates a denial of assistance before a final determination has been made regarding the approval or denial of a claim under such policy.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

