<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25032-NLV-YP-XDY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S76 IS: Setting Manageable Analysis Requirements in Text Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 76</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to improve the effectiveness of major rules in accomplishing their regulatory objectives by promoting retrospective review, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Setting Manageable Analysis Requirements in Text Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9C507CDD2DD744AE93559D7A7F1A9CCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Incorporating retrospective review into new major rules</header><subsection id="idB96A45790CD046B1994EFEDFF6B77C6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idC45711A3C131492DA896751F5B25B9B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 551—</text><subparagraph id="id380AD8EC86324B45B104122BC7E96738"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2CEDAFBE5475403A88BAD9EBECABB284"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAD655AD9109C41AD99B5672080A8EB34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F1FCEFB8B234F2B9510EE7CBDCD6DAA"><paragraph id="id9ac39d9dc82e441f992268944ce2ab47"><enum>(15)</enum><text><term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget established under section 3503 of title 44 and any successor to that office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1739C0B71C094B10A01B6FBC1F7DBDD7"><enum>(16)</enum><text><term>major rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator finds has resulted in or is likely to result in—</text><subparagraph id="id1834ad018c204021b01691ebc8e05c4e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30677dd1108144f6aa4870ce7da48a09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, or local government agencies, or geographic regions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27F3FAB1A8E8404C9693E49BF6CD246B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, health, safety, the environment, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89B880CAF5374C4E91D0A0BB14258732"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 553, by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48C04413071E418880EF4C441617F5B2"><subsection id="idDE4F109338C447BC87235BDC1BD6DCC0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Major rule frameworks</header><paragraph id="idD8ED675F25904899BA6C05E18F6BD436"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id2f8b13302246493f832dd6f1a53eb874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a proposed rule published by an agency in the Federal Register that the agency reasonably expects would meet the definition of a major rule, the agency shall include a potential framework for assessing the implemented rule, which shall include a general statement of how the agency intends to measure the effectiveness of the rule; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e3d17032ffc44a590f116521667950f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a final major rule published by an agency in the Federal Register, including a major rule that the agency did not initially reasonably expect would meet the definition of a major rule under subparagraph (A), the agency shall include a framework for assessing the major rule under paragraph (2), which shall include—</text><clause id="id0febb924c0a04f67a0c8ebf66a262a4c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement of the regulatory objectives of the major rule, including a summary of the societal benefit and cost of the major rule;</text></clause><clause id="idc1551f07d54a4eb8a35b82e686a3f8ae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the methodology by which the agency plans to analyze the qualitative and quantitative outcomes of the major rule so that the agency can assess—</text><subclause id="id4fa908f6e81a4a82a1af6e4c8e8b99fc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the effectiveness and benefits of the major rule in producing the regulatory objectives of the major rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idfd4e088199794bba94e4b240f4589e86"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the effects and costs of the major rule on regulated and other affected entities;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idd6c2e558eb67474e8f15d537a0f30884"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan for gathering data, including public input, regarding the methodology described in clause (ii) on an ongoing basis or at periodic times; and</text></clause><clause id="id33dd8971e2db4e298e90ee36325e4ea2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a time frame, as appropriate to the major rule and not more than 10 years after the effective date of the major rule, under which the agency shall conduct the assessment of the major rule in accordance with paragraph (2)(A). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC9DD67C97551496E995E6FC5B16708FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header><subparagraph id="idAD8D8257C234485A8E6999EDAF0D7BC4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agency shall assess the data gathered under paragraph (1)(B)(iii), using the methodology set forth in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) or any other appropriate methodology developed after the issuance of a final major rule—</text><clause id="id534ECFC50AE2469A9F44A09C96004599"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to analyze how the actual benefits and costs of the major rule may have varied from those anticipated at the time the major rule was issued; and</text></clause><clause id="id3E2454087ADD4A31ADEDDAB7A4B5C02F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether—</text><subclause id="id5592D15054784F9583CFFAB5E55AC389"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the major rule is accomplishing the regulatory objective of the major rule;</text></subclause><subclause id="idE8673DFBBD8D4E92A1AA4ED9AB65409F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the major rule has been rendered unnecessary, taking into consideration—</text><item id="idF53DE9F8889A4EA190C11E0D6F2BD9FB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>changes in the subject area affected by the major rule; and</text></item><item id="id89A9E50A086D41F6941252BFB51924A3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whether the major rule overlaps with, duplicates, or conflicts with other rules or, to the extent feasible, State and local government regulations;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id43E2911D6EC34CDBB366586219456495"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the major rule needs to be expanded, streamlined, or otherwise modified in order to accomplish the regulatory objective of the major rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id92368B9B002C4F1CA303E146EB89BB69"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other alternatives to the major rule or a modification of the major rule could better achieve the regulatory objective of the major rule by increasing the benefits of the major rule or imposing a smaller burden on society, or both, taking into consideration any changes in the regulatory environment that may have made the major rule more or less necessary or effective, and any cost already incurred.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB0DE8E6F47D44D8DB713A47237DD4809"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Different methodology</header><text>If an agency uses a methodology other than the methodology set forth in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) to assess data under subparagraph (A), the agency shall include notification of the revised methodology and an explanation of the changes in circumstances that necessitated the use of that other methodology as part of the notice required under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6418016577B14AE2A7169B833EAB0F8C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Subsequent assessments</header><text>If, after an assessment of a major rule under subparagraph (A), an agency determines that the major rule will remain in effect with or without modification, the agency shall, in consultation with the Administrator, include with the assessment produced under subparagraph (A) a list of circumstances or events that would necessitate a subsequent review in accordance with subparagraph (A) to ensure that the major rule continues to meet the regulatory objective of the major rule.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8F970B1289ED41C48B7AB2D150CAFFB5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which an agency completes an assessment of a major rule under subparagraph (A), the agency shall publish prominently on the website of the agency the results of the assessment, including the circumstances or events that would necessitate a subsequent assessment of the major rule under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD7946002D880409AB0A3C2B395326C72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency head responsibilities</header><text>The head of each agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="ida9d179e0291d4d4486a54160e225e4fb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversee the timely compliance of the agency with this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2b2ed611a9b49dba42a7acb10aa75fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the results of each assessment conducted under paragraph (2) are published promptly in accordance with paragraph (2)(D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB7643DB768D844B7855BFBC5492C2A6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>OMB oversight</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="idc1d5963b160f4815acc85d03ab24d7c1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidance for agencies regarding the development of the framework under paragraph (1) and the conduct of the assessments under paragraph (2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7E62FD5618143DEAA33E9560CCD5D6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage and assist agencies to streamline and coordinate the assessment of major rules with similar or related regulatory objectives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id053BC526AAC64EEAB2E3667A4AD219D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>exempt an agency from including the framework required under paragraph (1)(B) when publishing a final major rule, if—</text><clause id="id82C21B63534D456BB409140586E5B499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency did not issue a notice of proposed rule making for the major rule in order to provide a timely response to an emergency or comply with a statutorily imposed deadline, in accordance with paragraph (6)(B); or</text></clause><clause id="idaff17b874f6f4aefb9eadd166c8f20a8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator determines that— </text><subclause id="id4F9A5FD2C5CA4A9EB7A7CBDBF673D035"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the major final rule falls within a category of major rules that are routine or periodic in nature, including those issued on an annual basis in order to put in place annual spending programs; or </text></subclause><subclause id="idCB859C97A29B4680BC4D42BACB9D6360"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for any other reason, the conduct of an assessment would be impracticable, unnecessary, or contrary to the public interest; and </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD391BF0E16114EA6A6A86C803A9095B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>extend the deadline specified by an agency for an assessment of a major rule under paragraph (1)(B)(iv) or paragraph (2)(C) for a period of not more than 90 days if the agency justifies why the agency is unable to complete the assessment by that deadline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8FBAEF9E558A4229AE46151EBB231DA0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect—</text><subparagraph id="id1A73DF5B48734B2DB73B9CDEE7D1E157"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the authority of an agency to assess or modify a major rule of the agency earlier than the end of the time frame specified for the major rule under paragraph (1)(B)(iv); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0DBC0B50A5D24A0EB1BC03A5DB4F2141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other provision of law that requires an agency to conduct retrospective reviews of rules issued by the agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF9683D756C9143D5AACB97CDEBA342B6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applicability</header><subparagraph id="idE195E9E4A06D4D97838DAC245887CC86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to—</text><clause id="id78CFA800E1914AE884D3CA56EB2DA4C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a major rule of an agency—</text><subclause id="id747C6083882B4E7A8F611A8DF29C62C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the Administrator reviewed before the date of enactment of this subsection;</text></subclause><subclause id="idBEDB785096214091A2E81E62C6DFED78"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for which the agency is required to conduct a retrospective review under—</text><item id="id22962D27AFDD4BDF91D5042615A6CA19"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>section 2222 of the Economic Growth and Regulatory Paperwork Reduction Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3311">12 U.S.C. 3311</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="id6F25E2D9C6664C519387B9A768E49AD2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>section 170(d) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5370">12 U.S.C. 5370(d)</external-xref>); or</text></item><item id="id49670331557548B091BC1B685A3E0DEE"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any other provision of law with requirements that the Administrator determines—</text><subitem id="idB9B27F94BFAD484AB3EBE5731B30C992"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>include robust public participation;</text></subitem><subitem id="idCB8C37B7E47C41A4BC8A2055C6EAACAA"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>include significant agency consideration and analysis of whether the rule is achieving the regulatory objective of the rule; and</text></subitem><subitem id="id7C479BC5973741368534B0E454CF9EBD"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>meet, are substantially similar to, or exceed the requirements of this subsection;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="id96C102B3B98548A19337A799514750FC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for which the authorizing statute of the rule is subject to periodic authorization by Congress not less frequently than once every 10 years; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id7040AFE7705E41F2B975EB5FA5EA37DD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>for which the authorizing statute of the rule requires the promulgation of a new or revised rule not less frequently than once every 10 years; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3D47BE3C19624A9D963CCBF3C1D9F8B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interpretative rules, general statements of policy, or rules of agency organization, procedure, or practice.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3CEFF4EBA88C47A2A84154D7BEB2198E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good cause exemption</header><text>In the case of a major rule for which an agency has not issued a notice of proposed rule making, the agency shall publish the framework required under paragraph (1)(B) in the Federal Register not later than 6 months after the date on which the agency publishes the final major rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5276AD859C374C0FAF28C24599F91F52"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><subparagraph id="id3D3EB80139084007B9351D2AF58B57AD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Judicial review of agency compliance with this subsection—</text><clause id="id7D1594C64B4442B9B7D5880187BDB267"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be strictly limited to—</text><subclause id="idE8704059B69A4415AEDCB4BA28FDD647"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether an agency published the framework for assessment of a major rule described in paragraph (1); or</text></subclause><subclause id="id627F98E4A9EC4C748880D45483BE2151"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether an agency published the assessment or subsequent assessment of a major rule described in subparagraphs (A), (C), and (D) of paragraph (2); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idCBA0DEA4C4B5433DA676761BF779F333"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not include a substantive review of the framework, assessment, or action of an agency under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id874C1AAD572D41CE9FF850EEA27A2435"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remedy available</header><text>In granting relief in an action brought under subparagraph (A), a court may only issue an order remanding the major rule to the agency to comply with paragraph (1) or subparagraph (A), (C), or (D) of paragraph (2), as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id725F0F7597214AE9BB8A55A42CE5B10D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effective date of major rule</header><text>If, in an action brought under subparagraph (A)(i), a court determines that the agency did not comply, the major rule shall take effect notwithstanding any order issued by the court.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9240309CA1124DDA8D1E99D9F7BA5165"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>Any determination, action, or inaction of the Administrator shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA4A6C510E9174AE4A31A1ECD7ECD45E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

