<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25718-Y0H-4M-NK1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2052 IS: Flood Insurance Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the
                following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban
                    Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require that certain
 information is made publicly available, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flood Insurance Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H80ABC9258F5947EA9252AA515949F628"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public availability of program information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of chapter II of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H854D2A4CDFC945EB93805CA9E2496205"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E753D90DD7B4B939AC1AB67EBB83BED"><enum>1349.</enum><header>Public availability of program information</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF43164D8F9414105B9E44B76C32A30D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ECBE7DA9E894170B8762FF92C45028A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>loss ratio</term> means, with respect to the national flood insurance program in a fiscal year, the ratio of the amount of claims paid under that program during that fiscal year to the amount of premiums paid under that program during that fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34E481248C154071A22DEABC020A8911"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>multiple-loss property</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8E5AF418A1C410D8A4EAE7180E2EB33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a repetitive loss structure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idACC824239315446CAC7B1F65FD385F4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a severe repetitive loss structure, as that term is defined in section 1366(h).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1DB2664E8E24348AFDFAFF0547A11D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Flood risk information</header><paragraph id="HA588059935F4406DBE85C02402CBB399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate the national flood insurance program becoming a source of information and data for research and development of technology that better understands flooding, the risk of flooding, and the predictability of the perils of flooding, the Administrator shall make publicly available all data, models, assessments, analytical tools, and other information in the possession of the Administrator relating to that program under this title that is used in assessing flood risk or identifying and establishing flood elevations and premiums, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1043A34469934E3CAEDC04074FC1DAF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data relating to risk on individual properties, loss ratio information, and other information identifying losses under that program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD43D394025B413D92D6034E7C26459D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>current and historical policy information, limited to the amount and term only, for properties covered by flood insurance under the national flood insurance program (as of the date on which the information is made available) and for properties that are no longer covered by flood insurance under the national flood insurance program (as of the date on which the information is made available);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41923F68D39B4717B2D1459E6AEC7816"><enum>(C)</enum><text>current and historical claims information, limited to the date and amount paid only, for properties covered by flood insurance under the national flood insurance program (as of the date on which the information is made available) and for properties that are no longer covered by flood insurance under the national flood insurance program (as of the date on which the information is made available);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93FC13E663084EAA852747D39AF69D1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identification of whether a property was constructed before or after the effective date of the first flood insurance rate map for the community in which that property is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF5256FA1E9141DFBAF5599AC68E19A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identification of properties that have been mitigated through elevation, a buyout, or any other mitigation action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DF7FC7BE524589A22F1EC906B876D4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identification of multiple-loss properties with respect to which mitigation measures have not been undertaken.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE0032A701C4EA7AB289C2EA2B4813F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Open source data system</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall establish an open source data system by which all information required to be made publicly available by that paragraph may be accessed by the public on an immediate basis by electronic means.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H992C6469DA444F72AC8911AC700AFC8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish and maintain a publicly searchable database that provides information about each community participating in the national flood insurance program, which shall include the following information:</text><paragraph id="HC5B22A3D5D804184B7F6B559F5662C4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The status of the compliance by that community with the requirements of that program, including any findings of noncompliance, the status of any enforcement actions initiated by a State or by the Administrator, and the number of days of any such continuing noncompliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF73C9FA1C454421A567C103A5171FA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of properties located in areas having special flood hazards in the community that were built before the effective date of the first flood insurance rate map for the community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32BEF8B9E3D94152B5133E4EEB67BFAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of properties located in areas having special flood hazards in the community that were built after the effective date of the first flood insurance rate map for the community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD1960229B5441E4A729CF0E3643DFA6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The total number of current and historical claims located outside areas having special flood hazards in the community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30C20DBA4EA0470E89A268BF86EC1185"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The total number of multiple-loss properties in the community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD54EA924CC9F4AB7B183E3397EE66F0C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The portion of the community, stated as a percentage and in terms of square miles, that is located within areas having special flood hazards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC4F920447084A8FB26319E206AFA233"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of properties</header><text>The information provided pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) shall— </text><paragraph id="id8DE106A119894DFB9431D26B7BFEE114"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be based on data that identifies properties at the ZIP Code or census block level; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7742468926CE4904B00F42489912536F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to a property, include the name of the community and State in which the property is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D58A8E1CB9D4C0FB516B723EE43AB72"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifiable information</header><text>The information provided pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) shall be disclosed in a format that does not reveal individually identifiable information about property owners in accordance with section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


