<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD78A9EEFA07242739632BA2684E5D46E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2856 IH: Great Lakes and National Weather Service Funding Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2856</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the impoundment, transfer, or reprogramming of certain Federal funds made available to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2CC2ABE173D4EE58384977E65CD59CD" style="OLC"><section id="H8BB0E990039C423293F72772A6B0FF54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes and National Weather Service Funding Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA1B9EC6F68994BB6A3E2C00A96826F32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on deferral or transfer of certain Federal funds made available to NOAA</header><subsection id="H9A1D836AACC24E3A8FECC921803849EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Impoundment Control Act of 1974, discretionary appropriations (including amounts made available by the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/4">Public Law 119–4</external-xref>)) made available for the National Weather Service and the Great Lakes Region may not be impounded, transferred, or reprogrammed unless specific statutory authority is enacted into law after the date of the enactment of this Act, with express reference to this Act, permitting such an impoundment, transfer, or reprogramming.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9EF0E04EF2F049DFBFC45087862F9FED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall certify that the Administrator is in compliance with the requirements of this Act to the following committees:</text><paragraph id="H71943F3A3A6B4A16A5776D839BBE1179"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C3D5CAD89EF46D9A12E410570776E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40BB5224E123458B9B3DBA1761D2CE4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB892729A98A461DA5922838BBA28FD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEA17202FCF04F308A975027936EEE6F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

