<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBEF2D9FBB7164E43B238A4B9746BC444" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 682 IH: Heartbeat Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 682</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit abortion in cases where a fetal heartbeat is detectable.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H14F90CC313BF4E63AD310DE0928D7F0D" style="OLC"><section id="H24903BE065A0479DBAB80601A920233F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heartbeat Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF0935DB4D78749539771FD57934B4977"><enum>2.</enum><header>Abortions prohibited without a check for fetal heartbeat, or if a fetal heartbeat is detectable</header><subsection id="HFA4BDEFEEC9B4F68991FC7BF7C83AF31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Abortions prohibited without a check for fetal heartbeat, or if a fetal heartbeat is detectable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">Chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7C9576B598664E2D9F0B041ECD08B2D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the chapter heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Partial-Birth</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF66AC8A549254EFC8CCEA380E2DFC57D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 1531 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE95D4161F70D4A3AAE335002E855F2FF" style="USC"><section id="H0816B2691F074683B35528E30986F654"><enum>1532.</enum><header>Abortions prohibited without a check for fetal heartbeat, or if a fetal heartbeat is detectable</header><subsection id="H1E6A18C20BE34E5C9726FD4DCDB939D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>Any physician who knowingly performs an abortion and thereby kills a human unborn child—</text><paragraph id="HD62CB2D0A3294925868BBB98A9DEE0F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without determining, according to standard medical practice, whether the unborn child has a detectable heartbeat;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8CB4E0E4D149BE99D68F762D8B12BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>without informing the mother of the results of that determination; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EFF1E29C2AE417E836518272FA95619"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after determining, according to standard medical practice, that the unborn child has a detectable heartbeat,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both. This subsection does not apply to an abortion that is necessary to save the life of a mother whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, but not including psychological or emotional conditions.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H997B326065F347F2BCFFD0EA228F93D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply if—</text><paragraph id="HC0292736D8194791B8FE65F1307618BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in reasonable medical judgment, the abortion is necessary to save the life of a pregnant woman whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, but not including psychological or emotional conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4982BEE60C4C75B8B24FFA6EB64A76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the pregnancy is the result of rape against an adult woman, and at least 48 hours prior to the abortion—</text><subparagraph id="HC2898AC52A684E879BDDE18DC5F4658B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>she has obtained counseling for the rape; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF5E1AFFA0A94A6AAC66AABE5FF39255"><enum>(B)</enum><text>she has obtained medical treatment for the rape or an injury related to the rape; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC23BB61DFB5A4538A1DF7794790151A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the pregnancy is a result of rape against a minor or incest against a minor, and the rape or incest has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to either—</text><subparagraph id="HAE7E58CDDA9A45A19CC9423D60EA879B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a government agency legally authorized to act on reports of child abuse; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F188031324C406A92B4EFCC06ABC622"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H551F85C2A25C4C58BE619D80AAF22814"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Documentation requirements</header><paragraph id="H7A8353F868A54E268452033F28824941"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Documentation pertaining to adults</header><text>A physician who performs or attempts to perform an abortion under an exception provided by subsection (b)(2) shall, prior to performing the abortion, place in the patient medical file documentation from a hospital licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, a medical clinic licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, from a personal physician licensed by the State, a counselor licensed by the State, or a victim’s rights advocate provided by a law enforcement agency that the adult woman seeking the abortion obtained medical treatment or counseling for the rape or an injury related to the rape.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C4CE5F1E8C4F7FB62136D4FA70DEB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation pertaining to minors</header><text>A physician who performs or attempts to perform an abortion under an exception provided by subsection (b)(3) shall, prior to performing the abortion, place in the patient medical file documentation from a government agency legally authorized to act on reports of child abuse that the rape or incest was reported prior to the abortion; or, as an alternative, documentation from a law enforcement agency that the rape or incest was reported prior to the abortion.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E53B8AE570C4B0CAA748ED51C9800AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement for data retention</header><text>Paragraph (j)(2) of section 164.530 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to documentation required to be placed in a patient’s medical file pursuant to paragraph (6) of such section and a consent form required to be retained in a patient’s medical file pursuant to paragraph (7) of such section in the same manner and to the same extent as such paragraph applies to documentation required by paragraph (j)(1) of such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0012257A51C148BF9267BCAE47D607CA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional exceptions and requirements</header><paragraph id="H536266DB384B457C81EF05FEFFBC240B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the definitions set forth in subsection (j), the counseling described in subsection (b)(2)(A) and subsection (c)(1) or medical treatment may not be provided by a facility that performs abortions (unless that facility is a hospital).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED814C9A54884E64B71509E22D2C1C9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction in cases of reports to law enforcement</header><text>The requirements of subsection (b)(2) do not apply if the rape has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to a law enforcement agency or Department of Defense victim assistance personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94AE851D4380494FAC36A1471A3E1309"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Defendant may seek hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A defendant indicted for an offense under this section may seek a hearing before the State Medical Board on whether the physician's conduct was necessary to save the life of the mother whose life was endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, but not including psychological or emotional conditions. The findings on that issue are admissible on that issue at the trial of the defendant. Upon a motion of the defendant, the court shall delay the beginning of the trial for not more than 30 days to permit such a hearing to take place.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB24E19BE69F646BEA99068C266DFA41C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No liability for the mother on whom abortion is performed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mother upon whom an abortion is performed may not be prosecuted under this section, for a conspiracy to violate this section, or for an offense under section 2, 3, or 4 of this title based on a violation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H905ECE4B68CA4A3A933FFEE69E01F49E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirement for data retention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The physician shall include in the medical file of the mother documentation of the determination, according to standard medical practice, of whether the unborn child has a detectable heartbeat, the results of that determination, notification of the mother of those results, and any information entered into evidence in any proceedings under subsection (b). Paragraph (j)(2) of section 164.530 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to such documentation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6ACA59C6730A4F3590FDB58A70F26B4F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any provision of this section or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be invalid, the remainder of this section and the application of the provisions of the remainder to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection><subsection id="H48A521E8FB094BE5B79D31F0703AA2A6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA88262ABF42748629DF2AABA1D270001"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>counseling</quote> means counseling provided by a counselor licensed by the State, or a victims rights advocate provided by a law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13732AC93FA6487B818FE31204735690"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>medical treatment</quote> means treatment provided at a hospital licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, at a medical clinic licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, or from a personal physician licensed by the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5EAD9B00B9445DAF95003B678EBB11"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>abortion</quote> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text><subparagraph id="HDC96E9EADE054F768E13B2F801792F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H198B5AFC1EFB44D98AB1183A5C6C577E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="HAEC7267122F44094896C7AE7A7D994E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text></clause><clause id="H510291D687794F849BD40412B62D49AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H190CD81752114971B63D1A398680D590"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>attempt</quote>, with respect to an abortion, means conduct that, under the circumstances as the actor believes them to be, constitutes a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in performing an abortion. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5540E5324B6B464AB364AC443EC9BD5C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>facility</quote> means any medical or counseling group, center or clinic and includes the entire legal entity, including any entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with such facility. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H011E31B67B8649E1852CA46BE2E0CD56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>perform</quote>, with respect to an abortion, includes inducing an abortion through a medical or chemical intervention including writing a prescription for a drug or device intended to result in an abortion. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB17D50DCE282412BBD663C4A31938345"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <quote>physician</quote> means a person licensed to practice medicine and surgery or osteopathic medicine and surgery, or otherwise legally authorized to perform an abortion. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18173392DE474B8092B55326D3EA96FD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <quote>reasonable medical judgment</quote> means a medical judgment that would be made by a reasonably prudent physician, knowledgeable about the case and the treatment possibilities with respect to the medical conditions involved. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H250DBBB80D254B4381DB4C03684DA49A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <quote>unborn child</quote> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F32E846B1BD4A208706DD2C4FD5F711"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <quote>woman</quote> means a female human being whether or not she has reached the age of majority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC78E47998054413293E2300E7DC4A732"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="H872D1232B76C46968E004F2DDD504F0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Greater protections</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to pre-empt or limit any Federal, State, or local law that provides greater protections for an unborn child than those provided in this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H000D3DEFBAED4855BD8D55B5C7BA23B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Creation of recognition of right</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to create or recognize a right to abortion or to make lawful an abortion that is unlawful on the effective date of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FCD4804946D45A1BC1842F6E7419307"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the table of sections, by inserting after the item pertaining to section 1841 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H943C641679B44627ACDBC1F15604FD93" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1532. Abortions prohibited without a check for fetal heartbeat, or if a fetal heartbeat is detectable.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7220A60112446FD9530D684D646E652"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of chapters for part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended, in the item relating to chapter 74, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6CF1C2B3CAB47509137C9B46B120815" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry level="section"><toc-enum>74.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Abortions</level-header><target>1531</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

