<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49A2CEFAC8024C27B328180FC7489C66" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5499 IH: Fed Integrity and Independence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit dual appointments of certain employees of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB24A9AD356664A1390BA18974FFAE306"> 
<section id="H1521000B6390474B98813B11714E33A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fed Integrity and Independence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAAA447B895F04B02B0D14B8B3158BEAF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H51EBE4393BA54AC8B0054F97332BE721"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9D5E71317844CAB85F2E7AC1A94DF0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The independence of the Federal Reserve System from political interference from the President is fundamental to the effective operation of the central bank.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H303891EC6C5A4C1CAA4A83C136DC8DB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress structured the Federal Reserve System to ensure that its monetary policy decisions focus on achieving long-run goals and do not become subject to political pressures from the President that could lead to undesirable outcomes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81794D4527CD40B595B0572223A2ABD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To protect this independence, Congress made it so members of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System are appointed for staggered 14-year terms, and the Chairman of the Board of Governors is appointed for a four-year term.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H81EC31C177964C3B89BB6E6548FAEC79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that it is not appropriate for any employee appointed by the President—whether they are on leave or not—to serve as a member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61F36A4ED00F4DDABA3AC49F9C374C8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of Dual Appointment</header> 
<subsection id="H461E0BF98A9D4DD9B1B12BBD8C42EE31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Governors</header><text>The fourth sentence of the first undesignated paragraph of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/241">12 U.S.C. 241</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>business of the Board and shall each receive</quote> and inserting <quote>business of the Board, may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the member is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment, and shall each receive</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EFFF851211A41B5887CD538C3E8FD40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Reserve Bank Presidents; First Vice President of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York</header><text>The fifth subparagraph of the fourth undesignated paragraph of section 4 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/341">12 U.S.C. 341</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H32E7116371294F6881DF23B76FABEBCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after the second sentence (relating to presidents of Federal reserve banks) the following: <quote>A president of the bank may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the president is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A0E2ACF683A46B996152BCCE27999B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after the third sentence (relating to first vice presidents of Federal reserve banks) the following: <quote>The first vice president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the first vice president is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24E6CBFD6301432CAE75A8BBF9D5430A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual serving as a governor of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the president of a Federal reserve bank, or the first vice president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York on the date of enactment of this Act and who is ineligible to serve in such position due to the amendments made by this section are hereby terminated from such position on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

