<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC6A93B670EC94BA0ADD229E462520395" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 431 IH: Pony Up Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the United States Postal Service to reimburse fees charged for the late payment of bills that were delayed in the mail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6C70690E986430DBC95BFD9F790EA4B" style="OLC"><section id="H0E97562B7B144985AAE3563228F2C6F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pony Up Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8CBF2B73B32043529278D4FEFE6698D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment of fees resulting from delayed delivery</header><subsection id="H7E8012DB9FFD464D9446E0C0AC778222"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the United States Postal Service shall pay to a citizen assessed any fee or penalty for the late payment of a bill an amount determined under subsection (b) if such bill, notice of such bill, or payment is delivered late.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9BD6D61848F3420CB27F5AB5EE3794A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount to which a citizen is entitled under subsection (a) is the amount that is equal to the total amount of the fees and penalties described in such subsection that such citizen is obligated to pay.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1712F7194E714C60B4FD5261D3DE86A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HF297446EC3B54E2EA03E0593102BE043"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A citizen seeking a payment under this section shall submit to the United States Postal Service an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the United States Postal Service determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC73FB988FCC1451883365D79FD2ED527"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application submission</header><text>The United States Postal Service shall allow citizens to submit the application required by paragraph (1) on a publicly available website of the United States Postal Service, by mail, and at any post office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9A2497E2FE44B0FA07DE16A9F85B41C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unforeseen circumstances exception</header><text>For the purposes of this section, a bill, notice of bill, or payment is not delivered late if a cause not reasonably within the control of the United States Postal Service delayed the delivery of such bill or notice, including a major disaster or emergency declared by the President.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF675485506214C06AE813FB9680B0A67"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appeals</header><paragraph id="HB2A43BEBDD014211AE2F82A2B80855EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A citizen may appeal a determination made by the United States Postal Service under this section to the Judicial Officer by submitting such appeal in writing within 30 days after receiving notice of such determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94218A6CC6644C798AAE6FB88C6813B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>The Judicial Officer shall issue a decision with respect to an appeal under paragraph (1) as soon as practicable, and such decision shall be final.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FBEC88404634140871E98ECB9E07556"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the United States Postal Service shall issue rules implementing this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA97BCA6544DC4EB8B6AE10032E098730"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0844EFB6DEBE45F5A59E0F5A8A625F1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Delivered late</header><text>The term <term>delivered late</term>, with respect to a bill, notice of bill, or payment, means that—</text><subparagraph id="H228C998548904E9B9A9542AA5E497107"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such bill, notice, or payment was mailed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFBCA79A879E433D9043B54097D7031A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a bill or notice of bill, the United States Postal Service received the mail containing such bill or notice not less than 12 days prior to the date on which the payment for the bill was due and the United States Postal Service delivered such mail less than 6 days prior to the date on which payment for the bill was due; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBA5E52841294929A31F52CA4383CB34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a payment, the United States Postal Service received the mail containing such payment not less than 5 days prior to the date on which the payment was due and the United States Postal Service delivered such mail after the date on which payment was due.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9040102C4F8E4726B294432ADBCB803C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Judicial officer</header><text>The term <term>Judicial Officer</term> means the Judicial Officer appointed under section 204 of title 39, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H29924B087E2E46088069291F99CAA8DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on mail delivery delays</header><subsection id="H7CF999C2564E46C085A5DED8902CE4D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the United States Postal Service shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on delays in delivering mail, including, for each class of mail—</text><paragraph id="H3400C8711A644EC1A9595592B9338102"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the average delivery time and average delay time for—</text><subparagraph id="HA0CFA7D649DC4502A431A2071477F5AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mail delivered under an agreement between the sender, other than a sender primarily engaged in the transportation or delivery of parcels or letters carried out of the mails, and the United States Postal Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0821938022024859A7C97C5549082CA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all other mail delivered by the United States Postal Service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89E101B4A8A14C7D9565C6553A5938BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the volume of mail described in paragraph (1)(A) that is presorted and an explanation of the effect of presorting such mail on the average delivery time and average delay time for such mail; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41B7AEE76A0648D08B7466C89D79B821"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the volume of mail described in paragraph (1)(B) that is presorted and an explanation of the effect of presorting such mail on the average delivery time and average delay time for such mail.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AB5DCFA998648879C2826B8BCCD5059"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritization audit</header><paragraph id="H3DF61CA92AB54BC5A872F05A219A935E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspector General of the United States Postal Service shall conduct an assessment of the policies and practices of the United States Postal Service to determine if the United States Postal Service prioritizes the delivery of mail described in subsection (a)(1)(A) over mail that is the same class of mail and is not described in such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02EDF971F8A04BD3A51512DAF2D4FC3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the findings of the assessment required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31435F6158A043DD85ABB9A804FE09A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Class of mail defined</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the term <term>class of mail</term> means the items described in paragraphs (1) through (10) of section 3621(a) of title 5, United States Code, and the items described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 3631(a) of such title.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

