<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H289B03628148493CB28F80EB98F184E9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5149 IH: Protecting Girls’ Sports for Military Kids Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5149</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit male students from participating in female sports at schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H69571C3656A245C5A104578A19B51B62" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H347798CF5E4047009B99B28537979075" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Girls’ Sports for Military Kids Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H68F0A06C5E1A4490BDD52341A31709C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on male participation in female sports at DODEA schools</header> 
<subsection id="H76A67D9EFFEF4A9A8CFAF418CE13CA06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A male student may not participate in a female sport at a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HBCD8FC9869234E838025874DBD62EA00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H54CD4BAF1CB24EAABF87B3DFAA0716B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <term>female</term> refers to an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and uses eggs for fertilization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1622FBB65148422E80AE822676F8921E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Female sport</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>female sport</term> means an athletic program or activity designated exclusively for participation by students who are female.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB9064DDBFCF43CBA1F735DF94F9BFAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <term>male</term> refers to an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and uses sperm for fertilization.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

