<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25576-XNK-V0-L5J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 SRES 279 ATS: Designating June 2025 as “Great Outdoors Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250616">June 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 2025 as <quote>Great Outdoors Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of millions of individuals in the United States participate in outdoor recreation annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress enacted the Outdoor Recreation Jobs and Economic Impact Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/249">Public Law 114–249</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 999) to assess and analyze the outdoor recreation economy of the United States and the effects attributable to the outdoor recreation economy on the overall economy of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Outdoor Recreation Satellite Account, updated in November 2024 by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce, shows that outdoor recreation generated $1,200,000,000,000 in economic output in 2023, comprising approximately 2.3 percent of the current-dollar gross domestic product of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Outdoor Recreation Satellite Account shows that, from 2020 to 2023, the outdoor recreation sector grew nearly 3 times faster than the overall economy of the United States while also providing 5,000,000 jobs across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great American Outdoors Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/152">Public Law 116–152</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 682) provides billions of dollars to spend on priority deferred maintenance projects on Federal lands and waters and permanently funds the Land and Water Conservation Fund;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas regular outdoor recreation is associated with economic growth, positive health outcomes, and better quality of life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas outdoor recreation activities at the Federal, State, and local levels have seen a recent surge in participation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many outdoor recreation businesses are small businesses that are cornerstones of rural communities, and outdoor recreation is part of the national heritage of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is imperative that the United States ensures that access to outdoor recreation is available to all its people for generations to come; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 2025 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>Great Outdoors Month</quote> to provide an opportunity to celebrate the importance of the great outdoors: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf2dd85b7ea204db9af4860e978d0d685"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates June 2025 as <quote>Great Outdoors Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecd8f42492b1457789939fafcdab6bd8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all individuals in the United States to responsibly participate in recreation activities in the great outdoors during June 2025 and year-round.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

