<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB007D5E1526A44B48FF1B90A6EB0367F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2520 IH: César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park in the States of California and Arizona, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8A52664FB4AA49889D7A54446B0DBD43" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF3C0601DAEEF4B2CBF6B8FC4B20CF126" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0CD32CED9EAA40EABEE2672D91B6E87D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H95E7B21A835F46F8AB85B2084062BD6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H486A02FFA42A43EC8CC0D77D6C35F951"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on October 8, 2012, the César E. Chávez National Monument was established by Presidential Proclamation 8884 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320301">54 U.S.C. 320301</external-xref> note) for the purposes of protecting and interpreting the nationally significant resources associated with the property in Keene, California, known as <quote>Nuestra Señora Reina de la Paz</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H380E1A99D51947E69AE6F28216CCF554"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nuestra Señora Reina de la Paz—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H51474248915F400CB1310AF377E15210"><enum>(A)</enum><text>served as the national headquarters of the United Farm Workers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E480E62191246E3BD246EDAC869F558"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was the home and workplace of César E. Chávez, the family of César E. Chávez, union members, and supporters of César E. Chávez;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB1A04EE89CA4A26B9EC184E85B1D014"><enum>(3)</enum><text>while the César E. Chávez National Monument marks the extraordinary achievements and contributions to the history of the United States by César Chávez and the farmworker movement, there are other significant sites in the States of California and Arizona that are important to the story of the farmworker movement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2A854CB1B2C4AB1AE6F010A53442DE3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the study conducted by the National Park Service entitled <quote>César Chávez Special Resource Study and Environmental Assessment</quote> and submitted to Congress on October 24, 2013, the National Park Service—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA766F8232FD64BD398A6DBA70E3670AB"><enum>(A)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H96E187FAD01F46D5B6E754925FEC94A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>found that several sites associated with César E. Chávez and the farmworker movement—</text> <subclause indent="up1" id="H8A88F28AB06D49E183C2F8423D2A7A79"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are suitable for inclusion in the National Park System; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause indent="up1" id="H24BA09DB97EC4607949136CDCDEC11BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>depict a distinct and important aspect of the history of the United States not otherwise adequately represented at existing units of the National Park System; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H9E3E3ACA6A9A43AB8CA416FBB4D86B40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommended that Congress establish a national historical park to honor the role that César E. Chávez played in lifting up the lives of farmworkers; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2D15CFA3E114460BD563A8FD99D9BB2"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9ECE87BA0B664DC7B075F438356061F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>found that the route of the 1966 march from Delano to Sacramento, California, meets National Historic Landmark criteria;</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H321C879E961B428DB9C9AAE8181D0914"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommended that the potential for designation of the route as a national historic trail be further explored; and</text></clause> 
<clause indent="up1" id="H8A05A53759BB47CDB0068ED5E9F8BB37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>indicated that the National Park Service could work with partner organizations and agencies to provide for interpretation programs along the route of the 1966 march from Delano to Sacramento, California.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3E26B5BCFB6B4FA39EC246770E55B0EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to establish the César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BF60616656D41E29536292666956A64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to help preserve, protect, and interpret the nationally significant resources associated with César Chávez and the farmworker movement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D07F4FFF874496CAE87132EEB758C39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to interpret and provide for a broader understanding of the extraordinary achievements and contributions to the history of the United States made by César Chávez and the farmworker movement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA89C6736425344FBAC954103E3A035D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support and enhance the network of sites and resources associated with César Chávez and the farmworker movement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD6264AA950F04761A3AAEBE706E507C6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7559406666A4466C9372C694A1326A68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historical park</header><text>The term <term>historical park</term> means the César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park established by section 4.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDADFDB5FF11A4D2BBDF0B584066C9631"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Cesar E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 502/179857B, and dated September 2022.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A223EE138274ED49C27BE60C9067988"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED8E15EE55DC4B73818423A256112097"><enum>(4)</enum><header>States</header><text>The term <term>States</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CE0F851B0DE4BBBB1ED05B8FEA6080D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State of California; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62FB0AF2A69E473991E32F4ADECEC3AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State of Arizona.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CA9FCA28BA84CA4888EB635AA3C687C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The term <term>Study</term> means the study conducted by the National Park Service entitled <quote>César Chávez Special Resource Study and Environmental Assessment</quote> and submitted to Congress on October 24, 2013.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H8A57BAE0D49C47E3969BDD6B97880E04"><enum>4.</enum><header>César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park</header> <subsection id="H6885D3C01FD345148A58BA9BC4ECC1A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redesignation of César E. Chávez National Monument</header> <paragraph id="H2211A24FD3E5432DA48B8479A7DA0ADA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The César E. Chávez National Monument established on October 8, 2012, by Presidential Proclamation 8884 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320301">54 U.S.C. 320301</external-xref> note) is redesignated as the <quote>César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18FA8DBC8ECD42429CC8E93C0DE7ADDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Any funds available for the purposes of the monument referred to in paragraph (1) shall be available for the purposes of the historical park.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF7275AF722B4A708BD0D8AF303F92D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the monument referred to in paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>César E. Chávez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBFAC0B474D64F388BEAAF05A22137FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundary</header> 
<paragraph id="HC839849583C64E429056554653877827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of the historical park shall include the area identified as <quote>César E. Chávez National Monument</quote> in Keene, California, as generally depicted on the Map.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D892241A37949AD9A290BEBF1764C0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of additional sites</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary may include within the boundary of the historical park the following sites, as generally depicted on the Map:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF3710865392F429D872B88824C58980F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Forty Acres in Delano, California.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB81BC87C85A148719C761DF352431623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Santa Rita Center in Phoenix, Arizona.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD28405DFD8A84F7D8B11C09275B49FAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>McDonnell Hall in San Jose, California.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E1469D421D94436A85339B3E4F4419B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conditions for inclusion</header><text>A site described in paragraph (2) shall not be included in the boundary of the historical park until—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H778F3B9CCFD34D97B5471F96AEDA1A2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary acquires the land or an interest in the land at the site; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H400F92FEA80249E3804DE879E4765E8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary enters into a written agreement with the owner of the site providing that the site shall be managed in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED146F3654514F8FB4F7D9FE1E71A1E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary includes a site described in paragraph (2) in the historical park, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the addition to the historical park.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H512AEBBFC0CF4FC0A030EDAE95767257"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of Map</header><text>The Map shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CF3C4F157DA4CD3A1BFE890AA3D6A02"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header><text>The Secretary may acquire land and interests in land within the area generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Proposed NPS Boundary</quote> by donation, purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA71B21AB0AC441CAD1ED68457CBE63F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph id="HB200A8179C6E419CA7B5AFBDB5566191"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the historical park in accordance with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC477DAC46B5541C28390429CAB1E56CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8987ABAC53C54DF78D2FB97E789082C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text> 
<clause id="H2F123CF125104C98B6C8A8C7097BDBA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA1DBAF19C95345409A0C7488107CA96F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90B37725FEE94215856C729C42FEFD72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interpretation</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance and public interpretation of historic sites, museums, and resources on land not administered by the Secretary relating to the life of César E. Chávez and the history of the farmworker movement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CA860A848A94334AF740D9B22B84D10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the States, local governments, public and private organizations, and individuals to provide for the preservation, development, interpretation, and use of the historical park.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B1B1AFCD47E41C5AF3FE35FA2C887A8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>General management plan</header> 
<paragraph id="HF1BA6F50606A4D65A0D86D7C27D08893"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this subsection, the Secretary shall prepare a general management plan for the historical park in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3757412EECD4838B12393C3C59E4BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional sites</header> <subparagraph id="H2FC7962E61304F4BAA6AAA104FD7E54E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The general management plan prepared under paragraph (1) shall include a determination of whether there are—</text> 
<clause id="H23C6162DC00F4C6EA2D9295715D20D5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sites located in the Coachella Valley in the State of California that were reviewed in the Study that should be added to the historical park;</text></clause> <clause id="HC14545E94F4B40028654B99EBDDAD802"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>additional representative sites in the States that were reviewed in the Study that should be added to the historical park; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBB2ADAB7E8EC4CF0A3642F352CC5C8EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sites outside of the States in the United States that relate to the farmworker movement that should be linked to, and interpreted at, the historical park.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC129FA1EC25148D7B482C9FEAA588E2D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text>On completion of the preparation of the general management plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives any recommendations for additional sites to be included in the historical park.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73DB06DA890E400FA01533145439FB0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The general management plan under paragraph (1) shall be prepared in consultation with—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C3AD2E60F0E4CCAB438B878172EBA4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any owner of land that is included within the boundaries of the historical park; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A64BE3E6A4646FF8B4CA8B50C22F707"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate Federal, State, and Tribal agencies, public and private organizations, and individuals, including—</text> <clause id="H8CFB290368504151B4A2379177BEB963"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Chávez Center; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF35EFF6C846E47C49F6F9FC2802AFBE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the César Chávez Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCF27BA4F72534CBE8AD7E9A3AE3A5D83"><enum>5.</enum><header>Farmworker Peregrinación National Historical Trail study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(c) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7215D4A37CDE4FBC8450AA8624E5A0BD"> 
<paragraph id="HF5921DFBB3CD4B628D3EE2EFB6665F1B"><enum>(50)</enum><header>Farmworker Peregrinación National Historic Trail</header><text>The Farmworker Peregrinación National Historic Trail, a route of approximately 300 miles taken by farmworkers between Delano and Sacramento, California, in 1966, as generally depicted as <quote>Alternative C</quote> in the study conducted by the National Park Service entitled <quote>César Chávez Special Resource Study and Environmental Assessment</quote> and submitted to Congress on October 24, 2013.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

