<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25956-LLM-94-57Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2751 IS: Permanent OPTN Fee Authority Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collect registration fees from members of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Permanent OPTN Fee Authority Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDA5966FD9295497AA528B17711C381FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 372 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274">42 U.S.C. 274</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF66A0562CF1D41C7B7601A71C0D27242"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H5E7F22AB9D4249209D7101205C5C3A70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by moving the margins of subparagraphs (M) through (O) 2 ems to the left;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D742DF5CD1B45F49527FE46A08263E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H266524DFE2D04B62B2F092661A1ED15A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>, and</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H84617C6D18B744DB998C0D7EED9CD204"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the comma at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD257E4D6010F466DBE90398881ACAB9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>twenty-four-hour telephone service</quote> and inserting <quote>24-hour telephone or information technology service</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EF14DBCC3B545388994159267F47FCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in each of subparagraphs (B) through (M), by striking the comma at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84BCC7C059EC44478D9378E1FA9D7BB8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N), by striking <quote>transportation, and</quote> and inserting <quote>transportation;</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDEF4945E392435786F6AFFF5F9F518B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86F2E0EF9A7C42B2A93BA27DAE4549E2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D9E8750B64A4614A2DD84EBC77EC6FB"><subparagraph id="H35F7C769284D4B82BAB748A02C9EB850" indent="up1"><enum>(P)</enum><text>consider establishing a dashboard to display the number of transplants performed, the types of transplants performed, the number and types of organs that entered the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network system and failed to be transplanted, and other appropriate statistics, which should be updated more frequently than annually.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0B42C4981A5428783FEDF65F3D374D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H026E2EDB37564C96ACC49A9ACBAECA6E"><subsection id="HF9A714C07D6F4921BDE5957363BC64D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Registration fees</header><paragraph id="HCCC75A654D5F4CF18D2C551983A12770"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may collect registration fees from any member of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network for each transplant candidate such member places on the list described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i). Such registration fees shall be collected and distributed only to support the operation of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network. Such registration fees are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1867CCCFF29D42ECBA43133418B41013"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collection</header><text>The Secretary may collect the registration fees under paragraph (1) directly or through awards made under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F70E76BCE5F464E9A296C2ED9D160A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Any amounts collected under this subsection shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3AEB47C9685941C98E2DA1702435C337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be credited to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of the Department of Health and Human Services as discretionary offsetting collections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DD8F8C85D9C410CB212E63F8576E698"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be available, only to the extent and in the amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts, to distribute such fees among awardees described in subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HECDFE7C62F684477BB302E34D0EB0F6E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H77A065179AAA488C94B01890B4270E3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promptly post on the website of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network—</text><clause id="H732606F7997547738428CF7206145F32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of registration fees collected under this subsection from each member of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network; and</text></clause><clause id="H77E4B78E92F64F09AEBB7C8D6BDA64C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of activities such fees are used to support; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9E8C98FC94943E0946D4621168B7A94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>update the information posted pursuant to subparagraph (A), as applicable for each calendar quarter for which fees are collected under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F59F62E40994EFB82DB6D8922312145"><enum>(5)</enum><header>GAO review</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall, to the extent data are available—</text><subparagraph id="H6800FE7942954C1E9486CE5D6F46DD36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review concerning the activities under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55F01988CACD42588AD818172DF12FE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report on such review, including related recommendations, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

