<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B202A2241BF4689BA673B4FF375CC2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2089 IH: Generating Retirement Ownership through Long-Term Holding</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2089</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to defer recognition of reinvested capital gains distributions from regulated investment companies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HED496C1476924BFABAD1B26A50D4DA78" style="OLC"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H739CA1EF07B64BBAB2F3A21C843DDA05" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generating Retirement Ownership through Long-Term Holding</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBB281DA6ECF45C4ACFB09997D9805D8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Deferral of reinvested capital gain dividends of regulated investment companies</header><subsection id="H15E8D3F9AB20424E9B2D4DF22B06B9D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter O of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 1045 the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HFE446955DA0949E18E3BC98184CEA9C6"><section id="HC7B625F698E34B80BEF03283E043B088"><enum>1046.</enum><header>Reinvested capital gain dividends of regulated investment companies</header><subsection id="HC28F1FEB54EF4FA984EE0CAA5746AF08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonrecognition of gain</header><text>In the case of an individual, no gain shall be recognized on the receipt of a capital gain dividend distributed by a regulated investment company to which part I of subchapter M applies if such capital gain dividend is automatically reinvested in additional shares of the company pursuant to a dividend reinvestment plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB7A9DFD7F2E4DF4839C38EEB67CFAAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H56C1E934C7B346ACA4F1D5E9CBADFF7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capital gain dividend</header><text>The term <term>capital gain dividend</term> has the meaning given to such term by section 852(b)(3)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB855DF1B84364AC390A5ADF6870DEE42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recognition of deferred capital gain dividends</header><subparagraph id="H6DD0D6BB7B424196B6B39D64888849A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Gain treated as unrecognized in accordance with subsection (a) shall be recognized in accordance with subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H10D4358AC84C4AAB9EADE74F7C5DCA84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon a subsequent sale or redemption by such individual of stock in the distributing company, or</text></clause><clause id="HB8ED585A00A24664B45E7BC6B3CFA71B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon the death of the individual.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DFDC3FBB14E4FBAB303C682A0236B10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Gain recognition</header><clause id="H8F8113F73DA147DF901DA50E07C48E9C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon a sale or redemption described in subparagraph (A), the taxpayer shall recognize that portion of total gain treated as unrecognized in accordance with subsection (a) (and not previously recognized pursuant to this subparagraph) that is equivalent to the portion of the taxpayer’s shares in the distributing company that are sold or redeemed.</text></clause><clause id="H74620EBFEE004FABB6A62ECF8D4F537C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Death of individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by regulations, any portion of such total gain not recognized under clause (i) prior to the taxpayer’s death shall be recognized upon the death of the taxpayer and included in the taxpayer’s gross income for the taxable year ending on the date of the taxpayer’s death.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04FDD240929545A18754E3DEB816166B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Holding period</header><text>The taxpayer’s holding period in shares acquired through reinvestment of a capital gain dividend to which subsection (a) applies shall be determined by treating the shareholder as having held such shares for one year and a day as of the date such shares are acquired.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB00F1C1EE9F14F64B170C1D5E61284CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Section not To apply to certain taxpayers</header><text>This section shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="H889F554CC0E24D44B5F5ACE14F8B5A55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual with respect to whom a deduction under section 151 is allowable to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which such individual’s taxable year begins, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02BDCD2AD3E6467FAE53A0248ECB70CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estate or trust.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2FA42E792094A55AEEDB688DF1AF9A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA7DB125D2C0E42B89591DCFC70B8D8D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HBFBCB6AE22074FFBAE9C138CF6EDF255"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 852(b)(3)(B) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For rules regarding nonrecognition of gain with respect to reinvested capital gain dividends received by individuals, see section 1046.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E5E91C8FE5B4C8ABA6FAA004E41F3B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter O of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1045 the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H1104282DE4BB485F8AD49391A9DC4416" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1046. Reinvested capital gain dividends of regulated investment companies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21D871FAD31748B3A6C98B9A495F9187"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

