<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H496F43DF014545BB99A283AB15C4319A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5732 IH: Keep Air Travel Safe Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5732</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for funding for all Transportation Security Administration activities for a certain period in the event of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4B8277D964DF4408AA6AF150925313ED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H056D586528644A30B2286DA5199803EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep Air Travel Safe Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC6F73F99398942DB8E2FE65A6E7159FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Funding for the Transportation Security Administration in the event of a lapse in appropriation</header> 
<subsection id="HA3325235045A4AF69880FE067D03E674"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During any period in which there is a lapse in appropriations for the Transportation Security Administration, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall continue, using amounts described in subsection (g), all programs, projects, or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) of the Administration that were conducted with amounts made available for any account of the Administration in the preceding fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="HD699B84E7FE94D00A56DEAD03FA9875B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the corresponding appropriation Act for such preceding fiscal year; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CBF7076E2AD498786DD7FD844F47A92"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the corresponding appropriation bill for such preceding fiscal year did not become law, then in a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB2134E352D1B4EEB8F4A9EEC0022CDE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate for operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available, and authority granted, to continue a program, project, or activity for any fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be at a rate for operations not greater than—</text> 
<paragraph id="H09E92BC9F3C542A8A646175507AD6092"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate for operations provided for in the regular appropriation Act providing for such program, project, or activity for the preceding fiscal year; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B53BC0D1AAE45EF8E3F7D1D2341B5CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the absence of such an Act, the rate for operations provided for such program, project, or activity pursuant to a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H387719A91C3F475BB34467C79072B10D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available, and authority granted, for any fiscal year pursuant to this section for a program, project, or activity shall be available for the period beginning with the first day of a lapse in appropriations and ending with the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="H44F75F2778674D4E80B4E9065E3F70EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1925418EC74143098A31D67ABD28B209"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable regular appropriation bill for such fiscal year becomes law (whether or not such law provides for such program, project, or activity); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49030F179BBB46D092EAFCC519F75E91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a joint resolution making continuing appropriations becomes law; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8024977150F4A2287CBE47F5FD71AAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the first day of a lapse in appropriations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9FB7F87C00546DC9F8593161F196FF3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An appropriation or funds made available, or authority granted, for a program, project, or activity for any fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be subject to the terms and conditions imposed with respect to the appropriation made or funds made available for the preceding fiscal year, or authority granted for such program, project, or activity under applicable law on the first day of the applicable lapse in appropriations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE917B7C4043B4D4789FD6335603F6A08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>End of fiscal year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this section is in effect at the end of a fiscal year, funding levels shall continue as provided in this section for the next fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFD0BA2A0C9E04E9A942F96DD96B23EBE" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Amounts described</header><text>The amounts described in this subsection are the unobligated balances, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, of amounts made available under section 90003 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref> (commonly referred to as the <quote>One Big Beautiful Bill Act</quote>; 139 Stat. 358).</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

