<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25171-4Y4-6P-R5J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S820 IS: Caribbean Basin Security Initiative Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative, to enhance the United States-Caribbean security partnership, to prioritize natural disaster resilience, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idca7a243020a4441eb85b21481a42f09d" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caribbean Basin Security Initiative Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id330A013C4431402EB4C27C164321FBC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id3B35EF1B678A4DD6976D22E73574EC8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id31CD8FE7EC224DE5BF12FE83CA3E0C3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37249D86E0204257974D03BD5A3E5510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc326a0593f204792980f5d7d84d5cff2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beneficiary countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>beneficiary countries</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8e28a06f0c14525ac06037c9bdc45dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Antigua and Barbuda; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id706c0a1af7ff4b0792cee2a2aa636fde"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bahamas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0f76fd681164530b35bc05ccd1ba36a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barbados; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65365c1bfbef47cc92709c8fbe10dd4d"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dominica; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4e477f1bf2f4020b36301a0a4796962"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Dominican Republic; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7216d30569344d0aacacdbdb9d6078f5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grenada; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb1482eb49174021b7fe2cdceea1e11e"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guyana;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd93dc54474b8426ca4d6fc4a3ebdaa89"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jamaica; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide751e908a7f540c7b300bf9e77ecd0b5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Saint Lucia; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id839e2ebc8c62439da187bbe2cd3989ba"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Saint Kitts and Nevis; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3d485eccce645b0b7d649a972bb8a8a"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Saint Vincent and the Grenadines; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85bbf432212e4af9afeba8f5b9225b25"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suriname; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c3c9b669e424c4b8ace082bd25f1788"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Trinidad and Tobago.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB7F2E42F39E04DE38EEA426C9BAD4151"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative</header><subsection id="idd345ee941c2a4eba82c68062accacef5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization for the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development may carry out an initiative, to be known as the <quote>Caribbean Basin Security Initiative</quote>, in beneficiary countries to achieve the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D1F7AB8694B457B9A2332CA19D5AD2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H7798048D0B6E47FA9FA91B681C7B5F35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To promote citizen safety, security, and the rule of law in the Caribbean through increased strategic engagement with—</text><subparagraph id="idD9E00038DA6246FDA01E5EA2B5FCF4E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the governments of beneficiary countries; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4A39FB23C37439D9854795C324356A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>elements of local civil society, including the private sector, in such countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf91b1b0273544a1ab73a50632d3230a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To counter transnational criminal organizations and local gangs in beneficiary countries, including through—</text><subparagraph id="id4e69ad05bb4e4d86bc46ffddf5eb6ca2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maritime and aerial security cooperation, including—</text><clause id="id2b83f901f5c14f3fa4c637c86c8f584e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assistance to strengthen capabilities of maritime and aerial interdiction operations in the Caribbean; and</text></clause><clause id="id117ba6fcd07047d8b4df26ab73c545e7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provision of support systems and equipment, training, and maintenance;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8158040efe294474bd05946e33191c57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cooperation on border and port security, including support to strengthen capacity for screening and intercepting narcotics, weapons, bulk cash, and other contraband at airports and seaports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaaa8edd5ad9743a983faeaed6d516e36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>capacity building and the provision of equipment and support for operations targeting—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec7977d773744177a6a551875b733f8f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the finances and illegal activities of such organizations and gangs; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id791a36e40afc448d970037fc49dfafc4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recruitment by such organizations and gangs of at-risk youth.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70eba85fb75c4d7495f3b386d4ba55f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To advance law enforcement and justice sector capacity building and rule of law initiatives in beneficiary countries, including by—</text><subparagraph id="idd3d8d63f64844f3bbeeb68b94282ebf9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthening special prosecutorial offices and providing technical assistance—</text><clause id="id697c1c6e02864c15a9fc51f692881aa2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to combat—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09f14a61524a44c08bbd3e1dae6cf1ca"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">corruption; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id258d4aac6c1e4e6da843c973223eb7e7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">money laundering;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95b2690dfb2f449798b5c9ab29003c4a"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">human, firearms, and wildlife trafficking; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87dd66f238e94160bf38a6d3b7177084"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">human smuggling; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7874a4b7fa3d4be78f5e191982ef39af"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial crimes; and </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb144ffe7dcd04c838a05cbb5ec33875d"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extortion; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id871a52eef0394b39a8b6901c29d1bb98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to conduct asset forfeitures and criminal analysis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4d615eae07640839675c687b12ea854"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting training for civilian police and appropriate security services in criminal investigations, best practices for citizen security, and the protection of human rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdf64005be8d4f28b9a40d158cccaa23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting capacity building for law enforcement and military units, including professionalization, anti-corruption and human rights training, vetting, and community-based policing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4580e35d409a437fb3c7fa5e4c25a75a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting justice sector reform and strengthening of the rule of law, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77bc0f3fb4ba4fb8873d2a09ea598b30"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capacity building for prosecutors, judges, and other justice officials; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f5cab72f7914af88422e9498cdd7ec9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support to increase the efficacy of criminal courts; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee40b2dce2d646a49047140a83397ff1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>strengthening cybersecurity and cybercrime cooperation, including capacity building and support for cybersecurity systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25b369d87de24435a0114fff6f3e2f2e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To promote crime prevention efforts in beneficiary countries, particularly among at-risk-youth and other vulnerable populations, including through—</text><subparagraph id="id47551432a0a245ffbbac48d40c604fca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving community and law enforcement cooperation to improve the effectiveness and professionalism of police and increase mutual trust;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7836aab32f5e4ada9db8662113140697"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing economic opportunities for at-risk youth and vulnerable populations, including through workforce development training and remedial education programs for at-risk youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id898d210430df439eb75829f9cf48ab33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving juvenile justice sectors through regulatory reforms, separating youth from traditional prison systems, and improving support and services in juvenile detention centers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided1ce5b010f1491e845744170dc4891d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the provision of assistance to populations vulnerable to being victims of extortion and crime by criminal networks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id10c07876dc544039a5dd938cb0167014"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To strengthen the ability of the security sector in beneficiary countries to respond to and become more resilient in the face of natural disasters, including by—</text><subparagraph id="idc6a4f07206ca4e06af330415a8b37495"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out training exercises to ensure critical infrastructure and ports are able to come back online rapidly following natural disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7bda4e26908b40ff9c949deb2f0c03c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing preparedness training to police and first responders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b3a56f2344b4f81b4068554ca6cb779"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To prioritize efforts to combat corruption and include anti-corruption components in programs in beneficiary countries, including by—</text><subparagraph id="id28cc7d0351d5473c9fdfb50dd05b41d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>building the capacity of national justice systems and attorneys general to prosecute and try acts of corruption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cce01e7b1bb482f9fa61b1cd02a1e43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing the capacity of national law enforcement services to carry out anti-corruption investigations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f4b9355349a4c21aca0cabaa5656fb8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encouraging cooperative agreements among the Department of State, other relevant Federal departments and agencies, and the attorneys general of relevant countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2f16bda755141a3a4e2e16d14c20402"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To promote the rule of law in beneficiary countries and counter malign influence from authoritarian regimes, including China, Russia, Iran, Venezuela, Nicaragua, and Cuba, by—</text><subparagraph id="id597bae9e5a1f4e0e957866d287202c70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitoring security assistance from such authoritarian regimes and taking steps necessary to ensure that such assistance does not undermine or jeopardize United States security assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4afe3478ef6d4519b0f9bb645f903604"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluating and, as appropriate, restricting the involvement of the United States in investment and infrastructure projects financed by authoritarian regimes that might obstruct or otherwise impact United States security assistance to beneficiary countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1008d7568d864d56bf45350b98c45bbc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitoring and restricting equipment and support from high-risk vendors of telecommunications infrastructure in beneficiary countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabc85bfa74654b39bd3eb3e4a0b17c86"><enum>(D)</enum><text>countering disinformation by promoting transparency and accountability from beneficiary countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b6847f8ba8a4620bb0dda6a55daf03d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>eliminating corruption linked to investment and infrastructure facilitated by authoritarian regimes through support for investment screening, competitive tendering and bidding processes, the implementation of investment law, and contractual transparency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id283a182a68ad47308b3d2c5a1d29b5e4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To support the effective branding and messaging of United States security assistance and cooperation in beneficiary countries, including by developing and implementing a public diplomacy strategy for informing citizens of beneficiary countries about the benefits to their respective countries of United States security assistance and cooperation programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida12570ea3f4e4b0ba70d2aad316674bf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development $88,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029 to carry out the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative to achieve the purposes described in subsection (b). </text></subsection></section><section id="idB9B6B4D3800344998CFBD50D032B0AF5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><subsection id="id108D90D25A5A42ECAE87E811C7F3C670"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an implementation plan that includes a timeline and stated objectives for actions to be taken in beneficiary countries with respect to the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative. </text></subsection><subsection id="idBA9B9B35A8124A71B8BA442B213BBA04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementation plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="id86FD8AB2379E492CB8C289B50BC06712"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A multi-year strategy with a timeline, overview of objectives, and anticipated outcomes for the region and for each beneficiary country, with respect to each purpose described in section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1AA73D3CDFF74CFDBF865D3ED3EECD3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Specific, measurable benchmarks to track the progress of the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative toward accomplishing the outcomes included under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24F7C3D286F947389CD61ED9F3E9C74A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for the delineation of the roles to be carried out by the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Justice, the Department of Defense, and any other Federal department or agency in carrying out the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative, to prevent overlap and unintended competition between activities and resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB5B30B6D6BBD44028E06A2DBF1593286"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to coordinate and track all activities carried out under the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative among all relevant Federal departments and agencies, in accordance with the publication requirements described in section 4 of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394c">22 U.S.C. 2394c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD78954767E804229A8F67F99F5D738DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the process for co-locating projects of the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative funded by the United States Agency for International Development and the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs of the Department of State to ensure that crime prevention funding and enforcement funding are used in the same localities as necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73240C48EB874ED6A051C581B853429E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of steps taken, as of the date on which the plan is submitted, to increase regional coordination and collaboration between the law enforcement agencies of beneficiary countries and the Haitian National Police, and a framework with benchmarks for increasing such coordination and collaboration, in order to address the urgent security crisis in Haiti.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id258E8B81967742C3A5832B81F8B8146A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual progress update</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the implementation plan required by subsection (a) is submitted, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a written description of results achieved through the Caribbean Basin Security Imitative, including with respect to—</text><paragraph id="idD6CF11AF956F4EC88FA7970B720301BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of the strategy and plans described in paragraphs (1), (3), and (4) of subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2880FD9101B44BF1B72A052D996B1447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compliance with, and progress related to, meeting the benchmarks described in paragraph (2) of subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id116FC41840D44E529D53F4B27433E789" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funding statistics for the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative for the preceding year, disaggregated by country. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8A071DD5851B4E9FAFCDC99A45AE3328"><enum>5.</enum><header>Programs and strategy to increase natural disaster response and resilience</header><subsection id="idbcac542e9bbc41f287af22e6b9e13a80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Programs</header><text>During the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the President and Chief Executive Officer of the Inter-American Foundation, shall promote natural disaster response and resilience in beneficiary countries by carrying out programs for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HB9C9F146774F455595D3F8404A4AF0CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Encouraging coordination between beneficiary countries and relevant Federal departments and agencies to provide expertise and information sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1971FDF3EAA44C489EAAAF3BA4CE9D4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting the sharing of best practices on natural disaster resilience, including on constructing resilient infrastructure and rebuilding after natural disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F5317885FF42C1A49A3BF95670D279"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving rapid-response mechanisms and cross-government organizational preparedness for natural disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H479091BB002E4811A701B0E1556CAAEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and in consultation with the President and Chief Executive Officer of the Inter-American Foundation and nongovernmental organizations in beneficiary countries and in the United States, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy that incorporates specific, measurable benchmarks—</text><paragraph id="id0BA134B453664BFEACCC15E72B1BE08C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to achieve the purposes described in subsection (a); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBEB8CBE6319B44549260F3F9D801457B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to inform citizens of beneficiary countries about the extent and benefits of United States assistance to such countries. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D77F183C9B14DA0A0445F5DCBB1FB77" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual progress update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the strategy required by subsection (b) is submitted, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a written description of the progress made as of the date of such submission in meeting the benchmarks included in the strategy. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

