<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25870-5J6-8V-NCR">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2474 IS: Advocate for Employee Ownership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2474</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250728">July 28, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on
                    Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Labor to appoint an Advocate for Employee
            Ownership within the Employee Ownership Initiative, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0FE91E8CC3AE4F01A0D56D86EF693292">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H71591344312547A6A79388616B0FD830">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advocate for Employee Ownership Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HC8F7E84762F64ED0A0A3BCFDD35CEB06">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Establishment of the advocate for employee ownership</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H611021772F3041B3AC1B35B36D899A31">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title III of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1201">29 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9C20BC1AC6340CA89F35FBC0B0EE6B6">
                    <section id="H778F3D97611A4DFF9221077B2EE4DECE">
                        <enum>3005.</enum>
                        <header>Advocate for employee ownership</header>
                        <subsection id="H61450D331151400A9BF9D3010E40B09D">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Labor shall appoint an Advocate for Employee Ownership within the Employee Ownership Initiative established under section 346(b)(1) of the SECURE 2.0 Act of 2022 (division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>)). The appointment shall be made without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, relating to appointments in the competitive service or Senior Executive Service.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="H097049D252244F69984CAEE9447121FB">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Duties</header>
 <text>The Advocate for Employee Ownership shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3DEA62E9CD7A4D8FA4C9703C3E25CD57"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>consult with the head of the Employee Ownership Initiative established under section 346(b)(1) of the SECURE 2.0 Act of 2022 (division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>));</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H762B7D081F26478DBB5D0A0B9AC79246">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>act as a liaison between the Department of Labor, employee ownership advocates, employers considering employee ownership, workers interested in employee ownership, and other stakeholders, including employee stock ownership plan sponsors and participants;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H45086755D2EB470EACC57EED21A0FAC4">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>provide public education and assistance related to the expansion of employee ownership through the establishment and maintenance of practices that promote employee ownership, including the use of employee stock ownership plans;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H105D4E60A9584B6486F3DDAB65B4B236">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>provide assistance for purposes of resolving a dispute between the Department of Labor and any employee stock ownership plan sponsor, fiduciary, or participant and help facilitate communication between such entities and the Department of Labor for such purposes;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H7D27A00A5DA14E038CA0C0497B64037F">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>identify and recommend potential legislative and administrative changes, including related to access to capital issues, to increase practices that promote employee ownership plans, including the use of employee stock ownership plans; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H2DF230ACF32C498992EDCD9662C71F12">
                                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>coordinate with other Federal agencies, including the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Commerce, and State and local governments on outreach and education to inform employees and employers about the possibilities and benefits of employee ownership as a business ownership succession planning option.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="H70F5A25F0307495899EB62613456C4CA">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Consultation and input</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Labor shall solicit advice and input from the Advocate for Employee Ownership in developing regulations or interpretations of this Act that relate to employee stock ownership plans.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="H1C62BC9D270A48B69FDEE94F259ECB93">
                            <enum>(d)</enum>
                            <header>Compensation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advocate for Employee Ownership shall be entitled to compensation at the same rate as the rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code. </text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="H819D1F6E4C9E44CDBA0381B427A0F09C">
                            <enum>(e)</enum>
                            <header>Annual report</header>
                            <paragraph id="HBBD866084FE84BC3A112ADA26E2A8671">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than December 31 of each calendar year beginning after the date of enactment of this section, the Advocate for Employee Ownership shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives on the activities of the Office of the Advocate for Employee Ownership during the fiscal year ending during such calendar year, including the contents described in paragraph (2).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H86EBCA07245D418F944200D8C5019228">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Contents</header>
 <text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H70E5551E96E94BF095AF46CF85EF28E0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>summarize the assistance requests received by the Advocate for Employee Ownership during the fiscal year ending during the calendar year of such report;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC219A86F01E74CC7B4AD2B7A731DD62B">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the activities, including the activities described under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b), and evaluate the effectiveness of the Advocate for Employee Ownership during such fiscal year;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H49F6B2FD7BD145669872C9A9732C4E10">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>describe any significant problems the Advocate for Employee Ownership has identified during such fiscal year and ways to mitigate such problems;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H298E5A64F0B84E69B71CC05B9982E491">
                                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>contain recommendations for any administrative or legislative action that may be appropriate to resolve barriers to, and to incentivize, practices that promote employee ownership, including the use of employee stock ownership plans; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H5CDE4711AA2342499C9B257E15B78987">
                                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>describe progress related to employee ownership in businesses in the United States.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HC20C5D01F83B43E5A1F24E5685CA4363">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Concurrent submission</header>
 <text>The Advocate for Employee Ownership shall submit a copy of each report submitted under paragraph (1) to the Secretary of Labor, and any other appropriate official, at the same time such report is submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HD2EDD8111C30462DBC4C854A7D38F021">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
                                <header>Public availability</header>
 <text>The Advocate for Employee Ownership shall make a copy of each report submitted under paragraph (1) available to the public.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE286D2CEA4C849ADBB4F17C62574B03C">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
                                <header>Definition of employee stock ownership plan</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>employee stock ownership plan</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">section 4975(e)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6086B71A108843C2A526F2A22BA68D4D">
                            <enum>(f)</enum>
                            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subsection (d).</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE4087B9538E2446FA22AA5E9B019FCB6">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3004 the following new item:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD832114414E846889E2750398A37FA60">
                    <toc>
                        <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 3005. Advocate for employee
                            ownership.</toc-entry>
                    </toc>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

