<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A6EEF21B282494E8ED46E069CB2E291" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 749 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of September 22, 2025, to September 28, 2025, as “Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 749</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of September 22, 2025, to September 28, 2025, as <quote>Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Program was originally authorized on September 27, 2007, by the College Cost Reduction and Access Act of 2007;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas 2025 marks the 18th anniversary of the establishment of Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions by Congress;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions are degree-granting postsecondary institutions that have an undergraduate enrollment of no less than 10 percent Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander students;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the purpose of the Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Program is to improve the availability and quality of postsecondary education programs to serve Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander students;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, since 2007, over 280 colleges and universities have been eligible as Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions throughout the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, today, there are currently 208 funded and eligible Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions operating in the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, as of the 2024–2025 academic year, 69 Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions are or have been funded in the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions are of critical importance, as they enroll, support, and graduate large proportions of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander college students, the majority of whom are overwhelmingly from families with low incomes and are first-generation college students;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions comprise only 7.1 percent of all institutions of higher education, yet enroll 46 percent of all Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander undergraduate students in the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions employ many of the Nation’s Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander faculty, staff, and administrators;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions award 51 percent of the associate’s degrees and 44 percent of the bachelor’s degrees attained by all Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander college students in the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas over one-third of funded Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions maintain an Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander enrollment of over 20 percent;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions play a vital role in preserving the diverse culture, experiences, heritage, and history of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions create culturally relevant academic and cocurricular programs, research, and services which increase retention, transfer, and graduation rates, while also enhancing the overall educational experiences of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander students;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas celebrating the vast contributions of Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions strengthens the culture of the United States; and</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the achievements and goals of Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions deserve national recognition: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H00F5322063BA47A29B9F184D2DDAD740"> 
<section id="HD6389860C50E45118AEDAFC0DEF9BE5A" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H619CE42267AF4202B2B819D02C852B41"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>recognizes the achievements and goals of Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions in their work to provide quality educational opportunities to Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander and other students who attend their institutions;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BABB30012B849B1B8CDA828B515D7AB">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>encourages institutions of higher education that are eligible Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions to obtain funding and establish programs to serve the unique needs of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander students, families, and communities;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D0D2871E8E346BBA867A49E250DF259">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>recognizes the 18th anniversary of the establishment of Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions and expresses support for the designation of <quote>Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Week</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1528DDF7AA8A463D8E46FAADFD16BBCB">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>calls on the people of the United States, including the United States territories in the Pacific, and interested groups to observe <quote>Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions Week</quote> with appropriate activities, ceremonies, and programs to demonstrate support for Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

