<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0253690CB59246D5BC0542963A8073AD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3707 IH: NSF and USDA Interagency Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Science Foundation to carry out cross-cutting and collaborative research and development activities focused on the joint advancement of Department of Agriculture and National Science Foundation mission requirements and priorities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8133F42EC96246E18F63020E61B5B16A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H039E31D3402E49B1BE54501D94A522EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NSF and USDA Interagency Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H41AE69FF2C3E4FEDB19929B5BC4DFD00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Agriculture and National Science Foundation research and development coordination</header> <subsection id="H3B271855B10E4B679F7C495B0BE5EF39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) and the Director of the National Science Foundation (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall carry out cross-cutting and collaborative research and development activities focused on the joint advancement of Department of Agriculture and National Science Foundation mission requirements and priorities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H86A833B7A8CD49B1A22789846E05A3C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Director shall coordinate the activities under subsection (a) through the establishment of memoranda of understanding or other appropriate interagency agreements. Such memoranda or agreements, as the case may be, shall require the use of a competitive, merit review process, as appropriate. Such activities may include components proposed by Federal agencies, institutions of higher education, nonprofit institutions, and other appropriate entities, as determined appropriate under the memoranda or agreements.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF1E08820E8B245BAAE88154634C2E79D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Director may carry out the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H96ED6075A80145969B21F3279F2E6F63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conduct collaborative research in a variety of focus areas, such as the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFF50662BD0954A0FB1B69A8C00F950F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Plant, animal, and microbial biology relevant to agricultural challenges.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H93DE9FBD170F43BBB9E221C78E4BAF46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Food and nutrition security.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD3975A31ED74C89822C101481CC4FB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Rural economic revitalization.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEC2997613F674C54868FE6B70BC0FA4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Cyber-physical systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6947DDF5FA1148F98E534D06208A410A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Smart and connected communities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE5CB4E1889045D1B91BBAFB590253DA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Advanced sensors and models of soil and plant processes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FD42F8EA9A24334BC30DBB281203952"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Nano-biosensing and analytical technologies to improve food safety, water quality, biosecurity, plant and animal diseases, and soil health.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD7A4752159E4411E9E17CEA99C5F5D4A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Monitoring of food- or water-borne pathogens, allergens, and accidental, natural, or intentional bio- or chemical contaminants.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D23765350264403981E494A46C7C84A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Key emerging technology areas, such as artificial intelligence, machine learning, automation, robotics, digital agriculture, distributed ledger technologies (including blockchain), and information and communication technology for agricultural uses.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEC2E069F52274A78B51ADE01DD937547"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Development and testing of new precision agriculture tools.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3577E5348F374CCC88EC13390F22134F"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Workforce needs, education, and development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD824B431A2D242B685A4B9B561B97ECC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promote collaboration, open community-based development, and data and information sharing between Federal agencies, institutions of higher education, community colleges, area career and technical education schools, nonprofit institutions, and other appropriate entities by providing the necessary access and secure data and information transfer capabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD96101890256404CA22E200D7408A2A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support research infrastructure, including new facilities, equipment, and broadband deployment, as the Secretary and Director determine necessary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB76556C33714AF098C7DC9AAD3FC001"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Develop translational technologies for commercial utilization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF4F801953484C5CBB7E0B4CA3AF3881"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Organize education, training, and research initiatives relating to STEM education and workforce development, which may include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HAA7BAB5FE45D4B2293B65F924F90DFE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Activities supported by the Cooperative Extension System.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C1188C2A10C4547B667C42944D68514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Industrial partnership programs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H71F5AC9A35814D558B63616B44F9605E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Workshops for educating preschool through grade 12 teachers on how to increase agricultural literacy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE1001DEDF754F39B7D2D1B12EC17FF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Development of agricultural-based science curricula for kindergarten through grade 12 students.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE15CCE4AAE54EF3918AEB10AB990939"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Distribution of resources for educators to implement curricula, such as the workshops referred to in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD06303EBD8E34757B3B6C11E879889DA"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Award grants to institutions of higher education, community colleges, area career and technical education schools, or eligible nonprofit institutions (or consortia thereof), to establish a Center for Agricultural Research, Education, and Workforce Development.</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58D16314D12546B791DC6CE3E0FA45B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilitate relationships between public and private sector entities to carry out the activities specified in paragraphs (1) through (6) upon the termination of any memoranda of understanding or other appropriate interagency agreement entered into under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD585C6B230548AABCBF8FC1D74E78FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Director are authorized to—</text>
<paragraph id="HEE2595093C044856932C22539B8781D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out reimbursable agreements between the Department of Agriculture, the National Science Foundation, and other entities in order to maximize the effectiveness of research and development; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17C1582B58554FDC9B7BE63FF40833B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with other Federal agencies, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H121426E7792645DC8E1AA30A393B83D2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Director shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD4AE5BC8675745D2A9E29285D46C611D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Interagency coordination between each Federal agency involved in the research and development activities carried out under this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0FD33D69850F4B52B44003E56C695A9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Potential opportunities to expand the technical capabilities of the Department of Agriculture and the National Science Foundation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F949CE8777E4067AAF3BEB660C96228"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Collaborative research achievements.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FDE6F6824AD4D7BB92571C2E8421199"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Areas of future mutually beneficial successes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8154C769457147579870B9603CD8468B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Continuation of coordination activities between the Department and the Foundation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7F2C82563B5346429865675350609336" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities authorized under this section shall be applied in a manner consistent with subtitle D of title VI of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19231">42 U.S.C. 19231 et seq.</external-xref>; popularly referred to as the <quote>CHIPS and Science Act</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H06366BE4DC9F4F7E9C9AEFFE407C8D0C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HBDB0EE2D3D9F4AB093AD8546601EB8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means each of the following committees:</text> <subparagraph id="H35564DFC611545CFB277C4B89FCB9982"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E4CCCF4C27344E9ABA03703C5C19240"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CEA1D5C7ACF4F65A03299FBD0D2BB63"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H962F26DB72D44D049635B736CB804F56"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D7E584311064B8FB2B0821D0F777760"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Area career and technical education school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>area career and technical education school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB22557FC8F5E44A1876C6C9443F65037"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community college</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community college</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3167B of the Department of Energy Science Education Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7381c-3">42 U.S.C. 7381c–3</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA29EE00780004FB3ADD0B6FFA27B8207"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

