<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H79FAA7EFEB5F4630BC50A575A888BB79" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4179 IH: Countering Wrongful Detention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide the United States Government with additional tools to deter state and non-state actors from wrongfully detaining United States nationals for political leverage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H308410E5DF7845AFB8906AE5C0010E4F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEF2ED3AE973A4639B20BDD03F30A2620" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Wrongful Detention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H933FBF87EB8C4EFEB77DE67B9C0C6E81"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 306 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB003CBED6D92458195AE6539237AC339"> 
<section id="HC38D705264B145E6BDC573358644403B"><enum>306A.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header> 
<subsection id="H44DEFD5A55384AA4B479684343A12BB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the notice requirement of subsection (d)(1)(A), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, may designate a foreign country that has provided support for or directly engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention based on any of the following criteria:</text> <paragraph id="H3F2FAF7767524FF18AA524FA69BDB877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national occurs in the foreign country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF37D79E87977477CA8A2B2A9B8168D2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The government of the foreign country or a nonstate actor in the foreign country has failed to release an unlawfully or wrongfully detained United States national within 30 days of being notified by the Department of State of such unlawfully or wrongfully detained national.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38323D453A1E4D668846B43523269ED9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Actions taken by the government of the foreign country indicate that the government is responsible for, complicit in, or materially supports the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national, including by acting as described in paragraph (2) after having been notified by the Department of State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8B24D9BBC9A4EDE81FF92D4FED25447"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The actions of a state or nonstate actor in the foreign country, including any previous action relating to unlawful or wrongful detention or hostage taking of a United States national, pose a risk to the safety and security of United States nationals abroad sufficient to warrant designation of the foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H771F59C20DAC44AF82B9919A4E97718B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H851CC82CAB78454BA4033DEB1F29B803"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination by the Secretary of State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may terminate the designation of a foreign country under subsection (a) if the Secretary certifies to Congress that it is in the national interest to terminate such designation and that the foreign country—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5806A98537EA4173B6C4D8D461B7742E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has released the United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained within the territory of the foreign country;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H153DA8EAD9624A9F87FF954C84FABC8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has demonstrated changes in policies with respect to unlawful or wrongful detention and hostage taking; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB25954D077E4D308E6A6D6D1EAD68B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has provided assurances that the government of the foreign country will not engage or be complicit in or support acts described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A61B671634B474DBDA85723B6069130"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination unless approval by Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The designation of a foreign country under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 6 months after such designation unless a joint resolution of approval with respect to the designation is enacted into law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7294375DDD04756B15F5801E216373B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on subsequent designations if designation not approved; exception</header> 
<paragraph id="H1D5960792FC841D9942702B1EC6FD506"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a joint resolution of approval is not enacted into law with respect to a designation of a foreign country under subsection (a) before the expiration of the 6-month period described in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of State may not designate the foreign country under subsection (a) during the 6-month period beginning on the date of the expiration of the 6-month period described in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4423238535134901A1B5A48B8339A5FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A foreign country with respect to which a designation under subsection (a) has terminated by reason of the application of subsection (b)(2) may be re-designated as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention for purposes of subsection (a) if a joint resolution providing for such designation is enacted into law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A81D300FDF648FE862FCD8AF66DA200"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing and reports to Congress; publication</header> 
<paragraph id="HB8EF035187C147419B1F7D827EC86123"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7BEDC3BFCD6415EB36B53B2BA8DF485"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after making a designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that notifies the committees of the proposed designation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C3FDE01174845EEBFF1FB3D1ABAC7F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each report submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to the designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, the Secretary shall include—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D756CC561D5470291F4A460312897D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the justification for the designation; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2684CC069944737AD24722E0D91AC30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any action taken by the United States Government, including the Secretary of State or the head of any other relevant Federal agency, to deter the unlawful or wrongful detention of foreign nationals in the country.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FA2C7624F644A989D30367A74E7A7DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial briefing required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C584159CC0D4396A01453C53FCC0CF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any of the following countries should be designated as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a):</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C318F948204462BA6EB09052BA512AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Afghanistan.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H443ACA57AFFD4906BD06F6A87CD27A53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Eritrea.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA19B17C4E4A94F569F067760E791A7A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71D2D6BF143A45F49FB53C94133FFBD8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Nicaragua.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00D06660546B4E7CB490697167882255"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC7B6404EE184602A59081AE44C9A231"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Syrian Arab Republic.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H926918432D4E48B7A318FDAF9771A878"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Venezuela under the regime of Nicolás Maduro.</text></clause> <clause id="H7B9924B1F573403EA12D7194B6448437"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Republic of Belarus.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7329525C45B8418897FCE6C997F325D6"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFECE72F32B64B3EB2C87518F2BDBE43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The steps taken by the Secretary to deter the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals and to respond to such detentions, including—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB234883561D4F80B16949685E30A794"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any engagement with private sector companies to optimize the distribution of travel advisories; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6B7BFD3E3B464D6EBB757E2BE9FCB7CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any engagement with private companies responsible for promoting travel to foreign countries engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F03149B92A14D389DC332779A1D959F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of a possible expansion of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act of 1976</quote>) to include an exception from asset seizure immunity for State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C9CA97C75F648638BC5AD2621A624A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The progress made in multilateral fora, including the United Nations and other international organizations, to address the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals, in addition to nationals of partners and allies of the United States in foreign countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61AF229624F446F6A4CBD0DE0FEBD5DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs and the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, or designees thereof, shall provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on the countries listed under paragraph (2)(A) and actions taken by the Secretary of State to deter the wrongful detention of United States nationals, including any steps taken in accordance with paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03C9AAD617F0474B8E05A9B3DB20E31B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall testify before the appropriate congressional committees not less than once each Congress on activities to deter wrongful detention.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A943EB87934F409AB046124B0AB5DA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of State, and regularly update, a list of foreign countries designated as State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D443FD9B7E348629E48E9204F19E067" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6BB7B69BB97F46AFB83438D8C73DCAD9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED2CB0A5ADE1495F86402E8AD84BE279" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1C0B56E0DED4DC58660E7DE29894F7D">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Review and determination of available responses to state sponsors of unlawful or
              wrongful detention</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive review and make a determination of the use of existing authorities to respond to and deter the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals in the foreign country, including—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="HFAC036D7858546B385248CA3C4E39812">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inadmissibilities available under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="HE9E8AB50764B48E59058932433A1CC2B">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>visa restrictions available under section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note) or any other provision of Federal law;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="H5AB4F4DFCCD84923BDD80066EE4A3339">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>sanctions available under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="HEBFCCF6EF0F544C5A5A9E3BC059E1CF7">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>restrictions on assistance provided to the government of the country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of Federal law;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7B6E795FC2804910891CF778108B6E1A">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>restrictions on the export of certain goods to the country under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDD4E6B3C6E53475FAE30F13BD1B733E2">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designating the country as a country whose government has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="HBFE4DD377B754C5BBD36D765B103945B">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF02EBD12236F4FF2A17140E96C2B30C8">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7315BA8F0FF74F5D8E1BE63D15FC9609"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H52E7DFAC93534909BDFC3FAF7A6FF5A5">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>any other provision of law.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AD47F32FBBD46EF8F9C38425A2D5F00"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to imply that every United States national detained in a country designated as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a) should be or is determined to be wrongfully detained under the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

