<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0CEC550A00EC40BD9C6E193DA937C085" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 920 IH: Federal Initiative to Guarantee Health by Targeting Fentanyl Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to list fentanyl-related substances as schedule I controlled substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31BAE04A71A5464884C2221F36C19C06" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H7F059BCC3BD94713A826DC2BAD304DFF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Initiative to Guarantee Health by Targeting Fentanyl Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE5A88B9C2BE04F79BE61E1D06502F59C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fentanyl-related substances</header> <subsection id="HC2209470E165487C9EE1D7D06777FE5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schedule I of section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B81A85DBB65471FBE41DEFF4232CC77">
<subsection id="H2E5CF6ABD88C4E5A89EFDC41066EA4A6"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB8E89D7004EE44D7B74FB17CCA6F129C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless specifically exempted or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of fentanyl-related substances, or which contains their salts, isomers, and salts of isomers whenever the existence of such salts, isomers, and salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5664D15C8CEF4E8B80989C2B1320C4D7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In paragraph (1), the term <term>fentanyl-related substances</term> includes any substance that is structurally related to fentanyl by 1 or more of the following modifications:</text>
<subparagraph id="H196FDD2D56754F7CB45E74CAC23F4C93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>By replacement of the phenyl portion of the phenethyl group by any monocycle, whether or not further substituted in or on the monocycle.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DBFBBF9775C43D3901067BA1EB6E105"><enum>(B)</enum><text>By substitution in or on the phenethyl group with alkyl, alkenyl, alkoxyl, hydroxyl, halo, haloalkyl, amino, or nitro groups.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD818CF4696D64D8987727BC90C079E6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>By substitution in or on the piperidine ring with alkyl, alkenyl, alkoxyl, ester, ether, hydroxyl, halo, haloalkyl, amino, or nitro groups.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F5C493A530D4FE28E2EBC9CB2D409F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>By replacement of the aniline ring with any aromatic monocycle whether or not further substituted in or on the aromatic monocycle.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFD177827BB7D4878A4EC9A04A2285C25"><enum>(E)</enum><text>By replacement of the N-propionyl group by another acyl group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAA1C5CA4F3524EF589FD012087DF7EFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No minimum sentence</header><text>Section 401(b)(1)(C) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Any minimum term of imprisonment required to be imposed under this subparagraph shall not apply with respect to a controlled substance described in subsection (e)(1) of schedule I.</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

