<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC940DB67A5C4C1FA724E9E2C40FE9E7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5238 IH: Stop Super PAC-Candidate Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5238</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act to clarify the treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions made to candidates under such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H823A606E4A424503BEBC9D8BCFBF329B" style="OLC"><section id="H0897CDBAC93A4DF9924EECBFC78468F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Super PAC-Candidate Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0E85B19EFA17427E8BDA082FC4F3C16E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions to candidates</header><subsection id="H47C75A2BC7064E65876FEB938CD4D9FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment as contribution to candidate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301(8)(A) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101(8)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H54417D15079449148D2B6E71E0936364"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (i);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H541D9F9E5CB242AE8EE73734D04288B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (ii) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H603640589A654BF09C0525117ABE7123"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H0B84978AC8E04A1199BB5D291F2DF23E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H452BF526A6754310BBD9EDFEAF9D37FD" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any payment made by any person (other than a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, or a political committee of a political party) for a coordinated expenditure (as such term is defined in section 325) which is not otherwise treated as a contribution under clause (i) or clause (ii).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB36232D7EB5246A68243BBADD74F264B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Title III of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCB9246154BEC44D29DCF28259E4CDFB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HD0ADCF4CC3E242CC8D32191F75C3B2C6"><enum>325.</enum><header>Payments for coordinated expenditures</header><subsection id="H5407DFCF03AF4D27AA242B9B7F4E5902"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordinated expenditures</header><paragraph id="HCBD55A16681444B2A9654C8A5143D063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 301(8)(A)(iii), the term <term>coordinated expenditure</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H71A64F02B7054192B4008D6FCA0302AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any expenditure, or any payment for a covered communication described in subsection (d), which is made in cooperation, consultation, or concert with, or at the request or suggestion of, a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, a political committee of a political party, or agents of the candidate or committee, as defined in subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BB738E62DC4456A8D7A98059FDAF9A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any payment for any communication which republishes, disseminates, or distributes, in whole or in part, any video or broadcast or any written, graphic, or other form of campaign material prepared by the candidate or committee or by agents of the candidate or committee (including any excerpt or use of any video from any such broadcast or written, graphic, or other form of campaign material).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4BA8AABA7854D0081D0E060A1331556"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for payments for certain communications</header><text>A payment for a communication (including a covered communication described in subsection (d)) shall not be treated as a coordinated expenditure under this subsection if—</text><subparagraph id="HE38114FBF50141F1A59054A296A09C49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the communication appears in a news story, commentary, or editorial distributed through the facilities of any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, or other periodical publication, unless such facilities are owned or controlled by any political party, political committee, or candidate; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA212849AE004CC3A3DBB3ED6ECE923E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the communication constitutes a candidate debate or forum conducted pursuant to regulations adopted by the Commission pursuant to section 304(f)(3)(B)(iii), or which solely promotes such a debate or forum and is made by or on behalf of the person sponsoring the debate or forum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4E9D612FB094C4D8B5F55619B040BA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination described</header><paragraph id="HFC26741DCCD2448C8F4E510F95F4DE8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a payment is made <quote>in cooperation, consultation, or concert with, or at the request or suggestion of,</quote> a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, a political committee of a political party, or agents of the candidate or committee, if the payment, or any communication for which the payment is made, is not made entirely independently of the candidate, committee, or agents. For purposes of the previous sentence, a payment or communication not made entirely independently of the candidate or committee includes any payment or communication made pursuant to any general or particular understanding with, or pursuant to any communication with, the candidate, committee, or agents about the payment or communication.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4346D766841442BEBAF965651584E608"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No finding of coordination based solely on sharing of information regarding legislative or policy position</header><text>For purposes of this section, a payment shall not be considered to be made by a person in cooperation, consultation, or concert with, or at the request or suggestion of, a candidate or committee, solely on the grounds that the person or the person’s agent engaged in discussions with the candidate or committee, or with any agent of the candidate or committee, regarding that person's position on a legislative or policy matter (including urging the candidate or committee to adopt that person's position), so long as there is no communication between the person and the candidate or committee, or any agent of the candidate or committee, regarding the candidate’s or committee’s campaign advertising, message, strategy, policy, polling, allocation of resources, fundraising, or other campaign activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9140C57ECE2B45E5BF6F8A6E8F874791"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No effect on party coordination standard</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the determination of coordination between a candidate and a political committee of a political party for purposes of section 315(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50975D1DE10443378F634919E2D94318"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No safe harbor for use of firewall</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall be determined to have made a payment in cooperation, consultation, or concert with, or at the request or suggestion of, a candidate or committee, in accordance with this section without regard to whether or not the person established and used a firewall or similar procedures to restrict the sharing of information between individuals who are employed by or who are serving as agents for the person making the payment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EAA919263D34E8FBE6AE00B84E2073A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payments by coordinated spenders for covered communications</header><paragraph id="HF9A71E949A3E441EBC463C3444B3B1D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments made in cooperation, consultation, or concert with candidates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(A), if the person who makes a payment for a covered communication, as defined in subsection (d), is a coordinated spender under paragraph (2) with respect to the candidate as described in subsection (d)(1), the payment for the covered communication is made in cooperation, consultation, or concert with the candidate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H993624097C184397825353740DC2F861"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinated spender defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>coordinated spender</term> means, with respect to a candidate or an authorized committee of a candidate, a person (other than a political committee of a political party) for which any of the following applies:</text><subparagraph id="HD01C8312D80941CD97397B5881A21173"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 4-year period ending on the date on which the person makes the payment, the person was directly or indirectly formed or established by or at the request or suggestion of, or with the encouragement of, the candidate (including an individual who later becomes a candidate) or committee or agents of the candidate or committee, including with the approval of the candidate or committee or agents of the candidate or committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD828D289DAE54337A1C476BFE0E80EA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The candidate or committee or any agent of the candidate or committee solicits funds, appears at a fundraising event, or engages in other fundraising activity on the person’s behalf during the election cycle involved, including by providing the person with names of potential donors or other lists to be used by the person in engaging in fundraising activity, regardless of whether the person pays fair market value for the names or lists provided. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>election cycle</term> means, with respect to an election for Federal office, the period beginning on the day after the date of the most recent general election for that office (or, if the general election resulted in a runoff election, the date of the runoff election) and ending on the date of the next general election for that office (or, if the general election resulted in a runoff election, the date of the runoff election).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4618E94155F74992864F793D41F77673"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The person is established, directed, or managed by the candidate or committee or by any person who, during the 4-year period ending on the date on which the person makes the payment, has been employed or retained as a political, campaign media, or fundraising adviser or consultant for the candidate or committee or for any other entity directly or indirectly controlled by the candidate or committee, or has held a formal position with the candidate or committee (including a position as an employee of the office of the candidate at any time the candidate held any Federal, State, or local public office during the 4-year period).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E7D84DB0E71483394CB00873747A093"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The person has retained the professional services of any person who, during the 2-year period ending on the date on which the person makes the payment, has provided or is providing professional services relating to the campaign to the candidate or committee, without regard to whether the person providing the professional services used a firewall. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>professional services</term> includes any services in support of the candidate’s or committee’s campaign activities, including advertising, message, strategy, policy, polling, allocation of resources, fundraising, and campaign operations, but does not include accounting or legal services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A291AB8D42A493DA5C28F2AFCD7EE44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The person is established, directed, or managed by a member of the immediate family of the candidate, or the person or any officer or agent of the person has had more than incidental discussions about the candidate’s campaign with a member of the immediate family of the candidate. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>immediate family</term> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9004">section 9004(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AECD4AC2BBC47638AC2EF68326D884B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered communication defined</header><paragraph id="HF41BDF4FC4104C76911A2DA4D2293B7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered communication</term> means, with respect to a candidate or an authorized committee of a candidate, a public communication (as defined in section 301(22)) which—</text><subparagraph id="HABE039C9420C4E8795A316C050F61FDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expressly advocates the election of the candidate or the defeat of an opponent of the candidate (or contains the functional equivalent of express advocacy);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF75A9273809449B3A6A10420FA15CB77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes or supports the election of the candidate, or attacks or opposes the election of an opponent of the candidate (regardless of whether the communication expressly advocates the election or defeat of a candidate or contains the functional equivalent of express advocacy); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H809EAEBF5ACE4B57B917C1CD5A11F6CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>refers to the candidate or an opponent of the candidate but is not described in subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B), but only if the communication is disseminated during the applicable election period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90EE4D2047D148FF897BFFE5BB87874E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable election period</header><text>In paragraph (1)(C), the <quote>applicable election period</quote> with respect to a communication means—</text><subparagraph id="H6EF78AA2BFB84684A9EE3A8DF876911B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a communication which refers to a candidate in a general, special, or runoff election, the 120-day period which ends on the date of the election; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FD3AF3F1CE64714AB897AE397C74911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a communication which refers to a candidate in a primary or preference election, or convention or caucus of a political party that has authority to nominate a candidate, the 60-day period which ends on the date of the election or convention or caucus.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7345C34B86C4DD88692F5F10D6C3D84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for communications involving congressional candidates</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a public communication shall not be considered to be a covered communication with respect to a candidate for election for an office other than the office of President or Vice President unless it is publicly disseminated or distributed in the jurisdiction of the office the candidate is seeking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E510CB44CC646BBB78B82EB60DADBD8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Penalty</header><paragraph id="H1A18B033B1CB4B6C971192F62550D18F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who knowingly and willfully commits a violation of this Act by making a contribution which consists of a payment for a coordinated expenditure shall be fined an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="HCBE392FFEBC445E6B1C57D7EDE26738F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a person who makes a contribution which consists of a payment for a coordinated expenditure in an amount exceeding the applicable contribution limit under this Act, 300 percent of the amount by which the amount of the payment made by the person exceeds such applicable contribution limit; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BFFA805D4674293AA72272E092E4911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a person who is prohibited under this Act from making a contribution in any amount, 300 percent of the amount of the payment made by the person for the coordinated expenditure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD75DE3AAD0BB4D489E63DF87B567CF16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any director, manager, or officer of a person who is subject to a penalty under paragraph (1) shall be jointly and severally liable for any amount of such penalty that is not paid by the person prior to the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date the Commission imposes the penalty or the 1-year period which begins on the date of the final judgment following any judicial review of the Commission’s action, whichever is later.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3183DEA632904B51B51615B678027448"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="HB0176116500245D499E3B77E53FA9EB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal of existing regulations on coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective upon the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HC383BF69BC094F40AE918990E81B173C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regulations on coordinated communications adopted by the Federal Election Commission which are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act (as set forth in 11 CFR Part 109, Subpart C, under the heading <quote>Coordination</quote>) are repealed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A3161B24B1445858A529787CEE50B9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Election Commission shall promulgate new regulations on coordinated communications which reflect the amendments made by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37750B0CD2144822AFD6A729CA1E0DBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to payments made on or after the expiration of the 120-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act, without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated regulations in accordance with paragraph (1)(B) as of the expiration of such period.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8920FCFC3A1741668511362FFA5563B3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of ban on fundraising for super PACs by Federal candidates and officeholders</header><subsection id="HF33456980FC442B1BCF18037A67694EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 323(e)(1) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30125">52 U.S.C. 30125(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8912CDB0BC894FCCB4CFB2EDE8B2B618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85AEDFBA895B4D269E70B325A012629F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E7A922A2C443DCA41BF2223A3A8A9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE1C24F94CFC349BD8C0A3054289EE915" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HEBE442A5E8094352B1DCEADC8B5A713B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit, receive, direct, or transfer funds to or on behalf of any political committee which accepts donations or contributions that do not comply with the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act (or to or on behalf of any account of a political committee which is established for the purpose of accepting such donations or contributions), or to or on behalf of any political organization under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/527">section 527</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which accepts such donations or contributions (other than a committee of a State or local political party or a candidate for election for State or local office).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06CFEA2E99B842A89FB7A8DE8D54C2B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to elections occurring after January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

