<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A93EF014034430797B035B07F782407" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 401 IH: Recognizing the 60th anniversary of SkillsUSA.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 401</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 60th anniversary of SkillsUSA.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas May 8, 2025, marks the 60th anniversary of the founding of SkillsUSA, the Nation’s largest workforce development organization for students, dedicated to preparing America’s skilled workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its inception on May 8, 1965, SkillsUSA has remained committed to empowering students through career and technical education (CTE), forging strong partnerships among education, government, business, and industry to equip students with the skills needed to thrive in high-skill and in-demand careers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas career and technical education bridges the gap between classroom learning and workplace needs, serving as the backbone of a well-trained and educated workforce that strengthens business and industry, drives innovation, and sustains national and global economic leadership;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas SkillsUSA’s Framework, focusing on personal skills, workplace skills, and technical skills grounded in rigorous academics, ensures that students develop the competencies needed to excel as leaders in their careers, schools, and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through career and technical education, students gain real-world experience that leads to further educational opportunities, apprenticeships, and meaningful employment in sectors of the American economy critical to the Nation’s future;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the collaborative partnerships between career and technical educators, business leaders, and industry partners fuel economic development by equipping graduates with the skills and knowledge needed to be successful in careers poised for substantial growth in the years ahead;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas SkillsUSA serves more than 440,000 students annually across middle schools, high schools, and college and postsecondary institutions, preparing them to become high-performing, skilled professionals who will lead America’s workforce in shaping the industries of today and tomorrow;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as the Nation’s largest workforce development organization for students, SkillsUSA continues to lead the charge in closing the Nation’s skills gap, ensuring career readiness, and strengthening America’s talent pipeline; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas SkillsUSA’s <quote>Drive to 65</quote> strategic plan is charting a bold course for the future, expanding access, advancing workforce development initiatives, and reinforcing the organization’s commitment to preparing students for the evolving demands of the workforce: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H12854517CF04406D85B54AE4B427A849"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H884EEFF362DF465086FB71F3A415A252"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H698503742D5E4DA7BEC1DD6D2371D4CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the recognition of the 60th anniversary of the founding of SkillsUSA;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E3225073561440F86E29E4BAAE49B11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages students, parents, families, educators, school-based professionals, employers, and other critical stakeholders to recognize and support the mission of SkillsUSA in empowering students to become skilled professionals, career-ready leaders, and responsible community members; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA401EFD338814EC49EA68BA0650D6AC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the critical role SkillsUSA has in strengthening access to and opportunities within career and technical education that develop America’s future workforce.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

