<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25115-PFP-Y9-3F3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 S257 IS: Promoting Resilient Supply Chains Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 257</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250127">January 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the resilience of critical supply chains, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="H2444888161CB430483888ED3D7DC9F27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H95EB9BDA9C7C453EA36539D0CB951900"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Resilient Supply Chains Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4C6CAA77D8EC4D69ADDEA66A5163DEA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2444888161CB430483888ED3D7DC9F27">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H8522EEB0C3B3480A80653CE1240B2BC2">Sec. 2. Additional responsibilities of Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Analysis.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H067366A069414925A7E6BFC42731245A">Sec. 3. Critical supply chain resilience and crisis response working group.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H84EF9D189AD147658F6EEDEF081AC306">Sec. 4. Department of Commerce capability assessment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD560A6389F6845968FB3623C5EC8739A">Sec. 5. No additional funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9D9C855BDABC4D9AB61ADB20871D77DC">Sec. 6. Sunset.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6DEAE4C244444135889C6A2865AC3C84">Sec. 7. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H8522EEB0C3B3480A80653CE1240B2BC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional responsibilities of Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Analysis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall have the following responsibilities:</text><paragraph id="H9E81E082DE4C402991699D5D5E9762C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Promote the stability and resilience of critical supply chains and critical and emerging technologies that strengthen the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D14C789609840CF989660D5F51C3E09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lead the Working Group established pursuant to section 3 and consult covered nongovernmental representatives, industry, institutions of higher education, and State and local governments in order to—</text><subparagraph id="HB031A469F2B34BA595DF5F9BD1CA25FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote resilient critical supply chains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87ED6E62F2C146779B22E601812B79D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify, prepare for, and respond to supply chain shocks to—</text><clause id="H934531E11E74426590283E3E4AEC01FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>critical industries;</text></clause><clause id="H57C9C42372A240178F2886C2C4435459"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>critical supply chains; and</text></clause><clause id="HF340167CF1434298B608F227A8CDF4ED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>critical and emerging technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EBE3D0B956A43009766A526E3182B43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Encourage the growth and competitiveness of United States production and manufacturing in the United States of emerging technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD42F862A2C3B48D9939EFC8E4250DDE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assess the resilience, diversity, and strength of critical supply chains and critical and emerging technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE20BB932D74D2E8C82F604940806F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In consultation with the Secretary of State and the United States Trade Representative, support the availability of critical goods from domestic manufacturers, domestic enterprises, and manufacturing operations in countries that are allies or key international partner nations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H099632F784724CEBA91DAC2F4EF231A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Assist the Federal Government in preparing for and responding to supply chain shocks to critical supply chains, including by improving flexible manufacturing capacities and capabilities in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD27727DEBF6437CB50FE90483D2F467"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Consistent with United States obligations under international agreements, encourage and incentivize the reduced reliance of domestic enterprises and domestic manufacturers on critical goods from countries that are described in section 7(2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B80BDA246F041648DC6E6EA0BD3A27A"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encourage the relocation of manufacturing facilities that manufacture critical goods from countries that are described in section 7(2)(B) to the United States and countries that are allies or key international partner nations to strengthen the resilience, diversity, and strength of critical supply chains.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H067366A069414925A7E6BFC42731245A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Critical supply chain resilience and crisis response working group</header><subsection id="HEEC72F84A827406ABA75F3147AA7D5CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall establish a working group to be known as the <quote>Supply Chain Resilience Working Group</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>) composed of the Federal agencies that rely upon the Industry and Analysis Business unit analysis, including agencies enumerated in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCA628E4FD6C8494793A7240B37E808A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall carry out the following activities—</text><paragraph id="HE9EFE7F7425F45E9804FE81D39061340"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with the Working Group—</text><subparagraph id="H812CB38A86BC4B82B0E8CD6D1CF7C5C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing, mapping, and modeling critical supply chains, including for critical and emerging technologies, which may include—</text><clause id="H028FFF7DA1384DCB9318C1AF9EAAFFF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>modeling the impact of supply chain shocks on critical industries (including for critical and emerging technologies), and critical supply chains;</text></clause><clause id="H08142A3EDEAB4C3D9B8A8F874C8E73D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assessing the demand for and supply of critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology needed for critical supply chains, including critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology obtained by or purchased from a person outside of the United States or imported into the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H014CB6F3795347D2BDEF5D28B8395DFB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assessing manufacturing, warehousing, transportation, and distribution related to critical supply chains;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7DE667BC68A4A17B0C61A8C38EA4909"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying high priority gaps and vulnerabilities in critical supply chains and critical industries (including critical industries for critical and emerging technologies) that—</text><clause id="H8080D24D365C4AF8AA7D650E9B9754A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exist as of the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></clause><clause id="HF83BACC6EF424578B09E4DA2183E9449"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are anticipated to occur after the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26A55E879F2E46C0A8EAAF47505F19E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying potential supply chain shocks to a critical supply chain that may disrupt, strain, or eliminate the critical supply chain;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA31D3AF8802148229BB369B055C30EE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluating the capability and capacity of domestic manufacturers or manufacturers located in countries that are allies or key international partner nations to serve as sources for critical goods, production equipment, or manufacturing technology needed in critical supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49CA029D93884AAEA6E35AFCF29A20B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluating the effect on market stability that may result from the disruption, strain, or elimination of a critical supply chain;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90DD7143A2464CD9B2BC64D2A768798C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>evaluating the state of the manufacturing workforce, including by—</text><clause id="H1287B42F87754B1E81C85C5DDA20568F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying the needs of domestic manufacturers; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E67E745D8624AEC9B86F9653BACA2F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to create high-quality manufacturing jobs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89666DCCC5084289BCA4E9B3D18D6E87"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identifying and describing necessary tools, including commercially available risk assessment tools, that leverage data and industry expertise to provide insights into critical supply chain vulnerabilities, including how such tools fulfill the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1370B0122CA49018961B690F083A9AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in consultation with State and local governments, the Working Group, and (as appropriate) countries that are allies or key international partner nations—</text><subparagraph id="H4285B52CBE874AF4B64A2A96B7C1ABE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to reduce gaps and vulnerabilities in critical supply chains and critical industries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H192E2CA1839241728A200B5B89B39E11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encouraging consultation between the Federal Government, industry, covered nongovernmental representatives, institutions of higher education, and State and local governments to—</text><clause id="H5A7C365066FF441285AB3D49F3E67B1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>better respond to supply chain shocks to critical supply chains and critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies); and</text></clause><clause id="H3C4FDCFC4A614C4DAE02A7C6C0AD0242"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinate response efforts to supply chain shocks;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69316BAEF7674E3EBF55D853A2018D5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encouraging consultation between the Federal Government and the governments of countries that are allies or key international partner nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE956D97B8C842E89CB3C08E7E49C68D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to build the capacity of the United States in critical supply chains, critical industries, and emerging technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97883C7DF7934611A77294A20B6EC554"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to build the capacity of countries that are allies or key international partner nations in critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies) and critical supply chains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05F8D59F69304E42A6E738FDD6C69696"><enum>(F)</enum><text>developing and assessing contingency plans and coordination mechanisms to improve the response of critical supply chains and critical industries to supply chain shocks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D0D9368666245B6BD203D02AFE011A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Working Group membership</header><text>The Working Group shall include a representative from each Federal agency that relies on the analysis of the Industry and Analysis business unit, including—</text><paragraph id="H237DEA8B4D9948F5831B6ADEA570D94E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9AB8E3915149CDB91897AF04152DF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35F955C9E3AE4778A7120DD92FD272F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87431FAC532642B5AEDAC99BE77C047B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1E5B06D9A03407595E86C762B97D8FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC42DF5486C3D4A3F94FBD7A3F9E678C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8DEA589BC44BFBBBBD149432998566"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06FA366254034E73B92CC9F892545F16"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F696FDB3674417A2BC9E4DF614C76F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF1EBCF0831F4A37A2E911B563B31D8A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BA4B9E5DDED4354864A796FBDD52618"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designations</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HFF7E1BCEB86041558DBB472737C09445"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, designate—</text><subparagraph id="H0BBA679AB1C847678F923DC5905F4666"><enum>(A)</enum><text>critical industries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDB85E4CC3CA409481E980A63BA5AC98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>critical supply chains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H453DA162817B484F94F2656D154F90B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>critical goods;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78E7999D7EE4CDEA52ACF47976B8B60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide for a period of public comment and review in carrying out paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFED6723126A54A2499873F217207E6B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>update the designations made pursuant to paragraph (1) not less frequently than once every 4 years, including designations for technologies that are not described in section 7(12)(B) that the Assistant Secretary considers necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29141565F0364E838B59EC45B345774A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="HA417DD7D33D84C66A7746049DA37DB70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details supply chain activities, including applicable activities described in subsection (b) and responsibilities described in section 2, that the Assistant Secretary has conducted over the past year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15A1ABA1FDAF4DBCB100C0AF2BE0A9BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes supply chain data collected, retained, and analyzed by the Assistant Secretary over the past year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B4B670C502D4A26A562A5B5573A4410"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies and describes necessary tools, including commercially available risk assessment tools, that leverage data and industry expertise to provide insights into critical supply chain vulnerabilities, including how such tools fulfill each responsibility described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5FD7D8866A435DAFC81D9EA9A2EC09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies and describes all Federal agencies with authorities or responsibilities described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EA8FBB73DE34BBEBDE3BE9AAC50CEAF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identifies Federal agencies, programs, and bureaus with duplicative purposes to fulfill any of the authorities or responsibilities described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2CDC6AC9B9D43758F3EC91391BFCAFB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>National strategy and review on critical supply chain resiliency and manufacturing in the United States</header><paragraph id="HC5D9DB5B3CBE423D84A8F3AC8F5D5312"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Working Group, covered nongovernmental representatives, industries, institutions of higher education, and State and local governments, shall submit to the relevant committees of Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H649215D875024A21AF5162A13CA07477"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies—</text><clause id="H52E05150DB434AEDB3E8CDC62B16F7F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>critical infrastructure that may assist in fulfilling the responsibilities described in section 2;</text></clause><clause id="HCD5D86498E8D4FC08D8AB877583ED07F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>critical and emerging technologies that may assist in fulfilling the responsibilities described in section 2, including such technologies that may be critical to addressing preparedness, weaknesses, and vulnerabilities relating to critical supply chains;</text></clause><clause id="H9A3CF1A559F942E3AB933DE62D9F1BA1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>critical industries, critical supply chains, and critical goods designated pursuant to subsection (d);</text></clause><clause id="H82CED8503FF54803A90ED630487BFDA5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other supplies and services that are critical to the crisis preparedness of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HA82986E825EA4F5E871890CDDBEC06CB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>substitutes for critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology;</text></clause><clause id="H89A1B7BC847D4B75ACB94E7B8F4CD81A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>methods and technologies, including blockchain technology, distributed ledger technology, and other critical and emerging technologies, as appropriate, for the authentication and traceability of critical goods; and</text></clause><clause id="H49749C861B9E4C8696FDB800750AA970"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>countries that are allies or key international partner nations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83A67292C3C24637BD75B89F9290E497"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes the matters identified and evaluated under subsection (b)(1), including—</text><clause id="HAA9816B04E9A4AD0A7B763F25793F35E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the manufacturing base, critical supply chains, and emerging technologies in the United States, including the manufacturing base and critical supply chains for—</text><subclause id="H2189270D09C3458491E9209B7E1F1E60"><enum>(I)</enum><text>critical goods;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4ACA0379843946878FCD4CF981E3D651"><enum>(II)</enum><text>production equipment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H599E3AD95F0644529B3F90E43FC6353D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>manufacturing technology; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBDD95365D47443208D0C88158D6A7FAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of the United States to—</text><subclause id="H778FE4790A0C4954BA868ADE907B1669"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maintain readiness with respect to preparing for and responding to supply chain shocks; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H48B03965A2894E47B126CAC753285A49"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in response to a supply chain shock—</text><item id="HC299F283D19646A5906E26A447B42963"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>surge production in critical industries;</text></item><item id="HD00A51CD498E41C2AC1A54A3246FE5A6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>surge production of critical goods and production equipment; and</text></item><item id="H1D9F6B20482C4A59A9F7697F09469309"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>maintain access to critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology;</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BF0C99E11394A538340CA7097E99AAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assesses and describes—</text><clause id="H9163E4B73BE145D0965B7E42C03AF06F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the demand and supply of critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology;</text></clause><clause id="H8DBCA0BB41464562B496DAC87ADCA5E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the production of critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology by domestic manufacturers;</text></clause><clause id="H4FCCA9C003F24913AF6BBAB7F74A4C30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability and capacity of domestic manufacturers and manufacturers in countries that are allies or key international partner nations to manufacture critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H3547A715CBA74B73885A45B199A0B961"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how supply chain shocks could affect rural, Tribal, and underserved communities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H316E0CA4DE53412D945E4DD377443580"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies threats and supply chain shocks that may disrupt, strain, or eliminate critical supply chains, critical goods, and critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA9A0223AFC14C9086BFA38EC8465830"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with regard to any threat identified under subparagraph (D), lists any threat or supply chain shock that may originate from a country, or a company or individual from a country, that is described in section 7(2)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD7DF9A9599D461482B9E9A47FB241CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>assesses—</text><clause id="HF3AAB8764A6644E1AE743CC4CFE4F73C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the resilience and capacity of the manufacturing base, critical supply chains, and workforce of the United States and countries that are allies or key international partner nations that can sustain critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies) through a supply chain shock; and</text></clause><clause id="H304957558F5144F1BA6EEF2F1952A7A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effect innovation has on domestic manufacturers;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB37D6797A4184AA4916D5D484A0FD178"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assesses the flexible manufacturing capacity and capability available in the United States in the case of a supply chain shock; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29A5E58834894D43AE27660146E0D691"><enum>(H)</enum><text>develops a strategy for the Department of Commerce to support the resilience, diversity, and strength of critical supply chains and critical and emerging technologies to—</text><clause id="HD94F2330085D4606B56D8BE9D02D5BB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support sufficient access to critical goods by mitigating vulnerabilities in critical supply chains, including critical supply chains concentrated in countries that are described in section 7(2)(B);</text></clause><clause id="H637C754509EA4B61A109ED8A663F81FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with other relevant agencies to assist countries that are allies or key international partner nations in building capacity for manufacturing critical goods;</text></clause><clause id="H7FC009BB51D042CE9CCD3DC2B013320C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recover from supply chain shocks;</text></clause><clause id="HDCC7718B653A451DA5A7114C8FA99207"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identify, in consultation with the Working Group and other relevant agencies, actions relating to critical supply chains or emerging technologies that the United States may take to improve responses to supply chain shocks;</text></clause><clause id="H0EAC357792E740B4B22C8F2FBDB89AA9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect against supply chain shocks relating to critical supply chains from countries that are described in section 7(2)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="HA4C18111BB6F4407A3F06C01CB2595D6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>make specific recommendations to implement the strategy under this section and improve the security and resiliency of manufacturing capacity and supply chains for critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies) by—</text><subclause id="H24F845D124504E1C8A430C736AFFECAA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>developing long-term strategies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H456FE6E6308E496C98ED1D37BABB1525"><enum>(II)</enum><text>increasing visibility into the networks and capabilities of domestic manufacturers and suppliers of domestic manufacturers;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF29C183B721D409B974E60D7C332B95D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><text>identifying and mitigating risks, including—</text><item id="H16A8BF4F05DE4344AF65DF988198A012"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>significant vulnerabilities to supply chain shocks; and</text></item><item id="H53EA011F54B64DD882453BCCF882857E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>exposure to gaps and vulnerabilities in domestic capacity or capabilities and sources of imports needed to sustain critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies) or critical supply chains;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H39660A216FA442F881D4EE03E655ECF8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to reuse and recycle critical goods, including raw materials, to increase resilient critical supply chains;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFAD4F914381D40C684F6F85056D0364D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>consulting with countries that are allies or key international partner nations on—</text><item id="H7A80A051D91B4FFB873B02892F5090EC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>sourcing critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology; and</text></item><item id="H14E2F0953AA04C4595069B8D39173707"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>developing, sustaining, and expanding production and availability of critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology during a supply chain shock; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H3347AC48C65A418C848662BE75263AE8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>providing guidance to other relevant agencies with respect to critical goods, supply chains, and critical industries (including critical industries for emerging technologies) that should be prioritized to support United States leadership in the deployment of such technologies.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9F4983689D4B678962290C77C35C64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) may not include—</text><subparagraph id="HA032A628278047FFB7306C903F97EF48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>critical supply chain information that is not aggregated;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4157A538FE4D4CD1ADCD6F17B42F9965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>confidential business information of a private sector entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABF2CEB1073B4611B7472F2292141EE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>classified information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B0566A68E94A6280DE4D3DB99BC429"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1), and any update submitted thereafter, shall be submitted to the relevant committees of Congress in unclassified form and may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF741C89CD44BC3B6EC8E0011628220"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall provide for a period of public comment and review in developing the report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF62B586D4084484BB09A01AEC1AD54CC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the head of any relevant agency to obtain any information, data, or assistance that the Assistant Secretary determines necessary to conduct the activities described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9303771C27E642C0A4D345AE9B775CF3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require any private entity—</text><paragraph id="HE796CBA5AAD84706A10523F9015C5178"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to share information with the Secretary or Assistant Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E13887A305241C193B002CFF2F7BF1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to request assistance from the Secretary or Assistant Secretary; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED1D57BA6BD145F986F0C2EA4443A31A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to implement any measure or recommendation suggested by the Secretary or Assistant Secretary in response to a request by the private entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AE53DAF47604608890ECF2C0AC83606"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Protection of voluntarily shared critical supply chain information</header><paragraph id="H3345CE6262354323B3F513A2969A8DC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Protection</header><subparagraph id="H35357652CBEB4C5A84EA1F5D3F089D71"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, critical supply chain information (including the identity of the submitting person or entity) that is voluntarily submitted under this section to the Department of Commerce for use by the Department for purposes of this section, when accompanied by an express statement described in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H89426EC4D54B4FC3B23527AEFA90E477"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>);</text></clause><clause id="HFEBBE88FF6DF47698AE1F6F759DE91C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not subject to any agency rules or judicial doctrine regarding ex parte communications with a decision-making official;</text></clause><clause id="H2B725FD872FA4132BD1F9DA8E79DD21A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may not, without the written consent of the person or entity submitting such information, be used directly by the Department of Commerce, any other Federal, State, or local authority, or any third party, in any civil action arising under Federal or State law if such information is submitted in good faith;</text></clause><clause id="HDB55D5734C684BC1BC71A008F6A98A8F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may not, without the written consent of the person or entity submitting such information, be used or disclosed by any officer or employee of the United States for purposes other than the purposes of this section, except—</text><subclause id="HFF72A1ED39A641EE9AB7A921BA873D77"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in furtherance of an investigation or the prosecution of a criminal act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H10520C50E01041BB847298E8F1D25410"><enum>(II)</enum><text>when disclosure of the information would be—</text><item id="H7B2D714993CB4A8AB51B1B8855D94D45"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to either House of Congress, or to the extent of matter within its jurisdiction, any committee or subcommittee thereof, any joint committee thereof, or any subcommittee of any such joint committee; or</text></item><item id="H7086342CE8694F6B857A42FD8ECC827C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to the Comptroller General of the United States, or any authorized representative of the Comptroller General, in the course of the performance of the duties of the Government Accountability Office;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HC33191A48CDE402AB2C6A0E37D8635D9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>may not, if provided to a State or local government or government agency—</text><subclause id="H1B1C5D36D936477BA1003B7BE0AE2A53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be made available pursuant to any State or local law requiring disclosure of information or records;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBAE92711A323422381049630C7DE84D4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>otherwise be disclosed or distributed to any party by such State or local government or government agency without the written consent of the person or entity submitting such information; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H0A909E341219488F9FC095C35972FBC7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be used other than for the purpose of carrying out this section, or in furtherance of an investigation or the prosecution of a criminal act; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA8472E3F595D435EB58D71B54257DABC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>does not constitute a waiver of any applicable privilege or protection provided under law, such as trade secret protection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE03398328CE54C9CBBC121EE65478F11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Express statement</header><text>The express statement described in this subparagraph, with respect to information or records, is—</text><clause id="H3A369E2F551444E08A0228A701DDC07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of written information or records, a written marking on the information or records substantially similar to the following: <quote>This information is voluntarily submitted to the Federal Government in expectation of protection from disclosure as provided by the provisions of the Promoting Resilient Supply Chains Act of 2024.</quote>; or</text></clause><clause id="H4B92F9BEB5B7415CBEC8FE0601EE0A90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of oral information, a written statement similar to the statement described in clause (i) submitted within a reasonable period following the oral communication.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE73D0377946D4B348ED8EEBD96EBB8F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No communication of critical supply chain information to the Department of Commerce made pursuant to this section may be considered to be an action subject to the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC79116FA8F1647CC82098D2181746FAA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independently obtained information</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the ability of a State, local, or Federal Government entity, agency, or authority, or any third party, under applicable law to obtain critical supply chain information in a manner not covered by paragraph (1), including any information lawfully and properly disclosed generally or broadly to the public and to use such information in any manner permitted by law. For purposes of this subsection, a permissible use of independently obtained information includes the disclosure of such information under section 2302(b)(8) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9831AF5290542DCA39DD77D000C6D09"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of voluntary submittal of information</header><text>The voluntary submittal to the Department of Commerce of information or records that are protected from disclosure by this section may not be construed to constitute compliance with any requirement to submit such information to an agency under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64DEB0EEDF594853BC4CE87FC36CC8AB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inapplicability to semiconductor incentive program</header><text>This subsection does not apply to the voluntary submission of critical supply chain information in an application for Federal financial assistance under section 9902 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H84EF9D189AD147658F6EEDEF081AC306"><enum>4.</enum><header>Department of Commerce capability assessment</header><subsection id="H1D7F35103A8F43D0900F520DD87C748C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>The Secretary shall produce a report—</text><paragraph id="HE83593CF939B4C609366CD84924BF0AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying the duties, responsibilities, resources, programs, and expertise within the offices and bureaus of the Department of Commerce relevant to critical supply chain resilience and manufacturing innovation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A872ADDCFAF48838A42446C21CB2786"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying and assessing the purpose, legal authority, effectiveness, efficiency, and limitations of each office or bureau identified under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDED8AA3A19AA455CA6AF5C8D58BCB2D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing recommendations to enhance the activities related to critical supply chain resilience and manufacturing innovation of the Department of Commerce, including—</text><subparagraph id="H19CE3D07855C4913BA843936BD41541C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving the effectiveness, efficiency, and impact of the offices and bureaus identified under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFDF9D7F0A334D8FBCB9BED44C803057"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinating across offices and bureaus identified under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H759FD7B9F6574AA7980D3B083C2C450D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consulting with agencies implementing similar activities related to critical supply chain resilience and manufacturing innovation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCFD482C0FB64C71A13A8D38C4133DA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the relevant committees of Congress the report required by subsection (a), along with a strategy to implement, as appropriate and as determined by the Secretary, the recommendations contained in the report.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD560A6389F6845968FB3623C5EC8739A"><enum>5.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</text></section><section id="H9D9C855BDABC4D9AB61ADB20871D77DC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and all requirements, responsibilities, and obligations under this Act shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="H6DEAE4C244444135889C6A2865AC3C84"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6C39F9A3EC2442BBB9F29F72484DAB9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98587BEBF7BB4652A9B6B3DE8E63DC49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ally or key international partner nation</header><text>The term <quote>ally or key international partner nation</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HF6A21B2DD6E747029185E55CCF7539F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a country that is critical to addressing critical supply chain weaknesses and vulnerabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94ACA1AD5BBB4962B536391F095CCEB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H0997BD41B4F943B7A9B98397AE3AEF4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a country that poses a significant risk to the national security or economic security of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="HAEEA9F0A74D34BF4836EBCED8BFEDE5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a country that is described in section 503(b) of the RANSOMWARE Act (title V of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 5564).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD32CB263D2144F8A85067C2C4C887D02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce assigned by the Secretary to direct the office of Industry and Analysis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC1DE28A3FFF468CBC75AEC2D0E573B7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered nongovernmental representative</header><text>The term <quote>covered nongovernmental representative</quote> means a representative as specified in the second sentence of section 135(b)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2155">19 U.S.C. 2155(b)(1)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include a representative of a non-Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15E3EE7C036B45999914741E12E598D2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Critical good</header><text>The term <quote>critical good</quote> means any raw, in process, or manufactured material (including any mineral, metal, or advanced processed material), article, commodity, supply, product, or item for which an absence of supply would have a debilitating impact on—</text><subparagraph id="H783066A79185480B96404584457C43EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the national security or economic security of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BB758EC1A4D43759C11380886099679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>either—</text><clause id="H1AEB60569499402C96BE9C22E8F88F1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>critical infrastructure; or</text></clause><clause id="HEA6F83B56A4D42479FDD030E85E6342F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an emerging technology.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45470DD474F846D2A10FDBE0E06D3F5B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Critical industry</header><text>The term <quote>critical industry</quote> means an industry that—</text><subparagraph id="H97FCC78684A944D39624B501A3AE1630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is critical for the national security or economic security of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H010CE249DDB8485A830AEC7F1B87FDE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>produces or procures a critical good.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ED72485C0F0474E904B14F526988064"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>The term <quote>critical infrastructure</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1016 of the Critical Infrastructures Protection Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AB809CD4FED4172A3059AF7A32492D4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Critical supply chain</header><text>The term <quote>critical supply chain</quote> means a supply chain for a critical good.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3402C7D5676745FB96F348DBE5CC038E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Critical supply chain information</header><text>The term <quote>critical supply chain information</quote> means information that is not customarily in the public domain and relates to—</text><subparagraph id="HB9E83D97814348A78853F4422C1AABCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sustaining and adapting a critical supply chain during a supply chain shock;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D9FAF834D340E6AF167329820B744D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>critical supply chain risk mitigation and recovery planning with respect to a supply chain shock, including any planned or past assessment, projection, or estimate of a vulnerability within the critical supply chain, including testing, supplier network assessments, production flexibility, supply chain risk evaluations, supply chain risk management planning, or risk audits; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC3A698835274266886B4EC5AB4E1947"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operational best practices, planning, and supplier partnerships that enable enhanced resilience of a critical supply chain during a supply chain shock, including response, repair, recovery, reconstruction, insurance, or continuity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB819275FB404F60854D50997CB1FA6E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Domestic enterprise</header><text>The term <quote>domestic enterprise</quote> means an enterprise that conducts business in the United States and procures a critical good.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16086E364C834BDF8A5D304637AAC03D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Domestic manufacturer</header><text>The term <quote>domestic manufacturer</quote> means a business that conducts in the United States the research and development, engineering, or production activities necessary for manufacturing a critical good.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB07266C9FD46E081833A05C93C8819"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Emerging technology</header><text>The term <quote>emerging technology</quote> means a technology that is critical for the national security or economic security of the United States, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7798DFA2DDCF493C93253FF3D0A7D41A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Technologies included in the American COMPETE Act (title XV of division FF of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3276).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8194FBC987342F3A203BDF24B0BEA25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The following technologies:</text><clause id="H9274C3F2813E4AC7B92C7B5367CDAE1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence.</text></clause><clause id="H415654F14A6D4BE88E5E56FED3BE7B11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Automated vehicles and unmanned delivery systems.</text></clause><clause id="H0DF2F43DB77047F89B54123B9F61F030"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Blockchain and other distributed ledger, data storage, data management, and cybersecurity technologies.</text></clause><clause id="H0452F5B78CC9486DBE7BC93D0CBEB26E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Quantum computing and quantum sensing.</text></clause><clause id="HA4C35B2057A74E92A0DEE447F6AEBF2C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Additive manufacturing.</text></clause><clause id="HA48DF3948D7A4B1E9D1DF29035838CCD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Advanced manufacturing and the Internet of Things.</text></clause><clause id="HD6359E6135BB4EB282330538903BB8FB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Nano technology.</text></clause><clause id="HE47B43B2929045DCAF854498649C617D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Robotics.</text></clause><clause id="HA31638D3D72A41BC89E7B4C68A5438E8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Microelectronics, optical fiber ray, and high performance and advanced computer hardware and software.</text></clause><clause id="H33F3B28E37A54197A7A83EDF1293A8AA"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Semiconductors.</text></clause><clause id="H2C420DB73BDF45D9B9CDBB50202A7C76"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Advanced materials science, including composition 2D, other next generation materials, and related manufacturing technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6533C67E0448578FFED60D7A7120EA"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DB392339593484AA0DB46B7084A407E"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Manufacture</header><text>The term <quote>manufacture</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HE7F81D06E1014440A4D8F90632EE2515"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any activity that is necessary for the development, production, processing, distribution, or delivery of any raw, in process, or manufactured material (including any mineral, metal, and advanced processed material), article, commodity, supply, product, critical good, or item of supply; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1846E2447F7344CBBD583CDABBB48A1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include software unrelated to the manufacturing process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E4B816F7CF43FA86279C68F0576642"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Manufacturing technology</header><text>The term <quote>manufacturing technology</quote> means a technology that is necessary for the manufacturing of a critical good.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE5DEEA4567D49659B3181F2B82CCA14"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Production equipment</header><text>The term <quote>production equipment</quote> means any component, subsystem, system, equipment, tooling, accessory, part, or assembly necessary for the manufacturing of a critical good.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2A7A784319E40EF905CB233CA6F658A"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>program</quote> means the critical supply chain resiliency and crisis response program established pursuant to section 103(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8877B41D39FD406BAD3CDB98F0203D79"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Relevant committees of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>relevant committees of Congress</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H24D3E086009147CBAA631BD11478A86C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BD5164949DB4032A9D3919DCE9FA585"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86081160C6C4B45B4A3F51F3897051C"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Resilient critical supply chain</header><text>The term <quote>resilient critical supply chain</quote> means a critical supply chain that—</text><subparagraph id="H067561DA6B7D4D14AFBBD6967D658A0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures that the United States can sustain critical industry, including emerging technologies, production, critical supply chains, services, and access to critical goods, production equipment, and manufacturing technology during a supply chain shock; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0F1C003468C4A59AEE3CA652662AE2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has key components of resilience that include—</text><clause id="H1D665A2C5C564CD5A45BAB829F885F55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>effective private sector risk management and mitigation planning to sustain critical supply chains and supplier networks during a supply chain shock; and</text></clause><clause id="HF926FB1D492C4FBAB528056C78175542"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>minimized or managed exposure to a supply chain shock.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80818C2C09504E5AA87E1DF640C9E76B"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA48A70BD26094CB2B5FEA538C58224AB"><enum>(21)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88479ABB26CC4BFD98CE02C1781491DD" commented="no"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Supply chain shock</header><text>The term <quote>supply chain shock</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H84BE01AB68FC4A8FABCA0523FBD6ED7B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an event causing severe or serious disruption to normal operations or capacity in a supply chain; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E790BA16EF4FD186B31FDB3181239B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="HAB2CF85EB10242ADA658F5B785059876" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a natural disaster;</text></clause><clause id="H8249744B661B4AABBC40048A8E570C28" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a pandemic;</text></clause><clause id="HFC89C925D39747B98E6FA0543EEF7E96" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a biological threat;</text></clause><clause id="HB8A4EF89509741DFA68B9D5CA58AD195" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a cyber attack;</text></clause><clause id="HD4A0EAE8174F4226AA4319635165294C" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a geopolitical conflict;</text></clause><clause id="H8F9491CEF24C460BB23E4B16C4DBC6C1" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a terrorist or geopolitical attack;</text></clause><clause id="HBDB3CCED402C42EFA4DD7DBFE780B70B" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a trade disruption caused by—</text><subclause id="HAC22A239D69F48468A347E763A2C2142" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a country described in paragraph (2)(B); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H92B080416AE341C1BF97CFBB2960F95C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an entity or an individual subject to the jurisdiction of such a country; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8D84CB4966DF4FF6873FF085764D2EE9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an event for which the President declares a major disaster or an emergency under section 401 or 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

