<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2695008859A54E09BE55489D1F7ADF74" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 605 IH: Establishing the Select Subcommittee to Investigate the Remaining Questions Surrounding January 6, 2021.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 605</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing the Select Subcommittee to Investigate the Remaining Questions Surrounding January 6, 2021.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H0CC4AC6EC21D493A89292185AA7159B4"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H1C5D407CC0424D0398F1F5CECF556923"><enum>1.</enum><header>Select Subcommittee to Investigate the Remaining Questions Surrounding January 6, 2021</header><subsection id="HA0A5ED573D4D41CB85B57EB36CB7F356"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment; composition</header><paragraph id="H9DF2182F9AC840F48C373AEAE8B0180B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established for the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress a select investigative subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary called the Select Subcommittee to Investigate the Remaining Questions Surrounding January 6, 2021 (hereinafter referred to as the “select subcommittee”).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE0E93F454A4A699FEA434E3E09529E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph id="H06064090352D49F5A449BB4491F1270B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The select subcommittee shall be composed of not more than 8 Members, Delegates, or the Resident Commissioner appointed by the Speaker, of whom not more than 3 shall be appointed in consultation with the minority leader. The Speaker shall designate one member of the select subcommittee as its chair. Any vacancy in the select subcommittee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CB5509C3F0F43D48E1FB1DA9CD5497F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each member appointed to the select subcommittee shall be treated as though a member of the Committee on the Judiciary for purposes of the select subcommittee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F474C2B6664EFD97F6921921DE869F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary shall be ex officio members of the select subcommittee but shall have no vote in the select subcommittee and may not be counted for purposes of determining a quorum thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C55674B48084700B16CFF31652E237A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service on the select subcommittee shall not count against the limitations in clause 5(b)(2)(A) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A025B306C8544F68DCCA5D687787575"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigative functions and authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The select subcommittee is authorized and directed to conduct a full and complete investigation and study and issue a final report of the events surrounding January 6, 2021 regarding matters within the jurisdiction of the Committee on the Judiciary under clause 1(l) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives. The select subcommittee may not hold a markup of legislation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H649AB96146E04C2A9D1E0C3BB70FF454"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedure</header><paragraph id="H76747A37156040799AC7D80DD1830407"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives and the rules of the Committee on the Judiciary shall apply to the select subcommittee in the same manner as a subcommittee except as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H315C876455FE4B018294BB7463F1C537"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The chair of the select subcommittee may, after consultation with the ranking minority member, recognize—</text><clause id="HB9792309E45240FC974AF68F0465C84B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>members of the select subcommittee to question a witness for periods longer than five minutes as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(B) of such rule XI; and</text></clause><clause id="H54EAC5D8767E45268991742465F52FE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>staff of the select subcommittee or staff of the Committee on the Judiciary to question a witness as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(C) of such rule XI.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0C6C2CBE4CD40439B5D61652AE1DBD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The chair of the select subcommittee may authorize and issue subpoenas pursuant to clause 2(m) of rule XI in the investigation, study, and report conducted pursuant to subsection (b), including for the purpose of taking depositions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H460D8D150F29467E8D7662D100598C17"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With regard to the full scope of investigative authority under subsection (b), the select subcommittee shall be authorized to receive information available to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, consistent with congressional reporting requirements for intelligence and intelligence-related activities, and any such information received shall be subject to the terms and conditions applicable under clause 11 of rule X.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81EE8CB79BFD44E4A99260F0306B7756"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the select subcommittee is authorized to compel by subpoena the furnishing of information by interrogatory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA606A52C426B4D2687BEE9EA54C5D398"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC08A8DF8B8204BDD8268EDE0BE9B5C6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the select subcommittee, upon consultation with the ranking minority member, may order the taking of depositions, including pursuant to subpoena, by a Member, counsel of the select subcommittee, or counsel of the Committee on the Judiciary, in the same manner as a standing committee pursuant to section 3(t) of House Resolution 5, One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84760FA6F99540EDB2210CCCE08E27ED" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Depositions taken under the authority prescribed in this paragraph shall be governed by the procedures submitted by the chair of the Committee on Rules for printing in the Congressional Record on January 14, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F63C1D794BA4A499F76F8A2FD358581"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpoenas authorized pursuant to this resolution may be signed by the chair of the select subcommittee or a designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA44FF07DF545B68278C9EAE5DE7FDD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this resolution shall govern the proceedings of the select subcommittee in the event of any conflict with the rules of the House or of the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C2747DC52B141D089F57F030DB824E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfer of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration is directed to transfer any records in any form relating to the matters described in subsection (b) to the select subcommittee not later than seven days after adoption of the resolution by the House. Such records shall become the records of the select subcommittee.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1C0B3B3949C40C9930DADAFD74B0769"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Successor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on the Judiciary is the “successor in interest” to the select subcommittee for purposes of clause 8(c) of rule II of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC905F2B8DD784384B53A67F11DE3096D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final report of the select subcommittee shall be submitted to the Committee on the Judiciary by December 31, 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0DDB8FA16B345E6BE06138B7440E63A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The select subcommittee shall terminate—</text><paragraph id="HDADAA7C6638A48088B2306F66837D7BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>30 days after filing the final report under subsection (f); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC74CAA02578D41DD809BA2275152E67F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on the last day of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">whichever occurs earlier.</continuation-text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

