<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H13A0B2FED0C343D7B1304FCD79CE5AD0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5648 IH: Disaster Relief Continuity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5648</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for continuity of disaster relief funding in the case of a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H34B077FF957E41579520DB7273C8CB8D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6B0A8D83CAD4AD58F9D56D4B3150EBD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Relief Continuity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC60E9DDB3A4742FE9F5D2D6895DAEE8A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuity of disaster relief funding</header> <subsection id="H59077E966C494068B17DAADD90C610CF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Continuous appropriation for disaster relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Assistance Agency for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary to carry out the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) for the following activities:</text>
<paragraph id="H555118619CA5401DBE502D2ADDD5DC2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing financial and operational support for declared major disasters and emergencies, including individual assistance, direct aid, and necessary life-saving and life-sustaining activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF92E24608DCD4217873CBBFC29A84607"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covering the salaries and expenses of essential Federal Emergency Management Agency personnel directly involved in disaster response, recovery, mitigation, and grant disbursement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H145F0F15AC034037A4D16325EA551BC0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Continuing payments and grants for existing, federally-funded disaster recovery projects.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1EB5BF986F7B4808AE13F264A6042350" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Amounts made available pursuant to this Act shall be available until the first of the following occurs:</text> <paragraph id="HDB4D8A54DD9E4FF3A06BF6E37047AC70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAAD5B8F13EF437EB9C96A0963E90F65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7BC13800B4C42D4A5EB1A3BD1E74FA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA75D764AB51D4199B0993B83351EC0B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>Funds made available under this section shall not be used for nonessential administrative functions, new policy development, or nondisaster-related training or travel.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

