<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25133-F65-HN-CX8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S707 IS: No Bailout for Sanctuary Cities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that sanctuary jurisdictions that provide benefits to aliens who are present in the United States without lawful status under the immigration laws are ineligible for Federal funds intended to benefit such aliens.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA426A4FBC52E4968AFBAD2FC5023A301"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0BFD26B329BD4A7BA59BE7AD869A94FC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Bailout for Sanctuary Cities Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H5B1FF54831214B739F0F3FA3E3264249"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of sanctuary jurisdiction</header><subsection id="H1539F30CF57D46F8ACB934BADE6FD1EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), in this Act, the term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State that has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any government entity or official from—</text><paragraph id="HA22FFE0D2DC34CA0A09D17608AF0F854"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sending, receiving, maintaining, or exchanging with any Federal, State, or local government entity information regarding the citizenship or immigration status (lawful or unlawful) of any individual; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F38F2153DAA46B1AAD09650B9925D77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complying with a request lawfully made by the Secretary of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref>, 1357) to comply with a detainer for, or notify about the release of, an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1464199254424D0298358E8B29500D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>For purposes of this Act, a State or political subdivision of a State shall not be considered a sanctuary jurisdiction based solely on the State or political subdivision of a State having a policy under which officials of the State or political subdivision of a State will not share information with respect to, or comply with a request made by the Secretary of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref>, 1357) to comply with a detainer for, an individual who comes forward as a victim of or a witness to a criminal offense.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HFF045E98ADB24F37A495A5DFCE3008FE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctuary jurisdictions ineligible for certain Federal funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is the earlier of the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act or the first day of the fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, a sanctuary jurisdiction is ineligible to receive any Federal funds that the sanctuary jurisdiction intends to use for the benefit (including the provision of food, shelter, healthcare services, legal services, and transportation) of aliens who are present in the United States without lawful status under the immigration laws (as defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)).</text></section><section id="H709174FC995E4826AD3B4637F8225193"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on noncompliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that identifies each State and political subdivision of a State that has, within the preceding 1-year period, failed to comply with a request described in section 2(a)(2).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

