<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4E236F5BA47449FB844AF9BD1AE4D2B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 723 IH: Recognizing the 180th anniversary of the United States Naval Academy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 723</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 180th anniversary of the United States Naval Academy.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas October 10, 2025, marks the 180th anniversary of the United States Naval Academy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Secretary of the Navy, George Bancroft, established the United States Naval Academy on the mouth of the Severn River in the historic city of Annapolis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy instills the virtues of honor, courage, and commitment in its graduates;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has earned a distinguished reputation for its academic prowess, regarded as one of the premier public institutions in the country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy remains cognizant of the Nation’s ever-evolving security landscape and prepares its graduates to address emerging threats;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has educated leaders for the United States Navy and United States Marine Corps, the forces of which protect our maritime Nation at sea, on land, in the sky, and in space;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has developed midshipmen morally, mentally, and physically to be professional officers in the United States Navy and United States Marine Corps and imbues them with the highest ideals of duty, honor, and loyalty, providing graduates who are dedicated to careers in the naval services and have potential for development in mind and character to assume the highest responsibilities of command, citizenship, and government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has graduated 93,140 leaders, including those who have served and led in the Civil War, the Spanish-American War, World War I, World War II, the Korean war, the Vietnam war, Desert Storm, and the Global War on Terrorism, and 2,700 who sacrificed their lives in actions against an enemy or died in the line of duty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has graduated 1 President, 32 United States Members of Congress, 48 United States Governors, 21 United States Ambassadors, 8 Secretaries of the Navy, 30 Chiefs of Naval Operations, 9 Commandants of the Marine Corps, and 55 astronauts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Naval Academy has graduated 73 Medal of Honor recipients, 2 Nobel Prize winners, 45 Rhodes Scholars, 16 Marshall Scholars, and 40 gold, 16 silver, and 13 bronze medal Olympic athletes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Academy has provided an opportunity for young Americans from all parts of our great country to receive a college education and begin a life of service to the Navy, Marine Corps, and the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the official motto of the Academy, <quote>Ex Scientia Tridens</quote> (From knowledge, seapower), is indicative of the purpose of the Naval Academy that exists in order to educate the people by whom that power is directly wielded; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unofficial motto of the Academy, <quote>Don’t Give Up the Ship</quote>, exemplifies the determination of this Republic and has inspired and stiffened the resolve of many midshipmen over the decades to stay the course and persevere: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H51CCC204EAE04A5CB28CE7062EA154E7"><section id="H712C40CCFE364C6EBDF446520CC3E7CB" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H11EF0FD06CB342E290F00FC6D60CC9BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 180th anniversary of the United States Naval Academy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H098C38EEF7594015AF24672F9A872011"><enum>(2)</enum><text>remembers and venerates the Naval Academy alumni who gave their lives in war and while on duty to the Nation they loved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD97568B810CF45A5AE3F9AE028D94B1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms the academy’s motto <quote>Ex Scientia Tridens</quote> (From knowledge, seapower);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81F39C21942D4F0AB0BE54AD13F706AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the alumni who are still serving, the students in residence today, and their families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DB854E4366B462F9A715B245BAF3551"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirms the support of providing the best education possible to our future Navy and Marine Corps leaders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB237DDD278540E2AE4A4B03CB722BBF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>salutes the 180th year since the founding of the United States Naval Academy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38619EBF20B045A9B0A80A82F5BAD4E2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>invites all Americans to join in the celebration of the United States Naval Academy and in recognizing its accomplishments and its contributions to this great Nation.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

