<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H29C809D08FA14289A9AA536BC9498396" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3661 IH: Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3661</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to take certain actions relating to incident periods and extreme weather, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC62231EB68D4AB593BB7AD9FC1D229E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9F3AE76DEE454257A2A8F84C8B9512EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H47077DC517624FB0847C0F5D6B4E73C7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Incident periods</header> <subsection id="H64AD72FBDA1248F0B749FDC375B9619C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall convene an advisory panel consisting of emergency management personnel to assist the Agency in reviewing the process and procedures related to the determination of incident periods for all hazards for emergencies or major disasters declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H95EF3A576B1D4234ADC83721D8FA754A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
<paragraph id="HCBF48633F44843DE9DAC2AF648EC26B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This advisory panel convened under subsection (a) shall consist of at least 2 representatives from national emergency management organizations, at least 2 relevant county officials, at least 1 representative from the National Weather Service, and at least 5 representatives from each of the 10 regions of the Federal Emergency Management Agency selected from emergency management personnel employed by State, local, territorial, or Tribal authorities within each region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86B76D21B0EA45B6A652A312248159BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion on panel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the furthest extent practicable, representation on the advisory panel shall include emergency management personnel from rural, urban, underrepresented, Tribal, and insular jurisdictions and representatives of State or local governments with responsibility for the financial or budgetary impact of disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF8F2BFDDF5EB4B9B8740C1054117229D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing the process and procedures related to the determination of incident periods under subsection (a), the advisory panel convened under such subsection shall consider the effectiveness of incident periods, including—</text> <paragraph id="HE5CB9B22D67E498E9917640C00714D0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incident periods for slow on-set disasters;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF58A2F761634BDF97E0C5845D11D7CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incident periods for correlated non-contiguous disasters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6F047B0F0D64573B51128E9937D0791"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incident periods for compound disasters; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07793CC3261D47EFBE48EE1E1FDE2167"><enum>(4)</enum><text>incident periods for cascading disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F9BFBABEE4340B9B7DFB30229E5EC11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report regarding the findings of the review under this section that includes any recommendations of the advisory panel convened under subsection (a), including additional legislation that may be necessary to address such findings.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC7E1610A5E474E2DBEF422CE55A1A8D2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report discussing—</text> <paragraph id="H898A368043D340E7A02E9AF1A172DEAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the findings of the advisory panel convened under subsection (a);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3804B7190AFB4A1D91E3469C136EF94A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the implementation of recommendations from such advisory panel; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA836CC59380840AE89A3BD65D05450C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional legislative recommendations necessary to improve the effectiveness of incident periods.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0EAC586B666E4A64A6CC1446AA43E490" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediately following a 30 day congressional review period of the report described in subsection (e), the Administrator shall begin a rulemaking to issue such regulations as are necessary to implement the recommendations of the advisory panel.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFA96A0C10B2043A996825A80CCBC71BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mitigation and preparedness</header> <subsection id="H8CCA3416BEC44A7F878E0B90FF57ED90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may, under section 203 and 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5133 and 5170c)—</text>
<paragraph id="H58393E9686724E379C599F5DC6ED45B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider innovative preparedness and mitigation projects eligible for the purposes of mitigating impacts during an extreme heat event, including stockpiling and installing equipment for households, first responders, and public health and health care systems and emergency voucher programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21CBFE44E1794B79803095709E41AB68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider innovative preparedness and mitigation projects eligible for the purposes of mitigating the impacts of extreme cold; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6ECBA8091AA645B8B4BEEF187BABFB10" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to eligible uses of funds authorized, provide, and issue relevant guidance, for the establishment and function of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB8723372A6C049BF979C21E2167CDDFB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community cooling centers; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEDEAEF59F77E433AACEE2C3CCBE17089" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resilience centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FE598CC4F254C3D961C957F722E00BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other assistance provided under any other Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3A17F725A3C745188FF8C43CA2786401"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0F1E6E9B42A24944AC31EE643F8AF39E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community cooling center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community cooling center</term> means a public serving facility that provides an environment for people to maintain a healthy body temperature during an extreme heat event.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H019CB88600614657A204018D9BEC1897"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resilience center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>resilience center</term> means a public serving facility with a hazard resistant design with the purpose of programing, operations, and communication to build community resilience before, during, and after emergency events.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H866298C6BC9549DC80F4546B65253E46"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue guidance related to—</text>
<paragraph id="HD6DA404A7B094CCC9AD54AE6383F04FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extreme temperature events, including heat waves and freezes, and publish such guidance in the Federal Emergency Management Agency Public Assistance Program and Policy Guide;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC55528F6709A406188914081B3F1F360"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hazard mitigation, including eligibility criteria for projects that primarily mitigate the impacts of extreme heat and projects specified in section 3(a)(2); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H25A6438ADAEB42AE8C242F1CC8612E9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extreme heat for the purposes of hazard mitigation planning under section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>), the National Preparedness Course Catalog, National Disaster Recovery Framework, National Response Recovery Framework, and Threat and Hazard Identification and Risk Assessment.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6A270162FF1447CD99DE907631140CCB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on extreme heat and cold</header> <subsection id="HFAF2221AD77F4A2496B7B53569FF3C23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall conduct a study to measure the impact of extreme heat and recommend guidance on mitigating and responding to extreme heat and cold.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE232B65165EA4C919D8778805548695B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with relevant stakeholders and the heads of other Federal agencies.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4E7DC8DF829643808B31B1A194D4F624"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content</header><text>In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H7EC74E870AD642EEA7850CB23D95A6F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine and consider solutions to address the impact of extreme heat and cold on—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC3A79CE0D104BDE9092DD456E52846B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disadvantaged communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9AD4B036B0904E66B5520163A53BE42F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>buildings, roads, utilities, power generation, air conditioning units, and other relevant infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E11630AE267495C8C5B9598336B8990"><enum>(C)</enum><text>short- and long-term health outcomes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD43E5571D0C148BFAD65DB6FE34278B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>pets and livestock;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3268B7E84C742B39B675D2F261E7780"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the geographical and regional differences in the occurrence and impact of extreme heat and cold;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H988EED6521F44D4BB9B9C9AAF0CABB99"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the effectiveness of emergency alerts and the language used in such alerts to improve public safety during extreme heat and cold events;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1261E66F3FE3430EA435096B9FE4BF99"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine metrics for defining and communicating the severity of an extreme heat and cold event;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A066A9836FA48FE821AC57E695B8A33"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the compounding effects and consequential risk of extreme heat and cold and wildfire smoke;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F4A7B19CB92481AA8C7FDB6898921F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend best practices for community education and safety during extreme heat and cold events;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE86B51D07DA9487AA298B88D61F82F26"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the impact extreme heat and cold to the health and safety of the Federal Emergency Management Agency workforce when responding to disasters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25B3B29DD61F4C3CA2926F41564CAE95"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop guidance for first responder training protocol for extreme heat and cold emergencies; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D19CC0E6B0F459692CFD342464E6E97"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend guidance for incorporating extreme heat and cold into local and State government emergency management preparedness plans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H433B4791A8AF4DB399B4D41B6555CF0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not less than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate a report containing—</text>
<paragraph id="HDF093922E7454F019B085B3B0B9B78D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of study required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EE409E2873542A1AB8D42216A190CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional recommendations for developing a framework for mitigating and responding to extreme heat and cold emergencies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

