<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BUR25159-SX9-YG-3NS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 75 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that member countries of NATO must commit at least 2 percent of their national gross domestic product to national defense spending to hold leadership or benefit at the expense of those counties who meet their obligations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 75</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that member countries of NATO must commit at least 2 percent of their national gross domestic product to national defense spending to hold leadership or benefit at the expense of those counties who meet their obligations.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, the heads of state and governments of the member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (commonly known as <quote>NATO</quote>) renewed their earlier commitment to invest 2 percent of their national gross domestic product (referred to in this preamble as <quote>GDP</quote>) to defense spending to help ensure the continued military readiness of NATO;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NATO considers the 2 percent commitment as a floor and not a ceiling for what member countries of NATO have committed to invest in their national defense efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the current global security environment has caused the current leadership of NATO and the United States to consider raising this commitment even higher;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 23 of the 31 member countries spent at least 2 percent of their GDP on national defense in 2024; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the year 2000, NATO has lost almost $2,000,000,000,000 in mutual defense spending capability from member countries not meeting the commitment of 2 percent of their GDP towards defense; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is in the interest of all member countries to meet the 2 percent minimum commitment or have a plan in place to do so before the opening session of the NATO Summit in The Hague, which is scheduled to take place in June 2025: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that—</text><paragraph id="ida220ef42673d4406945acf19b6013b0e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any citizen of a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (commonly known as <quote>NATO</quote>) that is not meeting its commitment to spend 2 percent of its gross domestic product (referred to in this resolution as <quote>GDP</quote>) on national defense should not be allowed to hold any position within the leadership of NATO, including positions such as—</text><subparagraph id="id632f0ec14f1a40d5a9e32143d3cc7cee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary General of NATO;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b21edc5fd0247efb33069661638d5d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Deputy Secretary General of NATO;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide32a367853d443c688fba69b9830aae1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any Assistant Secretaries General of NATO;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15a23c29639c465fb37fb55a0dc6700d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the NATO Spokesperson; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d9a6eb656064a53981ff731ecf5b094"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any uniformed military leadership or command positions within the structure of NATO at the 2-star (OF–7) level or above; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2485a1ddeb94a22b5b40c3485572474"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any member country of NATO that fails to meet its commitment to spend 2 percent of its GDP on national defense should not be allowed to host any significant formal or informal meetings, conferences, or summits of NATO at the ministerial level or above, outside established routine corporate processes of NATO that direct military operations or coordination at a headquarters location, that would provide substantial economic benefit to the economy and enable the ability for that member country to receive international recognition, including—</text><subparagraph id="id80ced2299481464dbb064e99ff99c621"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the NATO Summit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc99252e03a3d4ba097d5168891fbab6b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meetings of NATO Ministers of Foreign Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5eaff945569c4f3bb90ff135bebf2446"><enum>(C)</enum><text>NATO Parliamentary Assembly sessions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60c36facaf134eccaea30ac414ccc3d4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the NATO Youth Summit or similar events.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

