<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC809C274AB24E72A16FD1643230D34B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 696 IH: Recognizing the 60th anniversary of independence of the Republic of Singapore and supporting a strong United States-Singapore relationship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 60th anniversary of independence of the Republic of Singapore and supporting a strong United States-Singapore relationship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 60 years ago, on August 9, 1965, the Republic of Singapore became an independent nation, following its separation from Malaysia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 will mark the 60th anniversary of United States-Singapore diplomatic relations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore has undergone rapid transition from a low-income country at independence to a wealthy, advanced economy today;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore transitioned from a recipient of United States and international financial assistance to a donor country, providing financial support to regional partners and multinational efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore’s growth has been marked by an open business climate and Singapore’s economy has been consistently recognized for its strong rule of law, protection of intellectual property, transparent regulations, and history of fighting corruption;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 5,800 American companies have regional offices in Singapore, helping the United States compete economically across Asia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Singapore have had a free trade agreement since 2004, and the United States has enjoyed a consistent trade surplus for over two decades, which grew nearly four-fold from $7,000,000,000 in 2004 to $27,000,000,000 in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore is the third-largest Asian investor in the United States and Singapore’s trade and investments support over 330,000 jobs in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore’s leadership in artificial intelligence, energy, and biotechnology represents an opportunity for jointly building leadership in advanced technology;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore plays an indispensable role in regional security through close collaboration with the United States military;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore and the United States share a vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States military forces routinely rotate through Singapore, facilitating patrols in the South China Sea and throughout the region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore has joined the United States in coalitions to counter global threats like ISIS and piracy in the Gulf of Aden;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Singapore is committed to interoperability, through purchasing defense equipment from the United States, joining multilateral exercises, and training Singaporean military personnel in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 30,000 Americans live in Singapore and almost 40,000 Singaporean citizens live in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas study abroad opportunities and academic exchanges between the United States and Singapore allow students and faculty to gain valuable educational experience and build their professional networks; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas closer cooperation between the United States and Singapore is in the interest of both nations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H041DDEE3DCFA447E924B34CAF1B4BC06"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H45B9E75D83B749EF9FBB458129F0A9FA"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="HF9C692FB1B1B4E25BE4C44200D267945"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 60th anniversary of the independence of the Republic of Singapore; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF510F0C9E8764106BE5E0BAF5864B969"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms its support for a strong United States-Singapore bilateral relationship with a focus on increasing economic, security, and people-to-people ties.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

