<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37B861B06CF3461197B640524F540B4B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4120 IH: Supporting the Mental Health of Educators and Staff Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4120</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625">June 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address behavioral health and well-being among education professionals and other school staff.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE9B3AD8848D549649A5CACE10F43575D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDA97954043BC4D07BC7ED17EDD5AED46" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting the Mental Health of Educators and Staff Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3CF184E99FF64CB38470C94FE6FE7FA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dissemination of best practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall identify and disseminate evidence-based or evidence-informed best practices for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6743D777E08C4F2597E3C9B8143C0937"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing suicide and improving mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E209D2A00CB4685B5CCBEC8E52841D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training education professionals and other school staff in appropriate strategies to support, maintain, and promote their mental health.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7494FA4173CB4B7C84BD22ABC802B301"><enum>3.</enum><header>Education and awareness initiative encouraging use of mental health and substance use disorder services by education professionals and other school staff</header> 
<subsection id="H22F4884F15BF45ADBFBD3B8A2CF80B01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, including medical professional associations, shall establish a national evidence-based or evidence-informed education and awareness initiative—</text> <paragraph id="H2998BEEC021C4C2298098706B0E03619"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to encourage education professionals and other school staff to seek support and care for their mental health or substance use concerns, to help such professionals and staff identify factors associated with risks for suicide and mental health conditions, and to help such professionals and staff learn how best to respond to such risks, with the goal of preventing suicide, mental health conditions, and substance use disorders; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB2A56274FCA4A1B8CD6421C874879FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address stigma associated with seeking mental health and substance use disorder services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2EBA3EE4DB444850BCF24FF0B7D56EEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide to the Congress an update on the activities and outcomes of the initiative under subsection (a), including a description of quantitative and qualitative metrics used to evaluate such activities and outcomes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD177D0A8F5FC4328B1819FEF388EC621"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H20FD9326A0CB4F099AB2C3863614BA3C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Programs to promote mental health among the education workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 1 of part E of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB67F81800BC04B9FB09F108D1D907D0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the second section 764 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294s">42 U.S.C. 294s</external-xref>, as added by section 4 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/105">Public Law 117–105</external-xref>) as section 764A; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59BD081FAB34473187A1354608C6B411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after such section 764A, as so redesignated, the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDBBC2A6C65114A64968882A707C645C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1C379EAA9066423796A50FF153CE5389"><enum>764B.</enum><header>Programs to promote mental health among the education workforce</header> 
<subsection id="H9FBC419DCF21420CA3E87F3C10DB458B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Programs To promote mental health among education professionals and other school staff</header> 
<paragraph id="H3EA913AFFAC54CC49B32F919B12C67AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants or contracts to eligible entities to establish or enhance evidence-based or evidence-informed programs dedicated to improving mental health and resiliency for education professionals and other school staff.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D9AEA51169646B8AD62A7B2AEE2331D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant or contract under this subsection, an entity shall be a State educational agency, a local educational agency, an institution of higher education, or a consortia thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A561DE053E14810B5B12C053E369519"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An recipient of a grant or contract under this subsection shall use funds received through the grant or contract to implement a new program or enhance an existing program to promote mental health among education professionals and other school staff, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H613C38E6BA5444569E41ACC667723681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving awareness among education professionals and other school staff about risk factors for, and signs of, suicide and mental health or substance use disorders, in accordance with evidence-based or evidence-informed practices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A499A65712441F9B8CF3E2CD8F1A35A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing new, or enhancing existing, evidence-based or evidence-informed programs for preventing suicide and improving mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35A5958BA3FA423A9E50968788EA4AD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing new, or enhancing existing, peer-support programs among education professionals and other school staff; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H24EC3C0263C64739AA2848684BC0D9F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing mental health care, follow-up services and care by a licensed or certified mental health professional (including by means of telehealth), or a referral for such care or services by a licensed or certified mental health professional, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8652FC5E2F0E4803B731E169C64AEDC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants and contracts under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities in areas with a high percentage of schools receiving financial assistance under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF12B301F21A442ED8D29BE035F72E6C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish a program to award grants to institutions of higher education, State educational agencies, local educational agencies, State or local governments, Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations, or other appropriate public or private nonprofit entities (or consortia of entities, including entities promoting multidisciplinary approaches) to support the inclusion in educator preparation programs (including administrator preparation programs), and in training, continuing education, or professional development programs for education professionals and other school staff, of evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies—</text> <paragraph id="HF30B11977235439481178E59B67AFD20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to address mental and substance use disorders; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33C90192343549BEADB973CCE2ED6B06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAAB7CA88228D4324BA2DCE9D22D86946"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant terms</header><text>A grant or contract awarded under subsection (a) or (b) shall be for a period of 3 years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB94665D4B0B4FDDBEE0D0185612DB4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application submission</header><text>An entity seeking a grant or contract under subsection (a) or (b) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB7773FF45A640869699368CCB6C4777"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>An entity awarded a grant or contract under subsection (a) or (b) shall submit to the Secretary an annual report evaluating the activities supported by the grant or contract.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB691301709C740D3AE665016A3CBD672" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4D980E2FCDEC4AB08B0BADBCF874F11D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD5534D5B64F410081C87131194B44E2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given to such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD2322499BA254E87A463788CD92F1591"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0D79CBC48B3742DEBE4D82ABBD4B9B57"><enum>5.</enum><header>Review with respect to education workforce mental health and resiliency</header> 
<subsection id="H6E8BAF98744A4F49B96F2E0E17AA8FB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCF69FD33F4BB4158890CECD54E46F7C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review on improving—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC2CA9D409CF1430DACDD1103E04278F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the mental health of education professionals and other school staff; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC559BE8CD87E43059DEB84FAEAC05B14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outcomes of programs authorized under this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EC380A3E1B345D6B5111F68B11C08C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the Congress on the results of such review.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB2C68C88BD854ECE9285FEE522AD379C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The review under subsection (a) may include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDF149214852B40AD9831D4E93C8D64F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assessing the prevalence and severity of mental health conditions among education professionals and other school staff, and determining the factors that contribute to those mental health conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AE39B11CF99494081E9F9BCE94FB80F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessing barriers to seeking and accessing mental health care for education professionals and other school staff, and actions taken by State educational agencies and local educational agencies, or other organizations, as appropriate, to address such barriers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1BF3BFE7FF04FA58B1EE4EF1AEBF83A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determining the effects of the COVID–19 public health emergency on the mental health of education professionals and other school staff and lessons learned for future public health emergencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F1B0703F5D3458E94658C4FF3D54819"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assessing programs and policies that promote mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff, including programs and policies to strengthen mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD909E29FFE8C4A5182D4D8BF93CCB58D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assessing the efficacy of training programs for education professionals and other school staff that promote resiliency and improve mental health.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFE2BB4F584FD426AB3D4D6E45071AC97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The review under subsection (a), as appropriate, shall identify best practices related to, and make recommendations to address—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC83B5D31B7CA41178EC748BA0DC37C0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving mental health and resiliency among education professionals and other school staff;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB301C0F329F54F8AB676F596D40256BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>removing barriers to mental health care for education professionals and other school staff; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0783678D60F8467BA2C62521FAEC4637"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strategies to promote resiliency among education professionals and other school staff in health care settings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD48FA77BA4F64E76AD1AD91099B6EFF6"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Congress a report on the extent to which Federal substance use disorder and mental health grant programs address the prevalence and severity of mental health conditions and substance use disorders among education professionals and other school staff. Such report shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE16B4FF7E94B4CFEBC03C94988167A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include an analysis of available evidence and data related to such conditions and programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778A182F68A0449094C0880DF6AC60B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess whether there are duplicative goals and objectives among such grant programs.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

