<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E5D282EE7164D7A8AADCF9AB6644EC6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5326 IH: Firefighter Learning And Management Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5326</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to cancel or delay certain courses and programs offered by the Academy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H91CCE419F6B748C1B445AE013736C187" style="OLC"><section id="H41AC3689D4C04DC19E9169BBDB21E301" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Firefighter Learning And Management Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FLAME Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H37F2BFD370474D94B7FD72B2BCC9A433"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HCA2094E376A04433A808934D3EAE6257"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control (in this section referred to as the <quote>Academy</quote>) of the United States Fire Administration, and the Emergency Management Institute, are located at the National Emergency Training Center in Emmitsburg, Maryland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F4B571AB1FA49BD953EA3A72BA303FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress directed the establishment of the Academy in accordance with section 7 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2206">15 U.S.C. 2206</external-xref>) to <quote>advance the professional development of fire service personnel</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8A3778CA8540F99894C1BD733BAB34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Academy is the American fire service war college and provides critical training and education programs for our nation’s first responders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39DFAC171DFA44F380324ABD12962761"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tens of thousands of career and volunteer firefighters from departments across the country benefit from courses at the Academy annually.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4440CD333F14CFF956902C3F3F53E42"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2017, an overwhelming majority of students at the Academy reported that their coursework helped improve their individual skills and enhanced their local fire department’s readiness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF3B1F710CC4481AEE97843F89FAAE9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2023, more than 40,000 firefighters participated in courses with the Academy. After participating in these courses, 90 percent of supervisors shared that their firefighters were better prepared to respond to emergencies as a result of their training at the Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B17AF52F25840DCA635FE84032261F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At a time when wildfires have ravaged—and continue to threaten—communities across the nation, the collaboration and education managed by the Academy has never been more important to secure the future of fire services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H725EC1F131964C4FA978BAFA47770093"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Given the importance of the programs at the Academy, it is critical to clarify the authority of the Academy to cancel courses and programming, and to require proper notice be given to Congress before any large-scale closures happen.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC3D6BF313AB042808C761C3868DC2E9B" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization to cancel or delay certain courses and programs offered by the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control</header><subsection id="H72B3CFE1CAFB424FB3485DAF7EDFC659" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Powers of Administrator of the United States Fire Administration relating to large-Scale cancellation actions; congressional review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2206">15 U.S.C. 2206</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4D574535D33F4FFA9EEBA8625CBC85A0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (n) as subsection (r); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E2085F90564EADADCE8CAFF50ABA0A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (m) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8FA2A650B2494AA0A53E940DCAD76203" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEB46B056638D41EBB33B797DE6520F4C" commented="no"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Large-Scale cancellation action</header><paragraph id="H6F1F2C6AB5184ECE928B18FCC41FC3FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator is authorized to implement a large-scale cancellation action relating to a covered course or program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD23C538D4BEA48EEABAB479EFB76353D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header><text>Not later than 60 days before the date on which the Administrator implements a large-scale cancellation action pursuant to paragraph (1), or in the event of an exigent circumstance, as soon as practicable thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a notice that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFC47B4B509C549E4850155B9650FBD95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of the covered courses or programs to be cancelled.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBC7E497A0794E639109042973071A16" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of the fire departments and agencies with personnel registered for the covered courses or programs to be cancelled.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FF3728A0BB848A48A50481101930315" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of personnel registered for the covered courses or programs to be cancelled, disaggregated by the number of such personnel in each of such fire departments or agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A99AA61F76F48AA9C72F2D6AE1BF10A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A justification for each such cancellation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14FFDFA70F9F4FF3A2D2F31739FBFCF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to students</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator implements under paragraph (1) a large-scale cancellation action relating to a covered course or program, the Administrator, not later than 45 days before the intended start date of such course or program, or in the event of an exigent circumstance, as soon as practicable thereafter, shall inform each student enrolled in such covered course or program, and the fire chief or other appropriate head of each fire department of such students, of such cancellation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FDAEF577C7E4D6FB02FA20B8C0249E5" commented="no"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Other cancellation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Superintendent cancels a covered course or program, the Superintendent, not later than 30 days before the intended start date of such course or program, or in the event of an exigent circumstance, as soon as practicable thereafter, shall inform each student enrolled in such covered course or program, and the fire chief or other appropriate head of each fire department of such students, of such cancellation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H398C4928A0A94168989260717A904C06" commented="no"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Reimbursement of certain expenses</header><paragraph id="H8243F531D7EB4347A788A1DCBC277F29" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the Administrator of FEMA receives an itemization under paragraph (3) from a fire department relating to a covered course or program that is cancelled, the Administrator of FEMA, subject to paragraph (2), shall reimburse such fire department for any covered expense related to such course or program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEC0375D02F04E00B25C0ECA081767DC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good cause</header><text>A reimbursement under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a covered course or program that is cancelled if such covered course or program is cancelled for good cause.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15B20AFB43A34BA3AB97BF72E61A261E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Itemization of expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the intended start date of the course or program that was cancelled, the fire chief or other appropriate head of a fire department affected by such cancellation may submit to the Administrator of FEMA an application for reimbursement that includes an itemization of each covered expense such fire department incurred.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59BA04205BAC4F37BDD1BD686752B75D" commented="no"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0AA56D656691404AB3B4A21D3F4D2153" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Backfill expense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>backfill expense</quote> means an expense incurred for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8C30C3FEF8A7414A9AE1012303B99B70" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Staffing adjustments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41BC12BB0F874FFFBDB8F258A3E0CBEF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Overtime compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53261F739F8947A884055102A6FCB064" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered course or program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered course or program</quote> means a course or program that is offered by the Academy—</text><subparagraph id="H7F21D843DA9948D289D97575AE65D427" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in-person and on-campus;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E691F29740A4D409FA4372BBCCBF09F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in-person and off-campus; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06643B4726E54F769BCA11C27B93120E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through synchronous or asynchronous virtual instruction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC033721E5560469A96D537A2EDF5BD44" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered expense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered expense</quote> means any expense that a fire department incurred for the planned participation of the personnel of such fire department in a covered course or program, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3C0F4CEEEFAF43378C7F36E452F54DDD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any travel expense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA94A10925AA746B98F645E08101FA574" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any backfill expense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FD9099A68134691B96AF467970ECDB0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Good cause</header><text>The term <quote>good cause</quote> includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H496FB10D552F400898435C07DFD7B791" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The closure of a facility of the Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC384EF7CD44ACE97AD4D2B2C871CFA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The illness or unavailability of an instructor of the Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H926B680978494DBF83E0CA6193832CC9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A national emergency that impedes access to a facility of the Academy by a student or faculty member of the Academy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC649790667044145B4616DAC121A224A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Large-scale cancellation action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>large-scale cancellation action</quote> means an action taken by the Administrator whereby the Administrator cancels at one time at least 25 percent of the total number of covered courses or programs planned to be offered by the Academy in a fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H526A50F30A864AA5A1BAB1C26D0CBE41" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header><paragraph id="H76018F433902434992810C6C9D78F0DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than March 30, 2026, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a study that includes the matters specified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDA0CAC36524863AD6DFB619B2E24E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters specified</header><text>The matters specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFB777483FF404837B182C5606E070DE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any impact of any large-scale cancellation action by the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control during calendar year 2025 of covered courses or programs (as such terms are defined in subsection (r) of section 7 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2206">15 U.S.C. 2206</external-xref>) as added by subsection (b)) offered by the Academy on the preparedness of fire departments for a national emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F4F7E84FFB642D094223C9FD9DE92A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any negative consequences of such cancellations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66114470FBBD48C9B4B40D6423A48170"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control contributes to establishing a common approach, including interoperability of fire and emergency response, for firefighters and first responders to provide mutual aid and combat fires, natural disasters, medical emergencies, and other similar events, and the value of such common approach.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55236BEC100245A1A95FCF91DD714A6F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of students who have attended a course or program at the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control during the immediately preceding 3 calendar years, disaggregated by the following:</text><clause id="H420189907F5F4F1E993BCFE0F464C1C2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any such courses or programs that are offered in-person and at the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control campus.</text></clause><clause id="H1264A80FAF514A8F95FA1F22903A6187" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any such courses or programs that are offered in-person and not at the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control campus.</text></clause><clause id="HC5249C09346E4397AB6CA9CFA4E28091" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any such courses or program that are offered by synchronous virtual instruction.</text></clause><clause id="H582B417EE1C34D2DB6903674848F0D79" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any such courses or program that are offered by asynchronous virtual instruction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ED31148364C45E5B9BD55360E7BE9A5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An identification and description of the most in-demand courses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

