<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5921607E1344651A26212AFF7ED798D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5681 IH: Stopping Terrorists Online Presence and Holding Accountable Tech Entities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the reporting of certain terms of service of social media companies for purposes of limiting the online presence of terrorist organizations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8AFAD64298A141F6A278624A81F1EFEE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6BD47E5B7B474189A08EEA8207BDE6F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Terrorists Online Presence and Holding Accountable Tech Entities Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>STOP HATE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section>
<section id="H4138EC7BB7364492B55A94D834B6B8EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Stopping Terrorists Online Presence and Holding Accountable Tech Entities</header>
<subsection id="HA19EC7C752E5424FAFE19B706C7A3E27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Terms of service publication</header>
<paragraph id="H8DE77ACF50AA48738C653F5170FF654D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, each social media company described in subsection (f)(4) shall publish terms of service, or lack thereof, for each social media platform owned or operated by the company in a manner reasonably designed to inform all users of the social media platform of the existence and contents of the terms of service applicable to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H39B79A93281C4C929417548E6580A8B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A foreign terrorist organization designated under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H24229929FECF480CB17EEA9F93DE750C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals or entities designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorists under Executive Order 13224.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CED2F0EEE054ECABFF1109AB2AA89FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional publication of information</header><text>In addition to the terms of service published pursuant to paragraph (1), the social media company shall also publish the following information:</text>
<subparagraph id="H1E71924A5D014113895750E7838E13E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for the purpose of allowing users to ask the social media company questions about the terms of service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8BAF79B0AEE4CAB963D9C00A3754110"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of—</text>
<clause id="H245C9E99063F4A27B25F3AFDAB3D86D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the process that a user must follow—</text> <subclause id="HB132A9C8C7FF431CA1CABB6752DE3B9F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to flag an item of content that the user believes violates the terms of service; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H073A408726E14C57B4166E93F898B2FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to flag a group or another user that the user believes has violated the terms of service; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9A2BF95F8B7D4239964B79C9A6203D19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the social media company’s commitments on response and resolution time.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H789B52210D6B4FD3967E8284FF3BD205"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A list of ways in which an item of content or a user may be actioned by the social media company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2EA4E150987D4206A09F6BA15BC6B21B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms of service report to the Attorney General</header> <paragraph id="HEE733D4B18204DBA99499149BD06A003"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each social media company shall electronically submit, on a triannual basis, a terms of service report to the Attorney General pursuant to paragraph (2), regarding information and enforcement of the terms of service identified in subsection (a)(1), that will include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HC6C34F2208314DBAA84CC0802E948625"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The version of the terms of service for each social media platform owned or operated by the company in effect as of the date of the report.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CF1D8B63BD848D0A4E6E04471A22310"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Data related to violations of the terms of service of identified under subsection (a), including the following:</text>
<clause id="HE0ACD68E13C146C094BC5D7A40E23DF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of items of content flagged.</text></clause> <clause id="H10B4F3E760364E1FB78C1CB6FE572E39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total number of actioned items of content.</text></clause>
<clause id="H9125E7BD9B1E4B2296547744CD20C606"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The total number of actioned items of content that resulted in action taken by the social media company against the user or group of users responsible for the content.</text></clause> <clause id="HA69DDB9B843C4E659B94691A9B560571"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The total number of actioned items of content that were removed, demonetized, or deprioritized by the social media company.</text></clause>
<clause id="HD4B9E33693BB45608A27A7F604D6EBFA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The number of times actioned items of content were viewed by users.</text></clause> <clause id="H2547864404D04F41B3BAB203FBC6A0EC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The number of times actioned items of content were shared, and the number of users that viewed the content before it was actioned.</text></clause>
<clause id="HD7A27968631B4BE5B4A9784DB15C1E5F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of times users appealed social media company actions taken on that platform and the number of reversals of social media company actions on appeal disaggregated by each type of action.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CD77BAA390840DA9BABDE84A99C5D59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>All information required by subparagraph (B) shall be disaggregated into the following categories:</text>
<clause id="H3912A5566C324AD3A361CBB26FAB10A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The category of content, including any relevant categories described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause> <clause id="H92A0BCF42A1E4972B1E1A5C7D9387383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The type of content, including posts, comments, messages, profiles of users, or groups of users.</text></clause>
<clause id="H362E65BB268D4365AF8EE377F75FBBAF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The type of media of the content, including text, images, and videos.</text></clause> <clause id="HD124812D082942DEA75EF69FF990044A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>How the content was flagged, including whether the content was flagged by—</text>
<subclause id="HB5999D3929FF45C8805E39F3F88F3F2C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">company employees or contractors of the social media company;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA868B3B4349E47B98BEE27468E964A77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>artificial intelligence software;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H1408CC01E8054DFCB1365F4AB3298BA7"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community moderators of the social media platform;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF97BBB5DF3434E43961B9DF3F742424E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>civil society partners; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H0EE2E38B9B9B4911B9339C8035ADF7F8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>users of the social media platform.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H68AAA41D644F450D9599F4E98B6DCBC0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>How the content was actioned, including whether the content was actioned by—</text>
<subclause id="H608609AFBF5741C4B4750C795263A40E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>employees or contractors of the social media company;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8D8449E2E2324C86AE28232A9A1CAF5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>artificial intelligence software;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3C9FAB5B38C049FD8F579D607A71F8FC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>community moderators of the social media platform;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2892954B53594B3E853818EB9D674627"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>civil society partners; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H4A8EA169F4224E20A7FA7443BE745462"><enum>(V)</enum><text>actioned by users.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6C4381DDF1D4F91B26CB201B3F40A05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A complete and detailed evaluation of the changes over time, including identifiable trends and analysis, with respect to the information in subparagraphs (A) through (C) since the previous report, if applicable, and those thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4DF3E1A223D74373B334BA2E1302FBD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 360 days after the date of enactment of this section, each social media company shall submit the first report required pursuant to paragraph (1). After the submission of the first report, the following reports will occur no later than January 31, April 30, and October 31 the following years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F982D91165040BE8A5823C4615F6681"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Attorney General shall make all reports submitted under this section available to the public in a searchable repository on the website of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAC29D02049284C8DB9CD285422C9C0D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header>
<paragraph id="HEF3C944A15CA4085BEE8D2A524FB1C84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may bring an action for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000,000 per violation per day against any social media company that does not submit a report required under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12B602C66A1A4E86A811ECA8F9A1632E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Violations</header><text>A social media company shall be considered in violation of the provisions of this chapter for each day the social media company does any of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HB9EF419C36144B27BCBE6D74B4BC1F64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fails to post terms of service in accordance with subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2726B43589114950BB72C059477F92B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Fails to timely submit to the Attorney General a report required pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE4FB3FF04A99407D8A87E6B8614164D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Materially omits or misrepresents required information in a report submitted pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H20C36838AC0F4F9188B8BFB3A56443FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H42FD38A38A8B4BBCB873113B37A2F6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National intelligence estimate</header><text>Not later than 360 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit a National Intelligence Estimate on the use of platforms by the individuals and entities identified under subsection (a)(1) to Congress. The Director shall ensure an unclassified version of the assessment is published on the Department’s website no later than 30 days following the submission to Congress.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBE40F45515FC4A8EAB329B5A30FC6551"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller general reports</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of enactment of this section, and then again 540 days after, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress reports on the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE4F85208F4C0467298D44FFC41DD3A88"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority to carry out this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H776262F2CCD04E53BFDD82C956A52C41"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7EB06CC88DBB41FC8349FDD4194A0DA3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Actioned</header> <text>The term <quote>actioned</quote> means that, pursuant to a violation of the terms of service of a social media platform—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H5FF3989E0D8D4310832DEAE5C139D84E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in the case of an item of content, that item of content was removed, demonetized, or deprioritized from the social media platform; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3D2FFD10700F4F07B48B9B753B8E4670">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a user, that user was banned from the social media platform, or the account of that user was demonetized.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD570E2A5F8C74A9682ED7463C1AE418B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>content</term> means, on an internet-based service or application—</text> <subparagraph id="HCAC83D17494845D1BC105B8E858DD0CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement or comment made by a user; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H96B8547478004BC9857111B1018C6CBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>media that are created, posted, shared, or otherwise interacted with by a user.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The term does not include media on a service or application exclusively for the purpose of cloud storage, transmitting files, or file collaboration.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85D4BF5DFEA84E18961AF2C685949B47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Social media platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social media platform</term> means any entity subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H52D6DF437F47494BB203C8D0D62EF716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a website, desktop application, or mobile application that—</text> <clause id="HAC3F9299A5464F588BA8311008E97CC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>permits a person to become a registered user, establish an account, or create a profile for the purpose of allowing the user to create, share, and view user-generated content through such an account or profile;</text></clause>
<clause id="H218568B9C698443680EB2A531C4DCBAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enables one or more users to generate content that can be viewed by other users of the platform; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1A981C8A22BE4255BA089075090FED51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>primarily serves as a medium for users to interact with content generated by other users of the platform and for the platform to deliver ads to users; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9B54305E23B46CE9BBCFFA7CBBFC2FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has at least 25,000,000 unique monthly users in the United States for a majority of the months in the most recent 12-month period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40CDCFD67EAE4E73919531752B70F11C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social media company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social media company</term> means a person or entity that owns or operates one or more social media platforms.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07FA2F291AB743D88007C028EF07E3FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Terms of service</header><text>The term <term>terms of service</term> means a policy or set of policies adopted by a social media company that specifies, at least, the user behavior and activities that are permitted on the internet-based service owned or operated by the social media company, and the user behavior and activities that may subject the user or an item of content to being actioned.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDDA7466D14DB43F5ABC4C706250468F8" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header> <paragraph id="H3173FB36E69D4AE98A5B45A0F00C0F8E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to diminish or infringe upon any right protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0675AEE9AB5C47ABBE180469014FCDD1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality and Privacy</header><text>The publication of the reports authorized in subsection (d) shall comply with any Federal, State, and local laws affecting confidentiality and privacy, including the Privacy Act of 1974.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

