<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F3FC1C2651F4B55B60A58C0B73D0BD5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 752 IH: Expressing support for the designation of September 19, 2025, as “Black Autism Acceptance and Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 752</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of September 19, 2025, as <quote>Black Autism Acceptance and Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas autism is a form of neurodivergence characterized by differences in social communication skills and by repetitive and highly focused behaviors and ways of thinking;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, despite recent efforts to serve Black autistic individuals, there appear to be significant racial inequities in the diagnosis and treatment of Black autistic children;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Black parents of autistic children reported significantly less autism concerns and behavioral concerns, with children more likely to be seen as <quote>disruptive</quote> instead of neurodivergent;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Black autistic individuals are more likely to be misdiagnosed, underdiagnosed, and diagnosed late;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Black autistic individuals are underrepresented in autism research;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Black autistic individuals have been found to have more difficulty in accessing specialty care;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Black community reports more accounts of marginalization and dismissal of concerns in health care settings, including in the autism space;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Black autistic youth face increased risk of negative outcomes during interactions with law enforcement; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Black autistic youth face disproportionate discipline at school, resulting in a higher prevalence of suspensions, expulsions, and other classroom punishments: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2D9D8BF58C5C460BBB669D30950956BE"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H45A6553DB0F048159EBC64DBC1ED4CC4"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9519B81D5B5F4980B1B60D252C66149B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>Black Autism Acceptance and Awareness Day</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF7C3897F56245D48095EAAE59D81F3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages all Americans to celebrate Black Autism Acceptance and Awareness Day by—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E634D5330D94F59AC359FEF842CABE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raising awareness about the inequalities facing Black autistic individuals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H129A5E141D9E43BEBF01517E0124BD48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting understanding, acceptance, and inclusion of Black autistic individuals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50B3914CA92C4650973B2F93E25D2627"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinforcing the importance of amplifying the voices of Black autistic individuals; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF1245435225464FA5453D5DBFAEEAE6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advocating for justice and equity for Black autistic individuals;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB1C1833BEE2403BB298656ED710A90C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that acceptance for Black autistic individuals is essential;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35E87FBA940941FD8C034F60D2AA9D9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that true acceptance for Black autistic individuals means culturally competent care, challenging existing biases, building community, and providing equitable access to resources and opportunities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70A8519FDC7A4419803F05F686392BA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that autism does not end after childhood, and resources and acceptance are needed for Black autistic individuals into adulthood; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H843B477837594EBAAEF16A17FB4CB241"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that neurological differences, like autism, are natural variations in the human experience, and those variations should be celebrated.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

