<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25784-PSC-FG-WD8">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2151 IS: NATO Burden Sharing Report Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2151</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr.
                    Paul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                    Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to submit annual reports on allied
            contributions to the common defense, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="id7da664a7f97748989f72dd9063ed015c">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NATO Burden Sharing Report Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id35928345417E4A69A0E5082E5F261ACC">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Report on allied contributions to the common defense</header>
            <subsection id="id0154B804BBA54A85B63AB69E0205713E">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Finding</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that section 1003 of the Department of Defense Authorization Act, 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/525">Public Law 98–525</external-xref>; 63 Stat. 2241)—</text>
                <paragraph id="idD80E6A345C24454F87D33980EF85653C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>expresses the sense of Congress that, due to threats that are ever-changing, Congress must be informed with respect to allied contributions to the common defense to properly assess the readiness of the United States and the countries described in subsection (c)(2) for threats; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id76B7D56622D74D718AC32B52174E9FD3">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>requires the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress an annual report on the contributions of allies to the common defense.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id613167CAB02740ACACE62D521BAE9A1A">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="id210166647F3A4EA4BFF3477181C8743A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the threats facing the United States—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id5130a6b37dd04ef0b3062d48b108b8b8">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>include near-peer threats; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc07889888d2443848e0318d07f988d89"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>require the United States to prioritize military assets and resources in accordance with the most recent National Defense Strategy;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idd3c9adf7a1d646129860e6b162335746">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the United States should not continue to shoulder a disproportionate share of the burden for European security while current and prospective members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization neglect to meet defense spending guidelines; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id33a83b582e09442d915cd7d878c978e0">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the President should seek from each member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization acceptance of international security responsibilities and agreements to make contributions to the common defense in accordance with the collective defense treaty to which such country is a party.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idfc5dfc5c835d4920b361277b3df11e68">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Reports on allied contributions to the common defense</header>
                <paragraph id="id0b9a971a6f9c42c380f66ec08eca04d1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than March 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the heads of other Federal agencies, as the Secretary determines to be necessary, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing a description of—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idb8b7e26fefa44228a78e2e7f24402021">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the annual defense spending by each country described in paragraph (2), including available data on nominal budget figures and defense spending as a percentage of the gross domestic products of each such country for the fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year in which the report is submitted;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id64244f10e43f4037bd27de0187ed680c">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the activities of each such country to contribute to military or stability operations in which the Armed Forces of the United States are a participant or may be called upon in accordance with a cooperative defense agreement to which the United States is a party;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idd768216880764bc2974efebbe489ee19">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>any limitations placed by any such country on the use of such contributions;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idfd033ffc26e249e4b1bfe7b76bfe040f">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>any actions undertaken by the United States or by other countries to minimize such limitations; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id822a21479eec40c3bb28d72f4c22e7d1">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>with respect to each such country—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1c7aaa2ebe54ca1b0e9b61767828c86"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contributions made by the country to Ukraine, including an indication of whether such contributions relate to hard or soft power;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id967ae79469d14ffd805a5999748f6b73">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the health of the defense industrial base of the country;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id5cc5169ccd9741c993fab053236660a2">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the comparative advantages of the defense industrial base of the country;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id5cb1b36450d944dcb68fce4eaf8a764c">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>the size and structure of the military forces of the country, including an estimate of the amount of time required for such forces to achieve full military mobilization;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id99628a0dc61049a8b1f14d030a35a68f">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>any area in which the country would be fully dependent on allied military assets;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id106e6f35e3ea48d38aae20fc01587e6b">
                            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>any delivery received or contract entered into by the country through the Foreign Military Sales or the Foreign Military Financing program during the preceding year;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idd2faf4a83369418bb403afb5ae185e36">
                            <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>any change in defense spending during the preceding year; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id7644d356b97b471dbea9cad8b3341b0b">
                            <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text>the amount defense spending anticipated in the subsequent year.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idee17f3ab2c94464bb71ed92a1a3435b9">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Countries described</header>
 <text>The countries described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id24c0aa0b15714ceba2fcb4b1d95bb434"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>Each member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id10351610297a42419bf41d119ea2bab7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Each country participating in a North Atlantic Treaty Organization Membership Action Plan.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ide5eb22ca63194d36a827b40fab6f877f">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Form</header>
 <text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4ED27521D8BB4965BD476B07ADBFEDBF">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Availability</header>
 <text>A report submitted under paragraph (1) shall be made available on request to any Member of Congress.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id05e2a4d051a84efab2ae4e1bbd222e0e">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
                <paragraph id="idcd53c0c8715b4dabb005137b1294636b">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79c5749e956c4e0896d954f382d0b1c2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

