<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBE265DED9EA4832B2960FC448E15662" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2484 IH: Seniors’ Access to Critical Medications Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2484</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish an exception to the physician self-referral prohibition for certain outpatient prescription drugs furnished by a physician practice under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEEE9871B41DD47BC8F26D19D12775885" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4AF5BEDEAE91436E8594FD5DEB9A55DC" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Seniors’ Access to Critical Medications Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5FEE2A882B6D425EB3A9971D9F3D1939"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing an exception to the physician self-referral prohibition for certain outpatient prescription drugs furnished by a physician practice under the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="H5455D371F1354B978F12164DC297DFDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1877(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE0C4F86960548B1BC172E037B763C6D"> 
<paragraph id="H58D003FE1C7C41A49C4CC153691DBBD3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Certain outpatient prescription drugs</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF13E7C0582F449199B74055762A9A03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of designated health services described in subsection (h)(6)(J) that are covered part D drugs (as defined in section 1860D–2(e)) and furnished to an individual during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on December 31, 2030, if—</text> <clause id="H5C516D28EE144607A6A5D64037513A71"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such drugs are prescribed by the referring physician (or by another physician or practitioner (as described in section 1842(b)(18)(C)) within the same group practice as such physician);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD603A7E60C8455B809345C0C0F870DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such individual has an ongoing relationship (as defined by the Secretary) with such physician or practitioner who prescribed such drugs (or with another physician or practitioner within the same group practice as such physician or practitioner);</text></clause> <clause id="H6877E5DBEA614D1C9B177429F9415610"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>within the 1-year period prior to the dispensing of such drugs, such individual had at least 1 face-to-face, in-person encounter with such referring physician (or with another physician or practitioner within the same group practice as such physician, as determined by tax identification number) during which items or services that are not designated health services and for which payment was made under this title were furnished to such individual;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE4B1B89C13274F37AC9BF1CDD3BBD3B3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such drugs are dispensed by the referring physician, a physician who is a member of the same group practice as the referring physician, or an individual who is directly supervised by such a physician, from a building described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii), including through—</text> <subclause id="HEF11572A1F6441B0A17AC84CF65C0EEB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in-person pickup by the individual or a caregiver or family member of such individual; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE5F22FF3E83A44D4B6D159FF580D5E00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a mail, delivery, or courier service; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HAB359A5974AA41E082408B5D0188C2EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such drugs are billed for by the physician dispensing or supervising the dispensing of such drugs, by a group practice of which such physician is a member under a billing number assigned to such group practice, or by an entity that is wholly owned by such physician or such group practice.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H301227B9D73A4F8AB1F696C70709247D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed as modifying any program requirements under part D.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H61D7DA2AC2F845AB92C297D1101B0A10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header> <paragraph id="H54A8B6457EE64EFEAA975440A02CEE93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study examining—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H271C149D65E041EABE70D017845EB1FA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pharmacies or pharmacy networks participating under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101 et seq.</external-xref>) that, after the date of the enactment of this section, dispense significantly more (as determined by the Comptroller General) covered part D drugs (as defined in section 1860D–2 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395e-102">42 U.S.C. 1395e–102</external-xref>)) compared to the amount of such drugs dispensed prior to such date;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A063FB6E8124D43B730DE7D8F412F35"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">common characteristics of the pharmacies and pharmacy networks identified under subparagraph (A), including, to the extent identifiable, the extent to which such pharmacies and pharmacy networks are owned by a physician or group practice (as defined in section 1877(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(h)</external-xref>) or otherwise integrated into a physician’s practice or group practice; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91B62893BC4F45AE92B347B41DE88AFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>common characteristics of arrangements entered into by physicians or group practices for purposes of dispensing drugs within physicians’ offices or otherwise integrating pharmacies or the dispensing of drugs into a physician’s practice or group practice, including, to the extent feasible and identifiable, an analysis of—</text> <clause id="HDFA15B9B23CE4515A9E00D4590DAB138"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specific physician specialties or subspecialties for which such arrangements are especially common or have shown substantial growth;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H63A9FD595D1846DD96EA37965FFEF826"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which physicians and group practices participating in such arrangements have such arrangements or integration with other physicians or group practices or other drug supply chain participants (including pharmacy benefit managers, insurers, wholesalers, distributors, or management services organizations);</text></clause> <clause id="HC15DFC96D8A74065BE2384CC55F2461D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>common contracting features of such arrangements relating to the utilization of covered part D drugs or services provided in connection with such drugs, including contract terms related to administrative or dispensing fees for such drugs and the types of payments provided in connection with such services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B353B1EAEC542E3BF8B056FD3C57AEA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">common measures, including notices or disclosures, taken by physicians and group practices participating in such arrangements in order to mitigate or otherwise address potential conflicts of interest posed by such arrangements; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFC0EC3F04D1E4A2F8F362A49D10BA4D7"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any components or features of such arrangements that may influence prescribing decisions or patterns among physicians and group practices participating in such arrangements. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CB138C41DAA44519E3C0823A91F5DE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of the study required under paragraph (1), which shall not include identifying or proprietary information with respect to the pharmacies or pharmacy networks examined.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H44FF524650114DEEB5BB1E100F6985F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Medicare improvement fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1898(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395iii">42 U.S.C. 1395iii(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>1,804,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>1,786,000,000</quote>. </text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

