<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73812AFB81F6467AA9B63B44C1F66CA1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1938 IH: Department of Defense PFAS Discharge Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1938</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to request modifications relating to certain permits issued under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81CE915A7AA248F0BBE04A055B826E51" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H75D6DED478004275BC9F41A9D678CE58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Defense PFAS Discharge Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9252CDFCC69640EF954286EF095E1E6F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Stormwater discharge permits for Department of Defense facilities</header> <subsection id="H051DA84E52084012A441D20CEF41402F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall, with respect to each permit under section 402(p) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(p)</external-xref>) that applies to a Department of Defense facility, request from the State that issued the permit, or the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, as applicable, approval of a modification to such permit, or a revision to an applicable stormwater management plan, to require—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1A97D441C4B04223A15F08FE6DA509C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitoring of discharges of perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances not less frequently than quarterly; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB356877018E244199FD5FE5EBB2F1736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation of appropriate best management practices or control technologies to reduce such discharges consistent with the requirements of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H10B1C17D2D2F42258B926315F200D9FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act, or otherwise made available to the Secretary in each fiscal year, for perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances remediation efforts, not less than 1 percent shall be obligated or expended annually for testing for such substances in stormwater runoff at Department of Defense facilities.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

