<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB16CA6F05064B7E8CCAE8084ABD994C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5564 IH: To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to provide for improved coordination between the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5564</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to provide for improved coordination between the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA38D9B7A74F14EEFB3517CFBD9BFA85F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD8B33BB1E92245F19DF99399B7D30681" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136a">7 U.S.C. 136a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6ECB5258B30D45719747ED28F0229251" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HD0B5A66E845C4BCABF03E0767B4F8CBA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination</header> <paragraph id="HEB666C5E24E54F7AAB978BFAD59AEF74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Risk mitigation measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any risk mitigation measures are required for any pesticide registered under this Act, the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9967625B44024AF886C7B081271FB6B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop such measures in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FCAEB4AFDFF405898DD2D00D70043F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct, and publish in the docket, with the corresponding action, an economic analysis—</text> 
<clause id="HE5CBCB031B6D478EAEAE71A57B810FE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determining the cost (including with respect to changes to use requirements and cost of making any associated labeling changes) to growers, State lead agencies, and other affected entities of the implementation of such measures; and</text></clause> <clause id="H17605535F96D4C18A5A83BCC3AB0C80B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the costs and benefits of the use of a pesticide that includes an assessment of how a reduction in risk to the pesticide user may be achieved by the use of risk mitigation measures.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FBF41B958AF4BACBB9F63FD4BF9EDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data and information</header> 
<subparagraph id="H287ED5F3E5CF44B6A3434661385B48DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination of data and information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With regard to the registration or registration review of a pesticide under this Act and for making a determination under section 408 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/346a">21 U.S.C. 346a</external-xref>) with respect to any action that impacts the sale, distribution, or use of a pesticide, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Director of the Office of Pest Management Policy, so that the Administrator has for the Administrator’s use and consideration for such processes—</text> <clause id="H233EB7A8B65F4981B59607F04D0D3AA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agronomic use data from—</text> 
<subclause id="HF6F9364C7CE243E7B51A69DEA9D4120F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF918A0BAA0FC4DB59C587E8FDC3D929B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>industry; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H8864EB9B2EFA44A5A5275D90F0026D05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any information relating to the availability and economic viability of alternatives to such pesticide.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DA0C82CA26B4F18B70A28F2B3A5604E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data and information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When issuing any decision resulting from the processes referred to in subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall publish in the docket—</text> 
<clause id="H73B6BDFB47EC46129F38504CB45D24E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the use by the Administrator of any data or information provided by the Secretary of Agriculture under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> <clause id="H04A402AC6F9A40BE90BA6177B544514B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the determination of the Administrator on whether to use such data or information, including, as applicable, the reasons that the data or information was not used.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CC6F87AB31F480B8E8D58D7A1C67CDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reasonable and prudent actions and measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the implementation of reasonable and prudent actions and measures identified by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to section 7 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>) with respect to the use of a pesticide registered under this Act, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Commerce—</text> <subparagraph id="H078A123A63BB499AA4E35A37FFB0F500"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to review the development of any such actions and measures that are a result of consultations relating to actions under this Act;</text>
                        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D6C5460686B4DAE8C1CE124E8DD3807"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fully consider the options for reasonable and prudent actions and measures in a manner consistent with practices established to evaluate the risks and benefits of a pesticide registered under this Act (including the reduction in risk to the pesticide user achieved by the use of risk mitigation measures) and to use that information to inform the final selection of reasonable and prudent actions and measures to be used to evaluate such risks and benefits and the implementation of such selection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36028B115F0B48C59B9BC41D4BEC499F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide feedback to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce on decisions relating to any such actions and measures that may affect end users of a pesticide registered under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33E37EF6E212473B95A649E92B8EC0BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The coordination requirements imposed by this subsection may be waived or modified for a specific action to the extent agreed upon by the Administrator, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the registrant so long as such agreement is published by the Administrator in the docket for the corresponding action.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

