<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CD43E37EEEA43C78B1F72CF6E49C7A6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 456 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the month of May 2025 as “Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 456</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the month of May 2025 as <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy, often referred to as <quote>PSP</quote>, is an adult onset neurodegenerative disorder that affects multiple areas of the brain and causes complex symptoms and care needs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, although some symptoms may appear similar to that of Parkinson’s disease, progressive supranuclear palsy is a distinct disease that is part of a family of conditions clinically defined as atypical Parkinsonism;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, while estimates vary and the disorder is often misdiagnosed, approximately 30,000 Americans are living with progressive supranuclear palsy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the symptoms of progressive supranuclear palsy can include cognitive impairment, gait and balance difficulties, speech and swallowing difficulties, stiffness, changes in personality, changes in vision, depression, and a variety of other symptoms that can have a severe impact on an individual’s quality of life and life expectancy;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy is aggressive in its progression, with most patients becoming dependent on care in 3 to 4 years;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is currently no disease-modifying treatments and no known cure for progressive supranuclear palsy;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy is believed to be caused by a combination of environmental factors and genetics, but the exact cause is still unknown;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are thousands of family caregivers, friends, and loved ones whose lives are greatly affected by progressive supranuclear palsy;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas additional research, support services, and education are needed to maintain quality of life for those affected by the disease, reduce delays to diagnosis and access to proper care, lead to better treatments, and find a cure for progressive supranuclear palsy; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the establishment of the month of May 2025 as <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Awareness Month</quote> will benefit patients, families, health care professionals, and communities across the country and further bolster awareness of the disorder: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCE724A3E8C174BC7A885F5604D95E9DF"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HABB886C6605E43B08DCDDB6FA3813B6E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H714174AEC7AB47DDB43FC714FA6C29FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42A5BB10C65349DAA50022ED4F269C00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36D6FB887EFA4DD2969D3B7EAFA4D978"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports research to find better treatments and a cure for progressive supranuclear palsy; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H512D56CB99744810B5937896B78F18F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the researchers, volunteers, organizations, families, and individuals across the country who are working to improve the lives of people living with progressive supranuclear palsy.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

