<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H601F7E33CD044C0CAE72486A180B2F12" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 255 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of State to transmit to the House of Representatives any record created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, relating to strikes on the Houthis in Yemen and the disclosure of confidential information to a journalist on the Signal application.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 255</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of State to transmit to the House of Representatives any record created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, relating to strikes on the Houthis in Yemen and the disclosure of confidential information to a journalist on the Signal application.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDC90CC7761B341F9A39BB08FDACD9066"> 
<section id="H92DF4B9BC1A34C2DA8A889648FBA3251" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested, and the Secretary of State is directed, to transmit, respectively, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, copies of all documents, Signal application chats, charts, or tables, including notes from meetings, audio recordings, records (including telephone and email records), correspondence, artificial intelligence large language model conversation transcripts, and any other communications created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, that refer or relate to any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H113EDA17C350445A88470C06B29949F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The full transcript of the Signal application group chat that included journalist Jeffrey Goldberg and pertained to extremely sensitive and confidential plans to strike the Houthis in Yemen, including all messages sent to such group chat before and after Mr. Goldberg entered and left such group chat.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E4E0DEF83AF4F679A19D85E8552197E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information pertaining to the strikes on the Houthis in Yemen.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE629595DAACB427286EB16C09E03153B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Coordination with partners, allies, and other countries concerning such strikes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC34D2FCC05BD41FC85D38D9B8EDED6F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Legal justifications for such strikes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B0C56483B3D4E1BA775865B6E0065DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any material produced as a result of Mr. Goldberg leaving such group chat and publishing an article describing his inclusion in confidential war planning, including any documentation related to potential consequences for officials who used a commercial application to coordinate war plans, discuss whether to strike the Houthis, and include a journalist in such group chat.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08C1E4D10FE54617B6186599D4D2F43D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>New executive branch process reforms, safeguards, or protections implemented in response to senior national security officials inviting a journalist to a group chat where highly classified information was discussed, considered, and planned.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FBA7E2CF5244A2B9CB41A0B20620B40"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any group chat or transcript that was used to develop war plans or discuss sensitive national security information.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

