<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E179F7DC218499795EBDB7CE7552228" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2364 IH: Helene Small Business Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2364</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a waiver of duplication of benefits for certain assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act as a result of a major disaster or emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C7C1F038A5F4431B461992F37E434C9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5816A7A4D8854B74BAA58A8ABB18A2B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helene Small Business Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF29D9671966243C1B8DD3289AC982F23"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver of duplication of benefits</header> <subsection id="H8E9DEE5ECA674389932DAF9390FED4F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of general prohibition</header> <paragraph id="H358808CD0778440CBE5DBCAC0A9E6438"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the general prohibition provided in section 312(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155(a)</external-xref>) upon request of a Governor on behalf of the State or on behalf of a person, business concern, or any other entity suffering losses as a result of a major disaster or emergency, if the President finds such waiver is in the public interest and will not result in waste, fraud, or abuse. In making this decision, the President may consider the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB8839D3F83B45398D0D5BA85EA0F385"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The recommendations of the Administration of the Federal Emergency Management Agency made in consultation with the Federal agency or agencies administering the duplicative program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97C32267B72F48469F6A677C4F9CECA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a wavier is granted, the assistance to be funded is cost effective.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4226A39958184796A086216E43A06AFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Equity and good conscience.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB388A00EB96B473F8DF583FB1BFE8DBE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Other matters of public policy considered appropriate by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F6186F61A4743F7BCA22CF37D71A1C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant or denial of waiver</header><text>A request under paragraph (1) shall be granted or denied not later than 45 days after submission of such request.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FED391C0D664931B801E2E567E85D63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on determination that loan is a duplication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 312(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155(c)</external-xref>), in carrying out paragraph (1), the President may not determine that a loan is a duplication of assistance, provided that all Federal assistance is used toward a loss suffered as a result of the major disaster or emergency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H454C352FF6A94761B70A998DA3FC4A71"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on income threshold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, no income threshold may be applied to limit the eligibility of a recipient from qualifying for a waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H23BAD7AF5893467381D11FEDD8A6D937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall apply to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act that occurred in calendar year 2023 or 2024.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

