<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25634-P21-J8-C2L">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2174 IS: Not A Trusted Organization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2174</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250625" legis-day="20250624">June 25 (legislative day, June 24),
                2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the President to give notice of denunciation of the North
            Atlantic Treaty for purposes of withdrawing the United States from the North Atlantic
            Treaty Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Not A Trusted Organization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NATO Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id0145e748820c4d00a5ca6d5506cc5355">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id1c327d7509a247728184512bbcae70d6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The North Atlantic Treaty (also known as the <quote>Washington Treaty</quote>) was signed on April 4, 1949, in Washington, DC, and created the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idb27706697eca47b6a5ca11d50d8cc818">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>NATO was intended to counterbalance the political and military power of the Soviet Union in Eastern Europe and was originally composed of 12 member states representing Western Europe and its transatlantic partners.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id9f719c359cc7465bbe11c97a2abdf68a">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The preamble to the Washington Treaty affirms that the Parties will <quote>unite their efforts for collective defense</quote>. Similarly, Article 3 of the Washington Treaty provides that each Party will <quote>maintain and develop their individual and collective capacity to resist armed attack</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idda39313173d549638911b3cfacd095ed">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The Warsaw Pact served as the collective defense bloc of the Soviet Union and collapsed in 1991, followed by the collapse of the Soviet Union itself by the end of that year.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5d413d9d7e364eef8299e48a512a07ae">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Shortly before the collapse of the Soviet Union, United States Secretary of State James Baker made assurances to Soviet Union leader Mikhail Gorbachev that NATO would not expand eastward.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id73c8c591804b44e7b14bd41a83fe9c36">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>The dissolution of both the Warsaw Pact and the Soviet Union fundamentally altered the security environment in Europe and rendered NATO’s founding collective defense mission irrelevant.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id606123a069e64b8a83f90a4a077721c8">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Despite its waning relevance and prior assurances to the contrary, NATO began a profound eastward expansion in 1999, which, as of 2025, culminated in a land border with the Russian Federation that exceeds 1,500 miles and encircles the Baltic Sea.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id75ab1868c55646b7aa0dd7436ef770b6">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>Successive National Military Doctrines and National Security Strategies of the Russian Federation have framed the expansion of NATO as a pervasive threat to Russian security.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idcce8d793f2b64dd4aa3934991bb9cb50">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>In a speech before the Munich Security Conference in 2007, President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin described NATO expansion as a <quote>serious provocation</quote> and referenced the assurances previously made by the United States.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ida3f83f4f4e2f4030ad5d8c1fe7f41789">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>The invasion of Ukraine by the Russian Federation in 2022 demonstrates the Russian Federation's willingness to employ military action in response to perceived security threats.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id30c9d23704c649378aeb46d391067139">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>NATO members have refused to rule out further expansion.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id06d7b3d4a54146ea9f95377fd731a213"> <enum>(12)</enum> <text>Since the founding of NATO, the United States has shouldered the burden of what was characterized as a <quote>collective</quote> security alliance, as the largest financial and hard power contributor.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="iddd07f024d2cc4c289351c7fe2aec1766">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text>At the Wales Summit in 2014, NATO members pledged to spend 2 percent of their gross domestic product on defense, known as the <quote>Wales Pledge</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1c5006b1bf93431caa7e7328483d344d">
                <enum>(14)</enum>
 <text>More than a decade later, nearly <fraction>1/3</fraction> of NATO members fail to meet the Wales Pledge.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4f6ebab01966427e9cbbf4a338afba14">
                <enum>(15)</enum>
 <text>Consistent with United States national security interests, Europe is not a priority theater for United States engagement. The principal interest of the United States in Europe is preventing the emergence of a regional hegemon.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idd962fb7484214a2795219477d9ce8ec6">
                <enum>(16)</enum>
 <text>The combined military and economic capacity of European NATO members exceeds that of the Russian Federation, serving as a sufficient counterweight to a prospective regional hegemon without United States engagement.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id28b52d564eaf439fa141f6ea6860a3a7">
                <enum>(17)</enum>
 <text>While the United States continues to subsidize European security, European NATO members are disincentivized from forward movement on burden shifting in the European theater.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id96a8dd596c984082be6a8bd35a096b57">
                <enum>(18)</enum>
 <text>Membership of the United States in NATO is inconsistent with the national security interests of the United States.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id8210dee1738943c6872ab2f9ec971dda">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Denunciation of North Atlantic Treaty</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Consistent with Article 13 of the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington April 4, 1949, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall give notice of denunciation of the North Atlantic Treaty for purposes of withdrawing the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id6100747f93b1459da91eea846bd1b546">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Fulfillment of requirement of section 1250A of the National Defense
                Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act satisfies the requirement of section 1250A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1928f">22 U.S.C. 1928f</external-xref>) for congressional authorization of suspension, termination, denunciation, or withdrawal from the North Atlantic Treaty.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id592bc38a9c4146f099817e7c5f113c9d">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on the use of funds</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds authorized to be appropriated, appropriated, or otherwise made available by any Act may be used to fund, directly or indirectly, United States contributions to the common-funded budgets of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, including the civil budget, the military budget, or the Security Investment Program.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idff528aeb3f7a4a1d9278fefdf1bda9c0">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Severability</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

