<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96048BE1EFBE45ED9AD7BC1DCBC30A26" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 259 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President to provide certain documents in the President’s possession to the House of Representatives relating to the access provided to the staff and advisers of, including any individual working for or in conjunction with, the Department of Government Efficiency to the systems, applications, and accounts, and any information contained therein, of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President to provide certain documents in the President’s possession to the House of Representatives relating to the access provided to the staff and advisers of, including any individual working for or in conjunction with, the Department of Government Efficiency to the systems, applications, and accounts, and any information contained therein, of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H27721E01C4DF418BB506B90FFB65163A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA9BD10B359F047B2973647E4C4209170"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested to furnish to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, memo, correspondence, or other communication in the possession of the President relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H58AFEB44A8644D898CCA9BE28903BC1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Excluding any individual employed by the U.S. Government prior to January 20, 2025, the name, age, and all professional and background experience of every individual that is working for, or in conjunction with, the Department on Government Efficiency (<quote>DOGE</quote>), including Elon Musk, Jeremy Lewin, Jordan Wick, Gavin Kliger, Nikhil Rajpal, Luke Farritor, Chris Young, and Edward Coristine, that have been provided access to any system, application, or account of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, including public facing and internal websites and social media accounts, physical access control systems, and permissioning systems, or any information contained therein.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F348B4C9E6F4EBEADCB72287005BE45"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each individual described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HD99BA850528046C5B2359A4863FCE72F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which of the systems, applications, accounts, physical access control systems, permissioning systems, or information therein described in paragraph (1) contained any confidential supervisory information, personally identifiable information, or sensitive compartmented information and, if so, what information was contained; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H645C840EFF364C18A86705E75D13253F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the level of clearance, access, authorization, or any type of permission required to gain access to each of the systems, applications, accounts, physical access control systems, permissioning systems, or information contained therein;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67A8AF46B2184B7B99EEE0F6A13752AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the level of clearance, access, authorization, or any type of permission held by the individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6BBCFDFD3BA432B8E470E4F2270BD82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether any of the access that the individual obtained or plans to obtain required or will require a level of clearance, access, authorization, or any type of permission that the individual did not have or will not have at the time that individual gained or will gain access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74B05A9A1AFB443E9487CA17ADD4406E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information contained in systems, applications, accounts, physical access control systems, permissioning systems, or information therein described in paragraph (1) (including confidential supervisory information, personally identifiable information, or sensitive compartmented information) to which an individual described in paragraph (1) has been provided access that is not available to the public under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, that has—</text><subparagraph id="H0019CA8D0FC84EFEA77A0E2679DDCB62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">been put into external systems, tools, or locations, or otherwise shared with any other person by any individual described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DA52C6F398B4F7DAFC8A31E78F2B408"><enum>(B)</enum><text>been copied or placed in the possession of any individual described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ABCD9C4A3E24181A54DEB831E169A7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">been modified by any individual described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D82D89E39D41E8B3DAE50AF4F0F870"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the accesses described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D8EA2DE46114D81BB1362AB4268F015"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all required steps to provide individuals described in paragraph (1) with this type of access (statutorily mandated or otherwise); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC15454E11B184FC39DF08C1B548F03EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all steps actually taken to provide individuals described in paragraph (1) with such accesses, the timeline of when such steps were completed, the identity of each individual who reviewed and approved the completion of the required steps by each individual, and the level of clearance, access, authorization or any type of permission that was granted for each individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9A518E8657E4EC6BA020098BF1B5689"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each individuals described in paragraph (1) provided with an access described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HFE94382306084948AE5554179E366CAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the signed Rules of Behavior for Privileged Users Form;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EBC6ADD8F604E0B927D07698E85AB56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Privileged User Access Request Form, along with the required business justification, supervisor approval, system owner approval, and Information System Security Manager approval; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19038ABF969E4E0E8EF61F103E153794"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of trainings completed, including all Privileged User Trainings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7724126F1FF49F899821D71B10F24FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of identified and potential conflicts of interest implicated by individuals described in paragraph (1), steps taken to mitigate such conflicts of interest, and the name of the individual who reviewed and approved the status of each individual with respect to such conflicts of interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26B64D44B0FC43B4B81122D677895599"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of full-time equivalent employees of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection as of December 31, 2024, with a breakdown of the number of such full-time equivalent employees by division and office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H854F9359EDD04406BBC22CCF7E61659C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of full-time equivalent employees of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection as of March 24, 2025, with a breakdown of the number of such full-time equivalent employees by division and office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H390BE656A22A42DBA0E62A2BACB5BCEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of full-time equivalent employees of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection that were not actively working as of March 24, 2025, due to a stop-work order or being placed on administrative leave, with a breakdown of the number of such full-time equivalent employees by division and office.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

