<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25569-P25-GJ-VVJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2883 IS: QUAHOGS Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2883</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an East Coast Bivalve Research Task Force.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quantifying Uncertainty and Action to Help Optimize Growth of Shellfish Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote>QUAHOGS Act of 2025</quote>.</text></section><section id="id0f9234d30c2b4460b8fbd72ae6339251"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="ide11b53753f8c414d91e979a287cd9f96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that bivalve trends in East Coast States regarding productivity and abundance are characterized and that research needs are identified;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id064c006021be4ed290ab040ee9b0cbaf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prioritize scientific research needs for commercially harvested and aquacultured East Coast bivalves;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83b41e36eaed4f38b0ac2353f9266f4d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to address the increased variability or decline in harvests of key bivalve species in East Coast States, including quahogs (hard clams), by creating a coordinated bivalve research strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb2bb35196bf4024a5cac2908224ada3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support collaboration and coordination for bivalve conservation efforts in East Coast States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3921b1f2d3af48abb75f7465102cd481"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="idF38B45B03B014DF0BB49372651CCD7C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bivalve</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bivalve</term> means aquatic mollusks that have an external 2-part hinged shell containing a soft-bodied invertebrate, including clams, oysters, mussels, and scallops.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dba1f75ba52416192b3f0b7841712b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8674C35AEFA34B8880986F440E9683DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quahog (hard clam)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>quahog (hard clam)</term> means the Northern quahog or hard clam, Mercenaria mercenaria, as well as the Southern quahog or Southern hard clam, Mercenaria campechiensis.</text></paragraph></section><section id="iddd5fb0081a3c4a4ab5334dcdf1a68add"><enum>4.</enum><header>East Coast bivalve research task force</header><subsection id="ide994d327182b4cd1baf8c8b9a33cd239"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Chairs of the New England, Mid-Atlantic, and South Atlantic Fishery Management Councils and the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission, shall convene an East Coast Bivalve Research Task Force (referred to in this section as the <quote>Research Task Force</quote>) to—</text><paragraph id="id56b496a7d7954c028c61a16a4dab2db0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review existing bivalve research in East Coast States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b96943da87147eab9d5760959dc839e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify applied research needed to better understand the increased variability and declining harvests of quahogs (hard clams) and other bivalves in some parts of the East Coast; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfc9db0fe1e549c6a7fb9a9d3f6b0c7b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support sustainable bivalve fisheries in East Coast States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1257ba6926eb4a9ca012582d0acb0f87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support sustainable bivalve aquaculture operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf94059d6943046b9a069e55688525728"><enum>(5)</enum><text>evaluate economic impacts of bivalve wild populations, fisheries, and aquaculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c2ec7c3013e4a848125593e71158105"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition and appointment</header><paragraph id="idd41d25f3e022431b8fa53ad724a564dd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Research Task Force shall be composed of not fewer than 16 and not more than 21 members, who shall be appointed under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18792232c9b1458fb060627bc90f3d24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall appoint members to the Research Task Force as follows:</text><subparagraph id="idff7173b0b057459f9e4a2670215068ce"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One representative from each of the following:</text><clause id="id9db3df7b43744555a4e4f104700c655f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration who is knowledgeable about bivalve research efforts in East Coast States.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id167116225458426fb9cab810302bc7d5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency who is knowledgeable about United States water quality assessments and standards for bivalve and human health. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5ee96721b554ab4bc2c22be2c2b4fae"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The United States Department of Agriculture who is experienced in aquaculture research or management.</text></clause><clause id="ida8d6a9807d00475d8adbc306ffdc07b3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The New England Fishery Management Council.</text></clause><clause id="id178919b8bfae484698fd83cdc608981b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council.</text></clause><clause id="id5b5ae8700a5f46e9bca1caf99a1d36e7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The South Atlantic Fishery Management Council.</text></clause><clause id="idcacfb30c35344da3b4e19ce7ef871e08"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cc49ae6feb647c4874c360b13480709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One representative from a State fish and wildlife management agency from each of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3d5eca36dbc41afabc69de8ee164ed6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the region defined by the New England Fishery Management Council;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04ef795230a3472c8838ee366b6a7c63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the region defined by the Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ee6c4254798416fa9f26130bd989903"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the region defined by the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86d0a83ce97f4a15b9ef4f09b75aa2ab"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not less than 1 and not more than 3 representatives of Indian Tribes with current or historic, or both, knowledge of and reliance on East Coast bivalves to be appointed with due regard to differences in regional perspectives and experience.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf03212caf1184dd1aa1c4055546bbae3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Not less than 3 and not more than 6 representatives from the bivalve fishing industry throughout the supply chain to be appointed with due regard to differences in regional perspectives and experience, including from— </text><clause id="ida31107845c914c959d0371231be35cfb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directed commercial harvesting;</text></clause><clause id="idbfd22e993ccb4a86ab3687617303063a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recreational harvesting;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58782e461df84d6093a40b6fa966f9fa"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fisheries of an Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="id5c704aef01e44e0fbbe3225b66e6b80f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>bivalve processors or distributors; or</text></clause><clause id="id4363c9cea52a4f948b3acae8ae8d5acd"><enum>(v)</enum><text>bivalve aquaculture, including hatcheries.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2277a28b80ef409495022eabc4af40a4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>5 representatives who are academic experts in bivalve biology and ecology, bivalve habitat restoration and conservation, bivalve aquaculture, comprehensive marine research planning in East Coast States, or the economics or social dynamics of bivalve fisheries and aquaculture, including at least 1 representative with expertise in quahogs (hard clams).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf2cdb405f9749a89be1608f19d0f0ad"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration representative described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) shall be the Chair of the Research Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id485218fe387c4863adaf4694a68611a2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="idc536fa3ce2b04df188634af69c7e5acf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Research Task Force shall—</text><subparagraph id="id9db1245827684119abdf79a29890b39e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review of bivalve science relevant to understanding current and potential future harvests of quahogs (hard clams) and other culturally or economically important bivalve species in East Coast States, as well as solutions to identified problems, including an examination of—</text><clause id="id7f8bd5c933084011acabe138dbc3a790"><enum>(i)</enum><text>traditional ecological knowledge of bivalve populations and their ecosystems, including potential for incorporation into management plans;</text></clause><clause id="idd5370e96b77e48e3a4880077e1634d66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>habitat requirements for bivalve populations, including water quality and potential for water quality improvement or alteration through habitat restoration or other means, as well as potential future habitat change;</text></clause><clause id="id00aefc15b2c54e1880010c71b82bfc1a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>impacts of erosion and sedimentation on bivalve populations and farms, including potential mitigation techniques;</text></clause><clause id="id4533580006704a9b996aaf5a580b78b4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>current and future impacts of climate change on bivalves, including ocean warming, ocean acidification, and sea level rise;</text></clause><clause id="idf5d31a98e9fb44bca229be4b014972fc"><enum>(v)</enum><text>conditions and techniques for successful restoration, including feasibility of multitrophic restoration, such as bivalves and seagrass meadows;</text></clause><clause id="id487ee778675d42cd918d386e1422ba5f"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>mitigation strategies for climate change impacts, including assisted migration;</text></clause><clause id="id71731adce96a487697f20d14cbea898c"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>culture and breeding techniques, including genomic modifications to meet different commercial, recreational, and restoration needs;</text></clause><clause id="idf6004873493a4ba8a2bcb70b59f28678"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>life cycle, including larval dispersal, recruitment dynamics, life-stage specific mortality, and growth rate;</text></clause><clause id="idc1770c3666fc463681a7cf742e9928a9"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>current and historic ranges, as well as potential future range shifts due to climate change;</text></clause><clause id="id36e8ff91093142b7bb5f5887b0036af7"><enum>(x)</enum><text>prevalence of diseases and disease mitigating strategies; </text></clause><clause id="id33e828a8b14344b8b32e623963032a3c"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>management strategies for sustainable bivalve aquaculture and potential impacts; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83ab2e0f38524937b7a8799c4e19f8f6"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>economic value and potential of bivalve aquaculture, including financial and regulatory barriers to entry for small-scale operations; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62ba5d27cc7d4c7eb1b26d6f7d5c7e1e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb32bfa95743b423ba992db7f139c3a00"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">scientific research gaps in understanding the ecology of culturally and economically important bivalve species in East Coast States; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02c71f1a1b7f44308a6d19ccaa8f78b7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the needs for developing solutions to declining harvests and other identified problems, including with respect to quahogs (hard clams); </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id017e663fb3a245b68c36bd64f3ec18fd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consider both current and future impacts on the health and populations of bivalves in East Coast States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8122e64e9bcb4d83ac717ddbe99f5248"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify solutions to current and predicted impacts on the health and populations of bivalves in East Coast States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d15682dbff84fd1986ec7a5b0ee25fe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3f426fd055d4a3190064823e77ee387"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date the Research Task Force is established, the Chair of the Research Task Force shall submit to the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and make publicly available, a report—</text><clause id="id06464e85efe048b88cfeca21d5e8e840"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describing the review conducted under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id57602481985e4e1ba004e1f7eee6d906"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that includes—</text><subclause id="idc8cc255eb475487583324a3b72c2610f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>recommendations on filling knowledge gaps that warrant further scientific inquiry; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id3dfb07831ab146678eb78fa412e04027"><enum>(II)</enum><text>findings from the reports of work groups submitted under subsection (d)(2)(C).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ab5cbc06e4f490fbb229b987f33b360"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim progress report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date the Research Task Force is established, the Chair of the Research Task Force shall submit to the individuals and entities described in subparagraph (A) and make publicly available an interim progress report describing the review conducted under paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf037b0a950c74e48b4004ab100dbc14b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header><paragraph id="ide7006c2f9e1a44b49b2950068d85d75a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vice Chairperson</header><text>The Research Task Force shall select a Vice Chair by vote from among the members of the Research Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5001826a19f0410d8ede37c2e0c152de"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Work groups</header><subparagraph id="idaaabc59de467457a8867b2ba41206aeb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Research Task Force—</text><clause id="id8eeb0aad6e0f4b5bb92a58b27bd27577"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of the establishment of the Research Task Force, shall establish a work group focused specifically on the research needs associated with quahog (hard clams) populations in Rhode Island and across the East Coast;</text></clause><clause id="ida2c2ac87a492438298ca4a314132f796"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of the establishment of the Research Task Force, shall establish a work group focused on the current and potential future impacts of climate change on bivalve populations in East Coast States; and</text></clause><clause id="idfd27d758697d4850ac3eaf4ee7bacd61"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may establish additional regionally or stock focused work groups within the Research Task Force, as members determine appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae2fcd4e355540d6818e69f94176bbe2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>Each work group established under this subsection shall—</text><clause id="id1420659cf23e4845afff1144f58e1d53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consist of not less than 5 individuals who—</text><subclause id="idf170cdc37bb0402d9af469ac21ab4796"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are knowledgeable about the species, issue, or region under consideration; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4318ee9fa04e42f58233e42160bc194b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall include at least 1 member of the Research Task Force, though the others need not be; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7dbd3f5979a44ee9a939e808a35376d7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be balanced in terms of stakeholder representation, including commercial and aquaculture fisheries, as well as experts in statistical, biological, economic, social, or other scientific information as relevant to the work group’s focus.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf68f9c9ab5f64534be78e6c26e79a3f0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date the Research Task Force is established, each work group established under this subsection shall submit a report with the work group's findings to the Research Task Force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb5d739e79ab49ef9497fd9c2e61a0b5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of the Research Task Force and each member of a work group shall serve without compensation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd71f334619334b92a21feec6231c7ee9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>A member of the Research Task Force and a member of a work group shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Research Task Force. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50732952d32f473184b60159abad90b0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall provide such administrative support as is necessary for the Research Task Force and its work groups to carry out their duties, which may include support for virtual or in-person participation. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id654208a26cf54b3481ce5933377ec259"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

