<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H770E1C27D0A34BE59EF4C67AD328C2D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1151 IH: Freedom to Invest in Tomorrow’s Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain postsecondary credentialing expenses as qualified higher education expenses for purposes of 529 accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF891C59B0214B5A8CC745D5AFA8FF85" style="OLC"><section id="HD52FC7A29F5C4CB6B25D29506158C70F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freedom to Invest in Tomorrow’s Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HD284AE6425094403B43EBA422817457E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain postsecondary credentialing expenses treated as qualified higher education expenses for purposes of 529 accounts</header><subsection id="HD660E86C25264721ADBF8AB7BE7AD508"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(e)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBA415C7F29774CAABCD1AD2F84DE78FA"><subparagraph id="HC3EA69A21D43448A8DB4B8CD13E2C760"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain postsecondary credentialing expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified higher education expenses</term> includes qualified postsecondary credentialing expenses (as defined in subsection (f)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H059AC90BDB61436E856A27DD267E2A6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified postsecondary credentialing expenses</header><text>Section 529 is amended by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (g) and by inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEB8EB3AA25E448FABD6C6DC71AF2C925" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H688AB5F228334C06ACC0F911F8950A0F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified postsecondary credentialing expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H378F17494D014A1D985A50A78816C429"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified postsecondary credentialing expenses</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H66F22202863A48A7BCEDF812660DC210"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tuition, fees, books, supplies, and equipment required for the enrollment or attendance of a designated beneficiary in a recognized postsecondary credential program, or any other expense incurred in connection with enrollment in or attendance at a recognized postsecondary credential program if such expense would, if incurred in connection with enrollment or attendance at an eligible educational institution, be covered under subsection (e)(3)(A), </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7848544057CB464DA7B7E2CDDB1A1070"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees for testing if such testing is required to obtain or maintain a recognized postsecondary credential, and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD161F9DF654B48E28654E9816E387720"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees for continuing education if such education is required to maintain a recognized postsecondary credential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB653B6DAF99A49CE9708436107036AC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential program</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>recognized postsecondary credential program</quote> means any program to obtain a recognized postsecondary credential if—</text><subparagraph id="HD32F794B4A0E4247A40BCCB6E087625A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such program is included on a State list prepared under section 122(d) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3152">29 U.S.C. 3152(d)</external-xref>),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93607C4CB8A04C819F775651C8E3D7BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such program is listed in the WEAMS Public directory (or successor directory) maintained by the Department of Veterans Affairs,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46080A3A36394248BE943315CBDB35D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an examination (developed or administered by an organization widely recognized as providing reputable credentials in the occupation) is required to obtain or maintain such credential and such organization recognizes such program as providing training or education which prepares individuals to take such examination, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87645559CA07465280C3AFD863643AEB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such program is identified by the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, as being a reputable program for obtaining a recognized postsecondary credential for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF364628DC7343D59FEC4F4EE3E4ED1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text>The term <quote>recognized postsecondary credential</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1191EECBEE164EF9BCC6B6D3E8256132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any postsecondary employment credential that is industry recognized, including—</text><clause id="H02CC701F62F04344BD7F4760085078CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any postsecondary employment credential issued by a program that is accredited by the Institute for Credentialing Excellence, the National Commission on Certifying Agencies, or the American National Standards Institute,</text></clause><clause id="HC45A9329797140FEAD6455D5AFAEBC68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any postsecondary employment credential that is included in the Credentialing Opportunities On-Line (COOL) directory of credentialing programs (or successor directory) maintained by the Department of Defense or by any branch of the Armed Services, and</text></clause><clause id="H285A25B7B15B46CDAC895CE0A42CE6AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any postsecondary employment credential identified for purposes of this clause by the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, as being industry recognized,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E7C724B5CF4AF28DD4FE629D4957AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any certificate of completion of an apprenticeship that is registered and certified with the Secretary of Labor under the National Apprenticeship Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50</external-xref>),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BC2ED577994FB0A392E027D51E4E4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any occupational or professional license issued or recognized by a State or the Federal Government (and any certification that satisfies a condition for obtaining such a license), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D1142639F3C4ED4BDF85E98D485DB3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any recognized postsecondary credential as defined in section 3(52) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3BFC511784984260B9F1E51A41219629"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

