<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC42FE0603D0432186E6850BECD9EF5F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 379 IH: Recognizing the roles and contributions of elementary and secondary school teachers in building and enhancing the civic, cultural, and economic well-being of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the roles and contributions of elementary and secondary school teachers in building and enhancing the civic, cultural, and economic well-being of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas education and knowledge are the foundation of the current and future strength of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas teachers and other education staff have earned and deserve the respect of their students and communities for their selfless dedication to community service and the futures of the children of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the purposes of National Teacher Appreciation Week, celebrated from May 5, 2025, through May 9, 2025, are—</text><paragraph id="HC1B81C267EA9476ABAFB06F16DF402A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to raise public awareness of the unquantifiable contributions of teachers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6234D3F5D124D5DA0120A2379C45280"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote greater respect and understanding for the teaching profession; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas students, schools, communities, and a number of organizations representing educators are recognizing the importance of teachers during National Teacher Appreciation Week: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB8BD2922459E48BEB860F03A6ADEF7C6"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA35D80BDC7694E8693665E1F45980B86"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H2A140AD0F16E4573AF8350329239BE08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>thanks elementary and secondary school teachers of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H238A961B04484632A7832291862C85FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes the profession of teaching and the contributions of educators by encouraging students, parents, school administrators, and public officials to recognize National Teacher Appreciation Week.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

