<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HACE22E14366E4FF7AF7E54644B2116F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1998 IH: Sanction Sea Pirates Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons engaged in piracy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5DCC28ECCC754D028A98692D94D2ED38" style="OLC"><section id="HD8B8F5236D2D480A86592B343CD3C128" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanction Sea Pirates Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2C1D1C7BBA68434FB9AFC1F1A2886FCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H47D7E0855CE84F51AC846D789348553B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2011, there were 212 attempted attacks against vessels off of the Somali coast, more than 1,000 crew were held hostage, and 35 seafarers were killed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7709F811E54C4548AAC09D3A8243D34A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Over the past decade through the beginning of 2023, rates of piracy in the Western Indian Ocean subsided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD14E2E670F894EBF826554CE0CD82382"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Houthi attacks against commercial vessels in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden since the Hamas terrorist attack against Israel on October 7th have impacted global shipping markets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54A016451073477AAEBE15C27CB4273C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There has been a surge in Somali pirate attacks, beginning in the fall of 2023 and lasting into 2024, that has coincided with and taken advantage of Houthi aggression.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF771EA9CB3C1426DAC386F7D6D137681"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On March 12, 2024, Somali pirates hijacked a Bangladeshi-flagged ship and took its crew hostage.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H217592F14D5041A982FAB46142AB9189"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H5EB5BFC554024859BA0D1041F0DAA19C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States Government should seek to stop piracy all around the world, including off the Somali Coast and in the Gulf of Aden;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB00DC710734C44279A9687BF9E9A260F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>high seas pirates, and the criminal networks and enterprises with whom they are affiliated, should be sanctioned upon identification; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2B95EBB42E04A19AFE40AC7253BC8E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should seek to work with allies and partners around the globe to combat piracy around the globe and to curb the surge in piracy off of the coast of Somalia and in the Gulf of Aden.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8A87C4607AEF41A984DEFD22A1A4A2FF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subsection id="H365B18EFB0124A9F880F7F75AD2B860E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines knowingly engages in piracy.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E49920982144492A6C13B1A91B9DABA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H172DDEE563384397B68E1A75E45117A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF25BB3051CAD40078CD4B9EB62CCC727"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="HC2180A89C5E34FBCA4FB6497D9FAA2E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="HDBEE6596D69445CAB5DEE110E6D3D5F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H77DC6C40EF5347D29A822CA896008805"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H8051B058AE7A47D1B2A7309B1E775439"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18B006CCCC8D44629308794C29BB08C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="HE0684E96825447E98F09B6ACE48EDA79"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause><clause id="H808753C5AA1F4F05BC29DC68D294A6D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H4A2D47323E6E46BEB2CA71622D78904F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF905731C1EC84032837AC3F4ED816DD3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31C4E26983F44BEA97B1D933E81039E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H82F3B2D0829941D9AD017C0344A21179"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77CB8C04290F44FDB07E2572558B3574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text><subparagraph id="H1D58956AA6ED402E887502AE1B7F0100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A58C31C810F475FB92330643B8959C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H824DFD7FB6FF41AC87F16B4B36F96107"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7AA7F905519480CAD23C91C1D6C24A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD28480B8839E4B448529AC6C4B8C6B35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0340B8560DCC42C1852B50283AB5500B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>In any judicial review of a determination made under this section, if the determination was based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act) such information may be submitted to the reviewing court ex parte and in camera. This subsection may not be construed to confer or imply any right to judicial review.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A8892438D6F4221AFCC807753768E53"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="HEF398BFE38904615AE0C3AD53BD88713"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ACC8F7C13294FAA972597FB507A6ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D83D1053CC3428A934617B7BFABEDA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the application of sanctions imposed with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President certifies to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate not later than 15 days before such waiver is to take effect that the waiver is crucial to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB56126B53B9B4604B64EF372786EABEF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H970980C9966C4E8EB394BF55B3B558D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E23DD082C94C269AA8BD775861A998"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4E8028E361384C53A182850830669987"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A936102D3E8478CA1D923E09E341C0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a permanent resident alien of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07DFDFAC2A644171836F39E1287D0646"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2A633884619450CACF74C6EE8B457C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Piracy</header><text>The term <term>piracy</term> means any act in violation of one or more provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

