<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA52D3FF48BE4B0CB24CB4EBC4D41BE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4904 IH: Pedestrian Hazard, Awareness, and Safety Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Secretary of Transportation to take certain actions to develop physical alternatives to better protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users against traffic incidents, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA9727C10048D4EF5A8FA2BFB4996CBD4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H374ECCE7916140288C67E23CF48E79D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pedestrian Hazard, Awareness, and Safety Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PHASE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H053FD4599CAE4852B924EA94BDCD0027" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>NIST innovative technologies to improve and enhance traffic control devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall transmit to the Secretary of Transportation potential solutions using innovative technologies to improve and enhance traffic control devices to better equip vehicle operators, including bicycles and protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users. The Director shall provide supporting evidence to ensure such potential solutions do not overwhelm, overstimulate, or otherwise distract vehicle operators, including bicyclists or pedestrians. Such potential solutions shall comply with all applicable Federal regulations.</text></section>
<section id="H973F397465484730AFD5A4DDB2D8CB3B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Physical alternatives to protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users</header>
<subsection id="H4C041C0D5C32440D8F6C27F61F874D04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out a study on developing physical alternatives to better protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users from traffic incidents that—</text> <paragraph id="H4F5C1B2D3D2A4E158DE58EF9B35F942E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes urban areas, as determined by the Bureau of the Census, in which pedestrian fatalities have increased in the data available as of the date of enactment of this Act to study where crashes involving pedestrians occur most frequently;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0483202F1AB94D978A242DEE4FC939A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine physical alternatives to reduce vehicle crashes with vulnerable road users and fatalities, including pedestrians; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D03E6C2A0E64C77BF69E595273915C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">studies intelligent speed assistance and blind spot detection safety systems’ impact on the safety of vulnerable road users including the ability of blind spot detection to detect all road users in a timely manner.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1A53FBE1F9344A67B3D8FD397C4190AB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall brief the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representative on the results of the study.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA4772ACF0D644DB8DA4569BEC973B76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a grant program to provide grants to cities, Indian Tribes, and municipalities to implement infrastructure that complies with all applicable Federal regulations and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>) and improves pedestrian safety, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H7256355B7CAC4F13BB456729E7052D39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>innovative technology for crosswalks;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64DCA7DFAC7C43EC8B09C97AA61527AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>additional pedestrian facilities both on and off the road;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBE8E34F4A9B24D8AB6BA621C0874C72C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expanded buffer zones;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC6B3F900A8048B7961800175C98D076"><enum>(4)</enum><text>pedestrian crossings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H118D5822428E4D648A34820785C097FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>increased pedestrian accommodation on bridges;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB896135EBA514A148278B93E5F14C39E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>upgraded highway traffic signals;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H559B5DB39609415D98A3562E6626B168"><enum>(7)</enum><text>accessible pedestrian signals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EC5355377D84A9D9BC5C50E41A56A8E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>accessible sidewalks;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H49C358F180164CEBB2C0A19DE97E5185"><enum>(9)</enum><text>increased signage;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE5843F9D5774D858449C8FA2C469C53"><enum>(10)</enum><text>increased lighting at crossings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27963904285A4C5584E9400EB8D76049"><enum>(11)</enum><text>adaptive or intelligent roadway and pedestrian lighting;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28A965815F8544C8A9EE88F8CE3C4F3F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>accessible curb ramps; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC6D82B339E34EB08F2610E9412A781C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>marked crosswalks and grade-separated crossings.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HABFC5C57F2BF4BBE8E82E3A27467B1D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (c), an applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H02FD71AE8FDD41D3B2C55B82C83D6FAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each fiscal year to carry out the grant program described under subsection (c).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

