<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9EF84DAB6BF543DB9A47513A16CF87D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2946 IH: Clean Energy Victory Bond Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2946</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to issue Clean Energy Victory Bonds.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF5A3B53A002456F8C884BB59BEDC8B9" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE292BB123D8B40A28C20D2BA49EC42BD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Energy Victory Bond Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="HDAB39EA2DDBB45378660A965664FD948"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HCF6979F790D34C789AC30E575FB11338"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Potential exists for increasing clean and renewable energy production and energy efficiency installation in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E2CBF1F1CB849B9A8CBCD6BF221344F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other nations, including China and Germany, are ahead of the United States in manufacturing and deploying various clean energy technologies, even though many of these technologies were invented in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H17CD7556C8B447068B4C1039AB8D5961"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Climate change represents an existential threat to the safety, security, and economy of the United States. Rapid and robust deployment of clean energy will reduce greenhouse gas emissions and mitigate the effects of climate change on American society.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD077627D90E749C985577DE1FE58CBF4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Many segments of the American public want to take charge of efforts to combat the effects of climate change and practice responsible consumer behavior.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8E5D120E954C4681857B729440029EBC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department of Energy (referred to in this section as the <quote>EERE</quote>) estimates that taxpayer investment of $12,000,000,000 into the EERE research and development portfolio has already yielded an estimated net economic benefit to the United States of more than $230,000,000,000, with an overall annual return on investment of more than 20 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7C4486AA8544436ABCF31AC14FF1B0EC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Investments in renewable energy and energy efficiency projects in the United States create green jobs throughout the Nation. New and innovative jobs could be created through expanded government support for clean energy and energy efficiency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA6C619B12CC5445F8F8901AB9DB38F0E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As Americans choose energy efficiency and clean energy and transportation, it reduces our dependence on foreign oil and improves our energy security.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H03AC011370D4403EA3843FA1B6A1DA4C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Bonds are a low-cost method for encouraging clean energy, as they do not require direct budget allocations or expenditures. The projects supported through Clean Energy Victory Bonds will create jobs and business revenues that will increase Federal tax revenues, while simultaneously reducing nationwide health and environmental costs incurred by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDFC301C03EE647D49315391121F974FE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Bonds are voluntary measures that allow Americans to contribute financially in whatever amount is available to them.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C8AD07DCF304F85BAAE4E673582FCD2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>During World War II, over 80 percent of American households purchased Victory Bonds to support the war effort, raising over $185,000,000,000, or over $2,000,000,000,000 in today’s dollars.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H23998C9D8935466EA57E27DF4A94F823"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HF9802621592C47BDAE973159413A76A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clean energy project</header><text>The term <term>clean energy project</term> means a technology that provides—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA58A0134028E4505A04EE890B2AC6B56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performance-based energy efficiency improvements; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H91FA270E56B646E9B06A625AB6412126"><enum>(B)</enum><text>clean energy improvements, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="HFBB16A5EA3994544BE36563320BB097D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>electricity generated from solar, wind, geothermal, small-scale hydropower, and hydrokinetic energy sources;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC87017425030471A8E724978691D1EFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fuel cells using non-fossil fuel sources;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB119927D606E4F358FABF33C017E3472"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>advanced storage technologies; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HEA948FA721EE470B87C6315FD0822EED"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>electric vehicle infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H73123AAD85A64EE5B5FC9D454E051105"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H18DDE3B108534B189AF29E1A33C0E29C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clean Energy Victory Bonds</header><subsection commented="no" id="H8831407F5EA949DCAF80EFFDB4C21A98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Defense, shall issue bonds to be known as <quote>Clean Energy Victory Bonds</quote>, the proceeds from which shall be used to carry out the purposes described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by section 5).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HECE327F18D42420FB9CDEE731D09C7F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings bond</header><text>Any Clean Energy Victory Bond issued under this section shall be issued by the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D3073B465444E6EB8B01332DEEBED6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a savings bond of series EE, or as administered by the Bureau of the Fiscal Service of the Department of the Treasury, in a manner consistent with the provisions of section 3105 of title 31, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA03FC919BE7240A392E3CBCDD3F2958E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in denominations of $25 and such other amounts as are determined appropriate by the Secretary, and shall mature within such periods as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA6D4C6ED4937427C8A318A58F0BDEC40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of Clean Energy Victory Bonds</header><text>The aggregate face amount of the Clean Energy Victory Bonds issued annually under this section shall be not greater than $50,000,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H51484A08BF974A1FAFE95B5E296BD780"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interest</header><text>Clean Energy Victory Bonds shall bear interest at the rate the Secretary sets for Savings Bonds of Series EE and Series I, plus a rate of return determined by the Secretary which is based on the valuation of—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H20238B58733646D1BFFCFAB30818304F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>savings achieved through reduced energy spending by the Federal Government resulting from clean energy projects funded from the proceeds of such bonds; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B8352E2A0CC4C95B7648C3F91CB423F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>interest collected on loans financed or guaranteed from the proceeds of such bonds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9EB8786ED3EC41408BC4C9EEA06B6A3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Full faith and credit</header><text>Payment of interest and principal with respect to any Clean Energy Victory Bond issued under this section shall be made from the general fund of the Treasury of the United States and shall be backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0B7CAC32BBEF45249C66954DDF808B5D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Promotion</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H408FFD20E4F1450183A3CC8A69811F98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall take such actions, independently and in conjunction with financial institutions offering Clean Energy Victory Bonds, to promote the purchase of Clean Energy Victory Bonds, including campaigns describing the financial and social benefits of purchasing Clean Energy Victory Bonds.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD0B1434970A54DAE8BB8860F60F91168"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Promotional Activities</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), promotional activities may include advertisements, pamphlets, or other promotional materials—</text><subparagraph id="H60219C2CAD5545488AA5A84ED4760926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in periodicals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1323B1634CA486C85A3D8B0CBBB9E12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on billboards and other outdoor venues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F5F57AD3CD84A69B38E81D34A6ED668"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on television;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA26F5A74E2A54C25BCD3D66559DF962C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>on radio;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB392FB5AFE1A4DC295A446D0A1783C1A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>on the internet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C3EF2DF1C374968B178E299A52528E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>within financial institutions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DF797F82EE7417FA468D766A62C52F8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other venues or outlets the Secretary may identify.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAC7BC4ABE1FB48EC9584E6ED632D267A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Clean Energy Victory Bonds Trust Fund</header><subsection id="H8E2C803ECB134A98B4D47CA4DC6D8624"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H651D650871294FBA9078A472A375F3B5"><section id="HF1A331C64C44440C9EC620C98D49464E"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Clean Energy Victory Bonds Trust Fund</header><subsection id="HAD1A230874E84F61AE5ACAF776EE861F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Clean Energy Victory Bonds Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of such amounts as may be apportioned or credited to such Trust Fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC4891158FC5418FAEC764EDF533F2D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Trust Fund—</text><paragraph id="HF361F6569D454BC4842C2C69F8A7600E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts equivalent to revenue from the issuance of Clean Energy Victory Bonds under section 4 of the <short-title>Clean Energy Victory Bond Act of 2025</short-title>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E66E1520384AD19D6D5721816B4D1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any gifts or bequests made to the Trust Fund which are accepted by the Secretary for the benefit of such Fund or any activity financed through such Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B913667B9A840669968997C6DB4CCED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures from trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Trust Fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to finance clean energy projects (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Clean Energy Victory Bond Act of 2025</short-title>) at the Federal, State, and local level, which may include—</text><paragraph id="H4147377B69364234A8D9FA2CA6046DDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing additional support to existing Federal financing programs available to States for energy efficiency upgrades and clean energy deployment,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0296197CAD93482A94BF4278EFF05FDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing funding for clean energy investments by all Federal agencies,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H304CAB75DE814BCD915F534D0827861D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing funding for electric grid enhancements and connections that enable clean energy deployment,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BFE1EE225CE49D8914382F9282D4BFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing funding to renovate existing inefficient buildings or building new energy efficient buildings,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55FCA7A5853D48198BDF4F61A56EF9DE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing tax incentives and tax credits for clean energy technologies,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H973A0FAED8A943019FAD2CD3A0D87C5A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>providing funding for new innovation research, including ARPA–E, public competitions similar to those designed by the X Prize Foundation, grants provided through the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department of Energy, or other mechanisms to fund revolutionary clean energy technology,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H685777D0A1FB4C15A4B5A0E00F7E665B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing additional support to existing Federal, State, and local grant programs that finance clean energy projects, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H143C980150B74A8FB36A57DE67B76367"><enum>(8)</enum><text>providing funding for zero-emission vehicle infrastructure and manufacturing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47B80B8193054952AE0DB254D42CE154"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project priority</header><paragraph id="H4F1E74E39CA5454A8A3AF2C397262CB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that not less than 40 percent of the amounts expended under subsection (c) in each year are expended for clean energy projects which are located in and reduce energy rates in disadvantaged and vulnerable communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE35BAC27D7804CB9985DE29FCC12E27F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disadvantaged and vulnerable communities</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>disadvantaged and vulnerable communities</term> means communities—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE22EA3333F964710AF67C90189D82E24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which bear disproportionate burdens of negative public health effects, environmental pollution, or impacts of climate change, </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD7CF855AED2941B69624858D1BB27D96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have significant representation of people of color, low-wealth individuals, or Tribal and Indigenous members, or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C6D0798F4AB4A77BAB0E7DACA0F515D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which have a high concentration of low- and moderate-income households as compared to other communities, </text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">as determined by the Secretary.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6C32086AC82A4BB3BC8BE751470BFBF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABA12F8847824888872681D1AA98FC93"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 9512. Clean Energy Victory Bonds Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

