<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25498-JNY-X1-W5P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S527 RS: Prescription Pricing for the People Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 42</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 527</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Federal Trade Commission to study the role of intermediaries in the pharmaceutical supply chain and provide Congress with appropriate policy recommendations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" changed="not-changed" id="id3b4a86a5-9346-4a99-95be-463448af349b"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Pricing for the People Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section changed="not-changed" id="idf7325fee-9026-42fc-ac8d-6e75b981b1dc"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idc2619ed2-bf3a-41d9-b14d-e80ccb2804a9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id6ac696ed-df36-4ad6-b820-493a3faaffd3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd36fafb1-c34a-4238-9519-37be5fbd5dc4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2d941af-c89e-43ba-acca-4720a521d55c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></section><section changed="not-changed" id="id133ab32e-12a2-4959-b61b-c91196b12d4f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study of pharmaceutical supply chain intermediaries and merger activity</header><subsection id="id30aebed3-e057-45e0-920d-c787f7ee50c1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="id46c5b3c3-1282-45c1-bbce-570f1ef9d825" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addresses at minimum—</text><subparagraph id="ida98b2f41-dbc6-463c-8d43-255e1e7f9a62" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether pharmacy benefit managers—</text><clause id="idcbcc33a1-7a5b-4c95-b742-56962955f4be" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>charge payers a higher price than the reimbursement rate at which the pharmacy benefit managers reimburse pharmacies owned by the pharmacy benefit manager and pharmacies not owned by the pharmacy benefit manager;</text></clause><clause id="ide3c4e17a-d0d7-4511-a011-78935a3d57c1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>steer patients for competitive advantage to any pharmacy, including a retail, mail-order, or any other type of pharmacy, in which the pharmacy benefit managers have an ownership interest;</text></clause><clause id="idc3c8ba8a-97f2-464e-9dc4-320e1b2e9131" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>audit or review proprietary data, including acquisition costs, patient information, or dispensing information, of pharmacies not owned by the pharmacy benefit manager and use such proprietary data to increase revenue or market share for competitive advantage; or</text></clause><clause id="id4d445827-50c2-4795-8142-fdd92b7b9c26" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>use formulary designs to increase the market share of higher cost prescription drugs or depress the market share of lower cost prescription drugs (each net of rebates and discounts);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32eff8a3-f2ba-4bc8-891e-dff5514450bc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trends or observations on the state of competition in the healthcare supply chain, particularly with regard to intermediaries and their integration with other intermediaries, suppliers, or payers of prescription drug benefits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bc03e3d-a7e2-4bf0-be40-2ef8ad167248" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how companies and payers assess the benefits, costs, and risks of contracting with intermediaries, including pharmacy services administrative organizations, and whether more information about the roles of intermediaries should be available to consumers and payers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc086a7f-0b50-40c2-9bf1-d1bd8ee37017" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether there are any specific legal or regulatory obstacles the Commission currently faces in enforcing the antitrust and consumer protection laws in the pharmaceutical supply chain, including the pharmacy benefit manager marketplace and pharmacy services administrative organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92a149211fe34adba72de433cc8d9299" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether there are any specific legal or regulatory obstacles that contribute to the cost of prescription drug prices; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idecc201d5-123b-4f90-8276-526c0bfe996b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides—</text><subparagraph id="ida854b909-5f5b-4119-8922-eb25ee81c028" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>observations or conclusions drawn from the November 2017 roundtable entitled <quote>Understanding Competition in Prescription Drug Markets: Entry and Supply Chain Dynamics</quote> and any similar efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35c75fef-0559-4df6-8d48-3b4c1b4a357d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specific actions the Commission intends to take as a result of the November 2017 roundtable, and any similar efforts, including a detailed description of relevant forthcoming actions, additional research or roundtable discussions, consumer education efforts, or enforcement actions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id818cc3cc-97ea-42a7-a006-4374c52bca4c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>policy or legislative recommendations to—</text><clause id="id17f56316-cfc7-4adc-b292-f36523c2001a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve transparency and competition in the pharmaceutical supply chain;</text></clause><clause id="idc94119a1-7114-4a9a-ba19-ddb3720b18b0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevent and deter anticompetitive behavior in the pharmaceutical supply chain; and</text></clause><clause id="id3f095229-96c8-466d-9a23-c28104479a6a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>best ensure that consumers benefit from any cost savings or efficiencies that may result from mergers and consolidations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf17016ae-4eb7-4923-9209-3ce38851bb04" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an interim report on the progress of the report required by subsection (a), along with preliminary findings and conclusions based on information collected to that date.</text></subsection></section><section changed="not-changed" id="id09bab420-5d98-4a68-a8b3-189b10b44110"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id561c5fb2-ebdc-403b-8e41-6a06809733cc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and nature of complaints received by the Commission relating to an allegation of anticompetitive conduct by a manufacturer of a sole-source drug;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8045a4fe-d014-4a56-b846-2bca29220aa7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ability of the Commission to bring an enforcement action against a manufacturer of a sole-source drug; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2278eeb-1571-4661-a2be-ba56985201da" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>policy or legislative recommendations to strengthen enforcement actions relating to anticompetitive behavior.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

