<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25726-41M-J7-6P8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2205 IS: Equal Representation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2205</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250629" legis-day="20250628">June 29 (legislative day, June 28), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a citizenship question on the decennial census, to require reporting on certain census statistics, and to modify apportionment of Representatives to be based on United States citizens instead of all individuals.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3294665D481843078788B3204CD75430"><section section-type="section-one" id="H14CD2C55075C46BCBC28F098C1D62E0E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Representation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H24B44ED0F39040EAAFDB491A039D926A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Citizenship status on decennial census</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141 of title 13, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2D6EBE7D51094CAFBB4EBFD329D64531"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07C3ED2CF6EC47E489168659DD5F8323"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E04421205A14554BCE0FED7C904E3EE"><subsection id="H26DD48C298ED42618569ADAD1BAFF5D9"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5FC2D7369A6D4C158F1E32D43539F8DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the 2030 decennial census and each decennial census thereafter, the Secretary shall include in any questionnaire distributed or otherwise used for the purpose of determining the total population by States a checkbox or other similar option for the respondent to indicate, for the respondent and for each of the members of the household of the respondent, whether that individual is a citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9BED4C3E62D4824924E2A9B51910C47" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after completion of a decennial census of the population under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make publicly available the number of individuals per State, disaggregated by citizens of the United States and noncitizens, as tabulated in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HF641CCA46E6A465A8682D0FADB9AC39F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exclusion of noncitizens from number of persons used to determine apportionment of representatives and number of electoral votes</header><subsection id="H99B855BDAC8048E5B620549EB235A42C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 22(a) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(a)</external-xref>), is amended by inserting after <quote>not taxed</quote> the following: <quote>and individuals who are not citizens of the United States</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4EF84F31BC434113B963E56FE53FC66B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to the apportionment of Representatives carried out pursuant to the decennial census conducted during 2030 and any succeeding decennial census.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6887FED00A2E427E8DB67637318953F7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or amendment made by this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the provisions of this Act and amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provision or amendment to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

