<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55713F2F23B341BBB41A3AD883C8A5DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2700 IH: Utilize No Phones in Learning to Unleash Growth in Grades and Educate Distraction-free Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2700</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require State educational agencies to implement policies prohibiting the use or possession of personal mobile phones by students in public school classrooms during school hours, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA85C259DCC1E44B1AB6A49307C8DC728" style="OLC"><section id="H11A0376CB23D4E1BA3A23D491DBFDC3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Utilize No Phones in Learning to Unleash Growth in Grades and Educate Distraction-free Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNPLUGGED Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5ECA1D76110041F8AA8D1D323C789AB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H7BE103D77B2E415D82FEACDBEEB8E188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HFF7EBD79AE9048988BCBE6029F2779E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public education is critical to the economic vitality, national security, and democratic governance of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF7299A28754E7AA72BC19EF11C43DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Disruptions to the educational process directly affect national productivity, civic engagement, and workforce development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F69E7F7CF34EECA52EB10A3B4C151F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The excessive use of mobile phones during school hours significantly impairs the ability of schools to maintain effective educational environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AC1CA4673904E8E896BFDAE01D162AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A growing body of peer-reviewed literature has documented the detrimental effects of mobile phone usage in classrooms on attention, academic performance, and mental health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E15EA86C6044318822D7AB6A9F5FEB1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Studies published in journals such as Computers in Human Behavior, Educational Psychology, and the Journal of Adolescent Health have shown that the presence of mobile phones in academic settings correlates with reduced focus, lower test scores, increased academic procrastination, and higher levels of anxiety and depression among students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB086D4D2DD4A32B50134C34EB9D857"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Social psychologist Jonathan Haidt, in both his academic work and public commentary, has—</text><subparagraph id="H694F271740D84B19A3F2A81BA60F0CD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>extensively documented the relationship between the rise of smartphone use among adolescents and the decline in mental health indicators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H980BC38915A44CEF86609D4FB0873B6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>produced research pointing to a sharp increase in rates of anxiety, depression, and self-harm beginning around 2012–2013, coinciding with widespread smartphone and social media adoption among teenagers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75A1EB37708642D2B6E91FB4B84E38A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>argued that overexposure to digital devices and online platforms undermines the development of resilience, emotional regulation, and in-person social connection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A3FA87682F4618BD9C1FB4085EA91D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Limiting in-school phone access is essential to reversing harmful psychological and academic trends in American youth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H694EABA473BA4C04915F83F52D349E18"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The presence of mobile phones in educational settings contributes to increased rates of bullying, cyber harassment, academic dishonesty, and classroom distractions, thereby undermining the core mission of public education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C0F3C0DF7CB4A1A8D638EA12E0FC69A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>These issues are not confined to a single state or region and are national in scope, with similar patterns of disruption and diminished student outcomes reported across state lines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H288C6CE6EAFC470BAB05AC8BE77BBDED"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The cumulative effect of diminished educational achievement has a substantial impact on the national economy and workforce preparedness.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1514D91DE1D649D79B884B11457972AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that each State educational agency, in coordination with each local educational agency served by the State educational agency and in consultation with educators, parents, and students, should establish and enforce a policy that—</text><paragraph id="H8CE62E6891B4441790C457D19CD392DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enables parents to notify students through school officials about forgotten items, changes in pick-up times, and other common issues; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB24E5ADF389F455FB7BF02A709B9B274"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enables schools to communicate with parents regarding time-sensitive items.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H171462EE55064E4289A5EF1C185209E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of student phone possession in schools</header><subsection id="HF7732E4EBE14401992917C6ABCD65673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the first school year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, each State educational agency, in coordination with each local educational agency served by the State educational agency and in consultation with educators, parents, and students, shall establish and enforce a policy that prohibits student possession or use of personal electronic devices, including personal mobile phones, in public schools during school hours.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA1CA79C40FC4AACA5A633A0F53AF855"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secure storage methods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A personal electronic device policy established pursuant to subsection (a) may include a requirement that public schools use secure storage methods, including—</text><paragraph id="HAE7BA206610549ED86FB448A4A724E18" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lockable lockers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9229666DBB04F0EA76CC4E9C9B57F8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>secure lock boxes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CD6CB112F0346B3B7E227DF79DC525B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>magnetic pouches or other signal-blocking storage devices; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1B8D147D02A4ECB8D7D22E301888C03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other technologies or materials deemed appropriate by the State educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE7D88765579440A9FFDC99C44B0976D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A personal electronic device policy established pursuant to subsection (a) may permit exceptions for—</text><paragraph id="H5593427FD7B94CCA83173BC6BB1C9A28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>students with medical or health conditions that require the use of a mobile phone or other personal electronic device as part of a treatment or monitoring plan, as certified by a licensed healthcare provider;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H713C73BC25FA4A74BC8D28BF6FA28650"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">students with disabilities or special needs for whom access to a personal mobile phone or other personal electronic device is—</text><subparagraph id="H6C5D3E2151C241FBBC8BA0B9617B078A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>documented as necessary in an individualized education program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7213227E8344A599DF164B0D4765A67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included as part of services or accommodations provided to the student pursuant to section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as a <quote>Section 504 plan</quote>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7B0E2273C4E4B6AB31C6B47193493F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an individualized basis for students—</text><subparagraph id="H1177C790BCD448829885E85940DC154F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who are English learners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65962591E5E74791972BD0650B00DCC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who have a demonstrated need for a personal electronic device to facilitate instruction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7350048106746828EDFFB591347F44C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire documentation in support of subparagraph (A) and (B) in accordance with procedures established by the State educational agency; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB2F326D15A47E0B2A74970CA468094"><enum>(4)</enum><text>additional situations as States and local education authorities deem necessary and appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA89EA1813E54D7680ACF25C8665C555"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum requirement</header><text>The requirements in this Act shall constitute a minimum standard. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt or prevent a State, State educational agency, or local educational agency from enacting more restrictive policies regarding student possession or use of mobile phones or other personal electronic devices during school hours, on school grounds, or during school activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC7D5259CE80744F5A58C352875178AA6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header><paragraph id="HD16C6133BC96425F83E9326CE878E653"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall establish a grant program to provide funding to State educational agencies to purchase, implement, or maintain secure storage methods, and related training or infrastructure, in accordance with a personal electronic device policy established by such State educational agency pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5410BD4131464EE1A4433A8E59BD717E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a State educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEF6BD60FAD634907BEF68EAF5C21989F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H259C46070480464CB7E364A0BA1581F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>English learner</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>State</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H165F710F94084ECE8590E3BE89901B6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individualized education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>individualized education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C3EFBAFF71459B96DD7454F2B9177A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mobile phone</header><text>The term <term>mobile phone</term> means any handheld communication device with cellular, Wi-Fi, or Bluetooth capability, including smartphones and similar devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H772A447F86674C9490E67C0C2D2BCA1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Personal electronic device</header><text>The term <term>personal electronic device</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HF75F56CAC0F24ED598904F88590C17EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes mobile phones, smartwatches, tablets, and other handheld or wearable devices with communication, internet, or multimedia capabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACBEB865DE524410988AF247C6486D2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include laptops or tablets that are authorized by the school and used solely for instructional purposes under teacher supervision so long as such laptops or tablets are restricted from accessing social media platforms, personal email, messaging or texting services, and other non-academic applications during instructional time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56ED61FDCBEA4E7287D3996C4EEA7B13"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public school</header><text>The term <term>public school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H17B323D4AB1A4E25B4D66F1878045F41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public elementary school; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78DEF4ABE50F46DCBB978DDF026B34EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public secondary school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC8DBCC0BCE4F6C9A0938450B8B75D9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>School hours</header><text>The term <term>school hours</term> means the period from the start of the instructional day until the end of the instructional day, as defined by the State educational agency.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

