<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25919-TXY-1S-TTT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 53 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Qatar of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 53</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Qatar of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the following proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Qatar is prohibited: </text></section><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H989ECF5139D54D76ADB5C1A2622B7489"><paragraph id="H3097CF3D5718499F8467A0E4F8AB6418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services described in Transmittal No. 25–16, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on March 26, 2025: The following Major Defense Equipment (MDE): Eight (8) MQ–9B Remotely Piloted Aircraft (RPA); Two hundred (200) KMU–572 Joint Direct Attack Munition (JDAM) tail kits for Guided Bomb Unit (GBU)–38 or Laser JDAM GBU–54; Three hundred (300) BLU–111 500-lb general purpose bombs; One hundred (100) MXU–650 air foil groups (AFG) for Paveway II GBU–12; One hundred (100) MAU–169 computer control groups (CCG) for Paveway II GBU–12; Twenty-eight (28) Embedded Global Positioning System (GPS)/Inertial Navigation System (INS) (EGI) security devices with M-Code; Twelve (12) EGI security devices with Selective Availability Anti-Spoofing Modules (SAASM); Ten (10) Lynx AN/APY–8 Synthetic Aperture Radars (SAR); Ten (10) L3 Rio Grande communications intelligence (COMINT) sensor suites; One hundred ten (110) AGM–114R2 Hellfire II missiles; and Eight (8) M36E9 Hellfire Captive Air Training Missiles (CATM). The following non-MDE items will also be included: Honeywell TPE–331 turboprop engines; Certifiable Ground Control Stations (CGCS); FMU–139D/B fuze systems; DSU–38 laser illuminated target detectors for GBU–54; KY–100M narrowband/wideband terminals; AN/PYQ–10 Simple Key Loaders (SKLs); Keying Identification Verification (KIV)–77 Mode 5 Identification Friend or Foe cryptographic appliques; Intrusion Prevention System (IPS)–250X High Assurance Internet Protocol Encryptor (HAIPE) Type 1 cryptographic communications security (COMSEC) devices; Cryptographic Core Modernization –700A Type 1 COMSEC chips; AN/DPX–7 IFF transponders; Link–16 KOR–24A Small Tactical Terminals (STTs); Semi-Automatic Ground 2 Environment (SAGE) Electronic Surveillance Measure systems; AE–4500 Electronic Support Measure; Compact Multi-band Data Link (CMDL); Remotely Operated Video Enhanced Receiver (ROVER) 6Si compatible systems; Common Munitions Built-in-Test Reprogramming Equipment (CMBRE) Plus Block II; Mayflower Multi-Platform Anti-Jam GPS Navigation Antennas (MAGNA)–I, AS–4841; imaging systems; Electro-Optical/Infrared (EO/IR) Multi-Spectrum Targeting System (MTS); Active Electronically Scanned Array (AESA) radars (SeaSpray 7500 maritime radars); Due Regard Radar (DRR); Automatic Information System (AIS) transponders; Rohde &amp; Schwartz Ultra High Frequency (UHF)/Very High Frequency (VHF) radios; satellite communications ground station antennas, modems, and terminals with Unifi Security Gateway (USG) encryption; Ku-Band SATCOM GA–ASI Transportable Earth Stations (GATES); secure SATCOM systems; DSU–33D/B bomb components; M299 Longbow Hellfire launchers; weapons loading equipment; spare and repair parts, consumables and accessories, and repair and return support; weapons integration; support and test equipment; facilities and construction support; publications and technical documentation; personnel training and training equipment; transportation and airlift support; studies and surveys; U.S. Government and contractor engineering, technical, and logistics support services; and other related elements of logistics and program support.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

