<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25103-5FV-V8-475"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S613 IS: Improving Flood and Agricultural Forecasts Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to maintain the National Mesonet Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Flood and Agricultural Forecasts Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id71bc0fd0b39a4d6fac92f95edd833dcb"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Mesonet Program</header><subsection id="ida3d6d2ec41494f73abfc26b0a8bbaa12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Under Secretary shall maintain the National Mesonet Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>), which shall—</text><paragraph id="id116b516688564fcb8614c5771c3ee529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obtain observations to improve understanding of and forecast capabilities for atmospheric, drought, fire, and water events, with a prioritization on leveraging available commercial, academic, and other non-Federal Government environmental data to enhance coordination across the private, public, and academic sectors of the weather enterprise in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e4dfe34f37d41dc9754435fe8e0e562"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish means to integrate greater density and more types of environmental observations into the Program on an annual basis, including by encouraging local and regional networks of environmental monitoring stations and in situ sensor networks, including soil moisture and ground-based profilers, to participate in the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1d2ac22670c4a9d91743af836c93c1a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish memoranda of understanding with networks outside of the scope of the Program in furtherance of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29a826b3cf5c474a89e892772c2e3bd5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate with satellite data and services acquired under section 302 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8532">15 U.S.C. 8532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9784483013b344998e663a032db9c64b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program elements</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Under Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id6d8e1437a7b248b2a01785a3ea22dde3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase data density by—</text><subparagraph id="idf3d0009e193b40148fb73a4483b17bfb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving and increasing the quantity and density of environmental observations used by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administration</quote>) and the National Weather Service to support baseline forecasts, including nowcasts, warnings, and hyper local forecasts that protect individuals, businesses, agricultural production, food security, the military, and government agencies in the United States, and enabling such individuals and entities to operate in a safe, efficient, and orderly manner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bc82c3f18f24dcfb834621143ccf414"><enum>(B)</enum><text>yielding increased quantities of boundary-layer data to improve numerical weather prediction performance, including in subseasonal to seasonal timescales;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f7ebf86d3d64aa5a5503a7c909acb74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying available terrestrial or marine environmental data, or quantifiable gaps in such data, to improve the understanding of air-sea interactions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9850457c20442d6b9e703a13f9d5c8b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting the National Weather Service in reaching its target of a 30-minute warning time for severe weather through better predictive model algorithms driven by increasingly effective observations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbeabbdaad80418d8888737aea8731bb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>monitor local meteorological conditions by—</text><subparagraph id="ide3579a50cf5846078281bf782d778682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acquiring soil and moisture data to monitor soil moisture, vegetation water content, and moisture loss from evaporation, in support of operational forecasting, the National Integrated Drought Information System, and local commercial, agricultural, and emergency management needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5889c6075017403caaba933714dc04c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting the National Coordinated Soil Moisture Monitoring Network in acquiring soil moisture and related data to support the development of decision-support products and other information services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3d1f6fcc7c24bcea7eeb767dc6cd951"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expanding and enhancing environmental observational networks in the roadway environment to provide real-time road weather and surface conditions for surface transportation and related economic sectors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b5f3a34648e4ebe877997970e6f3335"><enum>(3)</enum><text>administer the Program by—</text><subparagraph id="idf3c1ca95e55c418595c46999a3a6aba1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtaining data in furtherance of this section only when demonstrably cost effective and meeting or exceeding data quality standards available to the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d3b7f8c689a4c84961d9a8164c8e463"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the requirement in subparagraph (A), leveraging existing networks of environmental monitoring stations, including supplemental radar systems, to increase the quantity and density of environmental observations and data available to the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4710fa17a4804ad59598ddf9842bb1e7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing the critical technical and administrative infrastructure needed to facilitate rapid integration and sustained use of new and emerging networks of environmental monitoring stations anticipated in coming years from non-Federal Government sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6f97dfc973d4b5dbb3de28e65fcfd9e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coordinating with existing data developed by the Administration and used for forecasts, including data from the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service, the Integrated Ocean Observing System, the Global Ocean Monitoring and Observing Program, the National Data Buoy Center, and the National Ocean Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29a26c87371f4be8b17b0bf7de29f4ae"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifying and communicating to the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and other partners priorities of research and development needed to advance observations in the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id65b03520c86a4358bbf07d5586d53d55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial and technical assistance</header><paragraph id="idd661b9a977304226a7f658c998a8453b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the Program, in a fiscal year, the Under Secretary may award not less than 15 percent of the amount appropriated for the Program for that fiscal year for financial assistance to State, Tribal, private, and academic entities seeking to build, expand, or upgrade equipment and capacity of mesonet systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6129df1d5f6e42b09183abaa02759983"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other Federal awards</header><text>Financial assistance under this subsection may be made in coordination with and in addition to awards from other Federal agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69d4446ef8f3406bb1ac131b1be1d4eb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>Before receiving financial assistance under paragraph (1), the State, Tribal, private, or academic entity seeking financial assistance under this subsection shall enter into an agreement with the Under Secretary to provide data to the Program, subject to verification by the Program of the relative operational value and evaluation of the cost of such data, for use in weather prediction, severe weather warnings, and emergency response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51c88d9c9e4143c9bc4714d3ca120b24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance and other support</header><text>The Under Secretary may provide—</text><subparagraph id="id946a352d3940491b9f61c535087b18d9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>technical assistance, project implementation support, and guidance to State, Tribal, private, and academic entities seeking financial assistance under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id619fcd85ad134805854892ea512f3287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technical and financial assistance for maintenance of monitoring stations in underrepresented or remote areas of the country where it is financially unfeasible for one entity to operate such stations without such assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2290817bb7bd4960a0ccdd8de2155adb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>In providing financial assistance under this subsection, the Under Secretary shall establish terms to ensure that each State, Tribal, private, or academic entity that receives financial assistance under this subsection receives a level of support commensurate with the quality and other characteristics of the data to be provided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a4db707b5df4482a4d6d725b4caff5f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>A State, Tribal, private, or academic entity may only receive financial assistance under this subsection if the Under Secretary determines such entity will provide sufficient financial support from non-Federal Government sources and fully maintain the quality of the mesonet system and associated data standards required by the Program for a period of not less than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78914363c09948aba8c10675e5972cf9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Under Secretary shall prioritize providing assistance under paragraph (1) to not fewer than one entity in a remote area or an area that has a lack of environmental monitoring stations described in subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31e9b3cff2be4bf78985aa7d5924f3ae"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><paragraph id="idf30db78dee334366a4440ae61846e976"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall ensure the Program has an active advisory committee of subject matter experts to make recommendations to the Administration on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c53d9d330ef4ef7a22cc3c92212e901"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the identification, implementation, procurement, and tracking of data needed to supplement the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e96dc684e36413baff65ea8042e48fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements, expansions, and acquisitions of available data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb51f1f97a0b4966ac2d2bfcd11f6f2d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of existing committee</header><text>The Under Secretary may designate an existing advisory committee, subcommittee, or working group of the Federal Government, including the Science Advisory Board of the Administration, to carry out the requirement under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideba673985eff4eecb7c3ec4b38a0aabf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Academic expertise</header><text>The advisory committee under paragraph (1), in consultation with the Program, shall include expertise from one or more institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) to assist the advisory committee to identify, evaluate, and recommend potential partnerships, regional or subregional consortia, and collaborative methods that would expand the number of participants and volume of data in the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5616736d964247beb793d09e5988f0c9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regular briefings</header><paragraph id="id3c38cb6c51cb406e8ed6f1f09deee379"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than annually through 2035, and not later than June 30 of each year, the Under Secretary shall provide regular briefings to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives on all activities under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb86cad96c4494acdb313feb051e15bb9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing content</header><text>Each briefing required under paragraph (1) shall include information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="idcc6d1895f6884a29b56777273869d896"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Efforts to implement the activities described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ef722c262364a1cb62806733914d65e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any financial or technical assistance provided pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id922c1e02d66a42ec9135ae942bcbaadc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Efforts to address recommendations received from the advisory committee under subsection (d), if any.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd59e8372fa3f4ae0b6a10545bca937d4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The potential need and associated benefits of a coastal and ocean mesonet, or other emerging areas of weather data needs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde68641e58c44dea94e9ee281fa736b6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Progress toward eliminating gaps in weather observation data in States and regions of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94aec0c28b50404e84f4f68a468b6866"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other topic the Under Secretary determines relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA28AD095B2C840808E1998904D0D51BF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf3c8ed0bc6944eab993b8d3f7c87a45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Seasonal, State, subseasonal, Under Secretary, weather enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>seasonal</term>, <term>State</term>, <term>subseasonal</term>, <term>Under Secretary</term>, and <term>weather enterprise</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H774EBD4FD4E44646B8AD3D207671DD9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Weather data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>weather data</term> means information used to track and predict weather conditions and patterns, including forecasts, observations, and derivative products from such information. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2e556d195cb94bbeb92f009b3b27face"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>From amounts authorized to be appropriated to the National Weather Service, there shall be available not more than the following amounts to carry out this section:</text><paragraph id="id7e46d8124fc745a5a96569f40ce9515a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd77c53e325d9492f8ed0990409aa4113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$55,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide12206d6f7214629954448a4f2757cc9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$61,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3917c19625043a58eb5184e5a2ae184"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$68,000,000 for fiscal year 2028.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a24267f7f454d15be16e52c00e9c7f8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$70,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

