<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC1C4109D52E0441A956396BCEFBD4B24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4607 IH: Samaritan Efforts to Ensure Key Health Emergency and Life-saving Protections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide protections from prosecution for drug possession to individuals who seek medical assistance when witnessing or experiencing an overdose, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFDCBD4B573844E179F50CB3F5AEA0A7A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFB67381163C04BF0A61CB353CE657A3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Samaritan Efforts to Ensure Key Health Emergency and Life-saving Protections Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SEEK HELP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE80954C80DE7488BB90E8153B043D33B"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1D2524A976B4EEAAF2292AE333DBE9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD62A24225834C9C92AA6EC5905BC0B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>emergency response providers</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF14763DCCA44F9487BF1D89116F4C30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>opioid overdose reversal drug</term> means a drug approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C992A3FB5F545AAA23FB19878D6A065"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is indicated for the partial or complete reversal of the pharmacological effects of an opioid overdose in the human body; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DF1962573E94EA7A4E559C8204A1289"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has moved in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H393408FA8BAA444BA13308321DA74CD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDF0EACD824D4E5691D075E5AD308CE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>seek medical assistance</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC465848F2DD14DE3913B4197E06889B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting a drug overdose or other medical emergency to a law enforcement authority, an emergency response provider, the 9–1–1 system, a poison control center, or a medical or drug treatment provider; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA578F0B21F76424EAE24A86BC3462DDC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting another individual who is making a report described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0B11CB676B014EE3A4C5D53CC313E944"><enum>3.</enum><header>Good Samaritan protections for drug overdose responses</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDA7979FB7D94B7FA055541565BBB63C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil liability protections for administration of opioid overdose reversal drugs</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB79C617801474354B72AD0CF0390CBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual shall not be liable in a civil action in a Federal or State court for harm caused by the emergency administration of an opioid overdose reversal drug to another individual who is or reasonably appears to be suffering a drug overdose if the individual administers the opioid overdose reversal drug in good faith.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC55D8A5FB4F42A5B025969B5D9195AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to harm caused by willful or criminal misconduct, gross negligence, reckless misconduct, or a conscious, flagrant indifference to the rights or safety of the victim who was harmed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FBB0CC2F382494C9D5207E4B07E2620"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>With respect to a person who administers an opioid overdose reversal drug to another individual, this section supersedes the law of a State only to the extent that the State has no statute or regulation that provides such a person with immunity in a civil action for the use of an opioid overdose reversal drug, as described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CA2F0A2396A4635AB500F319D9F3456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal liability protections for seeking medical assistance for an overdose</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4EA3A7ACC9C4A9EB8253A327270CE17"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BF6C31EA05345DAA872D5E7C419E93F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in good faith and a timely manner—</text> <clause id="HB17098663933497C8500717B9F3CFFA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seeks medical assistance for an individual experiencing or reasonably appears to be experiencing a drug overdose; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H172A56A802D44905A71EC6EFCF292CC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seeks medical assistance for himself or herself for a drug overdose; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DF1A1B648534A51810CC818A205396F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>did not seek the medical assistance during the course of the execution of an arrest warrant, search warrant, or other lawful search or seizure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34532DAD624D48F19864927D7595F9EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Liability protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual shall not be subject to prosecution, civil asset forfeiture, or revocation of supervised released under section 404 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/844">21 U.S.C. 844</external-xref>) for possession of a controlled substance if a law enforcement agency, or other government agency, is made aware of the possession solely based on the fact that the covered individual sought medical assistance as described in clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE55FCB257A9348019CCA5406F629198E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Admissibility and seizure of evidence or contraband</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF91E6E0089DC4C3BAEC7EF3C101F895C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the admissibility of evidence in connection with the prosecution of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D6051CC11144A258EE8786DDF28F532"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense with regard to an individual who does not qualify for the protections under paragraph (2); or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE983D437AB8C427AA2EF43713321D521"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense not described in paragraph (2) that is committed by an individual who qualifies for the protections under such paragraph;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35BD614D57EB4363804A2C966E6C36BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit any seizure of evidence or contraband otherwise permitted by law; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF676C8D2CFCD479A9B7EA299D2FEA515"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the arrest of the individual or search and seizure of any evidence or contraband if there is an outstanding State or Federal warrant for the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDD055EFAD3DF4C1A9F5183275F457F1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public awareness campaign</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, shall carry out a public awareness campaign regarding the liability protections under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H044DB071236D42A9935CB1B068F5B1AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of JAG funds</header><text>Section 501(a)(1) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10152">34 U.S.C. 10152(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3445D1A1837542B49F9B7F73BF3CA5D3"> <subparagraph id="H1F85F6DF581249128CA1A8DF59D15067"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Training programs for law enforcement officers of States and units of local government regarding legal protections for individuals seeking medical assistance in connection with a controlled substance overdose.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF4D6C40445874CE9AE698642FF48148E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of block grant funding for public awareness campaigns and initiatives</header> 
<subsection id="H379B2C76FC894384B05953B5A75937E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State receiving a grant under section 1921 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21</external-xref>) may use amounts described in section 1922(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-22">42 U.S.C. 300x–22(a)(1)</external-xref>) to—</text> <paragraph id="H17D28967601142B8B1C2EAB3C370CC67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a public awareness campaign regarding the overdose Good Samaritan law of the State;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77C9C9655312453D8E5F74B1DB564FF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training to criminal justice professionals, stakeholders (including health care providers), emergency medical service providers, and the general public on applicable overdose Good Samaritan laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CC45CA815EC429A97101398ABA2AE1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the extent possible, share data with the Secretary regarding the impact of overdose Good Samaritan laws of the State on individuals experiencing an overdose, which shall include the number of calls seeking medical assistance that were received by a law enforcement agency, the 9–1–1 system, a poison control center, or a medical or drug treatment providers for seeking medical assistance in the event of a drug overdose.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E1C7494829844679506BEBD87F49B66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>overdose Good Samaritan law</term> means a statute providing protection from liability relating to seeking medical assistance in connection with a controlled substance overdose or administering an opioid overdose reversal drug.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1C35673C3D464AAE896D838CD05C287A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO report to study effectiveness and implementation</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A871E5D68DE47B88B798BF1FB780B79"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on evaluating the implementation of Good Samaritan laws for drug overdose and the effectiveness of grant funding provided to States and localities for awareness campaigns related to those laws.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6793E3E3069B4FBABA2B303CE585331A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88C5540E344D4612AAD89EF66AAECB01"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the extent to which States and localities have implemented and enforced Good Samaritan laws for drug overdose;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CC0CB5C4AA44A23B5F008FD1A7882EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the effectiveness of the laws described in paragraph (1) in encouraging the reporting of overdoses and the provision of timely medical assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD64137C4C7DA4E599D0FF042BE9891DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of the number of individuals impacted by the laws described in paragraph (1), including the number of individuals who have received legal protections or immunities under such laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C7DA40BA5C438BAA6349E21BDBB4EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyze the impact of the laws described in paragraph (1), including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H773970CEC3A54D2DA7C3A6188A465FDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of changes in overdose-related fatalities, emergency department visits, and the use of naloxone or other overdose reversal interventions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H364FCCD350234AF1954E0B4F3C491476"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data on the number of calls received for overdoses before and after the implementation of such laws;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ACE6E85748D4C60B0A67B75BB9EB497"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the effectiveness of grant funding provided to States and localities for the purpose of spreading awareness about the laws described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31681C524C7942BA9E1978CDC6DED07F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the reach and impact of educational campaigns, community outreach initiatives, and training programs aimed at informing the public, healthcare providers, law enforcement personnel, and other relevant stakeholders about the protections and benefits provided by the laws described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7252486D3AB647C3A0A758CC1E18AE53"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify any barriers or challenges encountered during the implementation of the laws described in paragraph (1) and associated awareness campaigns, including—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76DB618896704E8681FB1AC69F98B571"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examining the legal, logistical, resource-related, or cultural factors that may impede successful adoption and utilization of the laws; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12188245B8A74F829F933B818FB84319"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exploring any challenges faced by individuals seeking help or reporting overdoses due to potential legal repercussions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H741BF8D831F74365A3BF41C9F13C9C03"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">highlight any best practices identified in States and localities that have effectively implemented the laws described in paragraph (1) and conducted successful awareness campaigns, including recommendations on best methods for assessing and evaluating the implementation and success for Good Samaritan laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4434B9EC63BA4EDF89CDAABD291B0D04"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recommendations for improving the implementation and impact of the laws described in paragraph (1) and optimizing the use of grant funding for education and outreach efforts; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB663733A242B4D09AAA9C1DC61B3343C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>if multiple States or localities have implemented different variations of the laws described in paragraph (1), include a comparative analysis of their respective approaches identifying variations in outcomes, effectiveness, or challenges faced and providing insights for potential improvements or standardization of the laws.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBC20E5CF2AE445FF8DAD2A41DF7D667E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperation and access</header><text>Federal agencies and relevant State and local authorities shall cooperate with the Comptroller General of the United States and provide access to necessary information and data to facilitate the completion of the report required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

