<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25194-32C-Y1-S18"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 142 ATS: Recognizing the heritage, culture, and contributions of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 142</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the heritage, culture, and contributions of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States celebrates National Women’s History Month every March to recognize and honor the achievements of women throughout the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas approximately 5,300,000 American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women, alone or in combination, live in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women—</text><paragraph id="id1e02f56e0b6b47cbb275733e5c3f6e17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have helped shape the history of their communities, Tribes, and the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0204f321a28445e0926e35bc874dc597"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have fought to defend and protect the sovereign rights of Native Nations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9a53f14abe04dab9a1fc8cf95036af0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have demonstrated resilience and courage in the face of a history of threatened existence, constant removals, and relocations;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women contribute to their communities, Tribes, and the United States through military service, public service, and work in many industries, including business, education, science, medicine, literature, and fine arts, including Pablita <quote>Tse Tsan</quote> Velarde, a Santa Clara Pueblo artist and painter whose art work depicted traditional Pueblo life and preserved Pueblo stories and knowledge, and whose paintings were commissioned for display at Bandelier National Monument;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2025, more than 4,400 American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women are bravely serving as members of the Armed Forces of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2025, more than 43,000 American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women, alone or in combination, are veterans who made lasting contributions to the Armed Forces of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women broke down historical gender barriers to enlistment in the military, including—</text><paragraph id="id6ba8dc914bc94b7388a6c32ab82afd34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Laura Beltz Wright, an Inupiat Eskimo sharpshooter of the Alaska Territorial Guard during World War II;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8141a68dc0f443d8b05e73997fd0c0c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Minnie Spotted Wolf of the Blackfeet Tribe, the first Native American woman to enlist in the United States Marine Corps in 1943; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15d24ef4c22d472e9dc7585dcc573914"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Marcella LeBeau of the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe, a decorated veteran who served as an Army combat nurse during World War II and received the French Legion of Honour for her bravery and service;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have made the ultimate sacrifice for the United States, including Lori Ann Piestewa, a member of the Hopi Tribe who was the first Native American woman to be killed in action while serving on foreign soil and the first woman serving in the Armed Forces of the United States to be killed in the Iraq War in 2003;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have contributed to the economic development of Native Nations and the United States as a whole, including Elouise Cobell of the Blackfeet Tribe, a recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom, who—</text><paragraph id="ideca4dc12a46a4a8fb78fddcb2b6914d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>served as the treasurer of the Blackfeet Tribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id38022bf2d96d48dc82255462f3773509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>founded the first Tribal-owned national bank; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7a646089dac4998bad999b23743074a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>led the fight against Federal mismanagement of funds held in trust for more than 500,000 Native Americans;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2024, more than 11,600 American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women owned an employing business;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2024, Native women-owned businesses employed more than 72,000 workers and generated more than $11,200,000,000 in revenue;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2019, American Indian and Alaska Native women have opened a net average of 30 new employing businesses per day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have made significant contributions to the fields of medicine and health, including—</text><paragraph id="idc8a8f0eaef4b4d7b8d407d45d447e505"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Susan La Flesche Picotte of the Omaha Tribe, who is widely acknowledged as the first Native American to earn a medical degree; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c9b86be2c04420ba195ffa08be9b420"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Annie Dodge Wauneka of the Navajo Nation, who—</text><subparagraph id="idd820fe7d038940a58a8578d5b6465514"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advocated for better public health, education, and living conditions on the Navajo Nation leading to her becoming 1 of the first female council members for the Navajo Nation in 1951; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86f25cb587fa4510a06e050e4fc9876b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was the first Native American to receive a Presidential Medal of Freedom in 1963;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have contributed to important scientific advancements, including—</text><paragraph id="idf7d4e9432e1449de9e426fbbd8ec3e7a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Floy Agnes Lee of the Santa Clara Pueblo, who—</text><subparagraph id="id23fd305bcea04166b23e934b20000643"><enum>(A)</enum><text>worked on the Manhattan Project during World War II; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id890060664b2f4a47b660ce3064e50e65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pioneered research on radiation biology and cancer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6326995758cc44729c47e0030bb7f0b8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian Isabella Kauakea Yau Yung Aiona Abbott, who—</text><subparagraph id="idfe1d9c04ac5048099f3cdc03f44dd674"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was the first woman on the biological sciences faculty at Stanford University; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2aeed6bd33f43bd801a5c445f35274d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in 1997, was awarded the Gilbert Morgan Smith medal, the highest award in marine botany from the National Academy of Sciences; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7970c2113e5a42e29bf353da2d97f887"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mary Golda Ross of the Cherokee Nation, who—</text><subparagraph id="id93f1c651da2a48e799ed931d4cf70340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is considered the first Native American engineer of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8effd95e39184c99b8dd066cec6edfdb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>helped develop spacecrafts for the Gemini and Apollo space programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd2fc5e6ab5545e392bad541cfcfdc30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was recognized by the Federal Government on the 2019 1 dollar coin honoring Native Americans and their contributions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have achieved distinctive honors in the art of dance, including Maria Tallchief or Wa-Xthe-Thon-ba of the Osage Nation, who—</text><paragraph id="idf11aabfa811e4463be1813bf3dadbd22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was the first major prima ballerina of the United States and was a recipient of a Lifetime Achievement Award from the Kennedy Center; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef99006c546d4631913a7759ed85f4e0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was recognized by the Federal Government on the 2023 1 dollar coin with her sister Marjorie Tallchief of the Osage Nation, Yvonne Chouteau of the Shawnee Tribe, Rosella Hightower of the Choctaw Nation, and Moscelyne Larkin of the Eastern Shawnee Tribe of Oklahoma and the Peoria Tribe of Indians of Oklahoma, collectively known as the <quote>Five Moons</quote>, for the legacy they left on ballet;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have accomplished notable literary achievements, including Northern Paiute author Sarah Winnemucca Hopkins, who wrote and published 1 of the first Native American autobiographies in United States history in 1883;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have regularly led efforts to protect their traditional ways of life and to revitalize and maintain Native cultures and languages, including—</text><paragraph id="id9be5627e76864431bac7ee6c1885a1a7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Esther Martinez, a Tewa linguist and teacher who developed a Tewa dictionary and was credited with revitalizing the Tewa language;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5c579e7bc694561858a3dec1dc604a1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mary Kawena Pukui, a Native Hawaiian scholar who published more than 50 academic works and was considered the most noted Hawaiian translator of the 20th century;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida77e364b76f84faeb39e4ca599f4f66b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Katie John, an Ahtna Athabascan of Mentasta Lake, who was the lead plaintiff in lawsuits that strengthened Native subsistence fishing rights in Alaska and who helped create the alphabet for the Ahtna language;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcaa1150e823c434691e40666ef5c33a1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Edith Kenao Kanaka‘ole, a Native Hawaiian language and cultural practitioner who—</text><subparagraph id="idc5578072cd3548baa3542cc9329570b8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>founded her own hula school, Hālau o Kekuhi;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdecd63d314247648199b59e30366deb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>helped develop some of the first courses in Hawaiian language and culture for public schools and colleges; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc126e1f70dfa4591b7ed3d036ab423f0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was recognized by the Federal Government on the 2023 quarter honoring her significant contributions and accomplishments perpetuating Native Hawaiian culture and arts; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6330399a776f48faa6eb5700b381fbbe"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Dr. Gladys Iola Tantaquidgeon, a Mohegan medicine woman and anthropologist, who worked for 50 years at the Tantaquidgeon Indian Museum in Connecticut, the oldest Native American owned and operated museum in the United States, which she founded with her father and brother to preserve the culture and history of their Tribe, and which contributed to the Tribe's Federal recognition in 1994;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have excelled in athletic competition and created opportunities for other female athletes within their sport, including Rell Kapoliokaehukai Sunn, who—</text><paragraph id="id6b3cb15fcf2e48939bdb4070759f792b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was ranked as longboard surfing champion of the world; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc69fa00c5f3040f8ae9569e5676a5e8d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>co-founded the Women’s Professional Surfing Association in 1975, the first professional surfing tour for women;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have played a vital role in advancing civil rights, protecting human rights, advocating for land rights, and safeguarding the environment, including—</text><paragraph id="idb58ca31c3ec54d41a57cda6f94badda0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Elizabeth Wanamaker Peratrovich, Tlingit, a member of the Lukaax̲.ádi clan in the Raven moiety with the Tlingit name of K̲aax̲gal.aat, who—</text><subparagraph id="id1375197d8a224ff994d7346c6185edcf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>helped secure the passage of House Bill 14, commonly known as the Anti-Discrimination Act of 1945 (H.B. 14, Laws of Alaska. 17th Regular Session, Territorial Legislature. Feb. 16, 1945), in the Alaska Territorial Legislature, the first anti-discrimination law in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2dc4fb2c46d740e0987f811f3d06f8b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was recognized by the Federal Government on the 2020 1 dollar coin honoring Native Americans and their contributions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide59c2de093394f589b5216fd00e05b0c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Zitkala-Sa, a Yankton Dakota writer and advocate, whose work during the early 20th century helped advance the citizenship, voting, and land rights of Native Americans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3a9d38e95ba436ebdd4bf0aba43c9c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mary Jane Fate, of the Koyukon Athabascan village of Rampart, who—</text><subparagraph id="idd36b2abe6e6b4a5ebf6eff3b82fa7dc3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was the first woman to chair the Alaska Federation of Natives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a012abf175b4316a551ebf8d9bf480c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was a founding member of the North American Indian Women's Association; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf97034438dc449aeb65bcbf8ed8e6bcf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was an advocate for settlement of Indigenous land claims in Alaska;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have succeeded as judges, attorneys, and legal advocates, including—</text><paragraph id="id214e6922d2684bd5844352d88ba3a985"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Eliza <quote>Lyda</quote> Conley, a Wyandot-American lawyer and the first Native woman admitted to argue a case before the Supreme Court of the United States in 1909; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida73cc998f07e47c289ffaacb646450f7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Emma Kailikapiolono Metcalf Beckley Nakuina, a Native Hawaiian who served as the first female judge in Hawaii;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women are dedicated public servants, holding important positions in the Federal judicial branch, the Federal executive branch, State governments, and local governments;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian and Alaska Native women have served as remarkable Tribal councilwomen, Tribal court judges, and Tribal leaders, including Wilma Mankiller, who—</text><paragraph id="idebb612b266b14588a3a26fd87b50fcda"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was the first woman elected to serve as Principal Chief of the Cherokee Nation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a5ac46a98124d2695bdcf7e0a137ccc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fought for Tribal self-determination and the improvement of the community infrastructure of her Tribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd74b530ac33843fe9811678f814e86c2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>was recognized by the Federal Government on the 2022 quarter honoring her legacy of leadership for Native people and women;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women have also led Native peoples through notable acts of public service, including—</text><paragraph id="idc1fb3172e4074a0aacd86ad89dc79828"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Kaahumanu, who was the first Native Hawaiian woman to serve as regent of the Kingdom of Hawaii; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id215ecc968dd247b2bc8e572d3c20bea3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Polly Cooper, of the Oneida Indian Nation, who—</text><subparagraph id="id0fc423fb507341c287848fe536e8297b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>walked from central New York to Valley Forge as part of a relief mission to provide food for the Army led by General George Washington during the American Revolutionary War; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28d484ec6f9945bebe1474317b85df75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was recognized for her courage and generosity by Martha Washington;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States should continue to invest in the future of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women to address the barriers those women face, including—</text><paragraph id="id8ed85e4a539f49d69ca2a6efe87b1296"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access to justice;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb25c29319e814fe2bfd841e969e47a2c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>access to health care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc431c988bc474cc1b5cdf7e97a1343c9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>opportunities for educational and economic advancement; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women are the life givers, the culture bearers, and the caretakers of Native peoples who have made precious contributions, enriching the lives of all people of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id6a180960ab214455858e5f4d04a7e985"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates and honors the successes of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women and the contributions those women have made and continue to make to the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida25216f16226423b9173dff2dbc6e989"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of providing for the safety and upholding the interests of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian women. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

