<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BB6D1AE2FD34B4C8654FE214661A789" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2904 IH: Pursuing Equity in Mental Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address mental health issues for youth, particularly youth of color, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE4342C9177F0425FA341B7E9F85021B2" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4DB088764EF9492AAE337FFF2EC91BE2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pursuing Equity in Mental Health Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H182DB0D0CF3047E48C567EAAB43643BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Primary and Behavioral Health Care grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520K of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-42">42 U.S.C. 290bb–42</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0A8DC53B548549CCBF26ED3AB4C0D502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) through (i) as subsections (e) through (j), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AECCC05F71E4966B8836AF78621D850"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44013E4F6EED455486F2F313DDAC558B"><subsection id="H5DE562C8DBEA48B1AB1B4E069F5AEA15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special consideration regarding services for racial and ethnic minority groups</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under subsection (b), the Secretary may, as appropriate, give special consideration to eligible entities serving a high proportion of racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H88D2258699FF433C87771E45074BC07F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(G), by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB354500D5F9549EDA788DB787F74CA48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (i) (as redesignated by paragraph (1))—</text><subparagraph id="HD3C182B05B1B41D687BA767DFA5A500F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H053122E0EABA43C48338A09B4BDE86EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (d)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(2)</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86B7EA52A4234268BE936DBE9F52A472"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)), by striking <quote>$60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027</quote> and inserting <quote>$60,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and $80,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031</quote>. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H5BD690DD1DF0443399A3B0F4D6119492"><enum>3.</enum><header>Addressing racial and ethnic minority mental health disparities research gaps</header><subsection id="H14D5954CC34E4FF8BA97BF8563B8616E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, the Director of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities, and the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall seek to enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or, if the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine decline to enter into such an arrangement, the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute or another appropriate entity) under which the National Academies (or such other appropriate entity, as the case may be) agrees— </text><paragraph id="HA15E1D8EB9924F55A875090288CAB839"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct a study with respect to mental health disparities research gaps in racial and ethnic minority groups (as defined in section 1707(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E1C4B429DB4F8285B6F9AA77D47F4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to submit to Congress a report on the results of such study, including—</text><subparagraph id="H33DAB83116414B2E86575C65FAB8A233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a compilation of information on the prevalence of mental health outcomes in such racial and ethnic minority groups; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D569610AF7E40BCA9E919CDBE26C31F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of information on the impact of exposure to community violence, adverse childhood experiences, structural bias, and other psychological traumas on mental health outcomes in such racial and minority groups; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E0C9F00706849CA820EBA11219483B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a selection of potential recommendations that can remedy the research gap in such racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA93DBE8587D44302A17F8BB6D810D6E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report conducted by AHRQ</header><text>If no arrangement can be made with an entity specified in subsection (a), the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall conduct the study and submit the report, as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of such subsection.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3712739559E341AB83B327D690A50AC5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Health professions competencies to address racial and ethnic minority mental health disparities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 597 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ll">42 U.S.C. 290ll</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H91EC6195349843F58783D98963EC8D51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7758FF7789EB4DA29695FA530C670334"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C2BD2CF061E4299A45A2D8C62855F14"><subsection id="HA54EBB545CB0410D826BFC0334D2C143"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices; core competencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual receiving a fellowship under subsection (a), or an entity selected by the Assistant Secretary to administer the program under this section, may use amounts awarded under this section to engage in the following activities related to the development and dissemination of best practices or core competencies addressing mental health disparities among racial and ethnic minority groups for use in the training of students in the professions of social work, psychology, psychiatry, addiction medicine, marriage and family therapy, mental health counseling, and substance misuse counseling:</text><paragraph id="H0809D9FC544C45188271E2651C559051"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Formation of committees or working groups comprised of experts from accredited health professions schools to identify best practices and core competencies relating to mental health disparities among racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B8D554555A04E8C958C93420D1AD6A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Planning of workshops in national fora to allow for public input into the educational needs associated with mental health disparities among racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56CEE7626E424AA5A28548345817E8EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Dissemination and promotion of the use of best practices or core competencies in undergraduate and graduate health professions training programs nationwide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FEF541A0C5E46F48CB781D17CE74EEB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Establishing external advisory boards to provide meaningful input into policy and program development and best practices to reduce mental health disparities among racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H789D7CF22A424492BBCBA7FCBAF405FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>2027</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H177A1367A10A4272BE15081E504D1299"><enum>5.</enum><header>Racial and ethnic minority behavioral and mental health outreach and education strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 553 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ee-10">42 U.S.C. 290ee–10</external-xref>) of such Act the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H22783F8D52814510824E13B9497DE373"><section id="HFC62044D44C54B148FE74DD7C047A47E"><enum>554.</enum><header>Behavioral and mental health outreach and education strategy</header><subsection id="H194945B8C68645F9A03DE18F7B9E5330"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with advocacy and behavioral and mental health organizations serving racial and ethnic minority groups, develop and implement an outreach and education strategy to promote behavioral and mental health and reduce stigma associated with mental health conditions and substance use among racial and ethnic minority groups. Such strategy shall—</text><paragraph id="H4C30FF5CB2F54527818458E4441D0BD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be designed to—</text><subparagraph id="H35A905A1CEFF42E38A2835DAB77858D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the diverse cultural and language needs of the various racial and ethnic minority groups; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59BEDBC9CAD14E00A2AC40E36CBD0486"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be developmentally and age-appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H835E477451C24B8E8780E7D4A75C8237"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase awareness of symptoms of mental illnesses common among such groups, taking into account differences within at-risk subgroups;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAEDE14464574FE98B4F947B80AB3F5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide information on evidence-based, culturally and linguistically appropriate and adapted interventions and treatments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF18132AA274BAD8353AA19661F5168"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure full participation of, and engage, both individuals receiving behavioral and mental health services and other community members, which may include adolescents and young adults, in the development and implementation of materials; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADB6C4BC482943B1A93D115A6CDE9655"><enum>(5)</enum><text>seek to broaden the perspective among both individuals in racial and ethnic minority groups and communities serving such groups to use a comprehensive and integrated public health approach to promoting behavioral health by focusing on the intersection between behavioral and physical health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2774655441654C7689D4799621737562"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on the extent to which the strategy developed and implemented under subsection (a) addressed behavioral and mental health outcomes associated with mental health conditions and substance use among racial and ethnic minority groups.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC4947096576542A5A81920978C0AA5E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>racial and ethnic minority group</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 1707(g).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2CAEC8F3D33741188D5E5056F9B23963"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC03DE6CBC2084BBCAEEAF283B326113B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Additional funds for National Institutes of Health</header><subsection id="HB372ADF0E56F4B84AB3244F2B304A592"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated to the National Institutes of Health, there is authorized to be appropriated to such Institutes $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to—</text><paragraph id="H7F456F610F2C446EA2C9AD87468DFA6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>build relations with communities and conduct or support clinical research, including clinical research on racial or ethnic disparities in physical and mental health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4CA17E069EA41C58EAEC4D7F567E601"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out the Strategic Framework For Addressing Youth Mental Health Disparities developed by the National Institute of Mental Health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A293F4A55864F6C862E2EE15F634AEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>clinical research</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 409 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284d">42 U.S.C. 284d</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HDE9EDE96A606450296598007C72C467A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional funds for National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities, there is authorized to be appropriated to such Institute $750,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

