<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3D8E300227E14239B0FCEF79374FACBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4437 IH: Supervisory Modifications for Appropriate Risk-based Testing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4437</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce the regulatory burden on certain well managed and well capitalized financial institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A1178093B554001A99FD99FECC16822" style="OLC"><section id="HA2F4058DC9D54B698DE4BE6C73FBA280" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supervisory Modifications for Appropriate Risk-based Testing Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H63D105FEB90B43908CB32A852BD7F740"><enum>2.</enum><header>Examination relief for certain well managed and well capitalized financial institutions</header><subsection id="HC37FA69AA2404B3CA318E18BC8DB1921"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Insured depository institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10(d) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820">12 U.S.C. 1820(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8524BB33311444C6B13222CEBB8EDF5F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H37439481C9584851831FC8ACE453650A"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Examination relief for certain well managed and well capitalized insured depository institutions</header><subparagraph id="HDF42340FD01C4E01A8F1D4414423E31E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following shall apply to a well managed and well capitalized insured depository institution with $6,000,000,000 or less in consolidated assets:</text><clause id="H3A397859F27A46629A3E32BB5E745EE4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Alternating limited-scope examinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After an insured depository institution receives a full-scope, on-site examination from the appropriate Federal banking agency, the next examination of the insured depository institution by the appropriate Federal banking agency shall be a limited-scope examination, as determined by the appropriate Federal banking agency.</text></clause><clause id="H0E78EB8A42C64A939AB95FE367843A4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Combined examinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an insured depository institution is otherwise subject to separate safety and soundness examinations, consumer compliance examinations, and information technology and cybersecurity examinations, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall, upon request of the insured depository institution, combine two or three such examinations, as specified by the insured depository institution, and carry them out at the same time.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA211D99AE284D649CCDAF311D5A825C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an insured depository institution if—</text><clause id="HD33FE71C994C45FF92E2AD962C735457" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the insured depository institution is currently subject to a formal enforcement proceeding or order by the Corporation or the appropriate Federal banking agency; or</text></clause><clause id="H5182D5F6616A415787D85C80FD9FCCAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person acquired control of the insured depository institution since the most recent full-scope, on-site examination of the insured depository institution from the appropriate Federal banking agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6311765D422D40D7862DED502F5AD695"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Federal banking agencies shall issue rules to carry out subparagraph (A), including, with respect to an insured depository institution described under subparagraph (A), to—</text><clause id="HCA2B4880A02C480BA5E3CD08428972CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish procedures for the limited-scope examinations described in subparagraph (A)(i);</text></clause><clause id="H8F2D21EC588047A593A39A3BD76574B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish procedures for reviewing insured depository institutions that—</text><subclause id="H65E322CB25F947BFAFC6DE32951DD76C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>experience material changes in financial condition or operational risk profile between scheduled examinations; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7B37FF28608B4E7CBDEFF60B241C1B09"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have failed to comply with Federal or State banking laws and regulations; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0A2BCA868D504EFBADE52E5A5D265B02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">balance the goals of streamlining the examination cycle for individual insured depository institutions and reducing unnecessary regulatory burdens while maintaining sufficient oversight to ensure the continued safety and soundness of the insured depository institutions and compliance with all applicable laws and regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD12EDB22174ACAB6E5A6206B91366C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to limit the authority of a Federal banking agency to conduct off-site monitoring, targeted reviews, or additional full-scope, on-site examinations of an insured depository institution if the Federal banking agency determines such monitoring, reviews, or examinations are necessary to ensure safety and soundness or compliance with applicable laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H181B10D129F4425A8A28743C012E6AAA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H72FFACB580344E1CB067571EE395EF86"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consumer compliance examination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>consumer compliance examination</quote> means an examination to assess compliance with the requirements of Federal consumer financial law (as such term is defined in section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010).</text></clause><clause id="H55559E1F2CA44AAA813B39B7B2F72E1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Well capitalized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>well capitalized</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 38(b).</text></clause><clause id="HD768D2A817AF45EE86F661098C85400E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Well managed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an insured depository institution, the term <quote>well managed</quote> means that, when the institution was most recently examined by the appropriate Federal banking agency, the institution was found to be well managed, and the institution’s composite condition was found to be satisfactory or outstanding.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0ACB61A18E504A2399C5421AA55505C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insured credit unions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 204 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1784">12 U.S.C. 1784</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9681C77A65FD4A689DCD7960C623FBD1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H92C152D00BE64EDDA7613C47065F964C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Examination relief for certain well managed and well capitalized insured credit unions</header><paragraph id="H77BFCE4CD1C14D029638921615C52C63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following shall apply to a well managed and well capitalized insured credit union with $6,000,000,000 or less in consolidated assets:</text><subparagraph id="HAEAEAC4F298C4C43A0A4B3234AFD6EAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Alternating limited-scope examinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After an insured credit union receives a full-scope, on-site examination from the National Credit Union Administration, the next examination of the insured credit union by the National Credit Union Administration shall be a limited-scope examination, as determined by the National Credit Union Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DF0BE4BFA034A84A8C1C66BA9F7DA38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Combined examinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an insured credit union is otherwise subject to separate safety and soundness examinations, consumer compliance examinations, and information technology and cybersecurity examinations, the National Credit Union Administration shall, upon request of the insured credit union, combine two or three such examinations, as specified by the insured credit union, and carry them out at the same time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6A289A00DDF4227BE9B14436E3D804D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an insured credit union if the insured credit union is currently subject to a formal enforcement proceeding or order by the National Credit Union Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22DA0A5A059D4D14AB92B4DC10EDD30A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the National Credit Union Administration shall issue rules to carry out paragraph (1), including, with respect to an insured credit union described under paragraph (1), to—</text><subparagraph id="HEEFD983D87A04529BEAF151D50210032"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish procedures for the limited-scope examinations described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1A3B84B15B3449BA56BD72758213531"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish procedures for reviewing insured credit unions that—</text><clause id="H0A31DD055879418EAC4BA0E48B6CAAB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>experience material changes in financial condition or operational risk profile between scheduled examinations; or</text></clause><clause id="H2E07B7D7894E4AD1A9EAB4CD778B9AD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have failed to comply with Federal or State banking laws and regulations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFA636279BB84558A4BA3DA8A09A4CDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">balance the goals of streamlining the examination cycle for individual insured credit unions and reducing unnecessary regulatory burdens while maintaining sufficient oversight to ensure the continued safety and soundness of the insured credit unions and compliance with all applicable laws and regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H467ABAAB843B4C3D8532054F662D5971"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the authority of the National Credit Union Administration to conduct off-site monitoring, targeted reviews, or additional full-scope, on-site examinations of an insured credit union if the National Credit Union Administration determines such monitoring, reviews, or examinations are necessary to ensure safety and soundness or compliance with applicable laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82CB396085464C138C3B48F1C84B2110"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><subparagraph id="H1F91A1C15C4D46EBB3324CA776B1476C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consumer compliance examination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>consumer compliance examination</quote> means an examination to assess compliance with the requirements of Federal consumer financial law (as such term is defined in section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD27D555C0C14BAF967E9BC8FB414453"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Well capitalized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>well capitalized</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 216(c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD26AB1018FF04D89BDB6509E2FAE2DC1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Well managed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an insured credit union, the term <quote>well managed</quote> means that, when the credit union was most recently examined by the National Credit Union Administration, the credit union was found to be well managed, and the credit union’s composite condition was found to be satisfactory or outstanding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

