<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H433CEBD19B98480A8E37F50AD2978565" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4336 IH: CBP SPACE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4336</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to provide authority to adjust the rate of merchandise processing fees to offset the capital costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45C14D2EEBF74242813AB31F020E164B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDE0771CA5CF646FB98AE50CE7A5C64F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CBP SPACE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0879CD2DA9E24695B901E4BB6A761EA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to adjust the rate of merchandise processing fees to offset the capital costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection; modification to disposition of customs user fees</header> <subsection id="H1D086F8A079D4D64BE347D5C4B25427C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 13031 of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H494A6CB3580F46928727187312EA964C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(9)(B)(i), by striking <quote>salaries and expenses</quote> and inserting <quote>salaries, expenses, and capital costs</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E1DBA98BDFB443BBF4D9AFEDEB52C76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(3)(A)(i)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2BE3A18576774C408917EED7602EE419"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>, and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9618705CF5C94C829876290E5C3E9194"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking the comma at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB33D77FA03404AA1BC41981C152B2A01"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC08A31F7EE4940018E20CEA1C4E28D44" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HE9DF21F12425474F9B65E887FC497BAA"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>paying capital costs associated with passenger inspection services,</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H46D21913A897476CAC4351F341839DB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE210B57DA5D74651A988BC3A28AA8662"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of the Treasury and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection should work jointly to set an appropriate level for merchandise processing fees charged and collected under 13031 of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), such that U.S. Customs and Border Protection is able to adequately fund equipment upgrades and facilities construction, improvement, and maintenance at United States sea ports of entry.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H3EE668E12B6147028180461A7FD22E4A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on provision or maintenance of administrative, training, or recreational facilities at sea ports of entry for U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header>
<subsection id="HC430B15F272A4055BFBA2D2D320C377A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may not request or otherwise require a sea port of entry to provide or maintain administrative, training, or recreational facilities at the port of entry for purposes of facilitating inspection services of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC499A5218FD64F9A95C2F3BA455C1FE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify or otherwise affect the authority contained in section 482 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/301a">6 U.S.C. 301a</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HEBC1EFE1EC914763A8E211203F270DD1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual report on use of proceeds of merchandise processing fee</header>
<subsection id="H78DB374BF2284AD292F6B4C5105E2C73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report—</text> <paragraph id="H91F087D4686F4689AA1EEF7F81511290"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specifying the amount of proceeds from the merchandise processing fee collected under section 13031(a)(9) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985, as amended by section 1, during the year preceding submission of the report;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2073B64F2CF04E4AAB2D227D440E7DE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specifying the amount of such proceeds directed to inspection facilities at sea ports of entry; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4AC7CA5DE4F40948D99630F97D73993"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describing the outstanding capital needs of such inspection facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F7755D529A4455F85259FFEC7E9B172"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H0F5B1C9BCC464778AD37BE6940CC7FBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAEAE3809FDFD49FD9FC99CA074BFCC86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

