<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC81A4ACA67184017B08AD69F9B00CCB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 775 IH: No Net Gain in Federal Lands Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 775</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that there is no net gain in Federal land ownership in any fiscal year, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB71DD07DA834F4680BC984F0D34FB47" style="OLC"><section id="HD17108D7232C4C98928B69FAEFEE590D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Net Gain in Federal Lands Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4B4FA6BBF7C44E128BAACFAF4F536724"><enum>2.</enum><header>No net gain in certain federal land ownership</header><subsection id="H377E440AD90F42F68A948F9042915C37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No net gain</header><paragraph id="H6927878A99A44268B5DDA42D955AC734"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of acres of land, water, and interests therein acquired by the United States and put under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture in a State during a fiscal year may not exceed the number of acres of Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture disposed of in that State during that fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF2ED79667040F483503A4F88A89F62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>In applying paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H9CB81BF978B94B57A680E580A18C33D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>only the disposal of fee title to lands or waters may be counted against acquisition of fee title to lands or waters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5811FFB674F84FC1BB2981318190ED58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only disposal of interests in lands or waters of less than fee may be counted against acquisition of comparable interests in lands or waters of less than fee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0358F6E22C9240269DD2E3C963B94456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual inventory; determination, report</header><paragraph id="H749DBA5CFB01413C99E95DA8F0EC303F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inventory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall complete an annual inventory of the total number of acres of Federal land, categorized according to the type of interest (such as fee, easement, mineral interest, etc.), under the administrative jurisdiction of each agency of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture, as the case may be—</text><subparagraph id="H7480549F9D29463F82DB93F32DA1C9D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in each State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F6CCFBBE3E747588D759DF06D464FED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the aggregate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C77846D032B4C548D821926C4572610"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the inventory required by subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make an annual determination of the increase or decrease in the previous fiscal year of the total number of acres of Federal land, categorized according to the type of interest (such as fee, easement, mineral interest), under the administrative jurisdiction of—</text><subparagraph id="HAAA684AF6A884EA5BCB0EA68E1BBF94C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each agency of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture, as the case may be; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11EE3A7D8518483486567067C1278BAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of the Interior, in total, and the Department of Agriculture, in total, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAEC68723F10476690666C7B5C722F8E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the President and Congress a report containing the inventory and determination required under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H310813032B72423DAC5B9B58993097B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance land disposal</header><paragraph id="HE5CAF36362A04CA0BE97D796AA8B60D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the Secretary determines under subsection (b) that the Federal Government acquired more new Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of that Secretary in a State than it disposed of in that State during a fiscal year, the President shall convey to that State sufficient Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of that Secretary to comply with subsection (a) for that fiscal year. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA49403284843446F9295DCD61D697A18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No Major Federal Action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A conveyance under paragraph (1) shall not be considered a major Federal action for the purposes of section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07BC80ADB4174B7883BF69F900F32AEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H848EDFAF5490463EBF5DBC34ABC076B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal land</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HFB82929E91C94D9881917F02F909B29A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means Federal lands, waters, and interests therein, including lands held in trust by the Federal Government (except as provided in subparagraph (C));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B0C94CE6EC74C3CB4130B73F3E0D7C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes non-Federal land that is—</text><clause id="HC39A075A64014B6B9B12914A54723372"><enum>(i)</enum><text>leased by the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="HC2A77A9C248D4569B5F645F67BBB70EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>held as a conservation easement by the Federal Government; or</text></clause><clause id="H45368B8705B24439BF00819DD5D91454"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>requires oversight by, involvement in, or other authority is exercised by the Federal Government to an extent that prohibits use of the non-Federal land that is not specifically authorized by the Federal Government; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2D0C29B7B264B8E9A0431239DDB2085"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include land, water, and interests therein—</text><clause id="H5BFBB961EE0342E99A11C9CBF38870A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>held by an Indian Tribe or individual Indian subject to a restriction by the Federal Government against alienation;</text></clause><clause id="HB6C2836EE665452C966AAC8A9EC1BD8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>acquired pursuant to a foreclosure under title 18, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="H39136C8E1319491B8417F189FB0C0148"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>acquired by any department, agency, or independent establishment in its capacity as a receiver, conserver, or liquidating agent which is held by that department, agency, or independent establishment in such capacity pending disposal;</text></clause><clause id="HD67BC7CF8B644EF3A3B3ADA00294FCB0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has reverted to the Federal Government pursuant to a reversionary clause in a deed or statute;</text></clause><clause id="HC0941D6108CD40D6B6E693B946712B81"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subject to seizure, levy, or lien under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></clause><clause id="H474CAF5EFD494CAD8D4F52CA4E30B1E4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>securing a debt owed to the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C350333095046BB98BA3880AFB9A848"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE1712E4AB8B1446A996693B2E6C1CEDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture with regard to the Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of that Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H363D97233A834F409857FA05873FBE28"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior with regard to Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of that Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA8B74203F240279E43C4593A3057F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means the several States and the District of Columbia. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

