<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BF6FD737D6A4E17809D8B5FD5ADFD61" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4656 IH: Path to Florida Springs National Park Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine the suitability and feasibility of establishing Florida Springs National Park in Central and North Florida, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H70BF73BAEEBE43EE94060493882D2304" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H94206A9F2B5B4FC4B3C5118F7FBEFA26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Path to Florida Springs National Park Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4A5AEA98CAAA430BBD1071BDEC61824D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special Resource Study</header> <subsection id="H125759B1D7C34A3885F7039177982817"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBD6A936BB771402DBE3B22E73B65EB7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CF0A8DC644C4BC0900DA95BE53598DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study area</header> <subparagraph id="HFEE7CAB1A7CC44D48EAAA6CD566A7987"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>study area</term> means approximately 2,800 square miles of land in Florida located south of Jacksonville, north of Orlando, and east of Gainesville.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED88C8F66C314EE5B595554EA5D8DDE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>study area</term> includes—</text> <clause id="H7440E65CFB37492399EFB12A8AAA6B75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Ocala National Forest;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H032D3D53437E4C2E8B3758C597EF58A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lake George, Relay, Tiger Bay, Seminole Forest (Lake Tracy Unit), Rock Springs Run, Marshall Swamp, Ocala (Lake Delancy and Church Lake Units), Belmore, Camp Blanding, Ocklawaha River, and Grove Park Wilderness Management Areas;</text></clause> <clause id="HF5B3D84E50374E09AF843268E4E3C997"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lake George, Heart Island, Rice Creek, Hull Swamp, Crescent Lake, Lochloosa Wildlife, Clark Bay, Silver Springs Forest, Newnans Lake, Murphy Creek, Horseshoe Point, Moses Creek, and Pellicer Creek Conservation Areas;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD8F25EA14F0945ABA40FFFA8324BB4E5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lake George, Tiger Bay, Seminole, Etoniah Creek, Jennings, and Matanzas State Forests, and Indian Lake State Forest Campground;</text></clause> <clause id="HDF98FBDAB9F5494E8440901F5FE2F622"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lower Wekiva River Preserve, Dunns Creek, Haw Creek Preserve, Paynes Prairie Preserve, De León Springs, Blue Spring, and Faver Dykes State Parks;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E76B78BA427474D9DD5AF8DC6A50AC6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Longleaf Pine Preserve, Ocklawaha Prairie Restoration Area, Deep Creek Preserve, Paynes Prairie Preserve State Park, and Princess Place; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDA866031E3DA4756900C660438E61327"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Lake Disston Park.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H698215BAAD8241EDB3F8ABC7A6261E30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a special resource study of the study area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0961068D16544BD185A23C2A09C7FA11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6CC0BA9023E740C9BA054572E69D4E23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the national significance of the study area;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6427607E40464AD6B41B227DE23A4F9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the study area as a unit of the National Park System;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H157DA5DF12D94672AB2D1126B9FDCA03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider other alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of the study area by the Federal Government, State or local government entities, or private and nonprofit organizations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1CD92DB542D464C88DFB02CC302F7DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with interested Federal agencies, State or local governmental entities, private and nonprofit organizations, or any other interested individuals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC77C2ECC4734400DA203974CE41790DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify cost estimates for any Federal acquisition, development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with the alternatives described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07D5A1A6FFC54AB8B965ACF1929C3F15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable Law</header><text>The study required under subsection (b) shall be conducted in accordance with section 100507 of title 54, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69264BC3AA474ED8AC0E389EA2C93580"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out the study under subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that describes—</text> <paragraph id="H092F4B767AC94E159F31A16111519151"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD804F101A3BB4D29885C2EC4A54B57FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

