<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA25108-WJ5-FS-P02">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2039 IS: Wildfire Risk Evaluation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2039</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental
                Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and
            the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a quadrennial fire review, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0D35D49535ED4FB4BE072795D3924700">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H24F05AE8ABDB46B4A027D002E753E687">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Risk Evaluation Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HC30423DF8EA04CA5BF271D2D2F28245A">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HD7776DF840704BBC8DABADB36BF3B91A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wildfire management is a complex, multi-jurisdictional issue that requires a whole-of-government approach before, during, and after a fire;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEDEC5CF067E845138BA55CF192A5A409">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wildfires spread quickly and may invoke various Federal, State, Tribal, and local jurisdictions simultaneously;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H13772DA260CB4A6081C22C46D57D11B2">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>effective wildfire management requires interagency, cross-boundary, strategic, and holistic solutions;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H4B188C0C84F74C7B80CDC05B47A5A5FF">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments should be included in any planning, decision-making, or response activities with respect to wildfire management;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC3052EFC108F4D4F9A6196A97479F771">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>a purpose of a quadrennial fire review is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8efd7d93b9b47c990e6a3e351a5d453"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to forecast conditions that may present the greatest challenges for wildland fire management throughout the 20-year period immediately following such review; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c8485dffe4e4ab5bee3b7ee158d88bc">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to inform the development of long-term, strategic actions to address such challenges;</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE50368805B8441A6BA5B53CAECE98741">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the report of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior entitled <quote>The National Strategy: the Final Phase in the Development of the National Cohesive Wildland Fire Management Strategy</quote> (April 2014), as updated by the report entitled <quote>National Cohesive Wildland Fire Management Strategy Addendum Update</quote> (January 2023), represents a strategic, collaborative effort to address wildfire management in all landscapes and using the best science available to make meaningful progress toward the 3 goals established in such report regarding—</text>
                <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H777B334BCED04F0180DC578739A0789F">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>resilient landscapes;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D9C6037A4364A9B9118DADC87FD404B"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>fire-adapted communities; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF0E5D4BCB1CE4C51BFF4EB1F86D59A08">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>safe and effective wildfire response; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H392AA42785C046BBA67C5087E9B882E3"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission entitled <quote>ON FIRE: The Report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission</quote> (September 2023) presents a consensus set of recommendations developed by 50 diverse experts and intended to result in improved outcomes for wildfire management in the United States.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HBEC3DECC6D1A40A0B571CD68100B6151">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Quadrennial fire review</header>
            <subsection id="HD440E06E1C14452DBC8BDA89300AF0A6">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBACF1B577F524A7ABE25204E76FD7B54"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Qualified agencies</header> <text>The term <term>qualified agencies</term> means—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H32010F23D0B74272A426990BFE4AC74B">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the Secretary of Agriculture, the Forest Service;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4FD2F96A103E4A1CAD9ED295D8B88ED7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the Secretary of the Interior, the Department of the Interior;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HEF3519164A684CD79121CC134015A54B">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the United States Fire Administration; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H9AA6CA3FE38A4D41830781DBC07580F4">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>such other entities as the Secretaries determine appropriate.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HABDA9F30754B4EF8A4426733BA153BCB"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Relevant committees</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant committees</term> means—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idabe0585d838544afa43936a73d8da097">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources, Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H74899EC7186743389FEC4224C7B07D22">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Committees on Natural Resources, Homeland Security, and Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE0F99790DCA141659903670D63C75A45" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Secretaries</header>
 <text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE8416367CC0B400D9D2FD670A09C4D3F">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Quadrennial review</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries, acting jointly through the qualified agencies, shall conduct a quadrennial review of the comprehensive wildfire environment in the United States that includes—</text>
                <paragraph id="HA31C1DD152CA4AA2B0E04C5BC957880D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a quantitative analysis of changes to built and natural environments since the most recent quadrennial fire review and the impact of such changes on pre-fire mitigation, wildfire incident response, and proactive recovery from wildfire; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8A23161CB19945C4975E352437552BFE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the intersection between wildfire and public health, conducted in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H4CDD9697CCD34CC38753DD288A1B7EE8">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 4 years for the 20 years thereafter, the Secretaries shall jointly submit to the relevant committees a report that contains—</text>
                <paragraph id="H3CF9B92594EA4CC2AC2365CA15E7924C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the results of the reviews conducted under subsection (b) and specifies the administrative actions and outcomes that have occurred as a result of such reviews;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA4EEBC1EE4FE4D918F6BBAA2BAA57C4F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a summary of—</text> <subparagraph id="H72347149E14B478BA67A59EF18C67EA3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the challenges relating to wildfire that are anticipated during the 20-year period immediately following the report; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA2A364284BB045C1AEA8B0BF729E2D83">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the most significant long-term wildland fire management challenges;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HDCF71E00DD1F4140A4A360C7EB349259">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>recommendations regarding such Federal legislation and administrative actions as the Secretaries determine necessary to address the results described in paragraph (1) and the challenges described in paragraph (2);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBD907CFAC6DF4FF3B9C9F77EED13772E">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of any progress made toward—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H2A316E4FADAF488F921DE6AF23D9E892">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieving the 3 goals established in the report of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior entitled <quote>The National Strategy: the Final Phase in the Development of the National Cohesive Wildland Fire Management Strategy</quote> (April 2014), as updated by the report entitled <quote>National Cohesive Wildland Fire Management Strategy Addendum Update</quote> (January 2023); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HDD98E5BC2FB64836885A65FB7FB566C8">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing recommendations set forth in the report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission entitled <quote>ON FIRE: The Report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission</quote> (September 2023); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H03815A47CE3D45D39088931DE1B531FE">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>projected future scenarios to highlight areas of consideration for realignment of programs, strategies, capabilities, and the workforce that will assist the Secretaries in addressing the challenges described in paragraph (2).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

