<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25360-DGH-HS-YM3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>105 S1433 IS: Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1433</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reauthorize the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to promote the protection of the resources of the Northwest Straits, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="ID6A6404AA634A478BB39C2AD542506DC2"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ID08F85F2E3EE54987A0E1EC5D63A37AD5"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reauthorization of Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act (title IV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/384">Public Law 105–384</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 3458) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID58FF122DE75D4F909F4DA0FB24329F99"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 402, by striking <quote>Commission (in this title referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</quote> and inserting <quote>Commission.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3D5D1C18E1E34FE99000131BE4BC2DF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking sections 403, 404, and 405 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDF7A00DC6ED0C44D88FB3E63792644B07"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ID0B3681EEF88A4E8FB917C800B4F22462"><enum>403.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID91397366C40F4F329DD115FB4048E5F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The marine waters and ecosystem of the Northwest Straits in Puget Sound in the State of Washington represent a unique resource of enormous environmental and economic value to the people of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID86FA62FB83A04B028F049D25207432FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 20th century, the environmental health of the Northwest Straits declined dramatically as indicated by impaired water quality, declines in marine wildlife, collapse of harvestable marine species, loss of critical marine habitats, ocean acidification, and sea level rise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5b7b997d0a2477f97d5e904749edf3f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increasingly, the Northwest Straits have been threatened by sea level rise, ocean acidification, and other effects of climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48f97798068e41b78ee87563f12c5be0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>This title was enacted to tap the unprecedented level of citizen stewardship demonstrated in the Northwest Straits and create a mechanism to mobilize public support and raise capacity for local efforts to protect and restore the ecosystem of the Northwest Straits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7e4cfa1a2804211b85e83790db1d1e8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative helps the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and other Federal agencies with their marine missions by fostering local interest in marine issues and involving diverse communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID0DB482DD998B460891CCA155105F1F78"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative shares many of the same goals with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including fostering citizen stewardship of marine resources, general ecosystem management, and protecting federally managed marine species.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id816e94c41e474a28843075d57df575ea"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ocean literacy, kelp habitat conservation and monitoring, Veterans Conservation Corps internships, and removal of marine debris projects are examples of previous and ongoing partnerships between the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. Areas of partnership may evolve with emerging opportunities.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="IDAE11BC34E604415095476719533EC2C7"><enum>404.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID27319380CEE44D72BB690150DA70400A"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission established by section 402.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id577dca070f8541b0a596a676eda28526"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Marine resources committee</header><text>The term <term>marine resources committee</term> means a county government committee that assists in assessing marine resource and conservation needs. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID9E41A813E74C4FE88C6780DA817A9C05"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Northwest Straits region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Northwest Straits region</term> means the marine waters of the Strait of Juan de Fuca and of Puget Sound from the Canadian border to the south end of Snohomish County.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65db7f5812d74a4eb7116470eb695e04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2025</short-title> pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01821a987d4f4097b048234d84737bab"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ID5ADE008209B54575A376DD19BF19D1DF"><enum>405.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership of the Commission</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID54784C7CD861452AB92E5E6E76938366"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Composition</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0AB7A34542914DD0AF0E2DAD8FA773E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 14 members, except as provided in paragraph (2), who shall be appointed as follows: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8A360AB61CCA4F1DBB9A14675AA3A474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for San Juan County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7a85e258f4e4f0c8ec9293f16dd9edc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Island County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19b28ce633da4ebea1a12f975fc834e9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Skagit County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a47ee512e2b415685ee297145125db5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Whatcom County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf78c3eaa67449e488f151c05c2a6228"><enum>(E)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Snohomish County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b96b7de94af4bc19ed352d3ac2e55b2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Clallam County, Washington.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b8236baa6684bc3a9039f5af19fd571"><enum>(G)</enum><text>One member appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee for Jefferson County, Washington. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID128BB2877274415F9791D642EB4AC782"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members appointed by the Secretary of the Interior, in coordination with the Northwest Indian Fisheries Commission and in consultation with the Tribal governments affected by this title, to represent the interests of such Tribal governments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDAD3156D49AE6467A891E521938398D22"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One member appointed by the Governor of the State of Washington to represent the interests of the Puget Sound Partnership.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID7CA5A09F621C4E36972149E7233FFEEC"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four members appointed by the Governor of the State of Washington who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5D3D22B75C5F4CBAB0A3182F160B1A73"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are residents of the State of Washington; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDF4BA656738AD4B72B43EE2BA55B18F26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not employed by a Federal, State, or local government, excluding an institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79E229094EF84B0CAAC737B1372A4EF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional members</header><text>The Commission may, as determined necessary to improve the ability of the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission under section 406(b), appoint members in addition to those appointed under paragraph (1). Any such additional member shall be appointed by a consensus of the members of a marine resources committee that is not described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDE9FB56695A43473AA5D82AAA469F4B0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID6EE5A61B068748219FBBE565A1D1D420"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall select a Chairperson from among its members.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8F7521BDD4D14627ACB7DCFCFD66EC07"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, but not less frequently than quarterly.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID6DA4DAF2441C4836A4D483376A6EB9DB"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liaison</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDF93956D5CE484B099FBF014FBE5A0AAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall appoint an employee of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDBFF3837F0C86447489659F4F9B168966"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to serve as a liaison between the Commission and the Department of Commerce; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID420440FF0B464519969F069D4182A0EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate programs of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with activities related to the goal of the Commission described in section 406(a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F05420BE24E406C9DDD8F74FCC5D984"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to perform additional liaison functions benefitting the Commission and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, which may include, as agreed to by the Commission and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, attending meetings and other events of the Commission as a nonvoting participant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDD756E7675F9C44BD96ABE4839C8F87EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service as a member of the Commission by the employee appointed under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDD5B7FD2EE2BB4A35A4C05449734ED4E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is limited to the employee’s service as a liaison; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5C82FE2403DF4F18A5515AEF8749001C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not obligate the employee to perform any duty of the Commission under section 406(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id0dc279ad54f24595a249fa4342d51355"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Commission may enter into cooperative agreements with the State of Washington for staffing and administrative services for the purposes of supporting the duties of the Commission under section 406(b). </text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ID2E77093F7C62474483A4E6DCE203305B"><enum>406.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Goal and duties of the Commission</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDC575BA8502164F29BCA77C07516DA3C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goal of the Commission is to protect and restore the marine waters, habitats, and species of the Northwest Straits region to achieve ecosystem health and sustainable resource use by—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8126CD8025A449BCB5519C487734DFE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designing and recommending projects that are driven by the best available science, local priorities, community-based decisions, and the ability to measure results;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8282E541AEF948708B11FEE4A92F4299"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">building awareness and stewardship and making recommendations to improve the health of the marine resources of the Northwest Straits region;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDBBEAE18B38BF4C1D980F3FA659EEDD87"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintaining and expanding diverse membership and collaboration with partner organizations, such as the Puget Sound Partnership;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDAE7D465CF4F247D4831C5C2D7BC6F8CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding partnerships with Tribal governments and continuing to support Tribal treaties, cultures, and subsistence and Tribal treaty rights; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDF4A72A0BD2F44A00B536665084C24FFE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizing the importance of economic and social benefits that are dependent on marine environments and sustainable marine resources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID69B2BAF25619449A8F2513108EB2FA91"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Commission are the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID6273781AA60A49308B32225E758EAD56"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide resources and technical support for marine resources committees.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8DFC190AAEF74234B220AC38C00B42B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To work with such marine resources committees and appropriate entities of Federal, State, and local governments and Tribal governments to provide advice in developing regional programs to monitor the overall health of the marine ecosystem of the Northwest Straits region.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDE98EEB4ACA004AA29CBF56759C3E9E53"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To collect marine resources data and identify factors adversely affecting or preventing the restoration of the health of the marine ecosystem and coastal economies of the Northwest Straits region to inform decisionmakers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA4BB3854FE05469AA50B87ADB5DBFEAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop scientifically sound restoration and protection recommendations, informed by local priorities, that address such factors.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID0DCC664EE0DA40EABF5871D828DD246E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To serve as a public forum for the informal discussion of policies and actions, with respect to the marine ecosystem of the Northwest Straits region, of Federal, State, or local governments, Tribal governments, or the Government of Canada.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID675E560861324682B288306E1D731E8E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To inform appropriate authorities and local communities about the marine ecosystem of the Northwest Straits region and about issues relating to the marine ecosystem of the Northwest Straits region.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDD52C83EC312A4F27A237E26234BEF7FD"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To consult with all affected Tribal governments in the Northwest Straits region to ensure that the work of the Commission does not violate Tribal treaty rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7cf7ea31be0f45f88f11e0675555e67e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and collaboration</header><text>The Commission—</text><paragraph id="id32e17c83ef93435297052e2ddd84966c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall carry out the duties described in subsection (b) in coordination and collaboration, as appropriate, with Federal, State, and local governments and Tribal governments, including by—</text><subparagraph id="idccf7138862e342fea4f9193d73e47182"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical support and assistance to any Tribal government seeking representation and participation on the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbe7b0c44c7a4fd09e6f7e870d5685ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting the work and duties of the liaison to the Commission under section 405(e); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5c6556c45514d37adcaa75ebf7c2789"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may enter into cooperative agreements with nonprofit entities, such as the Northwest Straits Foundation, to provide assistance, including financial assistance, in carrying out the duties described in subsection (b). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id229ffb317908421381b66e5ab8dbc211"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Nothing in this title provides the Commission with authority to issue regulations or implement any Federal law or regulation.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb1875e69b4e24f8698cce5147ffed3cd"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acceptance of donations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, the Commission may solicit, accept, receive, hold, administer, and use gifts, devises, and bequests without any further approval or administrative action. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3DA627B7D27E403B8D51BD9DA362E87F"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID77E38862BB64492ABD16D505B8F66D7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, the Commission shall prepare, submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Under Secretary, and make available to the public a report describing— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8E6B712C74C2487898AAAD85781B2ED5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the activities carried out by the Commission during the preceding year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID140C41358185441D9C9C93B516B7C944"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress in achieving the benchmarks described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID293B6CE1BB7E418D82CF4DE33BCDC47E"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benchmarks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The benchmarks described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID1EF12AAF569D4740A884C4BA10433F28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection and restoration of marine, coastal, and nearshore habitats within the Northwest Straits region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID9FF15C3049B74F43B3B7F34C216AF6C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection and restoration of marine resources populations to healthy, sustainable levels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDFAFD6C4A387B4C44A899892E9B15C0F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of the water quality of the Northwest Straits region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID7C5FD85D2DAA4D0FA37044B431EABEEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collection of high-quality data and promotion of the use and dissemination of such data for the purposes of ecosystem monitoring.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE87EEA88C7EB4C00AFB0CF5F105CB6C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Promotion of stewardship and understanding of marine resources of the Northwest Straits region through education and outreach, including by targeted outreach to underresourced communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID79310639E58145A084869F806A55B728"><enum>407.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEC985B5013F24899B7C01C0C31D0C6D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary to carry out this title—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc033e376e2ca4d2ea3714ffcf7dea17d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, $10,000,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a5216d4355643d89cd3aea5ffdc6e4f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2032 and each fiscal year thereafter, such sums as may be necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26F5A15503314D58920033E565FB245D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE1760661DBC24B2CA1398A4C4BEC972A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary may, from amounts made available to the Under Secretary to carry out this title, provide assistance to the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this title. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5B20A40C212C48E08F61A9B8E6C86EA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary may provide the assistance described in paragraph (1), and make available amounts to the Commission to carry out the duties of the Commission, through a contract with the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve, unless the Governor of the State of Washington objects. If such Governor so objects, the Under Secretary may not provide such assistance and make available such amounts to the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

