<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1A0417EB72D340F5972F8B3684661EF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 645 IH: National Constitutional Carry Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 645</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enforce the rights protected by the Second and Fourteenth Amendments against the States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3ABAEAC0702F4E4DB3DF878742D1C77C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD84A0523CCF745C0A412A3FBB91C1F83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Constitutional Carry Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1D802059A2C349609FB6083B7CC6B45F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFF7ED853F8B74E42907DF88BA3C9342D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recognizing the preexisting right to self-defense, the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States guarantees individually to American citizens the right <quote>to keep and bear arms</quote>, including the right to bear arms in public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFCF01B6E9DA4B14AA6F1598341D4365"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Second Amendment decrees that these rights to keep and bear arms <quote>shall not be infringed</quote>, and was enumerated in order to preserve <quote>the security of a free State</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6433D700E6AC4CFA8FB7209DC97B5202"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In District of Columbia v. Heller (554 U.S. 570, 595 (2008)), the Supreme Court confirmed that <quote>[t]here seems to us no doubt, on the basis of both text and history, that the Second Amendment conferred an individual right to keep and bear arms</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B0C46A0294244E59CCC62943FBB2838"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In McDonald v. City of Chicago (561 U.S. 742, 791 (2010)), the Supreme Court ruled that the Fourteenth Amendment makes the Second Amendment fully applicable to the States. Four Justices concluded that the rights protected by the Second Amendment are fundamental to the Nation’s scheme of ordered liberty and deeply rooted in this Nation’s <quote>history and tradition</quote>, and therefore incorporated to the States through the Due Process Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment. Justice Thomas agreed that the rights protected by the Second Amendment are both <quote>fundamental</quote> and <quote>deeply rooted</quote> and, as such, are enforceable against the States under the Fourteenth Amendment’s Privileges and Immunities Clause.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6928785B1A34B99BF337AB21B549D80"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recently, the Supreme Court acknowledged in New York State Rifle &amp; Pistol Ass’n v. Bruen (142 S. Ct. 2111, 2156 (2022)), that the Second and Fourteenth Amendments protect the individual right to carry arms outside the home for self-defense. Further, the Court reiterated that the Second Amendment’s otherwise <quote>unqualified command</quote> only accommodates laws that are <quote>consistent with this Nation’s historical tradition of firearm regulation</quote> (Id. at 2126).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H884F2797BFCD4388AEC0DF6DCE697771"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Certain States and localities have enacted gun control laws that are not consistent with the text of the Second Amendment or this Nation’s historical tradition of firearm regulation. The criminalization of peaceable, public firearms carry is repugnant to the original meaning of the Second Amendment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D22FF4CBE554C52A5D16C58D864ECA9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any State or local restriction on the right of American citizens to keep and bear arms impairs the ability of the Second Amendment to achieve its textually specified purpose, <quote>the security of a free State</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H184F600F517D476893F8A26AAC6937A2"><enum>3.</enum><header>The right to keep and bear arms</header> <subsection id="H1482CCFEE886440B9427E37A78FC7182"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 927 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6B84E26B03D64AB7BBE25159641E9D90" style="USC"> 
<section id="H8AC5467BA1F745A6A44F0E0CDBDA7DF5"><enum>927.</enum><header>The right to keep and bear arms</header> 
<subsection id="HBD023B144CE543D097D9B4DD3A4754E6"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No State or political subdivision of a State may impose a criminal or civil penalty on, or otherwise indirectly limit the carrying of firearms (including by imposing a financial or other barrier to entry) in public by residents or nonresidents of that State who are citizens of the United States and otherwise eligible to possess firearms under State and Federal law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H881032F531D64BE89023238D08DF8FBA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of a State or a political subdivision of a State that criminalizes, penalizes, or otherwise indirectly dissuades the carrying of firearms (including by imposing a financial or other barrier to entry) in public by any resident or nonresident who is a United States citizen and otherwise eligible to possess firearms under State and Federal law, shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5053A86BEEF64C8FB3A9AE2C2C96D5DB"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> as used in this section includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the possessions of the United States (not including the Canal Zone).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8C1B5339E4E348B49C586C76831CAB11"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The term <term>public</term> as used in this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H496E6912125D491C82F34B39EF2FE8D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes any place held open to the public, regardless of ownership, but in the case of a privately-owned location held open to the public, does not include a place where the owner communicates clearly and conspicuously a prohibition of firearms on the premises; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9372586037A34C3EA5DFE056069EC82D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include a place where screening for firearms is conducted under State law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA26A9D46C3324475A2C55D15D22599A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by striking the item relating to section 927 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4D7DB6B2583E41D5899DCFDCDA3BF005" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">927. The right to keep and bear arms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

