<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC866B545DE224CA29510BB38CA5CFEE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 162 IH: First Amendment Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 162</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a right of action against Federal employees for violations of First Amendment rights.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B253637A87E4FC59E48CD61B4AD2653" style="OLC"><section id="H3618B60D6BBC45C6955FE4D559B56CF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Amendment Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H03C405BD17E845DBBEB208CAF85B2B8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Right of action against Federal employees for violations of First Amendment rights</header><subsection id="HE9EF7287F53D48168A3620D484760AF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal employee who, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage, of the United States, subjects, or causes to be subjected, any citizen of the United States or any person within the jurisdiction thereof to the deprivation of any rights, privileges, or immunities secured by the First Amendment, shall be liable to the party injured in an action at law, suit in equity, or other proper proceeding for redress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98A69953A6A946D5A657C5B5CCFE417B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section does not authorize a Federal employee to bring a suit against their Federal employer or the Federal Government for conduct that is within the scope of the employment relationship.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD24B973583944005B4AA673F0CD95964"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action or proceeding to enforce this Act, the court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC4A1636754443998F402FBE07BED261"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>Federal employee</quote> means an individual, other than the President or the Vice President, who occupies a position in any agency or instrumentality of the executive branch (including any independent agency).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB2D4FFDE9594C1AB6BF707E27A09955"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of a provision of this Act to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

