<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA0FA668D3974DE0854C6D2847D824D5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3580 IH: Oversight of Medicare Billing Code Cost Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3580</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase oversight and transparency with respect to Medicare billing codes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB1B6AD3EFFE24C33BF8E902FD01D443E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A412A60E0B94E9AAA5A8496A38EAC7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oversight of Medicare Billing Code Cost Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A86BBCDAD794EBFB58A272A846BA36F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing oversight and transparency with respect to Medicare billing codes</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B557804EA8747CA8FF48C74138F7272"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">HHS OIG study and report</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAD7B14F31DF4BC1A0CC9158A18193CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall conduct a comprehensive study of the processes used by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for adding, modifying, and removing billing codes under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>). Such study shall include an analysis of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H627E067BAA064822AEB92673B92BE0FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the level and types of data and analysis considered;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA07FC54E4549487989F411E19D247497"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends in the number and types of codes added, modified, removed, or revalued;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D1CAB525771462C803FD6724DF8D8A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas or specialties with the highest growth; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36BE66BA1C874BE3A3FEA2EA4D4F2F4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to monitor effects on outcomes, costs over time, and other issues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5229D54E0F340D8B648860A43B701A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action the Inspector General determines appropriate to improve transparency and oversight of the processes described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA63E08EFFFF14C0B8D76B4586C1A3428"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual reporting on new Medicare billing codes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1 of each year (beginning with 2025), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services a report listing any billing codes added under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act during the preceding year, along with the associated volume and expenditures for such codes under the Medicare program.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

