<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF0DE18158989498BA741FD6881D6F195" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3958 IH: To require the United States Postal Service to notify postal customers and relevant officials when operations are temporarily suspended at a post office, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3958</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the United States Postal Service to notify postal customers and relevant officials when operations are temporarily suspended at a post office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H05EC30C70E28423A85A7ADAEF624CAD7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H26C24E1E7DAB4C7591440166634FD406" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Notice of temporary post office closure</header>
<subsection id="HB529A123B851468AAFC1E33EFC6E6E5C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the United States Postal Service temporarily suspends operations at a post office, either voluntarily or involuntarily, the United States Postal Service shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFD4B888A63574D0E863875904CEE8E87" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit the notices required by subsection (b);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE721C18B31704B9EAC18DC8AC8E6ECCB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide persons served by such post office an opportunity for comment in accordance with subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D5074EDBE8D4C4C90CAF9430573FEB2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide services to persons served by such post office in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H42A17C8671244AE490C0ED40F514A048"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notices</header>
<paragraph id="H8DD94565487947949D5DA60BF2C667FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Suspension notice</header>
<subparagraph id="H20F0A68C31C844268C17B9100FDD5B17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service shall notify persons served by a post office and the relevant officials for such post office of the temporary suspension of operations at such post office.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24570BC6D81B490A85CFEF9CCAB2CAB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header> <clause id="H6853539A9B644EEC81A68E4D7EB8080A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by clause (ii), the notice required under subparagraph (A) with respect to the temporary suspension of operations at a post office shall include—</text>
<subclause id="HEA90DB18C8F24230AC7C71C57D2BD29F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a temporary suspension of operations that the United States Postal Service plans or expects, the expected date on which such temporary suspension of operations will begin;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1E7FBACEE405462AB8DB8404A991D136"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the reasons for such temporary suspension of operations;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF8499FD952014B04AD016EAC1C37AE6A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plans for—</text> <item id="HC17B29DDFB704279991432E751BBE702"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>providing retail postal services to persons served by such post office during such temporary suspension of operations;</text></item>
<item id="H1C04A39486D04A6881874BF3B3D88DDF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>providing persons served by such post office the opportunity required by subsection (c); and</text></item> <item id="HEB4CC130F03E4469AB28D67176F36C4D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>resuming the operations of such post office; and</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="H62FA4B6AA1A84FC29A54BE2F08F4C063"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an estimate of when the operations of such post office will resume.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1CBC861D62F54F1FBB65FCEAEBDD10A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Onsite notices</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), a notice required under subparagraph (A) placed at the physical location of a post office shall include instructions for accessing a website of the United States Postal Service containing the information described in clause (i) and may contain such information.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A5A443587E14024ADAFB1C4689E2308"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service shall provide the notice required under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H1EDAF94A62F04CCEAD673F623618E48A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a temporary suspension of operations that the United States Postal Service plans or expects, not later than the later of—</text>
<subclause id="HDD250206A7314133B82B2D1207ABF9FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">60 days prior to the expected date on which such temporary suspension of operations will begin; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBFB181FB5EC5496386FA05A547A8C6BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the earliest date on which the United States Postal Service plans or expects such temporary suspension of operations; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H6737F33E16FA40D9A92982A2E5760F82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in all other cases, not later than 14 days after the date on which operations are temporarily suspended.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C1FF9C8DC60478B8847F86647048D14" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service may not temporarily suspend operations at a post office unless the United States Postal Service provides the notice required under this paragraph, except that this subparagraph shall not apply if such temporary suspension of operations is not at the discretion of the United States Postal Service or is necessary due to health or safety concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38C1C7CFFFE049A9B869846DCE28148B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Status updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the United States Postal Service temporarily suspends operations at a post office for a period of more than six months, not later than six months after the date on which such temporary suspension of operations begins, and every three months thereafter until the date on which such temporary suspension of operations ends, the United States Postal Service shall provide to persons served by such post office and the relevant officials for such post office a notice on the status of such temporary suspension of operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EF3C34C5B9349E287289DC7E82A5ED1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reopening notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determining the date on which operations will resume at a post office at which operations are temporarily suspended, the United States Postal Service shall notify persons served by such post office and the relevant officials for such post office of the date of such resumption of operations at such post office and, in the case of a post office that has been relocated, the location of such post office.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76E13898B5CF47D49EADD6B3C6DC8332"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each notice required under this subsection with respect to a post office, the United States Postal Service shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H064C91BF83D340AABD223CCB18AC0F59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mail such notice to persons served by such post office;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD86FCE8D86AC44F9833767F3A1C59C9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>place such notice at the physical location of such post office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2221C8E5114B454DA862F1356BD28C09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make such notice publicly available on a website of the United States Postal Service;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H648C8B1022D146AEB12D72862194003F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish such notice on relevant social media websites; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC903B0EED66E4DD5A4BE5E4E2D836C45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>send such notice to a valid email of each relevant official.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFC01393147BC451182FECAE6ECAB1DBC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant officials defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>relevant officials</term>, with respect to a post office, means—</text> <subparagraph id="H86B43731F2A3420BADE1DE822195C195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress) representing a congressional district which includes all or part of the geographic area served by such post office;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D61A1A885A8462C8DF82BBFD24CC02C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each Senator representing a State which includes all or part of the geographic area served by such post office; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFF0E219941F44C2846D874C8E8FA036"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of each local government with jurisdiction over all or part of the geographic area served by such post office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC30B08934342488989CD0AB598FE3CD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Opportunity for comment</header><text>The United States Postal Service shall provide persons served by a post office at which operations are temporarily suspended an opportunity to present their views on such temporary suspension of operations, including the relocation of such post office.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H32681978E7284784B0636D8942CBE54B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Replacement retail postal services</header> <paragraph id="H7BF15E5AD7B94E03830578CF51C3C55B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the temporary suspension of operations at a post office, the United States Postal Service shall provide to persons served by such post office the services described in paragraph (2)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3F95DAE2AC1A424F81FECD499E72B2C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the same geographic area as such post office, to the extent practicable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD48A8F7D4224E6ABDEF3ECF509FD22A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that such post office provided such services immediately before such temporary suspension of operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A6777FE17AE476B8206405830B98255" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retail postal services</header><text>The services described in this paragraph are the following services not available from the post office at which operations are temporarily suspended:</text> <subparagraph id="H9C2844F016344D6783144675CCFC5110" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Retail postal services, including the sale of boxes and other packaging material sold by the United States Postal Service.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB512D30672D74ABDB1995A3A980F47C8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A means for holders of post office boxes at such post office to receive mail sent to the post office box of such holder.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H570360A2BF5143DE9BC7F7D08368B20B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Providing, accepting, and processing forms necessary for persons to request a change of mailing address or a temporary halt to the delivery of mail to such person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7546945702604695BE669609B3B2A4F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service shall provide the services required by paragraph (1) until the end of the temporary suspension of operations with respect to which the United States Postal Service is providing such services under such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBFC0E95DFB4B43FAB2B710F8D2C4DCFC" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply only with respect to temporary suspensions of operations at post offices that begin after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

