<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4027DE4A8BA481182C200FAB80137F6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 228 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the third week of March 2025 as “National CACFP Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 228</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the third week of March 2025 as <quote>National CACFP Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Agriculture reaffirms the vital role positive nutrition habits play in the healthy growth of children in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Agriculture also recognizes the importance of nutrition education for the most vulnerable and youngest children, as well as adults, through care centers and homes throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the child and adult care food program (commonly referred to as <quote>CACFP</quote>) provides meals and snacks to more than 4,500,000 children in child care centers, family day care homes, emergency shelters, and after-school programs and 115,000 adults in adult day care centers daily, covering the costs of nearly 1,700,000,000 nutritious meals and snacks each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research has found that participation in CACFP reduces the prevalence of the conditions of underweight, overweight, or obesity in children, which highlights the importance of healthful meal patterns along with accurate nutrition education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CACFP increases the quality of child care, especially for children in low-income communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CACFP increases the effectiveness and viability of Head Start programs, child care programs, including military child care, and adult day care homes for many providers, especially in rural areas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CACFP improves the cognitive, social, emotional, and physical health and development of children, leading to more favorable outcomes such as—</text><paragraph id="HAC560CF20F524F57A1FC76CFE5C01470"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a decreased likelihood of being hospitalized; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA00DDDA5345343B3AEDBD9063CE40803"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an increased likelihood of healthy weight gain; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AED7487E9B54F5C91EEDF50B9B36F92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an increased likelihood of a more varied diet, including increased consumption of vegetables, meat, eggs, whole grains, and milk;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the innovative approach to CACFP implementation, which pairs Head Start programs, child care homes and centers, including military child care, adult day care centers, emergency shelters, and after-school sites with either a nonprofit sponsoring organization or a State agency, highlights a unique public-private partnership that supports working families and small businesses; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the third week of March is annually recognized as <quote>National CACFP Week</quote> to raise awareness of the child and adult care food program of the Department of Agriculture: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEC612C062DF54962B699E58CFAEEF94F"><section id="H210ACDA6773E4BD38C930C21208F5957" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HECA9F49ED0374F569F4AE8284AEFB979"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the role of the child and adult care food program (commonly referred to as <quote>CACFP</quote>) in improving the health of the country’s most vulnerable children and adults in Head Start programs, child care programs, including military child care, family day care homes, emergency shelters, adult day care homes, and after-school care by providing nutritious meals and snacks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFBDF329E429491989D213C01DE6AE1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges support for continuing to strengthen CACFP by offering reimbursement for an additional meal or snack for children in care for a full day, reducing area eligibility from 50 percent to 40 percent, offering annual eligibility to for-profit child care centers, factoring in annual food inflation fairly for child care regardless of setting, and reducing administrative burdens to participation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H551228041C0243759125A0C365B99027"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that CACFP can, and should, be an important tool in reducing the costs faced by the care economy, including licensed or approved child or adult care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H340721D4B289410DB375B70AD057F5BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National CACFP Week</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

