<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DD0259A49574B69B867B95D2C046FDE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1948 IH: To authorize the International Boundary and Water Commission to accept funds for activities relating to wastewater treatment and flood control works, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the International Boundary and Water Commission to accept funds for activities relating to wastewater treatment and flood control works, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43E3A3529B7748D49AFD7F9157192D13" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H49B8B0B4AC5C464A99A11F2937B38F75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>International Boundary and Water Commission Authority</header> 
<subsection id="H6F6E25AEA5CE49BBA592A7CD9CAE66D0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission is authorized to accept funds from a Federal or non-Federal entity, including through a grant or funding agreement, to study, design, construct, operate, or maintain wastewater treatment works, water conservation projects, or flood control works, and related structures, consistent with the functions of the Commission.<italic></italic></text></subsection> <subsection id="HE16D5A8634D2417394B78C0CD763C8C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds accepted by the Commission under this section shall be deposited into the account in the Treasury of the United States entitled <quote>International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico</quote> and shall be available until expended to carry out the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8D76A4F11FD4E36BDA259FBB98B94F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header> 
<paragraph id="H059E6262DBF54577B8E1E47EA55D0B10" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limit on reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may not provide credit towards the non-Federal share of the cost of a project, or reimbursement, to non-Federal entities for funds accepted under this section in an amount that exceeds a total of $5,000,000 in any fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36B49048C2E64A4BBC622947C9BEB332"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Source of funds</header><text>The Commission may not accept funds under this section from any non-Federal entity—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC1897C0B1CDC43EE92E99BE382BC6A80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is domiciled in, headquartered in, or organized under the laws of, or the principal place of business of which is located in, a foreign country of concern; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB34D04130D014FF4A80BA9CE7D1DCBAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has in place any agreement with a foreign country of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF387FBA63EB9453C9FA7B0F520498E96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the last day of each fiscal year, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the funds accepted under this section that includes a description of—</text> <paragraph id="H1A73856385FF400EB8D068EB997D6E82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the activities carried out with such funds; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1F953864E1147388FB2A7F7BED9801E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>costs associated with such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H79549FFA060A4CDB9A5A9F3B7271CCA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A47972698B84F6DB918A6462AF944AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the United States Section of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD0E2D4D81D04367B033107D6AD8BE57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 10638 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19237">42 U.S.C. 19237</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

