<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC5BCEE8929DB4314A2E810E2940C22B0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 635 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Ghislaine Maxwell should not receive a pardon, commutation, or other form of clemency from the President of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 635</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Ghislaine Maxwell should not receive a pardon, commutation, or other form of clemency from the President of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on December 29, 2021, Ghislaine Maxwell was convicted in the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York on multiple counts related to the sexual abuse and trafficking of minors, including conspiracy to entice minors to travel to engage in illegal sex acts, conspiracy to transport minors to participate in illegal sex acts, transporting a minor to participate in illegal sex acts, sex trafficking conspiracy, and sex trafficking of a minor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas evidence presented at her trial demonstrated that Ghislaine Maxwell actively participated in and facilitated the grooming and abuse of young girls by the now-deceased convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, including by luring children to Epstein’s residence;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 28, 2022, Ghislaine Maxwell was sentenced to 20 years in prison and 5 years of supervised release, and is currently in the custody of the Federal Bureau of Prisons;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell participated in or facilitated the sexual abuse of hundreds of children;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas childhood sexual abuse and sex trafficking are heinous crimes that have lifelong physical and mental health implications for survivors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jeffrey Epstein is deceased, and Ghislaine Maxwell’s ongoing imprisonment is thus the only measure of justice available to these victims;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas there has been significant public speculation regarding the possibility that the President may seek to pardon Ghislaine Maxwell, and when asked about this speculation, he has explicitly affirmed his authority to do so;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Article II, Section 2, Clause I of the Constitution provides the President <quote>shall have Power to grant Reprieves and Pardons for Offences against the United States</quote>; and</text></whereas>
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Framers of the Constitution provided the President with such powers so he could address miscarriages of justice Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9429109146314422BF226045C9D35E3F"> 
<section id="H84996882E8ED4D6EA2C8A52183192A96" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HC1C18422B6BA4579A4837CF71CE60827"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns child sexual abuse, sex trafficking, and those who participate in or facilitate such criminal acts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA0323C907FF8445C934DED99D5BB01EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>stands with the countless victims of Jeffrey Epstein’s and Ghislaine Maxwell’s crimes in their lifelong struggles for healing and closure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5EABCBF51104AD4A29DF57101970ABF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms that Ghislaine Maxwell’s conviction and sentencing were more than warranted by the facts, and any receipt of a pardon, commutation, or other form of clemency by Ghislaine Maxwell would deny survivors the justice they deserve; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8A1BF15C6914EAFA01CA7F99732698F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>formally opposes the granting of a pardon, commutation, or other form of clemency to Ghislaine Maxwell.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

