<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H014CC289027B40DEB7FE5D298726A670" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 185 IH: Recognizing the need of Congress to prevent, address, and treat obesity as a disease in the United States on this World Obesity Day, March 4, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the need of Congress to prevent, address, and treat obesity as a disease in the United States on this World Obesity Day, March 4, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas obesity is a complex and multifactorial condition caused by genetic, environmental, behavioral, and other social determinants of health affecting both children and adults;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas obesity has reached epidemic proportions globally, contributing to a myriad of health issues and impacting the well-being of individuals;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas obesity is associated with an increased risk of developing coronary artery disease, hypertension, high LDL cholesterol, low LDL cholesterol, dyslipidemia, type 2 diabetes, chronic kidney disease, stroke, gallbladder disease, osteoarthritis, sleep apnea, cancer, mental illness, body pain, dementia, asthma, and over 200 others and other types of neurodivergent diseases, respiratory tract infections, and infertility and loss of pregnancy for women;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the costs come from treating obesity and its associated comorbidities are increasing, it is estimated that the annual medical cost of obesity was nearly $173 billion dollars in 2019, while medical costs were found to be $1,861 higher for those with obesity compared to patients at a normal weight;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government spends approximately $283 billion on obesity-related direct health costs in 2023, rising to $526.5 billion by 2033;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the indirect costs of obesity on the economy are the productivity costs included and presenteeism, as well as premature mortality, loss of quality adjusted life years, and higher rates of disability benefit payments;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas obesity continues to have a strong impact on the global economy, the total costs of obesity are estimated to range from 0.05 percent to 2.24 percent of a country’s gross domestic product, and the World Obesity Federation estimates that the global economic impact of obesity will surpass $4 trillion by 2035;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas researchers have estimated that by 2030, if obesity trends continue unchecked, obesity-related medical costs alone could rise by $48 to $66 billion a year in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas obesity-related conditions are among the leading causes of preventable and premature death in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas over 42 percent of adults in the United States and over 19 percent of children and adolescents in the United States are considered obese according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Black-American adults have the highest rates of obesity at 49.9 percent followed by American Indian and Alaska Native adults at 48 percent, Hispanic and Latino Americans at 45.6 percent, White-American adults at 41.4 percent, and Asian-American adults at 16.1 percent;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas children living in families with low incomes are 2.31 times more likely to develop childhood obesity compared to children living in higher income households;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas rural populations are significantly more likely to be obese than people living in urban counties; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas individuals with obesity often face stigma, discrimination, and coverage barriers: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6A84EE511EBB4F20B781B93F43B0CC91"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5E163E8D47C8475A9F4E69A8805CD877"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HF3E36DA5974E4E868FA65E1E95C71488"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the urgent need to prevent, treat, and address obesity as a disease on this World Obesity Day;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B410D70927348A8865FCEF9E0233ECC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the need to categorize obesity as a disease to reduce the risk of other diseases and related comorbidities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA532728A0D34992B03D916F03B606BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>understands that genetic, environmental, behavioral factors, and the social determinants of health contribute to obesity; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H430C86D78EF84BBE9D03F6D88A1F08D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages health care providers and researchers to develop evidence-based strategies for the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of obesity.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

