<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H560DC3C47BF24114AC88234D479BDDD7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3445 IH: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3445</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to make the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection an independent agency led by a commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25D70E02F0E5430AAFC02567A11E991A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4BC56F841BF94B3B8897DE590D27452E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H178BBA47B47A402EAB6FA08987D783EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Making the Bureau an independent agency led by a commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1014FE803C284AC787CBC1EB82BDA3A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1011—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E4FACC36EEC4209AE4631720E726E2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H61384F40427C4E038B0F774001315F26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in the Federal Reserve System,</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FE5F08307434CD898E0368731066381"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>independent bureau</quote> and inserting <quote>independent agency</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8F80DDBA1DC40B5B7D9B8D9C0881A5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b), (c), and (d);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8B1FE27538747C1864418AE233B746A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (j);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H525D38EA2FD84B06B29CFD42EB987990"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (j), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>, including in cities in which the Federal reserve banks, or branches of such banks, are located,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF97B58C3C3A2445D905AB6BBCBDDC704"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B3C777CC1B34695ADFA4F1E3A32F879" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEEA0E956075D4AEBA45971AA3BA75CF2"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Authority To prescribe regulations</header> <text>The commission of the Bureau may prescribe such regulations and issue such orders in accordance with this title as the Bureau may determine to be necessary for carrying out this title and all other laws within the Bureau’s jurisdiction and shall exercise any authorities granted under this title and all other laws within the Bureau’s jurisdiction.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H894D25946F954E0CBE4EE5CD566AF0AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Composition of the commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H77018A95AA5F443A8B4E811435AB735E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The management of the Bureau shall be vested in a commission, which shall be composed of 5 members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5E79C639ECC4169AAA89740DADF6286"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 2 of whom shall have private sector experience in the provision of consumer financial products and services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6307F1CC6DEE4C0896FF4AC58BB1470A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 1 of whom shall have been employed as a State bank supervisor (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1803">12 U.S.C. 1803</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A5BE1ECDFB7477F8F431D81C9A7136D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staggering</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the commission shall serve staggered terms, which initially shall be established by the President for terms of 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 years, respectively.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB68D86B5D9EB4D0BB4524C192F001800"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8E912558847A4C75BE0F2D8829803A13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except with respect to the initial staggered terms described under paragraph (2), each member of the commission, including the Chair, shall serve for a term of 5 years.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E6E0665198C4F06BCD87454593CB674"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may remove any member of the commission for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90C989BCD7E9417B9A298278AF6E9B59"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member of the commission appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term to which that member’s predecessor was appointed (including the Chair) shall be appointed only for the remainder of the term.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF9277C607AC49C7AEFCF06EA6EE52F0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Continuation of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the commission may continue to serve after the expiration of the term of office to which that member was appointed until a successor has been appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate, except that a member may not continue to serve more than 1 year after the date on which that member’s term would otherwise expire.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8AE11403D9A4089BE2F74687FCD1FDA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other employment prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No member of the commission shall engage in any other business, vocation, or employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2473925852B14A8BAFA8AF4882349BFB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Affiliation</header><text>Not more than 3 members of the commission shall be members of any one political party.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E1A3FA351934822AAA9BC8ACC390F54"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chair of the commission</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H80A481839F924C068D9CE6100E7ED2DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial Chair</header><text>The first member and Chair of the commission shall be the individual serving as Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection on the day before the date of the enactment of this subsection. Such individual shall serve until the President has appointed all 5 members of the commission in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDD9154AD0E5D4137A7D6A4AC9CD00BC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the 5 members appointed in accordance with subsection (c), the President shall appoint 1 member to serve as the subsequent Chair of the commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE34A2CB112F74ED2B14F944AD0EE388D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair shall be the principal executive officer of the commission, and shall exercise all of the executive and administrative functions of the commission, including with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H22DEE765229245A6AAC3DEF5A2156459"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appointment and supervision of personnel employed under the commission (other than personnel employed regularly and full time in the immediate offices of members of the commission other than the Chair);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56A90D2141D9414883FBE01906314603"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distribution of business among personnel appointed and supervised by the Chair and among administrative units of the commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1AF6A5D7431E48E894E5080D0B7EE00C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use and expenditure of funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1799A12252D0428CA6EFFEBE1AB2323F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In carrying out any of the Chair’s functions under the provisions of this subsection, the Chair shall be governed by general policies of the commission and by such regulatory decisions, findings, and determinations as the commission may by law be authorized to make.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE6EBA32346944D9852CF1F15065287E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requests or estimates related to appropriations</header><text>Requests or estimates for regular, supplemental, or deficiency appropriations on behalf of the commission may not be submitted by the Chair without the prior approval of the commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD1FD4EE28024849B4F88BA73EE0DA9D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Chair shall be known as both the <quote>Chair of the commission</quote> of the Bureau and the <quote>Chair of the Bureau</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H49E0EB3C63FE498CA0EEEB4351C09B30"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Initial quorum established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the 6 month period beginning on the date of enactment of this subsection, the first member and Chair of the commission described under subsection (e)(1) shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business until the President has appointed all 5 members of the commission in accordance with subsection (c). Following such appointment of 5 members, the quorum requirements of subsection (g) shall apply.</text></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4079CA982A541B5BC0A459DF85AAE0C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No impairment by reason of vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No vacancy in the members of the commission after the establishment of an initial quorum under subsection (f) shall impair the right of the remaining members of the commission to exercise all the powers of the commission. Three members of the commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except that if there are only 3 members serving on the commission because of vacancies in the commission, 2 members of the commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. If there are only 2 members serving on the commission because of vacancies in the commission, 2 members shall constitute a quorum for the 6-month period beginning on the date of the vacancy which caused the number of commission members to decline to 2.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF7E9FBE75076494FAEC985542AA09509"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Seal</header><text>The Bureau shall have an official seal.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB82BF7AE36D542AFA79A820CB7AF0B2C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compensation</header> 
<paragraph id="H3EF91AC5D4634F85BBD806BDB8A2863D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair shall receive compensation at the rate prescribed for level I of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB24821028C34495AAD12644891505C90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other members of the commission</header><text>The 4 other members of the commission shall each receive compensation at the rate prescribed for level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8331691099FE45538E96D0EC8F890D8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1012(c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H00B972B6ED42432D9314AE653A7624B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Autonomy of the Bureau</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Coordination with the Board of Governors</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78412796BBD24A83828D0C649AC19556"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Coordination with the board of governors.—</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7ACBA6FEF30648DC9CF7AB6A18230160"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEE3198D29C447E88BED7664188CF969"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1014(b), by striking <quote>Not fewer than 6 members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the regional Federal Reserve Bank Presidents, on a rotating basis.</quote> and inserting <quote>Not fewer than half of all members shall have private sector experience in the provision of consumer financial products and services.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA01B594F53E84494B010B66AFE4270F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Deeming of name</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reference in a law, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, except in subsection (e)(1) of section 1011 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5491">12 U.S.C. 5491</external-xref>), as added by this Act, shall be deemed a reference to the commission leading and governing the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, as described under section 1011 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010.</text></section> 
<section id="H6D273CF863E1417387E89DFA674A967E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<subsection id="HA12EE12DD4EC433381AC5164B6E01B72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010</header> 
<paragraph id="H52371C7D857A489583CB055183A6F5A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Consumer Financial Protection of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA545520929F742F19C905865527169BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau</quote> each place such term appears, other than where such term is used to refer to a Director other than the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48D386657E5842B28F8E9F7495FB34E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>, other than where such term is used to refer to a Director other than the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88411BC9578047698FC441A61739C295"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 1002, by striking paragraph (10).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D108FF1029E4AED9967D1CF19DA8232"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<subparagraph id="H92388706DD534649B5A6FA658115863B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="HF6F89313B3B9496EBBAB242C6DF061BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in section 1013(c)(3)—</text> 
<subclause id="HE03D2718AD7949249CEA71812871C0AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Assistant Director of the Bureau for</quote> and inserting <quote>Head of the Office of</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB4DEE6262C1C4C8C8543A1D787201125"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>Assistant Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Head of the Office</quote>;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H72B978931FEF4143AB13837B1B1052EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in section 1013(g)(2)—</text> <subclause id="H0BA7693BCC514FCFA95837E2917CF922"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Assistant director</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Head of the Office</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD5FE616E18E344098BC94BA57551CB5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an assistant director</quote> and inserting <quote>a Head of the Office of Financial Protection for Older Americans</quote>;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H3389B5A5B5164E36B372FA7B82DBBAA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in section 1016(a), by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau</quote> and inserting <quote>Chair of the Bureau</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5B083174F4A4FDDB6182C4A9291B488"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking section 1066.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD808035D6D4346D3AC1664582AE219A0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 1066.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0A012BCE14141F3889A4F351795344A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF67925CB2D6D4691ADBB7C095394B730"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 111(b)(1)(D), by striking <quote>Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Chair</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11B40DF1E2444F11B96BF654776C40CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1447, by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Chair of the Bureau</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D100A2171A24165A9588E2DDA4A2B00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Electronic Fund Transfer Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 921(a)(4)(C) of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693o-2">15 U.S.C. 1693o–2(a)(4)(C)</external-xref>), as added by section 1075(a)(2) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Chair of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H274B994BC01C41F993662FF0928E5816"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expedited Funds Availability Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Expedited Funds Availability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4001">12 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 1086 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H31611E4631634E6B94DB5513FB50D92A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal Deposit Insurance Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1812">12 U.S.C. 1812</external-xref>), as amended by section 336(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Chair of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H825E587A4AEA45278A147E79D4F865DC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1004(a)(4) of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3303">12 U.S.C. 3303(a)(4)</external-xref>), as amended by section 1091 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</quote> and inserting <quote>Chair of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H322ED4280CEF47C098F856B3C5466510"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 513 of the Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9702">20 U.S.C. 9702</external-xref>), as amended by section 1013(d)(5) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Chair</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCB585E2B9B842B2A4FFDF074924F867"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 307 of the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (12 U.S.C. 2806 et seq), as amended by section 1094(6) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H243D9BC4A1DE4AFC9B34ADEE22BC4856"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Interstate Land Sales Full Disclosure Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interstate Land Sales Full Disclosure Act (15 U.S.C. 1701 et seq), as amended by section 1098A of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H55A8BA3DAF334A22A6E9D729F01F1EF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1402—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CA4C2ADBA53414B80565B0F45D76601"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD04DC12B600E44FA8A19E72B2F7A29FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (12) as paragraphs (1) through (11), respectively;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6CB3DDDB36C4AC2BAA4DFE7D8C5227C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1403(c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD6F9638FBD92462AA986C6F68238751D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>him</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1700C3A36E6740CCA3666452C89ED0AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72A9A851EE8A4BA7B9887AFEF465D27E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1407—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA773FBCAA5F4D1EBE444F9E1E7FAC5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC23AADE4BE5240DF807574DD864CC25E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by striking <quote>Director or anyone designated by him</quote> and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B09BD9C7A6F4BDFA1A3D032980B6A13"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1411(a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36C67A85D95644B0A28C09FB52945C58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his findings</quote> and inserting <quote>the findings of the Bureau</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB40C5C6F965F4A50A25E4509A8801759"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his recommendation</quote> and inserting <quote>the recommendation of the Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B301777A0864A0CA60AD4259D69972A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 1415—</text> <subparagraph id="H5DC25091826245E694D675E1FE79D0CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>he may, in his discretion,</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau may, in the discretion of the Bureau,</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA7FDE8B0A6D43E48BB445C2E8AD2F09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H06B768F7FD164A78A6E4B9AD87DA0C40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in his discretion</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>in the discretion of the Bureau</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF640BFBDEA348AB8E1738DD856C79C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he deems</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau determines</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC2E065591941437BA2C7A644375347C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he may deem</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau may determine</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA464CCB183E140C89BA2201B71FBA774"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>the Director, or any officer designated by him,</quote> and inserting <quote>the Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51501FB506634ED1B221C21C1402B6F8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 1416(a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3F6B121555474E48B6FF5DC5337026E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection who may delegate any of his</quote> and inserting <quote>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, which may delegate any</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD18E00DDE8AB41FABE137F8D6B856299"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his administrative</quote> and inserting <quote>administrative</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7AE4D72A7E27496386DF0A796463E09E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>himself</quote> and inserting <quote>the commission of the Bureau</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D20409F1EBF46239A043AA99C50A0B8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 1418a(b)(4), by striking <quote>Secretary’s determination</quote> and inserting <quote>determination of the Bureau</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5997584BD056459FA4437FD35630E6AC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H54E6F434A10E4869AD8202341E7FF48E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2604">12 U.S.C. 2604</external-xref>), as amended by section 1450 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H55679395C4F44FA98C0B712B633B1B55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>)</quote> and inserting <quote>The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Bureau</quote>)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5135835D81A14F508E5D9982F8974CDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Bureau</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D108F0A6AB446EFA05EA465F9D1605D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5101">12 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 1100 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB4BB81E7499E4B0EB24D1678ED69979F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place such term appears in headings and text and inserting <quote>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A43BF59DE9D4B44A9D80A6275DD3C0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1503, by striking paragraph (10).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5CFF36B6DFF04AEFA2DFE4BD637AC403"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Title 44, United States Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3513(c) of title 44, United States Code, as amended by section 1100D(b) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, is amended by striking <quote>Director of the</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

