<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96AFC1D7FD484D1FB6B96DCB6AD5F065" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3498 IH: Henrietta Lacks Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3498</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award posthumously a Congressional Gold Medal to Henrietta Lacks, in recognition of her immortal cells which have made invaluable contributions to global health, scientific research, our quality of life, and patients’ rights.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H96D58EDC856C45119137EF6D38869BB5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3C829D37BA16477BB184D889F6220F94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Henrietta Lacks Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA0BC620D81F24912B2147236B404F5E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0F22D13CD1994068AC3C2299682DBFB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Henrietta Lacks, an African-American woman born on August 1, 1920, in Roanoke, Virginia, was raised by her grandfather on a tobacco farm in Clover, Virginia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78AC3C2D942D4CF3BDEC9C54BDCD9546"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Henrietta Lacks, her husband, and family moved to Baltimore, Maryland, in 1941 seeking economic opportunity at the Bethlehem Steel Plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9CC3C6C78424A30956D1A1C7EB517D9">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>In 1951, Henrietta Lacks sought treatment for her continuous vaginal bleeding from The Johns Hopkins Hospital, which was one of the few hospitals willing to treat African Americans at that time. Gynecologists discovered a large, malignant tumor on her cervix.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H566E67BFE48D4517881052C25AEDF567"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Unbeknownst to Henrietta Lacks or her family, medical researchers took samples of Henrietta Lacks’ tumor during her treatment without her consent. Henrietta Lacks’ cells, now known as <quote>HeLa Cells</quote>, doubled every 20 to 24 hours whereas other human cells died in the same time period. The HeLa Cells are the first known immortal line of human cells in history.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB43EB2891B54AF59B6896D96B4870BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On October 4, 1951, 31-year-old Henrietta Lacks died of an aggressive cervical cancer eight months after her cancer diagnosis, leaving behind her husband and 5 children.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CBE01FFFCFF4DEBAD51D0A4789D330D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The HeLa immortal cell line is the oldest and most used human cell line used in scientific research. Henrietta Lacks’ immortal cells have been commercialized and distributed worldwide to researchers, resulting in groundbreaking advancements in modern science and technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B8806DB8A4C428A9BB226B207288DEF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Henrietta Lacks’ prolific cells continue to replicate to this day and contribute to remarkable advances in medicine, including the development of the polio vaccine and drugs used to treat cancer, HIV/AIDS, hemophilia, leukemia, and Parkinson’s disease. HeLa cells have been used in research that has contributed to our understanding of the effects of radiation and zero gravity on human cells, and have informed research on chromosomal conditions, cancer, gene mapping, and precision medicine.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9022EFC691C84EFEB801A74E66224140"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The use of HeLa cells as the foundation for biomedical research has led to several Nobel Prize winning discoveries. The National Institute of Health located over 110,000 publications that cited the use of HeLa cells between 1953 to 2018. These advances were made possible by Henrietta Lacks’ cells, yet the revenues they generated were not known to her family for more than twenty years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CEF1F3E00234E4B803D4396B9A77489"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Henrietta Lacks is a linchpin to modern bioethics policies and informed consent laws that benefit patients nationwide by building patient trust and protecting research participants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9DD4E28732E4387BBE6EC73EB1DA4EA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Henrietta Lacks’ legacy has been recognized around the world through memorials, conferences, museum exhibitions, libraries, and print and visual media for changing the face of medical science.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H85613D9A20EE4EB7ADC7E761470CABE6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="H739DF0AA05BF4D82AE31E3CCD7CCA3F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of Henrietta Lacks, in recognition of her immortal cells which have made invaluable contributions to global health, scientific research, our quality of life, and patients’ rights.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB42DE6F062BF43E3B1C6805D68FBC539"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6E316E1ACB074147B5FC90505DAA0CE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian Institution</header> <paragraph id="HDF40A38EA8234E1D98D1B423196E5285"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be available for display as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H247216E55BF347B78EFFA8ECAF0A45DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with Henrietta Lacks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H75C7CF42742847759B3CDFAB2EF2BDB7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> 
<section id="HF47E3076D7974C31AEC13EE33140D46A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> 
<subsection id="HA7C29AFC76F34C86B73922324D844793"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB603E2482AE0418BBE6E11C39AB249D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7CD5DB7270A54FFF8478A260ACCDCBC9" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> 
<subsection id="H4710FED25A244CEF87C79CAD4520E727" commented="no">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF54C65102DF14263BF08F2C48B88B87F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>The amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

