<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC60D463D2CF943B68F59D3876045704F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3905 IH: Judicial Review Timeline Clarity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act with respect to judicial review of the issuance of a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill material, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC4D9B6331DC64BEAA40BF734B326F0B2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5151C2859942492D97E83BBB63F61EB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Judicial Review Timeline Clarity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB632EDE5F4ED48B2B05B40A6C341E7B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Judicial review timeline clarity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H43E1D981D8FC483482649CD61AD3E238"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (t) as subsection (u);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H389EB6B6BC0E42C7B45FE92638B8C7B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (u), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Nothing in the section</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Savings provision.—</header-in-text>Nothing in this section</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2976E1B1426046568D213DAD2C17E272"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (s) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H810ADA4C3B2F452B8CEE029FED15AF5F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD46789F62B8E4FE98376FC0AD4D3D696"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> <paragraph id="H0B20DDB35F5A49098FA4C25988C11A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>Notwithstanding any applicable provision of law relating to statutes of limitations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D4D3A29E5394E3998E1D91830703EBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an action seeking judicial review of an individual permit or general permit issued under this section shall be filed not later than the date that is 60 days after the date on which the permit was issued; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10C4E546D80B4CEDA872A1CC57C43704"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an action seeking judicial review of a verification that an activity involving a discharge of dredged or fill material is authorized by a general permit issued under this section shall be filed not later than the date that is 60 days after the date on which such verification was issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6996B7CABEA4DC6B927290D27C508CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on commencement of certain actions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no action described in paragraph (1) may be commenced unless the action—</text> <subparagraph id="H03A72A1D51344F98A333BA96F253242E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is filed by a party that submitted a comment—</text> 
<clause id="H6B3612845333402889E226F81352643A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>during the public comment period for the administrative proceedings related to the applicable action described in such paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7D3555F6C8F54652B2520320029B6067"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which was sufficiently detailed to put the Secretary or the State, as applicable, on notice of the issue upon which the party seeks judicial review; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACBA9C9ED5E5491ABC61D72C161539E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is related to such comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAB5CE1BEE2D4A60B637AF944F97C719"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>If a court determines that the Secretary or the State, as applicable, did not comply with the requirements of this section in issuing an individual or general permit under this section, or in verifying that an activity involving a discharge of dredged or fill material is authorized by a general permit issued under this section, as applicable—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC346318B9314D49A6D2FAFA59635F0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary or the State, as applicable, for further proceedings consistent with the determination of the court;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EFB6F9349654DAEA5490C9C1265748A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a determination regarding the issuance of an individual or general permit under this section, the court may not vacate, revoke, enjoin, or otherwise limit the permit, unless the court finds that activities authorized under the permit would present an imminent and substantial danger to human health or the environment for which there is no other equitable remedy available under the law; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2174E926DC0C46F689E6AFADD05015BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a determination regarding a verification that an activity involving a discharge of dredged or fill material is authorized by a general permit issued under this section, the court may not enjoin or otherwise limit the discharge unless the court finds that the activity would present an imminent and substantial danger to human health or the environment for which there is no other equitable remedy available under the law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94D5270F35074B7A978EED34F6575ACB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timeline to act on court order</header><text>If a court remands a matter under paragraph (2), the court shall set and enforce a reasonable schedule and deadline, which may not exceed 180 days from the date on which the court remands such matter, except as otherwise required by law, for the Secretary or the State, as applicable, to take such actions as the court may order.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

