<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA8C3CE489CA43A6ABFC3D2A8248A2EF" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 671 IH: Prioritizing mental health to the same degree as physical health to address the epidemics of suicide and drug overdose in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 671</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Prioritizing mental health to the same degree as physical health to address the epidemics of suicide and drug overdose in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas mental health and physical health are inseparable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mental health conditions require the same degree of attention as physical health conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mental health and substance use parity requirements for health insurance plans must be firmly enforced;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this resolution referred to as <quote>CDC</quote>), in 2023, suicide was responsible for 49,316 deaths, or about 1 death every 11 minutes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, in 2023, an estimated 110,037 lives were lost to drug overdoses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the World Health Organization, mental health and many common mental disorders are significantly shaped by the social, economic, and physical environments in which people live;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas social vulnerability, a metric that quantifies the impact of the social determinants of health on county-level populations, is directly associated with risk for adult suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to research published in Addictive Behaviors Reports, adults with a history of adverse childhood experiences (in this resolution referred to as <quote>ACEs</quote>) have a 4.3-fold higher likelihood of developing a substance use disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cultural stigma against mental health disorders is an especially notable social determinant of mental health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a growing body of research on the association between mental health stigma and suicidal actions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas additional research must be conducted to better understand the relationship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cultural stigma against mental illness can lead individuals to engage in self-medication practices, such as illicit drug use, instead of seeking out professional assistance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration’s (in this resolution referred to as <quote>SAMHSA</quote>) 2024 National Survey on Drug Use and Health Report, an estimated 23.4 percent, or 61,500,000, adults aged 18 or older reported having any mental illness (in this resolution referred to as <quote>AMI</quote>) in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, an estimated 5.6 percent, or 14,600,000, adults aged 18 or older reported having a serious mental illness (in this resolution referred to as <quote>SMI</quote>) in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, in 2024, among adults aged 18 or older, those who reported having SMI or AMI in the past year were more likely to have been past year users of illicit drugs than those without mental illness in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, 57.4 percent of adults aged 18 or older with SMI and 44.1 percent of adults with AMI reported to have been past-year users of illicit drugs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 21.2 percent for adults aged 18 or older with no mental illness reported to have been past year users of illicit drugs; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, in 2024, 16.8 percent of individuals aged 12 or older had a substance use disorder in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, to prevent the perpetuation of this dangerous cycle, mental health education and awareness must begin from an early age, and school-based mental health resources must be better utilized and better funded to achieve this goal; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mental illness stigma, and specifically self-stigma, is a significant barrier to mental health services for adolescents and adults that must be addressed: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6EF2FC3B183949C49E3E069E4E4C3C1B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8BF32324B769441B990A0BB934EBC119"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H27721299409446F6B33D930D0105702A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for parity between insurance coverage of mental health and physical health treatment, including full enforcement of existing Federal laws concerning mental health parity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H543D48919F8D42218EA10729CCA149D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">works to extinguish mental health stigmas in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE233026DD1041A19476FB565B649FB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the 2024 National Strategy for Suicide Prevention; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF8B5FF19C9A4D37B256AF1932116639"><enum>(4)</enum><text>seeks to provide as many resources and funds as possible to combat the epidemics of suicide and drug overdose by—</text><subparagraph id="H035FC8F0274B4FCA95A3A1DF29BD92E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting Federal, State, Tribal, and local initiatives to retain and expand the mental health workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1989A8757C14383BD98E7575EF608A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting access to and coverage of medication-assisted treatment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CDBCC24591442EA86333CE6E534F6EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopting evidence-based suicide prevention strategies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2824BAD5D99A4A1F8EF8F07EB5D043F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>funding linguistically, culturally, and age appropriate services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA33068776C947B8A548EA29FF74CB51"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving quality, coverage, and accessibility of crisis care service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF748171081584F74B7A53A8491BDABBF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>highlighting health promotion campaigns that utilize digital media to target adolescents and young adults.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

