<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25E81-KFS-JK-L32"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2560 IS: Uyghur Genocide Accountability and Sanctions Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2560</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To expand the imposition of sanctions under the Uyghur Human Rights Policy
            Act of 2020 with respect to human rights abuses in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region
            of the People’s Republic of China and to counter the genocidal policies of the
 Government of the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H36DB6B561D3C461FAEE587BB363045F2"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1A2B48D8450140C6A9CD6207F93A1EB7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H8FC71D3BDA56436391B20F961CCCAAD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uyghur Genocide Accountability and Sanctions Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDD4637DC7AD4D268591927B09C0BCB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H1A2B48D8450140C6A9CD6207F93A1EB7">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H26C201C171D64280B84EF84D04D6139C">Sec. 2. Expansion of sanctions under Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H578757312A3647A98918A7050CF5AA84">Sec. 3. Denial of United States entry for individuals complicit in forced abortions or forced sterilizations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H87700E64E6B54E729FB7267240719FDE">Sec. 4. Physical and psychological support for Uyghurs, Kazakhs, and other ethnic groups.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5B6F0BBE9ECE4053A8106B9269F3B686">Sec. 5. Preservation of cultural, religious, and linguistic heritage of ethnic and religious groups oppressed by the People’s Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA256CD7227B24F65A2D30054025E76A9">Sec. 6. Determination of whether actions of certain Chinese entities meet criteria for imposition of sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H10991A8ED26F4FACA2273F1DC9D17A04">Sec. 7. Countering propaganda from the People’s Republic of China about genocide and crimes against humanity.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H0CDDC1103D60460096F9FFB366E85C26">Sec. 8. Documenting atrocities in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H350DBFA650594923A5B55EAC26C3F72F">Sec. 9. Prohibition on certain United States Government agency contracts.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H3107451FCF0849119D4E631BD9452B48">Sec. 10. Strategy to address allegations of forced organ harvesting in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H4614F2D87AFE473BBD86C66FBF24C4B2">Sec. 11. Information on detained family members of United States citizens in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0c5095acb0a44d45b9d61c80638e73ce">Sec. 12. Report on ability of Department of Defense to identify prohibited seafood imports in supply chain for food procurement.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H60B1DCDA85264344BF98FE69AC15C233">Sec. 13. Prohibition on procurement and commissary sales of seafood originating or processed in the People’s Republic of China.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H26C201C171D64280B84EF84D04D6139C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of sanctions under Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020</header><subsection id="HDDA81D76980B42CCA461FFB3E318BE69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6 of the Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/145">Public Law 116–145</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6F65A5EF45664E4FBBEDD894E9E3A1EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HE1E87E1B0DFC489293BAF0E99E3B243D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H74EE344CA21547D7B8B52013B18B8F92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>persons in Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region</quote> and inserting <quote>persons residing in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region or members of those groups in countries outside of the People’s Republic of China</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HE5C4386ED17E49ADA1382809EE918B71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H67E4FFA43D564DE5B03A5838804D282E"><subparagraph id="HD5672529F423487AB0CE0110002E5DF7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Systematic rape, coercive abortion, forced sterilization, or involuntary contraceptive implantation policies and practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD22A00C58BDF4D37A722FAC164532D4C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Human trafficking for the purpose of organ removal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H309827A9499D41C38C18E7E072EB513B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Forced separation of children from their parents to be placed in boarding schools.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CD52FE1B22247F8BA29B8221B7D4986"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Forced deportation or refoulement to the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H837012F9124C438FA1B75EF24F0F0567"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF069AF558C724BA7B16BF15A1F7B2A12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8699DB502734A618D0C6D137FF4A7F8"><paragraph id="HDD6A876F16A641E9B4DCEF854CAF5F88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional matters to be included</header><text>The President shall include in the report required by paragraph (1) an identification of—</text><subparagraph id="H0AB7BC9DF0D940D1BC85A6A000606A06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each foreign person that knowingly provides significant goods, services, or technology to or for a person identified in the report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9EA46330C394B619960562B9EC288DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each foreign person that knowingly engages in a significant transaction relating to any of the acts described in subparagraphs (A) through (J) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94583475FA384BD5801E758FBBBE33BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22E8994FBCB9448F93FE62B40D6C0B6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H32EB28A0B05A4A38A9170E9E36275DA2"><subsection id="HDFE0FA0A71F0495898174ADB71D406B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation; regulatory authority</header><paragraph id="H1161B2E02B1B4FF2B59F774BD0F491C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under section 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6ED3F801EB40D88E577D6B1C2DE15C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFEE5A5F7280B4B18A54FD76C31D2D18E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section—</text><paragraph id="H9848ABB927D3412086145E771732AF06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5074006BE80142338F44DA042C614971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply with respect to the first report required by section 6(a)(1) of the Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020 submitted after such date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H578757312A3647A98918A7050CF5AA84"><enum>3.</enum><header>Denial of United States entry for individuals complicit in forced abortions or
 forced sterilizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 801 of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182e">8 U.S.C. 1182e</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H250FFD0592704DFF897B730DFBBE681E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>may not</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>shall not</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC0363ECCB04645985F585505ACBF44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFB0A1AC5665F4B7E8D0E3A7E59932F62"><subsection id="H5B56AFB785344380924ED8FF28127FF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of State may waive the prohibitions in subsection (a) with respect to a foreign national if the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H6FB2BC588F6048B0A9AED56B1143A526"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H78840B69091F4C0693AC6740964C0CEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the foreign national is not directly complicit in atrocities, specifically the oversight of programs or policies the intent of which is to destroy, in whole or in part, a national, ethnic, racial, or religious group through the use of forced sterilization, forced abortion, or other egregious population control policies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9E87E6EC06342E6BFD9A163EF896EDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>admitting or paroling the foreign national into the United States is necessary—</text><clause id="H22B4BD6F70C143E2A63556F5A966A392"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success on June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="H7742E2E8E26C402B9FD42E229622BE8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activity of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51230BA7A9B54A64BF71DF0012D49000"><enum>(C)</enum><text>it is important to the national security interest of the United States to admit or parole the foreign national into the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3253FAD49F47447EA3FFD7143794633A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides written notification to the appropriate congressional committees containing a justification for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB365D05D14143BBA391A82D3D8E39D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of State shall make a public announcement whenever the prohibitions under subsection (a) are imposed under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3A56E2420854B46A08547CB2B03CBDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information requested by congress</header><text>The Secretary of State, upon the request of a Member of Congress, shall provide information about the use of the prohibitions under subsection (a), including the number of times such prohibitions were imposed, disaggregated by country and by year and whether additional sanctions under any other Act were employed to advance the purposes of this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H87700E64E6B54E729FB7267240719FDE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Physical and psychological support for Uyghurs, Kazakhs, and other ethnic
 groups</header><subsection id="H335DB1F5D28E4A4785CEC3F12FC83EF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="H8BDDEF20D6504BB6BEF46606BE2106C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Using funds appropriated to the Department of State in annual appropriations Acts under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="appropriations">DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANCE</header-in-text></quote>, the Secretary of State is authorized, subject to the requirements under chapters 1 and 10 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 634A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394-1">22 U.S.C. 2394–1</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HD33BDC9803534C5B8B89CD5716F002AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide the assistance described in paragraph (2) to individuals who—</text><clause id="HFC7D6566616349F287916238C9130417"><enum>(i)</enum><text>belong to the Uyghur, Kazakh, Kyrgyz, or another oppressed ethnic group in the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause><clause id="H0F4E57542780486FB5CAB0D94D3ED8D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>experienced torture, forced sterilization, rape, forced abortion, forced labor, or other atrocities in the People’s Republic of China; and</text></clause><clause id="H8B856C0A5797499F95A1711556AE40F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are residing outside of the People’s Republic of China; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D3DB402592C48DFA96ECC9F649F0226"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to build local capacity for the assistance described in paragraph (2) through—</text><clause id="HAE294988549A4388BE2C8095E79A5D92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grants to treatment centers and programs in foreign countries in accordance with section 130(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152">22 U.S.C. 2152(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HCD930A2317364C7E87F24CA2A0393CA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>research and training to health care providers outside of such treatment centers or programs in accordance with section 130(c)(2) of such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E9DA2DC2DA84A859D753DEEDCA17A40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized assistance</header><text>The assistance described in this paragraph is—</text><subparagraph id="H7016F4F87E1A41BB9E79CE10A12466EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>medical care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C9AE21498724F37BB277530E54BCE5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>physical therapy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAC2AF235E3C444C9BD7928736D0E745"><enum>(C)</enum><text>psychological support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC90EB5F27C5B4884A6FBA27019E38DCC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="HFADFB9291A5749609C9242DFED6D21F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the direct care or services provided in foreign countries for individuals described in subsection (a)(1)(A); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEB3119703F745CA9C70BE6901B0356C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any projects started or supported in foreign countries to provide the care or services described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H033B27DDB2754B7D81066ABF99131F9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Not more than 50 percent of the costs of providing the assistance authorized under subsection (a) may be paid by the United States Government.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5B6F0BBE9ECE4053A8106B9269F3B686"><enum>5.</enum><header>Preservation of cultural, religious, and linguistic heritage of ethnic and
 religious groups oppressed by the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="H303BB62D935643F1B160B0236D542661"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that the genocide and crimes against humanity perpetrated by officials of the Government of the People’s Republic of China in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region aim to erase the distinct cultural, religious, and linguistic heritage of oppressed ethnic and religious groups.</text></subsection><subsection id="H782C7172FF3D4F4B82A5D3304BBE2360"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Government should use its diplomatic, development, and cultural activities to promote the preservation of cultural, religious, and linguistic heritages of ethnic and religious groups in the People’s Republic of China threatened by officials of the Government of People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFE9B922886041A9B015AC584568140A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="H01FF3703C6C2441E94DDAB05A98468B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the feasibility of establishing a grant program to assist communities facing threats to their cultural, religious, and linguistic heritage from officials of the Government of the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0C408C6245F453B91CDC092DE34CDAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides recommendations for Congress with respect to whether such a program needs additional authorities or funding.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24A681E06331473F94397E4CEA7A71C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, to support the establishment of a Repressed Cultures Preservation Initiative within the Smithsonian Institution to pool Institution-wide efforts toward research, exhibitions, and education related to the cultural, religious, and linguistic heritage of ethnic and religious groups the cultures of which are threatened by repressive regimes, including officials of the Government of People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA256CD7227B24F65A2D30054025E76A9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Determination of whether actions of certain Chinese entities meet criteria for
 imposition of sanctions</header><subsection id="H64919CEEF49C48588EE264103E170BDD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall—</text><paragraph id="HA7C25EB8587F4E0A94064423D8DBAC57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine whether any entity specified in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HE4D530C8CFFE453EA3B0CE2BAC9F1764"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuses against Uyghurs or other predominantly Muslim ethnic groups in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FE993CD9B7F4E3DA865382614AF17DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the criteria for the imposition of sanctions under—</text><clause id="H57BD8F0298F64BB9B4F176BFE6F7A1BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HC52D48FB6AA04FD192042C41B3D3C4B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 6 of the Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/145">Public Law 116–145</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="H699C54CFE5AA4C39985FBE2D2966AA6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 105, 105A, 105B, or 105C of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8514">22 U.S.C. 8514</external-xref>, 8514a, 8514b, and 8514c);</text></clause><clause id="H0661A0FE4EE94DD3A0533FD5658389D9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Executive Order 13818 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking the property of persons involved in serious human rights abuse or corruption), as amended on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></clause><clause id="HB58735BD7C5D4F3483EC0BA5E0FDAEE8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Executive Order 13553 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to serious human rights abuses by the Government of Iran and taking certain other actions), as amended on or after the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3C26C77B9C04ABF92FEBD52FB458ADE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Secretary of the Treasury determines under paragraph (1) that an entity is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuses described in subparagraph (A) of that paragraph or meets the criteria for the imposition of sanctions described in subparagraph (B) of that paragraph, include the entity on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD84B82D9AA34BE2BD944E5455D80ECC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on that determination that includes the reasons for the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6423F2D5F529474B9140EB68C4113DFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entities specified</header><text>An entity specified in this subsection is any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H52D0EB15D479402EB444D4770E73D66D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6BF8F96C6AE4BDCBEC978A8BA39AFBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Shenzhen Huada Gene Technology Co., Ltd. (BGI Group).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93240A63E89847C6BBD6458F8C652E3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Tiandy Technologies Co., Ltd.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16624D43708D4B1091A89482E33EE363"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Zhejiang Dahua Technology Co., Ltd.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C661C7C62DE499CA15C0E1229A07F94"><enum>(5)</enum><text>China Electronics Technology Group Co.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB5EFBBE02314C14B9BA983DB8A9A14A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Zhejiang Uniview Technologies Co., Ltd.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE209FEB91E8F42CDA9782CCEE4E9F7AB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ByteDance Ltd.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B36416C658C47A4BA8A9D4B95009575"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by subsection (a)(3) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H10991A8ED26F4FACA2273F1DC9D17A04"><enum>7.</enum><header>Countering propaganda from the People’s Republic of China about genocide and
 crimes against humanity</header><subsection id="HA475B22F574746A7A7179E366A27DF07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a strategy for countering propaganda and other messaging from news and information sources associated with the Government of the People’s Republic of China or entities associated with the Chinese Communist Party or influenced by the Chinese Communist Party or the Government of the People’s Republic of China that—</text><paragraph id="H93DE8B9AB2554BCF9924258D53EC5599"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deny the genocide, crimes against humanity, and other egregious human rights abuses experienced by Uyghurs and other predominantly Muslim ethnic groups in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF367FB9099AB450FA7C7B2094FD2C0E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>spread propaganda regarding the role of the United States Government in imposing economic and reputational costs on the Chinese Communist Party or the Government of the People’s Republic of China for its ongoing genocide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24EB3A7923CD4213A3CEEC349DE42035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>target Uyghurs and other people who publicly oppose the Government of the People’s Republic of China’s genocidal policies and forced labor practices, including the detention and intimidation of their family members; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE45986E3671344F0AEB6A5B23A476FE2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increase pressure on member countries of the United Nations to deny or defend genocide or other egregious violations of internationally recognized human rights in the People’s Republic of China within international organizations and multilateral fora, including at the United Nations Human Rights Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0B2A2866B8943479C9EB95580ABF8CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HE932AB26358F4D4EACBE86FB4A234E8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>existing messaging strategies and specific broadcasting efforts to counter the propaganda described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) and the reach of such strategies and efforts to audiences targeted by such propaganda;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4763315E43414EE08A66A8B76287720A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specific metrics used for determining the success or failure of the messaging strategies and media efforts to reach targeted audiences through radio, television, social media, print, and any other means of broadcasting or media and an analysis of the impact of such strategies and efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE15E2BDDEB41D4B7EF2B2456E2C65F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any new or pilot messaging strategies and media efforts expected to be implemented during the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and an explanation of the need for such strategies and efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FCCD403CA3C478D92F0EFFCD77898EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>measurable goals to be completed during the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and tangible outcomes for expanding broadcasting efforts and countering propaganda; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE3580C719DB4A44A8EEBB6293F150C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>estimates of additional funding needed to counter the propaganda described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2823EFA866C4208B3B747E80627BDCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized to use amounts made available for the Countering PRC Influence Fund under section 7043(c)(2) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022 (division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 646) to develop and carry out the strategy required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H0CDDC1103D60460096F9FFB366E85C26"><enum>8.</enum><header>Documenting atrocities in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State may provide assistance, including financial and technical assistance, as necessary and appropriate, to support the efforts of entities, including nongovernmental organizations with expertise in international criminal investigations and law, to address genocide, crimes against humanity, and their constituent crimes by the Government of the People’s Republic of China by—</text><paragraph id="HE1C76005717942B484B58F0C9E1054AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collecting, documenting, and archiving evidence, including the testimonies of victims and visuals from social media, and preserving the chain of custody for such evidence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC9F55269BE4DFD8A9A1FDF6F5BCA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying suspected perpetrators of genocide and crimes against humanity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79BFF50C89F44422AD88AFF476BBA719"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducting criminal investigations of atrocity crimes, including by developing indigenous investigative and judicial skills through partnerships, direct mentoring, and providing the necessary equipment and infrastructure to effectively adjudicate cases for use in prosecutions in domestic courts, hybrid courts, and internationalized domestic courts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FA315632A2A4EBF8D13C3454EDE75B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supporting investigations conducted by foreign countries, civil society groups, and multilateral organizations, such as the United Nations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DE6C65C913E4E81BEF740EDF8E6008A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting and protecting witnesses participating in such investigations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H350DBFA650594923A5B55EAC26C3F72F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain United States Government agency contracts</header><subsection id="H5D48E6F30C60452D86457BC4BD949855"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not enter into a contract for the procurement of goods or services with or for any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H37D959AE5B7F45A4A61CAD8A8C37B82A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any person identified in the report required by section 6(a) of the Uyghur Human Rights Policy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/145">Public Law 116–145</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58EF53617E6F415DB0446017A2CB1D72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any person that mined, produced, or manufactured goods, wares, articles, and merchandise detained and denied entry into the United States by U.S. Customs and Border Protection pursuant to section 3 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to ensure that goods made with forced labor in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China do not enter the United States market, and for other purposes</quote>, approved December 23, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/78">Public Law 117–78</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H751A47CE919E4DE98D1FC84196812B63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any person that the head of the executive agency determines, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, facilitates the genocide and human rights abuses occurring in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE367DBB353CB41CDBD767D940B39F2FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any person, program, project, or activity that—</text><subparagraph id="H72F13255F9B14E4DA467396225B5AA96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contributes to forced labor, particularly through the procurement of any goods, wares, articles, and merchandise mined, produced, or manufactured wholly, or in part, in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region or by the forced labor of ethnic Uyghurs or other persecuted individuals or groups in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6DB89D0C3CF4F2EBA08224E59E4DAE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>violates internationally recognized worker rights of individuals in the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6853342D403E48FDB5D7FD88760248B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The head of each executive agency shall consult with the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force, established under section 741 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4681">19 U.S.C. 4681</external-xref>), with respect to the implementation of subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4AE33BF75C9043238B1FCB45BC4BE4A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit a report on the implementation of this section to—</text><paragraph id="HACBAE6C30AA44813A6A06C1135D677F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4B32DD620E4F89AD47E127BB2245B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4FDC585D72940E1A2BCCB6C7B70EB79"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0C8AC4EA56494E998BEC29C6BD4EEF54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A4D6FE7F18F4C378C324EDD226A6803"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Internationally recognized worker rights</header><text>The term <term>internationally recognized worker rights</term> has the meaning given in section 507 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2467">19 U.S.C. 2467</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3107451FCF0849119D4E631BD9452B48"><enum>10.</enum><header>Strategy to address allegations of forced organ harvesting in the Xinjiang
 Uyghur Autonomous Region</header><subsection id="H00E7B3BDC299427685705310E1BBF459"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress—</text><paragraph id="H8331521C83D24EB0B779A0F2B5487402"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a determination with respect to whether the practice of forced organ harvesting has occurred in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region and to what extent the practice has been used from 2017 to the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE996C1656136437B97854071A5D516DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to the determination required by paragraph (1), a strategy to address forced organ harvesting in the People’s Republic of China and hold accountable individuals and entities engaged in the practice of human trafficking for the purpose of organ removal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H222EC97A658242D598F7DDEB2134C81C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To Be included</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HF4708D258F0443CB9CF48EA1E81C66C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specific steps to be taken to address the practice of forced organ harvesting in the People’s Republic of China and an analysis of what efforts in the past, if any, proved to be an effective deterrent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36130EB754C341789F9A932B96614784"><enum>(2)</enum><text>details on bilateral and multilateral diplomatic outreach to address the issue of forced organ harvesting, including the number and level of diplomatic discussions that have occurred with member states of the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation on the issue of forced organ harvesting and organ tourism by citizens of such member states to the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1FD555AB654EDF801E8E3A243D2B1F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>details on the use of existing rewards programs of the Department of State to seek actionable information on forced organ harvesting in the People’s Republic of China and whether additional authorities or funding are needed from Congress to expand such programs for that purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C4AFC054E414E09B707E83A4646F6C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Secretary of State may consult with the Director of National Intelligence and the head of any other relevant Federal agency in carrying out the requirements of subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H4614F2D87AFE473BBD86C66FBF24C4B2"><enum>11.</enum><header>Information on detained family members of United States citizens in the Xinjiang
 Uyghur Autonomous Region</header><subsection id="H5444BFDAF37F4447A6D6A7E2B287D031"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall, as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, begin compiling information on the family members of United States citizens and legal permanent residents detained or missing in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region, particularly those detained to silence or intimidate United States citizens or legal permanent residents engaged in human rights advocacy or journalism or those arrested because they participated in programs carried out by the Department of State, including—</text><paragraph id="HADAD2528E5DB49FA9DBF735B593C8A66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Gulshan Abbas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76C1081052684E11ABA7DA9F53F474F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ekpar Asat; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD81697D7FAA644999458B12B8F3417E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>employees of Radio Free Asia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H830B1C4B44244EB4AED25B2830E684FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The information compiled under subsection (a) should be used by United States Government officials and Members of Congress during interactions with officials from the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="H225F1502F09D4CD78E7325989E8A61F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Aggregation of information</header><text>The Secretary of State should consider aggregating the information compiled under subsection (a) for Members of Congress by State and congressional district of the United States citizens and legal permanent residents described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E2DB02F2185455EBA1AD16A468A8B0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State should consult with the Uyghur-American community to ensure that concerns about the safety of their families are taken into account.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0c5095acb0a44d45b9d61c80638e73ce"><enum>12.</enum><header>Report on ability of Department of Defense to identify prohibited seafood
 imports in supply chain for food procurement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a report assessing whether the Department has policies and procedures in place to verify that the food the Department procures does not include seafood originating in the People’s Republic of China the importation of which is prohibited under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>), including pursuant to a presumption under—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3660585763c42dc8fef8afd8f38b7c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 3 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to ensure that goods made with forced labor in the Xinjiang Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China do not enter the United States market, and for other purposes</quote>, approved December 23, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/78">Public Law 117–78</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act</quote>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4c2e0c996f342b8b3385c2ce8728208"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 302A of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9241a">22 U.S.C. 9241a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H60B1DCDA85264344BF98FE69AC15C233"><enum>13.</enum><header>Prohibition on procurement and commissary sales of seafood originating or
                processed in the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="HF5C1DFF6327B4DE1A30045BA85D8CC97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on procurement of seafood originating or processed in the
 People's Republic of China for military dining facilities</header><paragraph id="H9D6887B3B69E40C190218CE16BE3B47C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2) or (3), the Secretary of Defense may not enter into a contract for the procurement of seafood or seafood products that originate or are processed in the People’s Republic of China for use in military dining facilities, including galleys onboard United States naval vessels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB6AD060F71342EEB0A76B3DE745F727"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="HF1C20365CFC4439CB3D338E224F972D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Undue burden</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, or a designee of the Secretary, may grant exceptions to the prohibition under paragraph (1) to facilities on military installations located outside of the United States if such prohibition would unduly burden or prevent seafood and seafood products from being served at such facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9E65C2E680F485F878C3C15C8B30A1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>United states vessels visiting foreign ports</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, or a designee of the Secretary, may grant exceptions to the prohibition under paragraph (1) to United States vessels visiting foreign ports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA05721D3B36F42F798CAF4C30437E94F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may waive the prohibition under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E16DC131846461989D2C604310F4A94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on sales of seafood originating in the People’s Republic of
 China at commissary stores</header><paragraph id="H80D7843998F64412AB957C3EF7C049A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2484 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H457E74339AAB498BA96B6B6FAA29433E"><subsection id="HE2C6AB1E1D81465D81B50900F5D22DED"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Prohibition on sales of seafood originating in the People’s
 Republic of China</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4B2A659516841EC846ECCBF56E40C2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by paragraph (2), raw or processed seafood or seafood products originating in the People’s Republic of China may not be sold at commissary stores.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD85A236F60C40C8A6A48A14FF2B3EE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may waive the prohibition under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DEB266733434B8D801D4AD47927C660"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing on compliance</header><text>Section 2481(c)(4) of such title is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HF6109008A83B4D1DB2814A3A781A0C44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1766456B15A42A3A119FECD5C0138C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73355449482445A7962CBE5C3E750EA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph (E):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CDCAF5A124C4A139D61BC3CD01F0565"><subparagraph id="H88C561E000C6464592BDB0E47718D842"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of compliance with the prohibition under section 2484(l) of this title; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB9162575214C41A077B962FE2A66CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition rules</header><subparagraph id="H2FBDEAF6D83B420EBD932F60462B1B64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (l) of section 2484 of title 10, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall apply on and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1036FE27464A415E8ABE6F9A5608FE2C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disposal of remaining stock</header><text>The Director of the Defense Commissary Agency may determine how to dispose of any stock covered by the prohibition under subsection (l) of section 2484 of title 10, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), that remains as of the date described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD6C50916F10454EA22AD12DC987768B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The prohibitions under this section, and the amendments made by this section, shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


