<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA006B74388DC46C487548E59A09A530E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5353 IH: Peer to Peer Mental Health Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5353</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a pilot program to support evidence-based mental health peer support activities for students.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC610D03F0494255BCDED5DBE437B4D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC8C8A7422B37454AB2E015D16797ACE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Peer to Peer Mental Health Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0FFA61232410459A975469DD7568C163"><enum>2.</enum><header>Peer-to-peer mental health support</header> <subsection id="H6C071B8C65544376892981FCD32ED9EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use (referred to in this section as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may, as appropriate and within a relevant existing program, carry out a pilot program and make awards, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to support evidence-based mental health peer support activities for students enrolled in secondary schools (as such term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE00A181167C4AC7895F480FD0C0EB59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section, an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H1238C5D763BF4B3492B2477AFBBCE2DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a State, political subdivision of a State, territory, or Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9EF4E7FE9BE452BB24DDCBBEA725A37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Assistant Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Assistant Secretary may require, including a description of how the entity will measure and evaluate progress of the program in improving student mental health outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H03C21817EA174A7E956D8AC8FD8A0554"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H0C5855D1D4DE47A389431115A81DD8F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an eligible entity may use amounts provided under this section to implement or operate evidence-based mental health peer support activities in 1 or more secondary schools (as such term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) within the jurisdiction of such eligible entity, which may include providing training, as appropriate, to students, adult supervisors, and other appropriate individuals to improve the early identification of, response to, and recovery supports for mental health and substance use challenges, reduce associated risks, and promote resiliency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBCDDD54623E45ACA90D88A0CE0E77D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program oversight</header><text>An eligible entity shall ensure that mental health peer support activities under paragraph (1) are overseen by a school-based mental health professional.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF81964159DF1422CA4FB139AC7918AD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FERPA</header><text>Any education records of the student collected or maintained under this section shall have the protections provided in section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC05ED0CD89244BEBBC24C94466945C86"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation; report</header> 
<paragraph id="H61476165A03E422A89211B2F74780489"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall carry out an evaluation to measure the efficacy of the program under this section. The evaluation shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H36BA3E85063848A5A54BB1672E752176"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measure participation rates in mental health peer support activities, including any associated trends;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA219E641FD64950B92131B0DA64DA22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the specific trainings provided, or other activities carried out under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H840A1648BBB74BDFB96D9812C48AD5BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assess whether such mental health peer support activities impacted mental health outcomes of participating students; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2047600E99F94D1BAA0D5AD6E9FB776E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>measure the effectiveness of the pilot program in connecting students to professional mental health services compared to other evidence-based strategies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A250F18AC3A4B56A57A2BC68B79E044"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a report containing the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C2282F85F834680960FD83850D4030E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities applying for and receiving an award under this section, including the identification and dissemination of best practices for mental health peer support programs for students.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H37DA9EEFF78B44689306D893053ECEEC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Section 4001 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref>) shall apply to an entity receiving a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section in the same manner as such section applies to an entity receiving funding under title IV of such Act, except that section 4001(a)(2)(B)(i) of such Act shall not apply.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF0972A38D5014CFCA2E1E7BB6F842995"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on September 30, 2029.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

