<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25262-1HJ-M5-8P4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S923 IS: Harriet Tubman Tribute Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 923</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to redesign $20 Federal reserve notes so as to include a likeness of Harriet Tubman, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H659C68278D504714BF76AD9FC8BD414E"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD2CA197E31CE4E88B83A6F7668636EBC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Harriet Tubman Tribute Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2ABA97EB46C640C2932131EBB0E7F69D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Likeness of Harriet Tubman required to be included on the face of $20 Federal reserve notes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The eighth undesignated paragraph of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/418">12 U.S.C. 418</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Secretary of the Treasury shall ensure that the face of all $20 Federal reserve notes printed after December 31, 2030, shall bear the likeness of Harriet Tubman, except that the Secretary may delay such date by not more than 2 years if the Secretary submits to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a determination, after consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Engraving and Printing, the Board, and the Director of the United States Secret Service, that issuing such notes after December 31, 2030, would create an unacceptable risk of counterfeiting or to the safe, secure, and speedy functioning of the United States economy.</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

