<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25180-Y6F-FC-SHT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 129 ATS: Recognizing and honoring teachers who have earned or maintained National Board Certification. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring teachers who have earned or maintained National Board Certification. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas National Board Certification is based on rigorous standards developed by teachers for teachers to demonstrate the ability of teachers to advance student learning and achievement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research shows that students taught by National Board Certified teachers learn more than their peers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Board Certified teachers often positively amplify their expertise by serving in leadership roles as teacher mentors, principals, administrators, and district leaders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Board Certified teachers rank National Board Certification as their most important ongoing formal education, above graduate-level coursework and other training programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Board Certified teachers are among the thousands of educators around the United States who play a critical role in addressing the learning loss incurred during the COVID-19 pandemic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 29 States provide salary incentives for National Board Certified teachers, including 13 States that prioritize incentives in high-needs schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, 4,355 teachers earned their National Board Certification for the first time and 4,884 teachers successfully maintained their certification, benefitting thousands of students across the country; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of March 2025 there are a total of 141,464 teachers who have achieved National Board Certification: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id31aef417f3aa4719a3b043810020b357"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the teachers who earned or maintained National Board Certification as of March 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id731902a57c3c49d490d4cceea07241de"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance and contributions of National Board Certified teachers to student learning and achievement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b1dd77d370f4fe9acd117bd7553e3bd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages educators, administrators, school districts, and States to—</text><subparagraph id="id60fb145eeb804d3084a76d8f34ad660a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote increasing the number of new National Board Certified teachers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4803756670214f06a3c122282935ce02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the necessary incentives and support to candidates for National Board Certification. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

