<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A49BE0241D14D7EB3A8DD360F2B11B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4671 IH: Ensuring Casualty Assistance for our Firefighters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4671</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to develop a Wildland Fire Management Casualty Assistance Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D3C5079960148B48CC4B13F0C8267AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD137DCD04B034D8984DA5DB175C5DDCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Casualty Assistance for our Firefighters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3F89FFA2025145FDAF09E463B15CD345"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wildland Fire Management Casualty Assistance Program</header> <subsection id="H49FEB97D0085431799E8A69DF468ACDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall develop a Wildland Fire Management Casualty Assistance Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) to provide assistance to the next-of-kin of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DB60EC7F1A74B6C85E009FA43FE2BCC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">firefighters who, while in the line of duty, suffer illness or are critically injured or killed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3896847449B440FF87C28E30AF73685B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>wildland fire support personnel critically injured or killed in the line of duty.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98A5889108DC427B925E910A5DDCEF1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aspects of Program</header><text>The Program shall address the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1D095149649143168CCF542D439D2ABC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The initial and any subsequent notifications to the next-of-kin of a firefighter or wildland fire support personnel who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5E9DC3182F3D46C4BD61518662B56FEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is killed in the line of duty; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB857D8B12F04D97853A83C58598180C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires hospitalization or treatment at a medical facility due to a line-of-duty injury or illness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F9B75F6AA844D0CA67485ADA416953B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The reimbursement of next-of-kin for expenses associated with travel to visit a firefighter or wildland fire support personnel who—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F2F87AB6FE240BA87E1C091F81FBD05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is killed in the line of duty; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FA0DB316B7E410180F6478A73514713"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires hospitalization or treatment at a medical facility due to a line-of-duty injury or illness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B3AEA432B164D729DC6DBA1F4452328"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The qualifications, assignment, training, duties, supervision, and accountability for the performance of casualty assistance responsibilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF5B48EA8B4D468A88B7B0D38A5F4157"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The relief or transfer of casualty assistance officers, including notification to survivors of critical injury or illness in the line of duty and next-of-kin of the reassignment of such officers to other duties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93FF994E71B54A5DAC010A6FBCC5E8C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Centralized, short-term and long-term case management procedures for casualty assistance, including rapid access by survivors of firefighters or wildland fire support personnel and casualty assistance officers to expert case managers and counselors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81E3500EA7FE4C31AA81EB94650135FA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The provision, through a computer accessible website and other means and at no cost to survivors and next-of-kin of firefighters or wildland fire support personnel, of personalized, integrated information on the benefits and financial assistance available to such survivors from the Federal Government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71AA33AAA6EF4D86B30BB59E0121E259"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The provision of information to survivors and next-of-kin of firefighters or wildland fire support personnel on mechanisms for registering complaints about, or requests for, additional assistance related to casualty assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EC1BFCFFE0744B1937AF3EC187CBBBF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liaison with the Department of the Interior, the Department of Justice, and the Social Security Administration to ensure prompt and accurate resolution of issues relating to benefits administered by those agencies for survivors of firefighters or wildland fire support personnel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H284C6853796B4933BDF8090FBB41DCAE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Data collection, in consultation with the United States Fire Administration and the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, regarding the incidence and quality of casualty assistance provided to survivors of firefighters or wildland fire support personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF40FF8E823454D50B9F49903DA812B3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Line of Duty Death benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Program shall not affect existing authorities for Line of Duty Death benefits for Federal firefighters and wildland fire support personnel.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD5D70CDA671E4FAC8417A2E5AF2A51FB" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Next-of-Kin defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>next-of-kin</term> means person or persons in the highest category of priority as determined by the following list (categories appear in descending order of priority):</text> 
<paragraph id="H207A704C87F949C4BF5329612E61DB6A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Surviving legal spouse.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB2F046861DC45BFBA40E3A00FBD4230" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Children (whether by current or prior marriage) age 18 years or older in descending precedence by age.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C46FF79640A42049253D4D7B3A2FF20" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Father or mother, unless by court order custody has been vested in another (adoptive parent takes precedence over natural parent).</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECE0C3022FD2439EB8B63CD65BF289DA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Siblings (whole or half) age 18 years or older in descending precedence by age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4ED4B938718949A18CE5FCFF14AB11C8" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Grandfather or grandmother.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H133B54AB801848CEBF45402306207276" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other relative (precedence to be determined in accordance with the civil law of descent of the deceased former member’s State of domicile at time of death).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

