<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MAR25059-XHF-35-0P5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 280 IS: Celebrating the 250th birthday of the United States Army and honoring the bravery and patriotism of soldiers and veterans from Fort Leavenworth, Kansas and Fort Riley, Kansas.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 280</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250616">June 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 250th birthday of the United States Army and honoring the bravery and patriotism of soldiers and veterans from Fort Leavenworth, Kansas and Fort Riley, Kansas.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 1775, the Second Continental Congress passed a resolution creating the first continental army that could represent all 13 colonies, becoming the first national institution of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when Congress declared independence on July 4, 1776, the Continental Army became known collectively as the Army of the United States (referred to in the preamble as the <quote>Army</quote>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from the Revolutionary War to present-day missions, Army soldiers have consistently demonstrated their resolve to defend freedom at home and abroad;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the establishment of the Army in 1775, Army soldiers, civilians, and their families have supported the United States, bearing true faith and allegiance to the United States and the Constitution of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its inception, the Army's mission has been to deploy, fight, and win the wars of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the soldiers from Fort Leavenworth, Kansas and Fort Riley, Kansas have been pivotal to the Army’s mission of winning the wars of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fort Leavenworth, established in 1827, is the oldest continuously operating military installation west of the Mississippi River and the oldest permanent settlement in Kansas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fort Leavenworth has been known historically as the <quote>intellectual center of the Army</quote> for being responsible for cultivating and teaching leader development, collective training, and Army doctrine and battle command;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Combined Arms Center located at Fort Leavenworth delivers professional military education and functional training through 20 branch and 7 non-branch schools, providing the Army with agile, adaptive, and expert professional soldiers and leaders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all modern 5-star Army generals have passed through and studied at Fort Leavenworth, including George Marshall, Douglas MacArthur, Henry Arnold, Dwight Eisenhower, and Omar Bradley;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 1st Infantry Division, currently garrisoned at Fort Riley, is the oldest continuously serving division in the Army and was constituted on May 24, 1917;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 1st Infantry Division, nicknamed <quote>The Big Red One</quote>, has consistently been the first division to deploy into the wars of the United States, sending the first troops into World War I, World War II, the Vietnam War, and Desert Shield and Desert Storm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during World War II, the 1st Infantry Division was the first to reach England, the first to fight the enemy in North Africa and Sicily, the first on the beaches in Normandy during D-Day, and the first to capture a major German city;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during Operation Desert Storm, the 1st Infantry Division was instrumental in breaking the Iraqi lines;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elements of the Big Red One served admirably during the Global War on Terrorism in support of Operations Iraqi Freedom, Enduring Freedom, and Inherent Resolve;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the Army celebration in Washington, DC on June 13, 2025, 450 soldiers from the 1st Infantry Division marched in the parade, honoring the bravery and sacrifices of those who came before them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soldiers from Fort Leavenworth and Fort Riley, along with the Army as a whole, will continue to fulfill their mission of winning the wars of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 250th birthday of the Army is a historic milestone worthy of national recognition, celebrating its enduring legacy and contributions to the defense of freedom: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id055168c95c57425cb9c17f0f6e9f7c63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the United States Army on its 250th anniversary, commemorating its establishment on June 14, 1775;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d6bf8c2f48f4470a4c9fe16e7a4c8e3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the extraordinary service, sacrifice, and commitment of all who have served in the United States Army;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc0f89af2066415299c6fb0efcb63924"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses profound gratitude to the soldiers and veterans of the United States Army for their unwavering dedication to protecting the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id432fe3704ef24dfeb30a18d0f8a1ca43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the bravery and patriotism of the soldiers and veterans from Fort Leavenworth, Kansas and Fort Riley, Kansas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc19b5474ceb24dff82fd4d44542413e6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls upon the people of the United States to join in celebrating the 250th anniversary of the United States Army with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and expressions of appreciation for its enduring legacy and service to the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

