<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H580E9139C78641FC81D73E78662596B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3477 IH: Ensuring Airline Resiliency to Reduce Delays and Cancellations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3477</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250517">May 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to require certain air carriers to develop and regularly update an operational resiliency strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H97E8895B823D425CA0CDF85C1859E06B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37DBCCAA0BDD484DA3396341B24EF0B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Airline Resiliency to Reduce Delays and Cancellations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2F0FDA0618B345FAB0988F2103D7AD09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Airline operational resiliency plans</header> <subsection id="H7CE9640AE7554643B940ECC7E2E37C02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall require a covered carrier to develop and regularly update an operational resiliency strategy to prevent or limit the impact of future flight disruptions on passengers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE06CACF4E2A48AA95515FFE2A81B4BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operational resiliency strategy</header><text>In each operational resiliency strategy developed under subsection (a), a covered carrier shall include a description of—</text> <paragraph id="H548A2EA7E4B146CCA79228C7CFDCF1FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the potential impact of severe weather and other reasonably anticipated disruptive events on the operations of the carrier and how the carrier seeks to prevent or limit the impact of such events on passengers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBEF24DC14B645D08183D93C606C9802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential impact of severe weather events and other reasonably anticipated disruptive events on—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE7D9526F0564007B7D2CCB3DF5906D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">staffing models, including the ability of such models to ensure the workforce is able to adequately respond to such events and reschedule passengers, flight crews, operations staff, and other appropriate personnel; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6BDDDAA89C44AC7BECE26D025F876CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current information and technology systems of the carrier, including crew scheduling systems, and the preparedness of such systems to continue operations after such an event or disruption;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E5CFDB7F4FD4C24B60E40FE48B7A291"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the preparedness of the carrier to maintain operations and limit or prevent the impact of other potential disruptive events identified by the carrier;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC196AD3E337647A38C5BEDF4F76F4ECC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the carrier addresses known cybersecurity risks and information technology deficiencies and vulnerabilities to prevent potential flight disruptions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EEE78535EE84652BB03D475A39365E3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other issues the Secretary determines appropriate to protect consumers and maintain the operational stability of the airline industry.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H004A10553B6A48B5B8A2846EC807C5B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proprietary information</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a method to protect the confidentiality of any trade secret or proprietary information submitted in an operational resiliency strategy under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A6F3A1775D949B29120F05ED62BF926"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H66F433E10D6F46CF9725DC2D932F7A56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate an audit to evaluate the effectiveness of the operational resiliency strategies developed under this section by covered air carriers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H887D22FEA6AE470A902DEB6DD90BF9E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stakeholder feedback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the audit under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall solicit responses from the covered carriers regarding the findings of the audit and include any such responses in the report in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7710A2C445D48BE967878B2E9F8F809"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after completion of the audit conducted under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the findings of the audit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD8930F255634D90B8258D2965D7AB89"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="H4200E3BAB3624DFF80ABE9A3A246E90C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grant additional authority to the Secretary beyond the authority to require a covered air carrier to develop or update an operational resiliency strategy in accordance with this Act; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6E60A7897944750A7C2F96B4073C078"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the Secretary from assessing an operational resiliency strategy and providing guidance and technical assistance to a covered carrier in developing and updating such a strategy required under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9F760E00B87949C4A03690C2AFCBBA8B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered carrier</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered carrier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 259.3 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

