<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25222-FNW-P4-LVP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2615 IS: Validation and Evaluation for Trustworthy (VET) Artificial Intelligence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2615</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to develop voluntary guidelines and specifications for internal and external assurances of artificial intelligence systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Validation and Evaluation for Trustworthy (VET) Artificial Intelligence Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VET Artificial Intelligence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id944845a80b41459cbaa0972f62bc5757"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd278094c196b48dbad34340bfd88cac6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop consensus-driven, evidence-based voluntary technical guidelines and specifications for internal and external assurances through the testing, evaluation, validation, and verification of artificial intelligence systems, as appropriate based on the intended application, use-case, and risk profile of the artificial intelligence system;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc891f01fa2c64cd2854f1a08fda79857"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use meaningful assurance to supplement methodologies used to build trust in artificial intelligence systems, increase adoption of artificial intelligence systems, and provide for accountability and governance of artificial intelligence systems; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f599772641d43e1bf6f317591f311e5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to further the goals of the Artificial Intelligence Risk Management Framework, including any successor framework, published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute pursuant to section 22A(c) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id3748f553a752417986c09803bfe88330"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id570e82375307487cb3f27515e23c6691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence system</term> means a machine-based system that, for explicit or implicit objectives, infers, from the input the system receives, how to generate outputs, such as predictions, content, recommendations, or decisions, that can influence physical or virtual environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb1938c5b97846628e9654d339844634"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deployer</header><text>The term <term>deployer</term> means an entity that operates an artificial intelligence system for internal use or for use by a third party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id45b6c19b9b14405aa3cd15e0314cd566"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Developer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>developer</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6d3a7be1f154442ad02edfc09eed676"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an entity that builds, designs, codes, produces, trains, or owns an artificial intelligence system for internal use or for use by a third party; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc786f397c64c479792c9ddc75b3d388d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an entity that is solely a deployer of the artificial intelligence system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d5bf3881fa1480dbaa2812b440343c8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb9af16d4aa54991949586bef7d84e6d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>External artificial intelligence assurance</header><text>The term <term>external artificial intelligence assurance</term> means an independent and impartial evaluation of an artificial intelligence system conducted by a nonaffiliated third party in accordance with the voluntary assurance technical guidelines and specifications described in section 4 or consensus-driven voluntary standards, for the purpose of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ddd0bbbbf144a38b62986ab645e8024"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verifying claims with respect to the functionality and testing of the artificial intelligence system, including verifying whether it is fit for its intended purpose; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e0fdef25d0e4da9910dfd177158d43e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying any significant error or inconsistency in the testing, risk management processes, or internal governance, any substantial vulnerability, or any negative societal impact of the artificial intelligence system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf51a52d10cdd4346a9a0c88e7a824257"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Internal artificial intelligence assurance</header><text>The term <term>internal artificial intelligence assurance</term> means an independent evaluation of an artificial intelligence system conducted by the party being evaluated with an internal reporting structure that encourages impartial evaluations and prevents conflicts of interest, for the purpose of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03200F1E9C5241469E1B94DDF6F270BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verifying claims with respect to the functionality and testing of the artificial intelligence system, including verifying whether it is fit for its intended purpose; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF01305C225F04E30AA1F9FB954664647"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying any significant error or inconsistency in the testing, risk management process, or internal governance or any substantial vulnerability of the artificial intelligence system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6037bd18c84425ebe75be485648ead1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nonaffiliated third party</header><text>The term <term>nonaffiliated third party</term> with respect to the evaluation of an artificial intelligence system, means a person who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2793a3f2530041f2b3bd3db150a5681c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not related by common ownership or affiliated by common corporate control with the developer or deployer of the artificial intelligence system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2feb649e2ab47749ea81fde52eae4eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can demonstrate financial independence from the developer or deployer of the artificial intelligence system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45dd09c2b9004042b789b7af59cb2a22"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not employ any individual, who is also employed by the developer or deployer of the artificial intelligence system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id525612a1f90e4c098517d3b9d249c188"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is a qualified evaluator of artificial intelligence systems, with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd7a4530acfd4e16be93b90c6d14524a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrated expertise in relevant technical domains, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01e7392865704066bf6fe1f4fe14f51b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>data privacy and security principles; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1acaff7b908f47fe8c24850947e64361"><enum>(II)</enum><text>risk management practices in artificial intelligence systems; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b5310829e0742e79f78a756b45a0f97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>familiarity with the relevant details regarding the type of artificial intelligence system being evaluated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa296a70569a43e69730031f76217ff5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc4a0ede44d234a88a457faa3bae6391d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Voluntary assurance technical guidelines and specifications for artificial intelligence systems</header><subsection id="id07cdc782ed174ba9b1cee320a8932dd4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary technical guidelines and specifications for assurance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director, in collaboration with public and private sector organizations, including the National Science Foundation and the Department of Energy, shall develop and, not less frequently than every 2 years, shall review and update as the Director considers appropriate, a set of voluntary technical guidelines and specifications for internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e2692bc2a95469d9ceb01572d80e96e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The technical guidelines and specifications required by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="ideaa312b7c9ec47d1a8fc1d5a2663f9d9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify consensus-driven, voluntary standards for internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance that address—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide348d882e05640c2b69e8fc3f535496b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">safeguards for consumer privacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7c0237f99a4480691b3fd046df887c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods to assess and mitigate harms to individuals by artificial intelligence systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c4d5f6d52d346dbb4174b3937e2d0ca"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dataset quality;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a62c146a53b4331a91cd3e4e662bcb8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>documentation, disclosure, and provenance communications to external parties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc27d1455285a46d6a10756305a1d2fee"><enum>(E)</enum><text>governance and process controls;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2608f5fc91514528bda7c646b8364c14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical guidelines, best practices, methodologies, procedures, and processes, as appropriate, for internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance that effectively address the elements listed in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bd965f45da64387a94a6647b35337d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish common definitions and characterizations for testing, evaluating, verifying, and validating methods for internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ce8358da2de4833a7709c3c4c22c5d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommend criteria or approaches for a developer or deployer to determine the frequency and circumstances under which internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance activities should be conducted, accounting for the relevant risk and use-case profile of the artificial intelligence system, and any additional circumstance under which an assurance should be conducted;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8d97f7a7f274ecfb4de42bc68b25d0e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommend criteria or approaches for a developer or deployer to determine the scope of internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance conducted through testing and evaluating, accounting for the relevant risk and use-case profile of the artificial intelligence system, including the minimum information or technical resources that should be provided to the party conducting the assurance to enable assurance activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34eb517895e046a5b9e870d8cc37caf6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide guidance for the manner in which a developer or deployer may disclose, as appropriate, the results of an internal or external assurance or carry out corrective actions with respect to an artificial intelligence system following the completion of an internal or external assurance of such system, and guidance on the manner in which a developer or deployer may properly document any corrective action taken;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id20ba1dbfc6144bb0ab0348af99d70c04"><enum>(7)</enum><text>align with the voluntary consensus standards, including international standards, identified pursuant to paragraph (1) to the fullest extent possible;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idf16093bcb52f42f6ba8ecdfdfc48f70a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>incorporate the relevant voluntary consensus standards identified pursuant to paragraph (1) and industry best practices to the fullest extent possible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7529d440292c41f1bb4bde76f3c1fc6b"><enum>(9)</enum><text>not prescribe or otherwise require—</text><subparagraph id="id96e11ac3b3b84c9288156d95bf4c14fe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of any specific solution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6adab75620da474fb66797f2f727c050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of any specific information or any communications technology product or service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id104dc365950c48f385ecdeb7d94a3631"><enum>(10)</enum><text>recommend methods to protect the confidentiality of sensitive information, including personal data and proprietary knowledge of an artificial intelligence system, that may be obtained during the assurance process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id360d650bdaea4f1ea05d450527ec532c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder outreach</header><text>In developing the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required by subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="id9476199ae0154b33bd3828142015a2de"><enum>(1)</enum><text>solicit public comment on at least 1 draft of the technical guidelines and specifications, and provide a reasonable period of not less than 30 days for the submission of comments by interested stakeholders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9cc233e5d33844c4b18140c4f2245bf3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make each complete draft of the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications developed under subsection (a) available to the public on the website of the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idc48aa4bbcb2549aab6ffb85d113e0f74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>convene workshops, roundtables, and other public forums, as the Director considers appropriate, to consult with relevant stakeholders in industry, academia, civil society, consumer advocacy, workforce development organizations, labor organizations, conformance assessment bodies, and any other sector the Director considers appropriate, on the development of the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98ecab5ec96c4d10bf4d360cb6e169fe"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall publish the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required by subsection (a) as a standalone framework or document available to the public on the website of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subsection></section><section id="id2e84acb25a584edbac50ae404d1adb65"><enum>5.</enum><header>Qualifications advisory committee</header><subsection id="id1086df03d72f42718f07965bd2545818"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Director publishes the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required under section 4(a), the Secretary shall establish the Artificial Intelligence Assurance Qualifications Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id2267d23ebe3d4f009c9e206e3990f0b7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint to the Advisory Committee not more than 20 individuals with expertise relating to artificial intelligence systems, including at least 1 representative from each of the following:</text><paragraph id="id22cc43c79d1248c89e87ea8aa5df411d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e7240ce186348e3b760f2e97a77455e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Organizations developing artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde3a631a7b124218879f021ece512514"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Organizations deploying artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0553b83f04ef4242af827ea56ec1ad2a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Organizations assessing artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0de783f70cd3472095104bba12ab7d36"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumers or consumer advocacy groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc03b39c16ce244bdbdab96cb69a4fa9e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Public health organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb03f56b9e06411f8fa8fa5a3875112c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Public safety organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e6ad2866e184339b6c4215323b642ab"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Civil rights organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36de89d3fc3d4390a9a68abb78101426"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional accreditation organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fc325fc96d545ceb1606b0d81c21015"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Workforce development organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69f572a69b824c089c9bc510691581e8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Labor organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4bfc7c5783cf49cdb5cd6c90b7108a8d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Nonprofit assurance professional organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idae5872244c3d4a68a34ef0ec0a054906"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall—</text><paragraph id="idfae5e82da10f4c289e1865f9a48cb0b2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review and assess case studies from entities that provide licensure, certification, or accreditation to independent organizations with a primary mission of verifying compliance with applicable statutes, regulations, standards, or guidelines; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1fc7406034148cfbc1e2eb33b1f313f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the applicability of the case studies reviewed and assessed under paragraph (1) to the development, maintenance, and use of artificial intelligence systems for the purpose of developing recommendations under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0cc8631922944fee9948418f40cffab0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary establishes the Advisory Committee under this section, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the Secretary and Congress and make publicly available a report that includes recommendations for the Secretary to consider regarding—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56d73b4e40254d448095f9ae530fffb5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualifications, expertise, professional licensing, independence, and accountability that a party conducting an assurance of an artificial intelligence system should have, including with respect to the type of artificial intelligence system under evaluation and the internal and external assurance processes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e0c357635714219ace270aa29fc501b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether accreditation for internal artificial intelligence assurance and external artificial intelligence assurance can be met through a combination of existing licensure, certification, or accreditation programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide936f4ea1cad4213a31a567b2f85b669"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall terminate not later than 1 year after the date on which the Advisory Committee submits the recommendations required under subsection (d).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ef3391b1a164088872793dd3a0422f1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study and report on entities that conduct assurances of artificial intelligence systems</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb528ff9f80cc44b898fc76055ef2b0f7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Director publishes the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required under section 4(a), the Secretary shall commence a study to evaluate the capabilities of the sector of entities that conduct internal artificial intelligence assurances and external artificial intelligence assurances.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide158a76344c64e93af42eedd91043636"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the study required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id3ba9562b783d44babd4a0fde39097ba3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the capabilities of the sector of entities described in subsection (a) with respect to personnel, technical tools, evaluation methods, computing infrastructure, and physical infrastructure and whether such capabilities are adequate for providing internal artificial intelligence assurances or external artificial intelligence assurances that comport with the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required under section 4(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c30e0c1cbbe44e0bfc5a4db653bc082"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the features, best practices, and safeguards employed by such entities to maintain the integrity of confidential or proprietary information of a developer or deployer during an internal artificial intelligence assurance or an external artificial intelligence assurance;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id810cc8f69579464ba4a1cc4e917347c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the market demand for internal artificial intelligence assurances and external artificial intelligence assurances and the availability of such assurers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id187c930b8f4447e3a241e755d8a57f70"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess the feasibility of leveraging an existing facility accredited by the Director under the National Voluntary Laboratory Accreditation Program established under part 285 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, to conduct external assurances of artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd2c67ccf57794865b70f475a93d7a0db"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary commences the study required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the head of any Federal agency that the Secretary considers relevant, a report that contains the results of the study required by subsection (a), including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide247e8c139b646948b71321d16e60ea7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improving the capabilities and the availability of the entities assessed in the study;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37cbdd46488b4c84b8555d501ac68e13"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">descriptions of the features, best practices, and safeguards of the entities studied and the effectiveness of such features, practices, or safeguards at implementing the voluntary technical guidelines and specifications required under section 4(a) and at maintaining the integrity of confidential and proprietary information, as described under subsection (b)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07a4ba75fdb346eeb6764083e10a03f4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any conclusions drawn from the assessment of the facilities described in subsection (b)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88fa1ca574be40c097ff6eefa26b61d5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term the <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id6a41e769f2a64aae8cc14830988dc8df"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea0ab2c8cb594ab79675e30b6c39c454"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

