<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53CADB2E8F334F349D72A38A91FCAE3F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4909 IH: Voters on the Move Registration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4909</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the inclusion of voter registration information with certain leases and vouchers for federally assisted rental housing and mortgage applications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA2619BD9E9F47AD8E112C9755D250F6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4B2A059A6BA44FADB7AA86C75A89F1CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voters on the Move Registration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H34FDF29C2DFF4972887D78F3936031C4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of voter registration information with certain leases and vouchers for federally assisted rental housing and mortgage applications</header> <subsection id="H7CACE55EE29C40A4BFAC8615850D7E25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H19468FF1287F41DEA94DAE4DECED3502"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H771B199DF18741C0AFC621B7FE09B2D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Protection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4DE3F4FB6F8E4E42BF47886B2747E143"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal rental assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal rental assistance</term> means rental assistance provided under—</text> <subparagraph id="HB656F50E55A9472A8CF27B4388F14C97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any covered housing program, as defined in section 41411(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12491">34 U.S.C. 12491(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H61D61EB0EF814CCE9958E958FF8B251D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>title V of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>), including voucher assistance under section 542 of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1490r">42 U.S.C. 1490r</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H945F0BF808C04EB7AC8EDD186FC4D874"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Housing Trust Fund program under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4588">12 U.S.C. 4588</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8BEA454350E442639A39B12EABCFE659"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subtitle C of title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11381">42 U.S.C. 11381 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AC65A77221F4DD1A1A47F02A4802CA9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan</header><text>The term <term>Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan</term> includes any loan (other than temporary financing such as a construction loan) that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9A407AC3C6D44601B7382AD3FB114CE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential multifamily real property designed principally for the occupancy of 5 or more families, including any such secured loan, the proceeds of which are used to prepay or pay off an existing loan secured by the same property; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08FED6EAB4C74F4BA3ECE270D258B453"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way, by any officer or agency of the Federal Government or under or in connection with a housing or urban development program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or a housing or related program administered by any other such officer or agency, or is purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H98AFDBFF5FCC40F5835AFFB2C79E821E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Owner</header><text>The term <term>owner</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8(f) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41B93E883C074CA59BC66B984A5049D9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public housing; public housing agency</header><text>The terms <term>public housing</term> and <term>public housing agency</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EA7483F0BDE4A89B6225F3DC3DDD4CD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Residential mortgage loan</header><text>The term <term>residential mortgage loan</term> includes any loan that is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential real property, including individual units of condominiums and cooperatives, designed principally for the occupancy of from 1- to 4- families.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE677603A2B143E98B24541562E86EA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uniform statement</header> <paragraph id="H98DAC01E4FF34C41B21287D92182DA59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The Director, after consultation with the Election Assistance Commission, shall develop a uniform statement designed to provide recipients of the statement pursuant to this section with information on how the recipient can register to vote and the voting rights of the recipient under law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H61ED2C05CC22496AA46D0C773F9538FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In developing the uniform statement, the Director shall be responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EA6D39D6382492FA0D6645E2BBAE2BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing the format of the statement;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA20DE0711FE7484DA202E4414AA22DE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consumer research and testing of the statement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E86AB05CAF6472E993C9F765285FF2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consulting with and obtaining from the Election Assistance Commission the content regarding voter rights and registration issues needed to ensure the statement complies with the requirements of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H553B967089784583B4EA9A5A526098B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Languages</header><text>The uniform statement required under paragraph (1) shall be developed and made available in English and each of the 10 languages most commonly spoken by individuals with limited English proficiency, as determined by the Director using information published by the Director of the Bureau of the Census. The Director shall make all translated versions of the uniform statement publicly available in a centralized location on the Bureau’s website.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E081DF4F8FC45A0ACE3B35476273C48"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Leases and vouchers for federally assisted rental housing</header> <text>Each Federal agency administering a Federal rental assistance program, as appropriate, shall require—</text>
        <paragraph id="H70669B7AFE8E47D8915F3EBD749DB2FC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>each public housing agency to provide a copy of the uniform statement developed pursuant to subsection (b) to each lessee of a dwelling unit in public housing administered by the agency—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HFFDB5E3604944C9AA21FDE9613BC4F2C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>together with the lease for the dwelling unit, at the same time the lease is signed by the lessee; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF4A0A4F0758A454A93A25F9E4022F639">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>together with any income verification form, at the same time the form is provided to the lessee;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3ECFB179051947418081DB5546A0EF5E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>each public housing agency that administers rental assistance under the Housing Choice Voucher program under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>), including the program under paragraph (13) of such section 8(o), to provide a copy of the uniform statement developed pursuant to subsection (b) to each assisted family or individual—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HAD0F932C87434C8992D2286C9CF231C7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>together with the voucher for the assistance, at the time the voucher is issued for the family or individual; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H31229AB0CAAD41E19FF1812967DCD290">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>together with any income verification form, at the same time the form is provided to the applicant or assisted family or individual; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H90B094A9227D45A28A29E7D7BAE56636">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>each owner of a dwelling unit assisted with Federal rental assistance to provide a copy of the uniform statement developed pursuant to subsection (b) to provide to the lessee of the dwelling unit—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HCE72FD3671DE4271861A30B82761B23F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>together with the lease for such dwelling unit, at the same time the lease is signed by the lessee; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF2E1DED6A5944895A962899E1F5DC8B0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>together with any income verification form, at the same time the form is provided to the applicant or tenant.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HEDE94C4D20124E72A8DEB964B784D8F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications for residential mortgage loans</header><text>The Director shall require each creditor (within the meaning of such term as used in section 1026.2(a)(17) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations) that receives an application (within the meaning of such term as used in section 1026.2(a)(3)(ii) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations) to provide a copy of the uniform statement developed pursuant to subsection (b) in written form to the applicant for a residential mortgage loan not later than 5 business days after the date of the application.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2BC24D165AE94CF7A2E87EA9139C5BBC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federally backed multifamily mortgage loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Federal agency insuring, guaranteeing, supplementing, or assisting a Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan, or the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency in the case of a Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan that is purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association, shall require the owner of the property securing the Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan to provide a copy of the uniform statement developed pursuant to subsection (b) in written form to each lessee of a dwelling unit assisted by that loan at the time the lease is signed by the lessee.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF839BC32EC4D4ADA9002372297AFE3F9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Optional completion of voter registration application</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require any individual to complete a voter registration application.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9E1D9CB54224416ABB3AC1F0E5A4FEF7"> <enum>(g)</enum> <header>Regulations</header> <text>The head of a Federal agency administering a Federal rental assistance program, the head of the Federal agency insuring, guaranteeing, supplementing, or assisting a Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Director may issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

