<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25629-FYH-NJ-K0R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>90 S1383 IS: Veterans Accessibility Advisory Committee Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1383</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Veterans Advisory Committee on Equal Access, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HEE71740D328D4D57A00D705515ACC73E"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC15F9670EAC74A13B3A48779F662E71F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Accessibility Advisory Committee Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H316F54C4FE634B97BA56370B68BEC025"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Advisory Committee on Equal Access</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE40A7201E2D4881B4A8963DDDC8C6EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H207630B3D9FC43DE9DE1063A93282A76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs an advisory committee on matters relating to accessibility of the Department for individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62575479736249AAA8286D4A27F39E85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The advisory committee established by paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>Veterans Advisory Committee on Equal Access</quote> (in this section the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECC390C3A9144FD2988666590C756F11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H5F7A3C5236654B1189C8336C93F7C9B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voting members</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 15 voting members, appointed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. In appointing such members, the Secretary shall ensure the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBDC19CCBBC784735B29BA5F0EF9DB1C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four are veterans with disabilities, including mobility impairment, hearing, visual, and mental or cognitive disabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3809691C2B2040BA92F23522ADCAF1B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four are experts on issues described in subsection (f)(1)(A) or the provisions of law set forth under subsection (f)(1)(B). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD460943ACFC8413CB689291F42751E12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two are employees of the Department, one from the Section 508 Office and one from the Architectural Accessibility Program, who oversee the compliance of the Department with Federal accessibility laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H616B82EDC88545AF8439DFAEF4C49D02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Five are representatives nominated by national veterans service organizations that advocate for veterans with physical, sensory, mental, or cognitive disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H138C791634124343B9BD410F14860CE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall also include four ex officio members (or their designees):</text><subparagraph id="HD0CBFE48E29144B48CF7A6730A5D5632"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94124A539B63403FBB171C91EE607D67"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C870EA33578496FB8B8BFDCEF3BD5C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Memorial Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04DD411B711F46FB9F930F5A818FE2CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chairperson of the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (known as the <quote>Access Board</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7557587B946F4DB09FE8141F7F0E638C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms; vacancies</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H49012F70290543A2B2AE5720BD23FB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a term of two years. The Secretary may reappoint members to the Advisory Committee for such additional two-year terms as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7F79529D03044B7ABE5429EFFC677C50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall fill a vacancy in the Advisory Committee in the same manner as the original appointment not later than 180 days after such vacancy occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0479F82A35174021B18AE7768C9241AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HC052B8B0630C4CFE854B4AF63DEB739A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall meet not less frequently than twice each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92700B5FF3694AF5ABBE6869F16B5D4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>The Advisory Committee may form subcommittees, which shall meet as often as required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H254029B7D02C4D13BA8937CC0F201FB8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC3734AF8EB34A1B9A360B06421E47C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>Members of the Advisory Committee shall select a Chairperson from among the members of the Advisory Committee. If the position of Chairperson becomes vacant, the members of the Advisory Committee shall select a new Chairperson not later than 30 days after the date on which the position became vacant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H39480A5E397145F59DBAD073E37EF289"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="H74B5FAF4872647AABC14D164BD7408F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to consult and seek advice</header><text>On a regular basis, the Secretary shall consult with and seek the advice of the Advisory Committee—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H965510BD55844D6E8513CD9768261AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on improving the accessibility of the Department for individuals with disabilities, including improving—</text><clause id="H7DBFFA8C4DB84E6799DCFD49C2B4635C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the accessibility of information of the Department, including electronic information;</text></clause><clause id="HC7C3F6BA77E748E2B15E1FF792A791B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the accessibility of the services and benefits furnished by the Department;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC840FA5743A3469EB90CF3D98E237AAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the accessibility of the facilities of the Department;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26E6A3C2AD8944C8BAC088328D96A6A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the accessibility of facilities of health care providers furnishing care or services under the Veterans Community Care Program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code; and</text></clause><clause id="H7E7F8B58E6D74BDC8A1E84B05D8A117D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the acquisition process of the Department to ensure that products and services, including information technology and information and communication technology (as defined in the standards issued by the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board pursuant to section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>)), are accessible when purchased; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5771FCCA77141A681F595BA6CC2AB18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for ensuring the compliance of the Department with provisions of law relating to disability and accessibility, including—</text><clause id="H0A1B93FB3E404FA59710C3C7997C6AC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12184">42 U.S.C. 12184 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HFAA851AAB13545ED9045B207933C6EE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sections 504 and 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>, 794, and 794d);</text></clause><clause id="HAAB37289DCA44CDD8EE6AB24C4B35DEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Plain Writing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/301">5 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note); </text></clause><clause id="HA60F26BB288A4057910331D1CC8EB9DC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the 21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="H51EC8B4BB94D44AF98111D1849B6F209"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/480">Public Law 90–480</external-xref>); and </text></clause><clause id="HBC6F909171304D2CBD8C59AA4C5609F4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other provisions of Federal law as may be that ensure equal access to Federal facilities, benefits, or services for individuals with disabilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E07B11D21FD49968E039D88376AE236"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of advice</header><text>In providing advice to the Secretary, the Advisory Committee shall, focusing on the areas of greatest need for the Department—</text><subparagraph id="HBBF34D80CE4F47EB937B134A71C5284E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the disability access needs of veterans, the public, and Department employees for full access to the Department’s information, services, and benefits by reviewing relevant information, such as filed complaints by people with disabilities or physical assessments of the Department’s facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C0DE941DE4A40B0AD806E307A5F6153"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide assessments of accessibility at the Department and the compliance of the Department with applicable provisions of law relating to disability and accessibility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC82DB7EB3AE4A6EB6E6F7B0BA7CA210"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide advice on improving accessibility at the Department, including the accessibility of all—</text><clause id="H5D25629592FC4662A4E6D44A27FB346F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communications, including internal and public facing;</text></clause><clause id="H349D0907683947818843AA757ED1F46D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services and benefits; and</text></clause><clause id="HFB517B94F68F477CB26AE40DB10BA7FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5549CC382AE440EBDD256C4DFF5EDCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="HEBCB5001D34C4A1D88C46AF441F9CC03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports to the Secretary</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the first meeting of the Advisory Committee, and not less frequently than once every two years thereafter, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the Secretary a report that, focusing on areas of greatest need for the Department—</text><clause id="H003F46B6BDB242D38BDA353B8B620A94"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies and assesses access barriers affecting veterans, the public, and employees of the Department;</text></clause><clause id="HFE3E7953183F4493AED28362529BC606"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determines the extent to which the programs and activities of the Department address the barriers identified in clause (i), including compliance of the Department with provisions of law relating to accessibility law and reporting;</text></clause><clause id="H748101331F9A4C198875C58DDB431A6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides recommendations and access priorities to improve the accessibility of the Department’s services, benefits, information, technology, and facilities; </text></clause><clause id="H8A15C2D39F934FBEB9FF1B8D028A1B3E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a description of access improvements and assesses the Department’s implementation of recommendations from previous reports of the Advisory Committee, including any unmet recommendations that remain necessary for improving accessibility for the Department; and</text></clause><clause id="H65317F97640D458792B6695AD9313BC4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides any recommendations for legislation, administrative action, or other actions that the Advisory Committee determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCBCE37AF15C46F99814842B39AADA3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reports to Congress and Federal agencies</header><clause id="H35BD14B1079A4CD880CB4140AD334982"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the receipt of a report required under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a copy of such report and any comments and recommendations of the Secretary concerning such report that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5CEF8CD4E8F44EABF8F29360DF29DE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>The Secretary shall publish on a publicly accessible website of the Department such report and such comments and recommendations as may have been submitted along with such report.</text></clause><clause id="HF619DC5207C04AF49D43B9E187A5F5BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subclause id="H7B9D2144B9D24EA0A105264540B1811A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE15B50F5B296433792693E1A6E08C1E9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5EDDEE42D87D46EA923D7D336785DFF1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26280E83A43E4B3B9B8AD231CC79C92D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Advisory Committee personnel and resource matters</header><paragraph id="H65E332EE04B24DBCAD51D8898210AED3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>A member of the Commission who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall not be compensated for the performance of the duties of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73BFFAD243D5469C91BDDC8929D9A8FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Advisory Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF758AA7DE45E414E842F6A48EF4C47ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that such personnel, funding, and other resources are made available to the Advisory Committee as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the duties of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED835EC4F05E499182CE5FF06F235309"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Secretary shall furnish to the Advisory Committee such information as the Advisory Committee may request from the Secretary, subject to applicable provisions of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H607BACBFE1B741B4AA798AFAAA6CC164"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination of Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB6FD55E3D9EB478F9DCC3C016B65BACD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Abolition of inactive advisory committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and before establishing the Veterans Advisory Committee on Equal Access under section 2, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="H9F6824F3EBFF4ADCB81216C64108A3CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abolish an advisory committee of the Department of Veterans Affairs that—</text><subparagraph id="H400C479ED46145B4BA54D9CD72796DA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was not established by an Act of Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E14AF25011B451E98BBD1EBBCE6C7BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is inactive;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ECF949D01FB43C2BD62CE88ABECE49E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consolidate two advisory committees described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDC5B81873D1414580630C85A5866F9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a recommendation to abolish an advisory committee of the Department that—</text><subparagraph id="HDE262BF4093846D9AC7AEF9A509DE845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was established by an Act of Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DAB58E3D5B849BAB73D6B27F85BA3C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is inactive.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

