<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25088-R9J-45-7RM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S321 IS: Decoupling America's Artificial Intelligence Capabilities from China Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 321</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250129">January 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit United States persons from advancing artificial intelligence capabilities within the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Decoupling America's Artificial Intelligence Capabilities from China Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b1a0f2ab1e74a478e885d444347b88e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5EB42F62339B4DAEBF6734629077F829"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence; generative artificial intelligence</header><text>The terms <term>artificial intelligence</term> and <term>generative artificial intelligence</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2741 of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 3. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22F4140D945E43C4B4D3203061AF5A68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence technology or intellectual property</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence technology or intellectual property</term> means technology or intellectual property that could be used to contribute to artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence capabilities. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6efecb04cea44bf69a42fbca28b297f4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chinese entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>Chinese entity of concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2741 of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id120A98A4E14D4DF198E050DF83D802C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interest</header><text>The term <term>interest</term>, with respect to an entity, includes an interest in the entity—</text><subparagraph id="id4BAF2342329B43B0AE4CD9F16B9B7FD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>held directly or indirectly through any chain of ownership; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id726E78BF3BC14BBA93D3B6C01617A771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>held as a derivative financial instrument or other contractual arrangement with the entity, including any financial instrument or other contract that seeks to replicate any financial return with respect to the entity or an interest in the entity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id21DDFE7BA3294A2583B52D500DCB3984"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Military-civil fusion strategy</header><text>The term <term>military-civil fusion strategy</term> means the strategy of the Chinese Communist Party aiming to mobilize non-military resources and expertise for military application, including the development of technology, improvements in logistics, and other uses by the People’s Liberation Army. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id664CD2C05EEC4971B16628DB1A564703"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intellectual property</header><text>The term <term>intellectual property</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id2B371D0311F74186A78480AF6D5139B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any work protected by a copyright under title 17, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6462CFBC7FA042FDA15CF53C650E32CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any property protected by a patent granted by the United States Patent and Trademark Office under title 35, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75BE4FAD332147BC9EA6E40595DEA1C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any word, name, symbol, or device, or any combination thereof, that is registered as a trademark with the United States Patent and Trademark Office under the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 5, 1946 (commonly known as the <quote>Lanham Act</quote> or the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1051">15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id322A54A047B842CD8C8DAD90BB87C7C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a trade secret (as defined in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBA0A7CF4551548998B394C1263745999"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Technology</header><text>The term <term>technology</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92694c0002d147458a5d69ace1611e8e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given that term in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19053fc218544fdab647e1100ca8af8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause id="id38b8dc8d2e52427ab868689a9b9cd1d5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any semiconductor, circuit board, operating system, graphics processing unit, central processing unit, tenor processing unit, field-programmable gate array, random access memory, hard drive, solid-state drive, dataflow architecture, or cloud-computing service, that is manufactured, designed, developed, supplied, deployed, completed, assembled, restored, converted, or replicated to function artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence; and</text></clause><clause id="id9b6c208405664fe7afaf5759286764b8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other hardware, software, equipment, device, component, robotic, computer, processor, network, machine, accelerator, circuit, storage, system or subsystem, server, or related good, tool, or service, that is manufactured, designed, developed, supplied, deployed, completed, assembled, restored, converted, or replicated to function artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0AF0B45A72B44462A38EB684B68CF13D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Terms from Export Control Reform Act of 2018</header><text>The terms <term>export</term>, <term>in-country transfer</term>, and <term>reexport</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idED3A4F8CFD3948F5B2BC0992C20C80AB"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2741 of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 4. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id2E7743BD884F4865BFAC9506475418E0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibitions on import and export of artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence technology or intellectual property</header><subsection id="id3D6D28593B5F41F1811F557C7D13A4F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on importation</header><text>On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the importation into the United States of artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence technology or intellectual property developed or produced in the People's Republic of China is prohibited.</text></subsection><subsection id="idDCC0AF8BC9F3425BB9098713BCCB750C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on export</header><text>On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence technology or intellectual property to or within the People's Republic of China is prohibited.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7eabe216ffa34477858f2e5a6e9872d2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07e7c1027dbd4af681413ec63a306588"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who willfully commits, willfully attempts to commit, or willfully conspires to commit, or aids and abets in the commission of, the violation of a prohibition under subsection (a) or (b) shall be subject to the criminal penalties set forth in subsection (b) of section 1760 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4819">50 U.S.C. 4819</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person who willfully commits, willfully attempts to commit, or willfully conspires to commit, or aids and abets in the commission of an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d654f80077347488b24f834e177bf1c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who violates a prohibition under subsection (a) or (b) or any regulation, order, or license issued to carry out any such prohibition shall be subject to a civil penalty set forth in section 1760(c) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4819">50 U.S.C. 4819(c)</external-xref>) for each such violation to the same extent as a person who commits a violation described in that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8f1dacc00fd48e981eeca38af389c18"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue regulations implementing this section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4404710bf6cd4e4aba74a148d61048da"><enum>4.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence research and development</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc413505b57ae44709584c4625dc6f97d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFAC034EE3765495DB5CF068DA2931B6A"><chapter id="idf4a09006d24a4a0698693261c514f746" style="OLC"><enum>124</enum><header>Research and development that benefits the People's Republic of China</header><section id="id43740e375cd841bbabec4a42eb6b4c9d"><enum>2741.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida61f7bc060594bf1947d9e3d440e84a9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6c4aff7ab1845948cbb80c215d95465"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (10 U.S.C. note prec. 4061; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41b9d1461b5d421485c98ea2c7fb3066"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fe9b1764a1045e7b3c070fd20c6deaa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an artificial or automated system—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e1e9a4852dd4269a831d2a7238c12e9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that performs tasks under varying and unpredictable circumstances without significant human oversight;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36426b46b0fe456ea1cc3982e5526a3b"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that can learn from experience and improve performance when exposed to data sets;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1166cb4d5d1e4b1e85a096791d77559a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>developed in computer software, physical hardware, or another context that solves tasks requiring human-like perception, cognition, planning, learning, communication, or physical action;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4795d0c8828441ba8b0ed3626d2c984d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>designed to think or act like a human, including through cognitive architectures or neural networks;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9535e99833cf4234a8044fd6859e90f8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>that has or is derived from a set of techniques, including machine learning, statistics, or other data processing or artificial intelligence techniques, that is designed to approximate a cognitive task;</text></subclause><subclause id="idec3ca34ae2a643fc9d0d5a86c260244b"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>designed to act rationally, including through an intelligent software agent or embodied robot that achieves goals using perception, planning, reasoning, learning, communicating, decision-making, and acting; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id999d62b5b6274f938f5fc5d297b93ac6"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>that is intended to or capable of interacting with humans, detecting human emotions, determining associations with social categories based on biometric data, or generating or manipulating image, audio, video, or related material; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id98aed13cbe61472eb6a27e22b414b285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other artificial or automated system, software, or process that uses computation as whole or part of a system to determine outcomes, make or aid decisions, inform policy implementation, collect data or observations, or otherwise interact with humans or communities of humans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfaba98da8d3447daaf3eae81a639eaf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The term <term>control</term> has the meaning given the term in section 800.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2e63be69fdc4afdb6f9af2e60fc249f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corporation</header><text>The term <term>corporation</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idf87a172a958644c5a91a8dfd356e28ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an entity with the business structure of a corporation, a company, a limited liability company, a limited partnership, a business trust, a business association, or another similar entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1dde0a00013a4c9fb2a6ea4d0d78fcd6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any subsidiary or branch of an entity described in subparagraph (A) tied to an entity described in subparagraph (A) through a series of contracts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id867cc303c6ab461b949d02a29efcd8b4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The term <term>development</term> means creative and systematic work that draws upon knowledge gained from research and practical experience, which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id848aa98d65d645dfb64967f5c186daab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is directed toward the production of new products or processes or improving existing products or processes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ide61d73a046fb408abc577916614018da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>like research, results in gaining additional knowledge. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id50cf3a5e438b4764af5252df275600af"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>entity of concern</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id99850af06b3740a4bf59d05d4f7e9e0d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of education, including a college and university, organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79b8b4bbed184546a54d72d16796872e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a research institution, research lab, or research and development center organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04dc565a5bb74351acd035670230c323"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any corporation—</text><clause id="ida8fe0cb7db704aac80ff4ef29054fffd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause><clause id="idb56f6a1d72b4433bade5cc8e1760b33b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is headquartered in the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause><clause id="idcf78854d8c414470b5082dc6a0805abe"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has its principal place of business in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></clause><clause id="id53ee16091aa64f2da7b9849035f90b6b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the equity securities of which are primarily traded on not less than 1 exchange based within the People’s Republic of China; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb05986dd56224420b2f9670f90adf0a3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China (as defined in section 204 of the U.S.-China Relations Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6903">22 U.S.C. 6903</external-xref>)) and any governmental department, agency, ministry, research institution, research lab, research and development center, or any other entity, subdivision, or affiliate of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or the People’s Liberation Army. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8fa219bfd5ac4b2a98342447a2e1b946"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> means a department, an independent establishment, a commission, an administration, an authority, a board or bureau of the United States, a corporation in which the United States has a proprietary interest, or any other agency of the executive branch of the Federal Government. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b4af78c2e7447479f304ee2a276205c"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial assistance</term> means a grant, loan, or contribution provided by the Federal Government. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bb7095ef0954993899827d808ecf3e3"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Generative artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>generative artificial intelligence</term> means an artificial intelligence system that is capable of generating novel text, video, images, audio, or other media based on prompts or other forms of data provided by an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb41839e1e065451f8b5a46e71fa709dc"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Peoples's Republic of China</header><text>The term <term>People’s Republic of China</term> includes Hong Kong and Macau. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ida4245b341c924deeac85deeee6008c0e"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The term <term>research</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb747a7df3ddb4c31a5df4289b9898af3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a systematic study directed toward fuller scientific knowledge or understanding of a subject studied; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id563b859190114106b4b3a4606214675a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes activities involving the training of individuals in research techniques if such activities—</text><clause commented="no" id="id98bb6029057041b290f0043b2fd947c2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use the same facilities as other research and development activities; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id860614213dd44e1ea990cf44e05fcf75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are not included in the instruction function. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd516a09542fa4bac8eeb8770a3dad19a"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>The term <term>research and development</term> means a basic or applied research activity and a development activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7d86f38f25f49d0948ddaa465cb68d7"><enum>(12)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1521471b03c4c39946330c4fc50a41d"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Territory</header><text>The term <term>territory</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id60e94652acb74f9e87e23cba34cca456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e950efa2c274d38b914ed1aca28afb7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ef1c01b615443a3b062bf7cd6a5d213"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Virgin Islands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f2dd914357f420a99f7d01fd2fd2262"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb91226da8c0542d389b20c5143dd4bda"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81db0a650a194be1902201e8539dd319"><enum>(F)</enum><text>American Samoa.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd07f0a7c882a4f00bfc1ee3cfb36e84b"><enum>(14)</enum><header>United States Person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18963a2e4ac943f686168b8d14a46b0c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 1711 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6010">22 U.S.C. 6010</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0afb564b0654c3aa8696fdf91fd0d60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="id36306458a19341b9b66e91932a840d86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a corporation that is incorporated or organized under Federal law or the laws of a State or territory;</text></clause><clause id="id55f82138252543ed83075901a821f5fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an institution of education, including a college and university, organized under Federal law or the laws of a State or territory;</text></clause><clause id="iddfd2a8eb7d26450baf1788a8d48a82dd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a research institution organized under Federal law or the laws of a State or territory;</text></clause><clause id="ida3418ef63de7479a857639d0af4d6809"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a person that is—</text><subclause id="id8b55b4e2ce774af89a442fb545936bf8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a protected individual (as defined in section 274B(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324b">8 U.S.C. 1324b(a)(3)</external-xref>, wherever located or employed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide8347462d22c4864998876d557774d04"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an alien who has been admitted to the United States as a lawful permanent resident; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b0c36732fd34af6b15d76c24f39e321"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a person or corporation controlled by an individual or entity described in this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id650ec3527ec34e00a8bedd648b6525e7"><enum>2742.</enum><header>Unlawful acts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3e0f6adf94e4475a98ef949f283b10f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>A United States person may not intentionally conduct, attempt or conspire to conduct, or aid and abet in conducting research or development of artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence—</text><paragraph id="idcef9e09f87514ba98c91a604227613d3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26be7d4a47f948d6805923755c7aa18e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1aee0ea95bcd4ec6b03182c5362202c2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on behalf of an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaf8c6affb284b249755afe2101c79b2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in collaboration with an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccd54c8decb84ec4ad74aaf53361b128"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for a national of the People’s Republic of China working for or on behalf of an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaba80391e2eb4c1d9d169948255271b3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>on behalf of a national of the People’s Republic of China working for or on behalf of an entity of concern; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d003b64325246aa84b92294d268c8eb"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in collaboration with a national of the People’s Republic of China working for, or on behalf of, an entity of concern. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfb2898d8e0d3423c8b9e79e6e7cc64fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of research</header><text>A United States person may not intentionally transfer, attempt or conspire to transfer, or aid and abet in transferring information relating to research of artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence—</text><paragraph id="id131a13e02e894b1aad441511fb3e6eb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94eed4c29f834fb1a72d6685cd641d44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>directly to or from the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b33cef6934340ab809562aff43e10d4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc132939f6ed947c893ecadcac4956445"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on behalf of an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f4b0bca853b460192fd2ae1b192748a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>directly to or from an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8ab5cc0c5e3431cac8fdfb425b02d09"><enum>(6)</enum><text>for a national of the People’s Republic of China working for or on behalf of an entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9c918f4334f467d9865f19577d3823f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>on behalf of a national of the People’s Republic of China working for or on behalf of an entity of concern; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a9403a84f7a452584d9ba86eed70ce1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>directly to or from a national of the People’s Republic of China working for or on behalf of an entity of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idafb88ca846f04ccfac67e7f8ee966e06"><enum>2743.</enum><header>Penalties</header><subsection id="id31573466897649ddaf00b5f0611bdb61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fines; forfeiture</header><paragraph id="idbeb1952b0eb44110a40ce5b3a67f9b95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entities</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90f8bb4d880942078c6a5ae88613c8c1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A United States person that violates section 2742 that is not an individual shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0f427be09f347c789555d72fcaea1d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be fined not more than $100,000,000; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide125b3d0a14746248b5f04b2cce015e8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forfeit any license, contract, subcontract, grant, or public benefit awarded by any Federal agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09713782c06240fb9d88062f3e7b073d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Associates of entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An officer, director, partner, agent, or employee that violates section 2742 shall—</text><clause id="id7e944a340d344155b3f391e5518309f8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be fined not more than $1,000,000; and</text></clause><clause id="id4422a0a6232349169232c1cfb4fb54c6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>forfeit any license, contract, subcontract, grant, or public benefit awarded by any Federal agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbc0bc2779654e929ea5b7497480a6b8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text>A United States person who is an individual that violates section 2742 shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70b7faa5455545a69ac762467b741e05"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be fined not more than $1,000,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f1d3f4599b045a480490d844bbd0a90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forfeit any license, contract, subcontract, grant, or public benefit awarded by any Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4b577991106542998bcf98a9fe61d0b0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for Federal financial assistance</header><text>A United States person that violates section 2742 shall be ineligible to receive Federal financial assistance during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which a penalty is imposed under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id69130a16f9dc49b69561bfb025f31d50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc41973799854b13a0582123348c4990"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a United States person that violates section 2742, the United States may bring a civil action against the United States person in any district court of the United States in which the United States person resides, is found, or has an agent, without respect to the amount in controversy.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15fdc81e18ea4d9fadbc7449015a3042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Damages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil suit brought under paragraph (1) against a United States person, the United States shall be entitled—</text><subparagraph id="idde3bba3d24ff4ce8923731562d74c258"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33baf14ac79c4f59a1587c35b1c84b82"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relief in equity to restrain and prevent a violation or threat of violation of section 2742; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id498b95f478054e1f9f63b78815580234"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other appropriate equitable relief;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1b2e2b059c443f29ed3407d50240c08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to relief in damages for—</text><clause id="id7975e8c705354f14a0736a50a43ab213"><enum>(i)</enum><text>punitive and nominal damages; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bf8781e5d5644b5ad72a2e6739b5545"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">three times the amount of damages sustained by the United States as a result of the violation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8f4131caa9e4215b2b98fec4a8f4f0a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> three times the cost of the civil action, including reasonable attorney’s fees;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd8ca56c482174aae9d4928afb967803f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to a civil fine of not more than $100,000,000 if the United States person is not an individual; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b91bd915f3b4e50ba079de87075ce07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to a civil fine of not more than $1,000,000 if the United States person is an individual</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="iddbcaa415cff4443f92599b07cf498bd0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Citizenship and immigration consequences</header><text>Section 101(a)(43) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb06652b7eb3f4ea791af7e3496f7d22d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (T), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f4d7beb1f684e20a75c153c5f994a62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (U) as subparagraph (V); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c71a030a89a44b896fd6e73401e7e93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (T) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA53C91FAFB1547479B5C37BE423FD82F"><subparagraph id="id6c879cf308b14e528509905dc83841f4"><enum>(U)</enum><text>an offense described in section 2742 of title 18, United States Code (relating to research and development on behalf of the People's Republic of China); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5bb49a00a5b438b865dc0ff1c4991d5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id0425ddbc-2e97-47b6-ba5f-8c29eebb8e49"><toc><toc-entry level="chapter" idref="idf4a09006d24a4a0698693261c514f746">Chapter 124—Research and development on behalf of the People's Republic of China </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id43740e375cd841bbabec4a42eb6b4c9d">2741. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id650ec3527ec34e00a8bedd648b6525e7">2742. Unlawful acts. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idafb88ca846f04ccfac67e7f8ee966e06">2743. Penalties.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6960AF71AD6437B9DA87868721AA37F"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Education, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6db290bec99e4b2caca7bc5609ce915e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promulgate regulations to enforce the prohibitions under section 2742 of title 18, United States Code, as added by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaba4f72d5ada48c3afac747e77d3c8de"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the heads of other Federal agencies to ensure the enforcement of the prohibitions described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idefed67aa520f417ea9647bb9a3611c0b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on United States persons holding an interest in or providing financing to Chinese entities involved in artificial intelligence research and development</header><subsection id="id69067ab9c7f846a9b2cfaab428449a30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, a United States person is prohibited from knowingly holding or managing an interest in, or lending money or extending credit to, a Chinese entity of concern that—</text><paragraph id="ida0460e35da5f41a4862891fad128aa61"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1fc2fca193d247a99006b0cf2681e228"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducts research or development relating to artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03401373c7614a419f12ebc89015b1f9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produces goods, including hardware and software, that incorporate research or development relating to artificial intelligence or generative artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id865b9cc4c2394de2832271d7205c1306"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ida417beda85d94c91a147f5a684ea4be7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assists in the implementation of the military-civil fusion strategy of the People's Republic of China; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0af7bcfd841b44be8d55db14934ad5c4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assists in the development of surveillance capabilities; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id504adffca41540b3a281d506d5eb7897"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is implicated in human rights abuses. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id26eacda5eb8e4628a76e41a35f140bf4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="id56814d7446db4993b0deb31c46a061c5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise the authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to the extent necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d2199dc5c714bed8595a0d476471aca"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

