<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25A06-MJ0-HM-R72">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2875 IS: Custom Health Option and Individual Care Expense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 2875</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the treatment of health reimbursement arrangements integrated with individual market coverage.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD546D1F031004AD199FEFB5091F71038">
<section id="id3fb3ef6a2cac4f8da38d82f98b395a68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Custom Health Option and Individual Care Expense Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHOICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D6B30FBE7544668A93322E6C9FC8BEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of health reimbursement arrangements integrated with individual market coverage</header> <subsection id="HA08C1D72FB9C4513BAB70C2651F92F8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9815">Section 9815(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HE646128F8CED4244838EDAE738EF83B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Exception.—</header-in-text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEF878C858FF74B0BA0686C02345CE4E5"><text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Exceptions.—</header-in-text></text>
<paragraph id="H632550C006BE4E36B00605AF946A725D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Self-insured group health plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA99D58BC5114D72BD3097DA8024B479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50772432F18D42C4B35901D2C57C2715">
<paragraph id="H8BAA8832EDC744F8ABC199F21684645C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Custom health option and individual care expense arrangements</header>
<subparagraph id="H115F23C3425345E69121032BD995668A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subchapter, a custom health option and individual care expense arrangement shall be treated as meeting the requirements of section 9802 and sections 2705, 2711, 2713, and 2715 of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1DDED1C9C544992ACF1270094B30579"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Custom health option and individual care expense arrangements defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>custom health option and individual care expense arrangement</term> means a health reimbursement arrangement—</text>
<clause id="H17C301B22AFA4CE5B23E68C5D64ACC31"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is an employer-provided group health plan funded solely by employer contributions to provide payments or reimbursements for medical care subject to a maximum fixed dollar amount for a period,</text></clause> <clause id="H4A8A436F01AB4B9CAC46ECD0D68AC194"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which such payments or reimbursements may only be made for medical care provided during periods during which the individual is covered—</text>
<subclause id="HB0FA0766B6034CB99D0C1BF596F73FFF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>under individual health insurance coverage (other than coverage that consists solely of excepted benefits), or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7036669CE3564C0E9016AD32F2748E85"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under part A and B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act or part C of such title,</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H951B2F0F29E046C19F1B11994E58FECD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which meets the nondiscrimination requirements of subparagraph (C),</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H6B44C999734C4902AD6BA03B2B7C8DF5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which meets the substantiation requirements of subparagraph (D), and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB3DA5D8891AC4A48A696ADEEEB056756"><enum>(v)</enum><text>which meets the notice requirements of subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1EED9FD692E741608B59DB7F0EFD62D1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header> <clause id="H0A001DED4DA5402FA48D1F4AD469FB00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An arrangement meets the requirements of this subparagraph if an employer offering such arrangement to an employee within a specified class of employee—</text>
<subclause id="H96316E0D4BC34AE29BEADC3CC34BD5E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>offers such arrangement to all employees within such specified class on the same terms, and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H075D7F9D0E3B486AB0A356EC9D11FEAD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not offer any other group health plan (other than an account-based group health plan or a group health plan that consists solely of excepted benefits) to any employees within such specified class.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">In the case of an employer who offers a group health plan provided through health insurance coverage in the small group market (that is subject to section 2701 of the Public Health Service Act) to all employees within such specified class, subclause (II) shall not apply to such group health plan.</continuation-text></clause>
<clause id="HE03BFE5A44D647F3BD25F41A8E289C1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specified class of employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, any of the following may be designated as a specified class of employee:</text> <subclause id="H0A5F46524E994AF585C91F0727341FA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Full-time employees.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3DFD8BFD16F64E0581DA705672168C7C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Part-time employees.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7C60AC000B5B4C038EFC92AB909295C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Salaried employees.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H39D0AEEDB0644A7A9A6ABF247A1E13F4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Non-salaried employees.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H448A2EE589D545B19CF31BF9954F2784"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Employees whose home location is in the same rating area.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H26C6048618F148C2BCD64ACE9E96E2B9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Employees who are included in a unit of employees covered under a collective bargaining agreement to which the employer is subject (determined under rules similar to the rules of section 105(h)).</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBFCED2E50424445A9E9FBA842B7A3C08"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Employees who have not met a group health plan, or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, waiting period requirement that satisfies section 2708 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H57846F305222446793F919BF853ADFC6"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Seasonal employees.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H33A668EDD8824D8EB1716E456CF69833"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>Employees who are nonresident aliens and who receive no earned income (within the meaning of section 911(d)(2)) from the employer which constitutes income from sources within the United States (within the meaning of section 861(a)(3)).</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3F102B7F71804B209A1139991A140BB2"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Under such rules as the Secretary may prescribe, employees who are hired for temporary placement with an unrelated person that is not the common law employer.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41b9ce247b6d4dd18bbd39b337c1d25d"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>Employees who are hired in the same date range.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC67D7D0ED4544B3CB8596C821DECA7D3"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>Such other classes of employees as the Secretary may designate.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">An employer may designate (in such manner as is prescribed by the Secretary) two or more of the classes described in the preceding subclauses as the specified class of employees to which the arrangement is offered for purposes of applying this subparagraph.</continuation-text></clause> <clause id="HB3B82486093A4E4D9C15396A492961F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special rule for new hires</header><text>An employer may designate prospectively so much of a specified class of employees as are hired after a date set by the employer. Such subclass of employees shall be treated as the specified class for purposes of applying clause (i).</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H2699408FA7044A0F87B2C877E99BFCD5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rules for determining type of employee</header><text>For purposes for clause (ii), any determination of full-time, part-time, or seasonal employment status shall be made under rules similar to the rules of section 105(h) or 4980H, whichever the employer elects for the plan year. Such election shall apply with respect to all employees of the employer for the plan year.</text></clause> <clause id="H297EB91F15514671AE770F879297DC36"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Permitted variation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i)(I), an arrangement shall not fail to be treated as provided on the same terms within a specified class merely because the maximum dollar amount of payments and reimbursements which may be made under the terms of the arrangement for the year with respect to each employee within such class—</text>
<subclause id="H7D111356EE204C4FB0E0C75E69DE10A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increases as additional dependents of the employee are covered under the arrangement, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5DC7834E64A140DB913E0846959EEB00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>increases with respect to a participant as the age of the participant increases, but not in excess of an amount equal to 300 percent of the lowest maximum dollar amount with respect to such a participant determined without regard to age.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFDB22326D374FDD93359ABE6EE15982"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Substantiation requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An arrangement meets the requirements of this subparagraph if the arrangement has reasonable procedures to substantiate—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H5471EBBFDFFB4824B7102D6DA03CBF1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the participant and any dependents are, or will be, enrolled in coverage described in subparagraph (B)(ii) as of the beginning of the plan year of the arrangement (or as of the beginning of coverage under the arrangement in the case of an employee who first becomes eligible to participate in the arrangement after the date notice is given with respect to the plan under subparagraph (E) (determined without regard to clause (iii) thereof)), and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H8D65634F8A9849F5A5AFEEBA194A9A43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any requests made for payment or reimbursement of medical care under the arrangement and that the participant and any dependents remain so enrolled.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B5A36BCA44B45EEBA6A5D3BBFA34752"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Notice</header> <clause id="H354C18DA28DB474096F7E1AC0817AD6F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iii), an arrangement meets the requirements of this subparagraph if, under the arrangement, each employee eligible to participate is, not later than 60 days before the beginning of the plan year, given written notice of the employee’s rights and obligations under the arrangement which—</text>
<subclause id="HB047691776B04B83BBA37B5E0C06629E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is sufficiently accurate and comprehensive to apprise the employee of such rights and obligations, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5B9C66E4FA74478ADA35B46FFF3EE13"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is written in a manner calculated to be understood by the average employee eligible to participate.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H37A77E80283A438EAF2959C2A1BD4F29"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such notice shall include such information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</text></clause> <clause id="H684AA86D8D554EC7BC89B4E7E6EEB6A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice deadline for certain employees</header><text>In the case of an employee—</text>
<subclause id="HCEB374963DA14925B8F02731BDE04716"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who first becomes eligible to participate in the arrangement after the date notice is given with respect to the plan under clause (i) (determined without regard to this clause), or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3C01D67B887C46788C2958D13B0AB63D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whose employer is first established fewer than 120 days before the beginning of the first plan year of the arrangement,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">the requirements of this subparagraph shall be treated as met if the notice required under clause (i) is provided not later than the date the arrangement may take effect with respect to such employee.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H7392888E9E9E40A594676FC857E47959"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of <enum-in-header>CHOICE</enum-in-header> arrangement permitted benefits on <enum-in-header>W–2</enum-in-header></header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H029A4C3583F44740884D84E3A325FFC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6051(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (18), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (19) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (19) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD3B8C70717E841828951CDF6C7898C72"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC039A2EA7DC443EF8726D13944C0210B"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of permitted benefits for enrolled individuals under a custom health option and individual care expense arrangement (as defined in section 9815(b)(2)) with respect to such employee.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA86914EA3FF4A74BF9AB171776175AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of current rules relating to certain arrangements</header>
<paragraph id="H6C982AE32C3742DEA26378957A7E0FD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>To the extent not inconsistent with the amendments made by this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H119D1081E3AF4A78962227C49524805B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no inference shall be made from such amendments with respect to the rules prescribed in the Federal Register on June 20, 2019, (84 Fed. Reg. 28888) relating to health reimbursement arrangements and other account-based group health plans, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1CE03737E7D74ABBAAAD98D338C6A40E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any reference to custom health option and individual care expense arrangements shall for purposes of such rules be treated as including a reference to individual coverage health reimbursement arrangements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE41732020DD4CD2B435DF3ADBFE83FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other conforming of rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Labor shall modify such rules as may be necessary to conform to the amendments made by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H331B51BE353D449CBC81AD8BE93A873C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEBB2CB701AD6494ABC21447F635B5F9D" commented="no" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Participants in CHOICE arrangement eligible for purchase of Exchange insurance under cafeteria plan</header> <subsection id="HCC8981CC1A0A4DA48159E93043AFE1CA" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/125">Section 125(f)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2028658CB4B34EADB502B5AFDF3C5A1E" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="H61B72BA3C7BA4E2EB81224A837CDF433"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for participants in CHOICE <enum-in-header></enum-in-header>arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of an employee participating in an custom health option and individual care expense arrangement (within the meaning of section 9815(b)(2)) offered by the employee’s employer.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H244207622744448F9DBF9F28DFB68EA8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H86A2DD1696EB4B5EB1BE7C68302B5DD3" commented="no" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Employer credit for CHOICE arrangement</header>
<subsection id="H9011353788DC4FFD83A1EF5FA4F0096C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFAF884C369DF4E16AD2A1580909E9162" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H03F20C3C2F3F4407B506AF848E105F71" commented="no"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Employer credit for CHOICE arrangement</header> <subsection id="H1CAB09FD3356466EAD865CA6494BDF3F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible employer, the CHOICE arrangement credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount, with respect to each employee enrolled during the credit period in a CHOICE arrangement maintained by the employer, equal to—</text>
<paragraph id="H4482925314664C88A442E7CB520C41B9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$100 multiplied by the number of months for which the employee is so enrolled during the first year in the credit period, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62C53FAAD1D64465BA91FE8541EB9BEC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one-half of the dollar amount in effect under paragraph (1) for the taxable year, multiplied by the number of months for which the employee is so enrolled during the second year of the credit period. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD505696D8C054E16947FA8E3230DA7D3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Arrangement must constitute minimum essential coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee shall not be taken into account under subsection (a) unless such employee’s eligibility for the CHOICE arrangement (determined without regard to the employee being enrolled) would cause the employee to be treated under section 36B(c)(2) as being eligible for minimum essential coverage consisting of an eligible employer-sponsored plan (as defined in section 5000A(f)(2)).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H135DE28F980E4E28BDEEBED044846A01" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text>
<paragraph id="H402A9717EA954704B2D55EF256BD8241" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CHOICE arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CHOICE arrangement</term> means a custom health option and individual care expense arrangement (as defined in section 9815(b)(2)(B)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD20145EDD5DA468FB4F6AE3321FDC460" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The credit period with respect to an eligible employer is the first 2 one-year periods beginning with the month during which the employer first establishes a CHOICE arrangement on behalf of employees of the employer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44471D075AB94432AF1A2EFBDADAC19D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible employer</term> means, with respect to any taxable year beginning in a calendar year, an employer who is not an applicable large employer for the calendar year under section 4980H.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H76DF0380B1D5497197F4429DA1FDB6DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header> <paragraph id="H7448DD5DEB8249E9904330CF8B3F0382"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2026, the dollar amount in subsection (a) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3D077E4BD66D4E5288E2A7D016AC8A90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2D2083F35B74503A9A29B2D6324C558"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3B2EA6AD298843C59BF460D89692F95D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any amount after adjustment under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $10, such amount shall be rounded to the next lower multiple of $10.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H02365ECD18F94501B8DC040B03D406E1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93D6D5AF5D8A414FAC462933C04AD1D2" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HC206A23CAEB64835A6ABE2BD60B24814" commented="no"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the CHOICE arrangement credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE5250FF6AF9B4B8B9A585F3613BAE635" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit allowed against alternative minimum tax</header><text>Section 38(c)(4)(B) of such Code is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H763F11E253234ABB902913FF2AF20A6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (x), (xi), and (xii) as clauses (xi), (xii), and (xiii), respectively, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02167F3D267D4F9FB205074F51BE3156"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ix) the following new clause:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H728E73AB03AF480F970A517DD32F7041">
<clause id="H89C4B3FBC0D442DCBA44382AB62D9453"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the credit determined under section 45BB,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1BF60A57C05C48AAB3DB82AD07F3D118" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6FD7E9697E6F4581AB50B3462520A370" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45BB. Employer credit for CHOICE arrangement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HFD3EFE37E7A04FE991F485ADB340334F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

