<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9B2ED8068B441718F9B8A7899172414" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3312 IH: Supporting Every at-Risk Veteran In Critical Emergencies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3312</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants for the creation and operation of veterans response teams within law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H182AA285B685488DAC863C3CF8E712F5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H987FDA09835D46168115F347FA785407" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Every at-Risk Veteran In Critical Emergencies Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SERVICE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H33697A714724415F81530BD529EA7383"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veteran Response Team Pilot Program</header> <subsection id="HE772BEA4FDDA41A7B3DE980864FBFF77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, is authorized to operate a pilot program to make grants to States, units of local government, and Indian Tribal governments, to support the creation and operation of veterans response teams in the law enforcement agencies of the jurisdiction, in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31AD6A5383CF4EF3A69A2DC6224EB874"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants To develop veterans response teams</header> 
<paragraph id="H6B1ECFA7D9584D2781D06C68A4F0DFA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Activities of a veterans response team</header><text>A veterans response team may include a program that does the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H5ED61E780A474669860C9FBA0376BC4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provides law enforcement officers who are veterans with a pin that identifies the department of the Armed Forces in which the officer served, which the officer may wear while on duty.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF96080F1EC114587B59F6B61B9AAC01A">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Uses the Veterans Re-Entry Search Service of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBBB39DC3E3B4E3E9252229F1882D4B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishes a system of communication and information sharing with the Department of Veterans Affairs and other community resource agencies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C94E1891D80460FB17DE33BBFDFB0B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establishes a working relationship with the Veterans Justice Outreach specialist.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70720E2A58F5459A9BABEC957CA7CB0C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Establishes a working relationship with the local justice system and veterans court, if applicable, including identifying veterans upon entry into the court system and local detention facility, with notification to the local Department of Veterans Affairs office for confirmation and appropriate services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27EC385CA2474DD8AE398C3FD857A5AF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provides training and education for law enforcement officers on mental health issues related to military service, such as post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, depression, and anxiety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32F9142EC78D4E8997FF71CD2F608686"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Meets regularly to discuss issues veterans are facing in the community, as well as suitable responses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2D8A0D2038243A7BEF6D0A55C36B9AB" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Organizes coordinated and trained teams of first responders to respond 24 hours per day, and 7 days per week, on a volunteer basis, to calls for assistance involving a veteran in crisis.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE1D9C67ADCE4E449FED74477DA79535"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Develops a plan to—</text> <clause id="HF3BD9D2EE6334C6596BA9A215EECCF39"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measure the success of veteran response teams; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H239D1576E34447A2B448C00FA57DB32C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">track nationwide best practices on how veterans response teams provide law enforcement officers with essential information during and following veteran-involved incidents to which veterans response teams respond.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95F46DBCC26F451BB6DC8E10A80614E1"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Offers veterans who have come into contact with the veterans response team the opportunity to maintain ongoing contact with the veterans response team.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D96C805995C480F9A9175A794C8CFB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Creation, Hiring, and Training of Veterans Response Team</header><text>The creation of a veterans response team within a law enforcement agency pursuant to a grant under this section may include doing the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HEDC7FAB6728642D6A1E1C00076C4FA83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identifying a law enforcement officer in the law enforcement agency who is passionate about and committed to forming a veterans response team, and will serve as the leader of such team.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB183C5FFA6A467F860CDE7D2A98ED2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identifying other law enforcement officers in the law enforcement agency who are interested and willing to participate on the veterans response team.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1A79924288840E59AACA15E2A595EFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identifying and inviting interested community members to join the veterans response team, which may include members of veteran resource organizations, the local office of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the regional veterans justice outreach program, other law enforcement agencies, fire and emergency medical services departments, hospitals, social work agencies, other entities within the justice system, nonprofit organizations, and other appropriate entities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A7023C6908C4C27881F20F7143518F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immersing veterans response team members in the veteran community by attending veterans events, responding to incidents involving veterans, as described in paragraph (1)(I), and making public appearances to further engage with veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16C305CB0CE746F792917DCA4317323A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Providing training on veterans experiencing crisis for individuals involved with the veterans response team, and for other law enforcement officers who are likely to come in contact with veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0513BADD043A4614AD6C8781C0791966"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C46EB7F68E54DA49433A55638D12D83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide a report to Congress on the progress of the pilot program that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H135EF8F62EF14A84829EBF1377CB06B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of applicants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB991CBE6B26E48BAA08D45643753DB13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of grants awarded.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD11C7CC5BBB0404AB7C8D4FA4108B4A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The average grant amount sought by an applicant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DBA355C56634266AC21AFF1952FBEB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The average amount of a grant awarded.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H667D14EAE9DE4FEEB9EDE56587F1827E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other information that the Attorney General determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H250681961E4643758CDCBBA521EED696"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the pilot program under this section shall be carried out using funds made available for grants under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381 et seq.</external-xref>) for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

