<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H035511664F1345138B2EED8AD954DCD9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5415 IH: Nitazene Control Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5415</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to permanently schedule the class of benzimidazole-opioids known as nitazenes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50FB2487DF0D4CE18B1716C321843F3E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D94C9554E244F6FB03D89DEA3827F09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nitazene Control Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HA505922E13FF479486604320C7F253D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF2FECD4D9E7141ACA9E7A3AC336A0DBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2-Benzylbenzimidazole opioids are a class of synthetic opioids first synthesized in the 1950s. They exhibit significant potency at the mu-opioid receptor, with some substances exceeding the potency of fentanyl.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E573EBC94124FFD9E65EAEFCCE9984F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) has temporarily or permanently scheduled multiple 2-benzylbenzimidazole opioid compounds under Schedule I of the Controlled Substances Act due to their high abuse potential and lack of accepted medical use.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC5CE3573AB494CB0AFE102109AC7448B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nitazenes and related compounds have emerged in the illicit drug supply as designer drugs and contribute to overdose and fatal poisonings in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F9921D7D166433B9C3D3D0154C19ED2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A class-wide permanent scheduling of 2-benzylbenzimidazole opioids is necessary to preemptively address the proliferation of new analogs, streamline enforcement, and protect public health.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A15BB6193AF4DF1AC3D452067424578"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The HALT Fentanyl Act created pathways for research using Schedule I controlled substances which apply to scheduled nitazenes.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBB371B63F8374B418BAB429D126AE334"><enum>3.</enum><header>Schedule i classification of nitazenes</header> <subsection id="HEE7D4EBD35E44294833E77BC3D0AB240"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of Schedule I the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HB3CCA292CE9542B78A1A23144B98701C" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H3D9AD4BBE5794D939E8465D769187A48"><enum>(f)</enum><text>2-Benzylbenzimidazole opioids, commonly referred to as <quote>nitazenes</quote>, their isomers, esters, ethers, salts and salts of isomers, esters, and ethers, including:</text> <paragraph id="H6CFF33DA73DD4AE0B5D2DEAF2DB9A7BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Is structurally related to 2-benzylbenzimidazole with the following modifications:</text>
<subparagraph id="HD1CA205F418E4C99BAC7C2CDC1EB88BE">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>At the 1-position, substitution with an alkyl linker connected to a substituted amine group containing hydrogen, alkyl, alkenyl, and/or heteroaryl group (e.g. morphilino, pyrrolidino, or piperidinyl groups), whether or not further substituted.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC55FC3E94AE34ACB8C1E8BD4762E650A">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>At the 2-position:</text> <list level="paragraph"> <list-item>i. Replacement of the alkyl portion of the benzyl group with a substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, alkoxy, carbamates group, nitrogen, sulfur, and/or oxygen atoms.</list-item> <list-item>ii. Replacement of the phenyl portion of the benzyl group with an aryl or heteroaryl group.</list-item> </list> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6E33B4DE37C401EA9630C848EF0ABCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Substitution on the phenyl portion of the benzimidazole ring with a hydrogen atom, halogen, nitro, cyano, substituted or unsubstituted amide, amine, alkyl, alkoxy, aryl, and/or heteroaryl groups.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE35ECCF8A268485FA9735AA9FB0DE2FD">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>At the 6-position, substitution with hydrogen, nitro, trifluoromethyl, methoxy, trifluoromethoxy, cyano, and halogen groups.; and</text>
                            </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC1C99F8E0C004DF6B10CE27C1FF3A1CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Exhibits agonist activity at the mu-opioid receptor.</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such substances include, but are not limited to: etonitazene, clonitazene, metonitazene, isotonitazene, protonitazene, butonitazene, etodesnitazene, flunitazene, N-pyrrolidino etonitazene, N-desethyl isotonitazene, and N-piperidinyl etonitazene.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7DC18ABF1F1A46E4B8738B458FF38EA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of temporary status</header><text>Any substance included in the amendment to section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act made by this section that was temporarily scheduled under section 201(h) of the Controlled Substances Act shall be deemed permanently scheduled and subject to the requirements of Schedule I as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H905A1BD712F741C6B843D600A491694C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to authorize the initiation of new research using substances described in the amendment made by subsection (a) without proper registration and scheduling compliance.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

