<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25141-GC5-LG-8C6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S738 IS: Dangerous Viral Gain of Function Research Moratorium Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide a moratorium on all Federal research grants provided to any institution of higher education or other research institute that is conducting dangerous gain-of-function research.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dangerous Viral Gain of Function Research Moratorium Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id85578f2dffde4bdfa5eb52044fcf8756"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal research grants for institutions and research institutes conducting dangerous gain-of-function research</header><subsection id="id1684dea11e4d46d9b387b797808b1bfa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67b06bca7df54fa7bf3ab1e9727afbd7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gain-of-function research</header><text>The term <term>gain-of-function research</term> means any research that—</text><subparagraph id="id113fa76135734bd8959535a551fedb47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involves the genetic alteration of an organism to change or enhance the organism's biological functions, which change or enhancement may include increased infectivity, transmissibility, pathogenicity, or host range (which is the spectrum of hosts that an organism can infect); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b1dba29fe634753b64f91ef1dcb6372"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be reasonably anticipated to confer attributes to an organism, such that the organism would have enhanced infectivity, pathogenicity, or transmissibility, or otherwise pose a threat to national security, public safety, or the health of humans, companion animals, or livestock, poultry, seafood and aquaculture species, or game animals. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7ac8f35380f4815867a90578c525f31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organism</header><text> The term <term>organism</term> means an influenza virus, a coronavirus (including a Middle Eastern Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) virus, SARS–CoV–1, SARS–CoV–2, or SARS-like viruses), or an agent or toxin on the Select Agents and Toxins List of the Department of Health and Human Services or the Department of Agriculture under part 331 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, part 121 of title 9, Code of Federal Regulations, or part 73 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or any synthetic construct of such virus, agent, or toxin. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8a5de2a0aaf54e958e43c7bea15ff007"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no research grants supported by Federal funds may be awarded to institutions of higher education, or other research institutes, that are conducting gain-of-function research. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

