<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD84B429686E04B07BB6CEFEA0B13DBDF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5186 IH: To authorize the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program to support the defense biotechnology supply chain, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5186</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program to support the defense biotechnology supply chain, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H158AC43974294E3781FCEE95BAA1B363" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC60D4F8DFCE4827AB2F158824C3B1D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Biotechnology supply chain resiliency program</header> 
<subsection id="HD07F2959CA564C7D9D34566BC277F83B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header> 
<paragraph id="H5D77868D06344B6EAB2EAC1BCC550000"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of relevant Defense Agencies, may establish and implement a program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) to develop, scale, and transition biotechnology research from the military service laboratories, including biotechnology-based chemicals, materials, fuels, and other products relevant to the mission of the Department of Defense that support the resilience, sustainability, and responsiveness of the defense supply chain.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3EC7041B4754E1E9B48BAD296F6B3CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Under the Program, the Secretary of Defense may carry out the following activities:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5552816DB05D499FBDC480EA2D550232"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conduct an assessment of supply chain vulnerabilities in the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59A9768C138F4B6E825AA097A068C8BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Direct the military service laboratories to establish mechanisms to collaboratively—</text> 
<clause id="H533753E43F714F5786FB125512A2EFAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct applied research, including experimentation, advanced technological development, advanced component development, and rapid prototyping in bioindustrials, biomanufacturing, and related disciplines to support defense missions;</text></clause> <clause id="HA24499E7D2C1468C88453D6DF3734FAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop, prototype, test, and transition biologically derived materials and products to reduce reliance on foreign supply chains and vulnerable supply chains;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H893B7800B23F41D38FB96735B15BF587"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>upgrade, expand, or construct physical and digital infrastructure, including laboratory facilities, of the Department and its partners to support bioindustrial research, development, testing, prototyping, and production;</text></clause> <clause id="H63E224C40603473EBCA4825AB09F62BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>as needed, enter into contracts, cooperative agreements, grants, or other transactions with relevant Federal entities and non-Federal entities such as commercial entities, research institutions, and academic organizations to execute the activities under this paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBB2F6422F52542EB92B81130AC5EB6CE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>support education, training, and workforce development initiatives to build and sustain a skilled bioindustrial and biomanufacturing workforce.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13084BFE968446C6BC8D50CF2B658395"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Collaborate across the military departments, Defense Agencies, and other Federal entities to ensure alignment with national bioindustrial and supply chain strategies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H625EAC50E2CF4DEBB4068BD37EC22B7A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Promote the development and utilization of next-generation feedstocks and processes in ways that support local economic growth.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67B7003B034E4B5E94CA77ADE4D4B319"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Modernize infrastructure through investment in facilities that enable rapid prototyping and advanced materials testing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1506EF5645A4EB68F24CC2A19258C8D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Establish performance metrics and benchmarks to measure progress toward operational integration and transition to programs of record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83980D126766445FBE117AEA99BEC084"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other considerations</header><text>In the event the Secretary carries out the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAA1CAD5F28F24A32824116B399AD6EA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prioritize technologies and capabilities that address critical defense supply chain vulnerabilities and enhance military readiness, including technologies and capabilities necessary to—</text> <clause id="H24EA6F62709A4188B35DF753AACF324F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce logistics through field-enabled manufacturing of materials such as construction-grade bio-cement and deployable infrastructure components;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC69B34E32DD64F94A5D45CBC399644AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enhance performance through development of novel materials including protective coatings and biologically derived composites; or</text></clause> <clause id="H26AFDB4072474BC2A82398F11D516225"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve cost efficiency of manufacturing and reduce dependency on foreign supply chains;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE781716B3414823AC4E1BEFE3CE645A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with representatives of industry, academia, and other Federal agencies with relevant expertise, to accelerate development and transitions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E4746C99E54495698532ED51B522CAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the Program supports the development and fielding of emerging technologies such as biotechnologies that provide operational and strategic advantages to the Armed Forces, including through—</text> 
<clause id="H885CB8B621D044F7B55B8EF99D70BDF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cross-service and public-private partnerships; and</text></clause> <clause id="H936F6B398DA344CD9295B376D04550BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applied research, pilot-scale production, and technology transition efforts focused on biomanufacturing and materials innovation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F2207A373C2482C8073A7C1F204A118"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan and reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H6C0C058866E942D591516C4D4F68EBBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after electing to commence the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a plan for the allocation of appropriations to fund the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAA2471A707D41EEAB6D5868D2435EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after commencing the Program, and annually thereafter until the Program terminates under subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report detailing all activities carried out under the program. Each report shall include, to the extent applicable, the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9FE95A01C12E4E6BBFDF1313A33C3EB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of key research, development, and prototyping efforts initiated or continued during the year covered by the report, including technical objectives, anticipated defense applications, and funding.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13E3F0A88FCE4770901E9CD464E1AF05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of significant partnerships or agreements executed with industry, academic institutions, and other Federal agencies, including the purpose, national security nexus, and funding level of each such partnership or agreement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22AF6CDA186E422AB81F405DE7B9BC51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of infrastructure enhancements undertaken to support bioindustrial development and scale-up, including facility modernization and equipment acquisition.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE00664E35A8C4C6AAE42A2433F9CB64A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An evaluation of program performance against established milestones or metrics, including progress toward the transition of technologies to operational use or acquisition programs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1420778A2DA04B21AC433018B79E9112"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An identification of major technical, logistical, or policy challenges encountered, and actions taken to mitigate such challenges.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20870012B7CE4D929588827BC1E9F98D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any recommendations for additional authorities, funding mechanisms, or interagency coordination necessary to enhance the effectiveness of the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14C5B29D5CF145929C66B077B165A404"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CE8D02E4D5A45D6AA00420B9CEE7322"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header> <paragraph id="H219DE3B7D8A24F53927C0AC7F42620DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the authority to carry out the Program shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50B171587247478FA99A8734E707CFFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Program may be continued after the termination date specified in paragraph (1) if, before such date, the President—</text> <subparagraph id="H01DD3504474B48719524C25B047B7EFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that continuation of the Program is necessary to meet national economic or national security needs; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56B6499CD41E4166878204253CC9DB81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits notice of such determination to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

