<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDBC0C18591F3477F9CDA43BC5E569229" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 267 IH: Recognizing the 10th Anniversary of Educators Rising.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 10th Anniversary of Educators Rising.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Future Teachers of America was established in 1937 to inspire high school students to pursue careers as teachers in America’s public schools;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Future Teachers Association evolved into the Future Educators Association, which was acquired by Phi Delta Kappa (PDK) International in 1994 and rebranded as Educators Rising in 2015, transforming into a nationwide movement dedicated to preparing and inspiring the next generation of extraordinary educators;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising addresses the critical teacher shortage in middle and high schools across the United States by reimagining pathways for teacher recruitment through innovative Grow Your Own (GYO) initiatives that attract and cultivate local talent, helping to create teaching staff reflective of student body demographics;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas research shows that over 60 percent of K–12 teachers in the United States teach within 20 miles of the high school they attended, underscoring the importance of local pathways into the teaching profession;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas teachers who share similar backgrounds and experiences with their students foster stronger student-teacher relationships, improved academic outcomes, and more inclusive school climates;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising operates as a community-based Career and Technical Student Organization, identifying, educating, and supporting middle and high school students in rural, urban, and suburban communities with a passion for education;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising provides a robust curriculum that includes foundational pedagogy, real-world clinical experiences, and professional development to prepare students for success in postsecondary education and careers in education;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising boasts a presence in all 50 States and the District of Columbia, with over 1,400 chapters and 38 State-level partnerships;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Educators Rising National Conference brings together thousands of students annually to compete, showcase their skills, network with peers and professionals, and celebrate their achievements;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising partners with higher education institutions and State Departments of Education to create seamless transitions into teacher preparation programs, addressing teacher shortages and fostering community-centered teaching workforces;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Educators Rising Collegiate supports students transitioning to higher education and prepares students for careers in education;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas PDK International’s scholarship program annually awards nearly 100 scholarships ranging from $500 to $5,000 to students pursuing careers in education through Educators Rising, Educators Rising Collegiate, Pi Lambda Theta, and other programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since 1994, over 325,000 students have participated in Educators Rising, including nearly 145,600 students since its rebranding in 2015, showcasing the program’s significant impact on cultivating future educators;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Educators Rising has been recognized as a model solution to the teacher shortage crisis by numerous States, including Connecticut, Louisiana, Illinois, and Pennsylvania, for its ability to build strong educator pathways; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, 2025 marks the 10th anniversary of Educators Rising’s rebranding, solidifying its role as a vital movement in addressing the teacher shortage and supporting students in their journey toward careers in education: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6886993ED9D9434989B5FDB55011A443"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCC1B51CFCE5F47AC92C2BE2C47A70AD2"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE8B4452D58F749039D9CC5EE6300C3A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">celebrates the 10th anniversary of Educators Rising and commends its contributions to addressing the teacher shortage crisis by creating innovative educator pathways;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AFB7C6D5F7C43C4BA27115A28CF1DB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of Grow Your Own initiatives in increasing the Nation’s education workforce by inspiring and preparing students to pursue careers in teaching;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F4E049CF1B1480DB2CE254604775A13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the continued development of partnerships between secondary schools, postsecondary institutions, and organizations like Educators Rising to prepare and support students for success in the education profession;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CC8E4DB95F042CE9E9B25A0D28A6698"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends Educators Rising for its role in fostering a dynamic teaching workforce reflective of the Nation’s student demographics; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75416D11453A4524A77B018FBDDE5097"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages continued investment in programs like Educators Rising that inspire and equip the next generation of educators to transform schools and communities.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

