<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7002D54DAB434543A69D00A1E462BDD2" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1179 IH: Chiquita Canyon Tax Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250210">February 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exclude from gross income certain relief payments to the victims of the Chiquita Canyon elevated temperature landfill event.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H597A39E2AC7B4913AC753C46573BD7EF"><section id="H74A06708FF3E444F910FB7DB981524AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chiquita Canyon Tax Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3349BC8C8B1D40069C61E4871B99BC28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chiquita canyon disaster relief payments</header><subsection id="H46BECB20A20B4845921C1AB9B8229B9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaster relief payments to victims of chiquita canyon Elevated Temperature Landfill Event</header><text>Chiquita Canyon elevated temperature landfill event payments shall be treated as qualified disaster relief payments for purposes of section 139(b) of the Internal 2 Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16196C4EBDF04823BA10D2AA9BCC6865"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chiquita canyon elevated temperature landfill event payments</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term, <term>Chiquita Canyon elevated temperature landfill event payments</term> means any amount received by or on behalf of an individual as compensation for loss, damages, expenses, relocation, suffering, loss in real property value, closing costs with respect to real property (including realtor commissions), or inconvenience (including access to real property) resulting from the Chiquita Canyon elevated temperature landfill event if such amount was provided by—</text><paragraph id="HC747A3A6EF274132B682734BA33738BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or local government agency,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D848876B46445028EB937D7EBBBCDDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Waste Connections, Inc., or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H595D7DED90AF4E919F69D78FB6EF095E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any subsidiary, insurer, or agent of Waste Connections, Inc. or any related person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F253EE5C54640AA9AF33093912A002A"><enum>(c)</enum><header> Elevated temperature landfill event</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>Chiquita Canyon elevated temperature landfill event</term> means the elevated temperature landfill event occurring beneath the Chiquita Canyon Landfill in Los Angeles County, California, beginning on May 1, 2022.</text></subsection><subsection id="H14534952132C468F814BDC1F27D44B2D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to amounts received on or after March 1, 2024.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

