<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H620805EEF56E48CA8C2C81A7A9A66079" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3979 IH: Leveraging Efficiency Awareness for Pumping Systems Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3979</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to provide information and education tools to farmers on the cost savings, energy savings, water conservation, and carbon emissions reductions that can be realized through the use of energy-efficient pumping systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8AA7F4570FAB4DFEB296D3A3C6AC366E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H658272703BB44A3FB1671B954EEC094B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Efficiency Awareness for Pumping Systems Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LEAPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H22A47E30B6644F20843C03745A4F18E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD3D9EE2C97144F60A8A8A556F0FBF7F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are over 600,000 pumping systems used for irrigation on agricultural land in the United States, many of which still rely on fossil fuels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2CD250BCEC44FDB99A87C3423A734BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Improving the efficiency of agricultural irrigation pumping systems can save up to 22 billion kilowatt hours of energy per year and eliminate 8.3 million metric tons of carbon emissions annually.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CB0E734998C49968E1567530D387FBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Energy savings from electrifying agricultural irrigation pumping systems can save farmers and ranchers more than $1.8 billion annually in energy costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F432DD56C2E4DBAA2F5AC28BBCB935D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pumping systems play a central role in the watering of livestock and the management of animal waste in every State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF6914932BD74A69BAFEFC40ECC53C08"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pumping systems are a critical component of the Nation’s $2,300,000,000 aquaculture industry.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D2E442DF9954C21A8C2BE9B94874784" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Improving the efficiency of pumping systems used in raising livestock and fish can significantly reduce energy use, save producers millions of dollars annually, and provide meaningful reductions in carbon emissions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3C9DBCBD9274AFDA77FEE79FB89D44D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Agricultural irrigation pumping systems utilizing plastic piping can provide significant drought relief benefits, dramatically reducing water losses from evaporation and seepage; agriculture uses 37 percent of the Nation’s surface and ground water, 30 percent of which is lost to seepage and evaporation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD2BB530E72A4B92AB0964E96F8577C3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Reducing the friction in piping used for agricultural irrigation and livestock watering can provide meaningful energy and cost savings; there are potentially 2,500 kWh of energy savings for every 10 miles of plastic piping utilized in delivering water for crops and livestock.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4B8D7C7235E4983817F1AEFFBA1EC23"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Solar pumping systems can play an important role in protecting riparian habitat and improving water quality in streams, rivers, lakes, and estuaries through providing alternative watering options for livestock.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H16F19049C2DA44D8A1E6CCB84CC9C348"><enum>3.</enum><header>Information on energy-efficient pumping systems</header> 
<subsection id="H9F8B8E792EC940AB8F1A6987CAD92D04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with pumping system experts, in order to educate farmers on the benefits of energy-efficient pumping systems, shall develop and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Agriculture easily accessible information on cost savings, energy savings, water conservation, and carbon emissions reductions that can be realized through the use of energy-efficient pumping systems.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H39A537EB6818480D84AC5683F4BD14C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall include information on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1CF1CBCC31034C2083FD28DCF86F2E1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pumps, pipes, motors, drives, and controls that can provide energy savings and cost savings, conserve water, and reduce carbon emissions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H483BA1D1A27F4C0FB09D8F0AAD0136A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Agriculture programs that provide farmers resources for acquiring energy-efficient pumping systems and drought management infrastructure, including the environmental quality incentives program, the Rural Energy for America Program, and the conservation stewardship program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4625C250FCE44F58A5FCC476F36117E9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Energy efficiency pre-assessment tool</header> 
<subsection id="HEB3611D765C34A23A5F3AC3D1ED541EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with pumping system experts, in order to raise awareness of the benefits of energy-efficient pumping systems and increase participation in Department of Agriculture programs that promote energy efficiency, shall develop and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Agriculture a user-friendly tool to—</text> <paragraph id="H9161EA7121CD40B6A1E7AFDB9FFBB93A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist farmers in making a preliminary assessment of the energy efficiency of existing pumping systems; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H904AC59C01794AB098C27AF47F59FCAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide an estimate of potential energy savings, cost savings, and carbon emissions reductions that may be realized through pumping system improvements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4539ED6F302648AF9DAB7D3271D22F88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <paragraph id="HE4D998F587F14F218DAF3BDD1E6DFBB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ease of use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the tool made available under subsection (a) provides a user with projected energy savings, projected cost savings, and projected carbon emissions reductions through the input by the user of the following data relating to an existing pumping system:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE6165CACB99A4E7193E4AE65383BF28B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Pump type.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B89E348838D401687997D9A3A5DE468"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Flow rating and actual flow.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4A93CEBA70049B180EEDBFC4142B05D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Pressure rating and actual pressure.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03B9B5F69E884AA1A9AA843094411138"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Speed rating and actual speed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9AA2DFBFF034A4F893DC98304E780CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the tool made available under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H69AB2922A59648C1B33B0F712930947C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in assessing the energy efficiency of a pumping system, takes into consideration pumps, pipes, motors, drives, and controls associated with the pumping system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63BEC75611F94551AEBA5569BFE76B73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in projecting the energy savings, cost savings, and carbon emissions reductions that may be realized through pumping system improvements, takes into consideration the cost of electricity and the profile of the existing pumping system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7DE7117B7D774099AD23D0912E71C33E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Energy auditor education</header> <subsection id="HCF57E5227CF54F0293CFDD4596200FBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with pumping system experts, in order to increase the effectiveness of Department of Agriculture energy efficiency programs, shall establish a process to educate persons performing energy efficiency audits for the Department of Agriculture on energy use and energy efficiency in pumping systems.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2CFACC0DBF244CCBAD9F539BC6B5C88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the use of existing education and training programs focused on energy use and energy efficiency in pumping systems.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC766B391BCFF4DB1ACDDB2D14687AA7A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Conservation stewardship program activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1240I(2)(B)(i) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839aa-21">16 U.S.C. 3839aa–21(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and energy-efficient pumping systems</quote> before <quote>, as determined</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB862363717414815B4CE3084548649A8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H61CD068DA1A5452AB568010F1883AE23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B9FE5533FDD465EA30E84E217B06C1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pumping system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pumping system</term> means any pumps, pipes, motors, drives, and controls used to move water and other fluids on farms, ranches, and aquaculture operations.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

