<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2B83CD3900240B3A6FA3DD3FD7A9DB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2532 IH: To prohibit certain removals of employees of the Department of Health and Human Services and sub-agencies and operating divisions thereof, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2532</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain removals of employees of the Department of Health and Human Services and sub-agencies and operating divisions thereof, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB5EFD3B4C5F64C589C89F1AE3C3D4D33" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H01259311C54E450B8E9B3FF1451FB713" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain removals of employees for Department of Health and Human Services and sub-agencies and divisions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be obligated or expended to remove any employee of the Department of Health and Human Services or any sub-agency or operating division of the Department of Health and Human Services under any agency action (including any reduction in force conducted pursuant to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code or any agency reorganization) that provides for—</text> <paragraph id="H28AC4FF336B84BBFB6B6A6E4EE82F292"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the removal of 3 percent or more of the total number of employees at the Department of Health and Human Services within a 60-day period; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF82FDAE0FECF4A8D99F681FF26D28CF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the removal of 3 percent or more of the total number of employees at each sub-agency or operating division within the Department of Health and Human Services within a 60-day period.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

