<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25263-91K-J9-897"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S791 IS: Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site in the State of Maryland as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H94BC160652084F5BA899A8949FDBFD33"><section section-type="section-one" id="H48DEC00186F348DF9619AD9946219C58"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC6C19295299D4D59907469CA0EFCB5DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header><subsection id="H52B4D7235E7C4C04B7D0C4DAC3E72389"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HD4E4942443F5452084CA70FCA53E987A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Thurgood Marshall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15536e4d48704a5db6c911ae2e590c0f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">led the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Legal Defense and Educational Fund from 1940 to 1961; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8856c82a7be403fa70b42d802ead4b9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">successfully argued 29 of 32 civil rights cases before the United States Supreme Court, including the landmark 1954 Brown v. Board of Education case that ended racial segregation of public schools;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf232499d86524b998576a8879f1cdd3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President John F. Kennedy appointed Thurgood Marshall to serve as a judge on the United States Court of Appeals for the 2nd Circuit from 1961 to 1965; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2876854a7da3437baa0e880e3d83e726"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Lyndon B. Johnson appointed Thurgood Marshall to serve as United States Solicitor General from 1965 to 1967;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DADDE485E414C968A0E685DCF3487F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>nominated by President Lyndon Johnson and confirmed by the Senate, Thurgood Marshall became the first African American to serve on the United States Supreme Court, serving as an Associate Justice from 1967 to 1991;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF5E6B7C3924EA680B20D32C2A0E633"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as a result of his long legal career, Thurgood Marshall is credited with ending legal segregation in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEB483A7DCC2464AB4DF41BD632B0A6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Public School 103, now known as the <quote>Justice Thurgood Marshall School</quote>, located at 1315 Division Street in Baltimore, Maryland, was the site of the elementary education of Thurgood Marshall;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H309164F9AF9B4C169A3A1AA06DA07C11"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Justice Thurgood Marshall School is owned and operated as a museum by the Beloved Community Services Corporation, which has completed a historic restoration for adaptive reuse of the School;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99E474321AA449988683F8959A8E1E38"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress authorized the National Park Service to prepare a special resource study of Public School 103 in 2019 which was transmitted by the National Park Service to Congress in 2023; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id023b91fd301b44c0b57055786a3c5ba5"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the special resource study referred to in paragraph (8), the National Park Service found that Public School 103 met the criteria for national significance and suitability for addition to the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6C64DA3C35345F8B99129FB454B095B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of future generations the significant historic contributions of Justice Thurgood Marshall by—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc74f47e356b44569900cc10cf592d466"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing the elementary school attended by Marshall as a national historic site; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d6d22224d774c229ac65c869f401127"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing for the administration of the National Historic Site as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF84709C13B3F491EA809C6FA5D5048C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id340af75f06b141daa4156848bd12083c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The term <quote>management entity</quote> means the management entity for the National Historic Site designated by section 4(e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41CC1D98655F4DA8A293CB523286D989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National historic site</header><text>The term <term>National Historic Site</term> means the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site established by section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49C1D1C9B1DC4E82BB6D50FEFEDDEBDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>School</term> means the building located at 1315 Division Street in Baltimore, Maryland, known as Public School 103, which is owned and managed by the Beloved Community Services Corporation, a nonprofit organization established in Baltimore, Maryland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D20E53086A149C88C8E6EDEEE2BC76A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2BB9E1422E274849849D25AA05319A79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site</header><subsection id="H3FEDDF7DBD2041E59168463E1176B6CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established as an affiliated area of the National Park System the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1847977E9AD14ED5A9B8400D9FFEB3BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The National Historic Site shall consist of the School, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Justice Thurgood Marshall School National Historic Site Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 962/194939, and dated September 2024.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE3E3D8D684934025919F6C9E63CF515E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ownership</header><text>The School shall continue to be owned, operated, and managed by the Beloved Community Services Corporation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H96D3D3E9DFCF40EF82EC4973B112CFEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The National Historic Site shall be managed in a manner consistent with—</text><paragraph id="HC7F73514641E43928D444C580BB2183F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30D184D075EB4914A016F7991CFCBC94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE275B70F80BE40D8B4006700DD0B57B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The Beloved Community Services Corporation shall be the management entity for the National Historic Site.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF5CEB4B19C914B86BD29BB1EF4C40A1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H0DDF8A7149F7421F9EB747C391748567"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may provide technical assistance to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the management entity for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the National Historic Site; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C41AEB286E4AEAB854B82D700EA285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall enter into an agreement with the management entity that delineates the roles and responsibilities for the management of the area consistent with the policies and standards that apply to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8B98E661CE44A72988A97A4A510AA41"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limited role of the secretary</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5bffdd5d89d846eea7800505c32e1275"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to acquire the School; or </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb83ed450a60d4b969754794871ac6bad"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the National Historic Site.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA3F0018D4F8C49F89DC0AF71A24E5636"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

