<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F947F91F56149F39ECB52AE60AC2574" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2175 IH: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 130 South Patterson Avenue in Santa Barbara, California, as the “Brigadier General Frederick R. Lopez Post Office Building”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 130 South Patterson Avenue in Santa Barbara, California, as the <quote>Brigadier General Frederick R. Lopez Post Office Building</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2030F0F6AE444B27B73A92F4ECC241B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9A8C326B3E1F4562BB82A8C46E80D877" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Brigadier General Frederick R. Lopez Post Office Building</header>
<subsection id="HF671C4D4CFCB4F50AF604F1210917467"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 130 South Patterson Avenue in Santa Barbara, California, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Brigadier General Frederick R. Lopez Post Office Building</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1094061A44604CC2A1512A95E7A2BF4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Brigadier General Frederick R. Lopez Post Office Building</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

