<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H147A7DE1216D469E802DA8FF97998BD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5745 IH: Marine Fisheries Habitat Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote fish habitat through the enhancement of certain offshore oil and gas platforms and pipelines as artificial reefs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H35F9EAD671EB4B3FA413BD0DE295DF59" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5DA3BA11F0F74E97BAC04BE519BBC817" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marine Fisheries Habitat Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H00728E57D7004E3D888B655078193DD2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of certain offshore oil and gas platforms and pipelines for artificial reefs</header> <subsection id="HA7B08E937F9742D9A63118A6A56C226F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984</header><text>The National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCFCC3FEFC43C464D960800B1105B1BC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending section 206 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2105">33 U.S.C. 2105</external-xref>) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB0BD830CAEB7499C91C3DBE514A8C594" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H06C4ACBD490647439BE17120495CAD29"><enum>206.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD52E33038EA4042AB6344BA843AD2AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere in the Under Secretary’s capacity as Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H921665F4B9A74930BDCBACE8039502E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial reef</header><text>The term <term>Artificial reef</term> means a structure or facility and associated equipment and infrastructure which is located, constructed or placed in Covered Waters that enhances fishery resources and commercial and recreational fishing opportunities, including, without limitation, Approved Structures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B500684E8344E08A7BEFC8FAEAF8EAF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Principal Deputy Director Exercising the Delegated Authorities of the Director of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50B4C40D1D73499E80EDE594A7A3D22A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decommissioning</header><text>For the purposes of this title, the term <term>Decommissioning</term> means ending oil, gas, or sulphur operations on an offshore lease, right-of-way, or right-of-use and easement and returning the area subject to such lease, right-of-way, or right-of-use and easement to a condition that complies with applicable law, including, without limitation, Reefing in Place of Approved Structures, or removal of platforms and structures, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H227BB7FDF94E4E8DABF6475147F621A1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Established reef ecosystem</header><text>The term <term>established reef ecosystem</term> means an area with identified reef-associated species, including species of corals, crustaceans, fish, or other marine life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7891618D92B74B1682108747F3D3828A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Approved structure</header><text>The term <term>approved structure</term> means an Eligible Structure which the Secretary of the Interior has approved for Reefing in Place pursuant to Section 207(a)(5)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BBCC70562C94B21BE7C7D02ADFE38B7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligible structure</header><text>The term <term>eligible structure</term> refers to an Inactive Structure that is determined eligible for Reefing in Place by the Director pursuant to Section 207(a)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84701FA99FDC430DB3E56F9D7B896E08"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Inactive structure</header><text>The term <term>inactive structure</term> means an oil or gas platform, structure, facility, pipeline, and associated equipment and infrastructure—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4807A2F86C784E3E965841509A7FE37A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that either—</text> <clause id="HD99EE338F7FF4261B738DCEC77A21E6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Applicant determines is no longer useful for operations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H982CB003D32D41C38D3544CB1625CEDB">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is located on a lease, right-of-way, right-of-use and entry or other similar right that has expired, terminated, been relinquished or abandoned or is no longer valid and effective; or</text>
                                    </clause> 
<clause id="H2D4225806DFE4BD18237D79C0E446123"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is currently on the sea floor as a result of an act of God or event of force majeure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H146BB0B3268A467F85169680B4606FF2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Partial removal</header><text>The term <term>Partial Removal</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9C0C0524C4334A919865EC1A114AABDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the severance and removal of a portion of an Inactive Structure at a level that maximizes the vertical relief of the structure in the water column at the minimum depth from the surface to maintain navigational safety, as determined by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Commandant of the Coast Guard; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DC06B9FAB45414FACB46C0393A18DFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>optionally, the placement of the severed portion of the Inactive Structure on the sea floor in proximity to the base of the unsevered portion of the structure or at an alternative reef planning area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAB686F6055A4DFCAE7065138DF28040"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Reef in place</header><text>The term <term>Reef in Place</term> or <term>Reefing in Place</term> means Decommissioning of an Approved Structure, in whole or in part, by abandoning in place, Toppling in Place, or Partial Removal of the Approved Structure in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9472F4E83B04F3A842C20F7A4EFF2B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attempts to maximize reef ecosystem for benthic and pelagic species throughout the entirety of the water column; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61E3F76687634AF78FE7E5109682405F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is at the appropriate minimum depth from the surface to maintain navigational safety as determined by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Commandment of the Coast Guard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H751E691E73F44D4F9587B2BCF55E8C27"> <enum>(11)</enum> <header>Applicant</header> <text>The term <term>applicant</term> refers to a current or former lessee, right-of-way holder, right-of-use holder or operating rights owner that has assumed operational control or regulatory responsibility over an Inactive Structure, or has received an order from the Secretary of the Interior to perform decommissioning on an Inactive Structure, or is otherwise legally responsible for Decommissioning an Inactive Structure. Parties that do not meet any of this criteria may apply to the Director to be deemed an Applicant for the purposes of this title, to the extent that multiple parties meeting the definition of Applicant exist, the party designated to the Department of the Interior as the single entity to serve as an operator or agent for the decommissioning operations shall be the Applicant for the purposes of this title.</text>
                            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB1F20F1D6F24236B5FE6101BD25F3D9"><enum>(12)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, Johnston Island, Midway Island, and Wake Island.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B65135ACC4C49B9BAFEBA2FEF309B4F"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Topple in place</header><text>The term <term>Topple in Place</term> or <term>Toppling in Place</term> means detaching an Approved Structure or a portion of the Approved Structure from the seabed and toppling the approved structure or a severed portion of the Approved Structure onto its side on the seabed in the same area or immediately adjacent to the area where the Approved Structure was originally installed or abandoned.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45AB30F0C8374B179F683A2FB613D805"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Covered waters</header><text>The term <term>Covered Waters</term> means the navigable waters of the United States and the waters superjacent to the Outer Continental Shelf as defined in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>), to the extent such waters exist in or are adjacent to any State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CF76CD4F29F49ECBF8D0E3382B5B7B0"><enum>(15)</enum><header>State program</header><text>The term <term>State Program</term> means any State Artificial Reef program authorized under section 207(c).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EBBCCB7258048C7918E4610797749AA"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Reef planning area</header><text>The term <term>Reef Planning Area</term> means an area identified and designated as such by the Director under section 207(a)(4).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D40B02E48F648FE971BE7D3A913800F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending section 207 to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H03F8EA78E3BF437982928C7E2DC06DCA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H130DB45243E74F40ABC9F22BB1EF2C2C"><enum>207.</enum><header>Reef in place</header> 
<subsection id="H0747E6A1852A4615B8694085F947B6F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reef in place</header><text>An Applicant may elect to Reef in Place the Inactive Structure in accordance with the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE1BEB4F2C7AC48C6B587D1DB2326DFC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of intent to reef</header><text>To Reef in Place, an Applicant may submit a Notice of Intent to Reef an Inactive Structure at any time to the Director.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48488714E5BF4A0AA55F79D83B93D9E2">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Assessment</header>
 <text>Within 180 days of submission of a Notice of Intent to Reef under Section 207(a)(1), initiate the following assessment.</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="H171E8B61E4ED42C7A4875119AF1C93F9">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Director shall, in response to an Applicant request, conduct or appoint a State or qualified third-party to perform on its behalf, an assessment of each Inactive Structure, which shall, with respect to each Inactive Structure include an assessment of—</text>
                                        <clause id="H7A37D8C42DF94A5CB1F1DEDD0092B78A">
                                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in consultation with the Administrator the localized corals, fish species, and other marine life that use the Inactive Structure as a habitat; and</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="H06DEEB1E41064E0F98691563A444F1F0">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the economic benefits of Reefing in Place, including a comparison of the cost to replace the Inactive Structure with an equivalent cubic volume, including interstitial spaces, of appropriate artificial material if the Inactive Structure is removed.</text>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H724633CF117640E8B3901BC5A64F68D2">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                                        <header>Assessment conducted by applicant</header>
 <text>The Director may permit an Applicant to conduct an assessment or enter into an agreement with a State or qualified third-party to perform on its behalf, an assessment report for each Inactive Structure to be submitted to the Director, which shall, with respect to each Inactive Structure satisfy the assessment criteria set forth in subparagraph (2)(A).</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H43D6291973984996B4A2B75F080ECB84">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>To the extent practicable, the assessment under this subparagraph (2) must be completed within one year of receipt by the Director of the Notice of Intent to Reef.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EB42ABBDF49497FAC0D6DCFEE50EE92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility determination</header><text>Not later than 60 days after completion of the assessment conducted under subparagraph (2)(A), or receipt by the Director of the assessment report conducted under subparagraph (2)(B), the Director, after consultation with the Administrator, shall make a formal determination that the Inactive Structure is an Eligible Structure if—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDF2E38732714DD6908CE9DF19D78F35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is an Established Reef Ecosystem on, under, or in the immediate vicinity of the Inactive Structure, or there is potential for a reef ecosystem on, under, or in the immediate vicinity of the Inactive Structure; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H844714EF73A94A948DFF7EDEEC7F6D07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reefing in Place of the Inactive Structure is appropriate based on criteria described in the National Artificial Reef Plan (as amended) developed pursuant to Section 204.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H660B9820FEB1496BB192188C070D8DE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Designation of reef planning areas</header> <subparagraph id="HB219EF903D0D41D78F48FCA8294F7DF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the Director determines an Inactive Structure is an Eligible Structure pursuant to paragraph (3), the Director, in consultation with the associated State Reef Program, shall designate the footprint of the Eligible Structure or other proposed reefing location, along with any surrounding area deemed necessary for Reefing in Place, as a Reef Planning Area.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03085613B264409F86EFE51972602D4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Designation as a Reef Planning Area under subparagraph (4)(A) shall be made by the Director prior to any Reef in Place activity.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9FE1A3144FB41C7A80BEA86FBE87F91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require the redesignation of, or otherwise affect, any area already serving as a reef permitted area or existing Artificial Reef site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9896088319884E66B723535F287FF7D2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Not later than three years after the date on which the Director determines an Inactive Structure is an Eligible Structure, the Applicant may Reef in Place if—</text> <subparagraph id="H72C48B6EFE07485B892BB007681F2470"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the Eligible Structure—</text> 
<clause id="HCF674369A7D64A3681F15F5069612EE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all associated wells have been permanently plugged and abandoned pursuant to applicable law, including any departures approved by the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement;</text></clause> <clause id="HE04904ADCDE643AEB5CAF5B4B0A638A7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>hydrocarbons and other hazardous liquids have been removed in accordance with applicable laws and regulations;</text>
                                        </clause> 
<clause id="H61F38099346F4D388D0974A0AE1AC43A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if required by law or regulation, the Applicant installs identifying markers to protect and aid navigation;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8784C4B492049B5899E1424C46ACF35"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Applicant confirmed there is no outstanding responsibility or liability related to the Eligible Structure other than Decommissioning and related maintenance monitoring; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C170CBBDF8D48C7BB2DF1E1AC1F1397"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Applicant has transferred, or has an agreement to transfer, liability to a State agency upon completion of the reefing activity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C936D20A6524E82B20623964F05EA8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>And, the Secretary of the Interior determines the criteria in subparagraph 5(A) have been met and the Eligible Structure is reasonably sound and secure, upon which the Eligible Structure is deemed an Approved Structure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1EEF3CE1A474BE0B5B5C34FDFC8D99D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Secretary of the Interior, the Administrator, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Natural Resources of the Senate a report summarizing all actions taken in relation to an Inactive Structure under this Section 207 that occurred in the preceding twelve (12) months, including, without limitation, each Notice of Intent to Reef, assessment, Eligible Structure determination, Reef Planning Area designation, Approved Structure determination, and appeal submitted or conducted pursuant to this Section 207, which shall include a comprehensive map.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01E0857A1AB14E2E8420A15718FE54DE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Any Applicant may determine that it will not complete Reefing in Place at any time, regardless of whether or not it has, or prior Applicants have, completed any of the processes described in this Section 207. Any Applicant shall be entitled to terminate the processes commenced in this Section 207 upon written notice to the Director and remove or otherwise Decommission the Inactive Structure in accordance with applicable law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7FB3DBE8CF144E4B9E96E3F3F99ADD6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Other reefing or decommissioning mechanisms preserved</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall eliminate, modify or otherwise limit the ability of any party from pursuing the reefing of any Inactive Structure under any other program authorized by the National Fishing Enhancement Act or pursuing any other method of Decommissioning.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2F294AC0C9FE4909ACF13959972DE2E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Any Applicant aggrieved by a decision made under paragraph (a) may submit a written appeal within 60 days of the decision to the Director describing why the decision should be reconsidered. The Director shall respond with an appeal determination no later than 60 days after receipt of the appeal. Any determination made by the Director under this paragraph (b) is a final agency action subject to judicial review.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72120C3C178E4188AE02B6D5F211C824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State programs</header> 
<paragraph id="H3880EB0537184FA4A8BE6B172720AA2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that has a program to convert inactive structures into artificial reefs may enter into an agreement with any applicant to assume responsibility and liability no later than one year after a reef planning area is designated for an Eligible Structure in Covered Waters in exchange for an amount of funds that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B8C632ADD0547E0AA4FA0EFC01CD418"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is determined by the State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H079BFD10932544879E2142ADCD1CCB5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not exceed 50 percent of the cost savings gained by the Applicant due to reefing as determined by the Applicant and approved by the State, unless the Applicant consents to a greater amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7C5584B688A44579D24783294D13B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Upon acceptance by a State of an Eligible structure into a State Program described in subparagraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H855E364754FB4F03949C032E25A02F02"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Applicant shall have no responsibility or liability with respect to the Approved Structure following completion of the reefing activity unless otherwise agreed to by the Applicant and a State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42643F9914844E71929F4AE9BCAE16E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State shall be—</text> 
<clause id="HF6AF8668640948F2A845DD7D70112E6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solely responsible for the continued maintenance of the Approved structure, including maintaining any identifying markers installed to protect and aid navigation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H70095D86EDE94BECA6CB738F74B3F79A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exclusively responsible and liable for the Approved structure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6AC71D2B7394C1DBADD3806FEE391AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Outer continental shelf lands act</header><text>Section 5 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE1063520C78C4E72AA444DBBA883BA4C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Artificial reefs</header> <paragraph id="H484199618A6C4C77B5533A34A68F541F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDCE573C4478145D58A97450AC9405D64">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>For the purposes of this section, the terms <term>Administrator</term>, <term>Applicant</term>, <term>Approved Structure</term>, <term>Artificial Reef</term>, <term>Decommissioning</term>, <term>Director</term>, <term>Eligible Structure</term>, <term>Established Reef Ecosystem</term>, <term>Inactive Structure</term>, <term>Partial Removal</term>, <term>Reef in Place</term>, <term>Reef Planning Area</term>, <term>State Program</term>, <term>State</term>, and <term>Topple in Place</term> shall have the same meaning as set forth in section 206 of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref></text>
                                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35EB28720B974642A97EA685AD04B978">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                                        <header>Removal order</header>
 <text>The term <term>removal order</term> means any order, notice, or request to fully or partially remove an Inactive Structure sent by any Federal agent, including, without limitation any order to perform decommissioning.</text>
                                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE53044D090847B5A9C6C950C15AD815"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on removal orders</header> 
<subparagraph id="H066FB0662A6A4E98BA079B1936860CF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may not issue or enforce a Removal Order for an Inactive Structure during any of the following periods—</text> <clause id="H86FCB00EF966441B881489790633DBDE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial notice period</header><text>From the date an Applicant submits its first Notice of Intent to Reef pursuant to Section 207(a)(1) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref> for a given Inactive Structure and for a period of one year thereafter.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H29A8D3B3409E4BD0AAED04CE0E4E72A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Assessment period</header><text>From the date an assessment required under Section 207(a)(2) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref> is initiated, but not later than 18 months after the Notice of Intent to Reef is submitted.</text></clause> <clause id="H871A2D7552374D338F54F6B2697367EB"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <header>Pending determination</header> <text>After submission of an assessment to the Director pursuant to Section 207(a)(2) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>, and before the Director has made an Eligible Structure determination under Section 207(a)(3) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref></text>
                                        </clause> 
<clause id="H6BD97256793B4114BC7741669EDFC951"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Eligible determination</header><text>After a determination that the structure is an Eligible Structure under Section 207(a)(3) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>, and for a period not to exceed three years following such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47B97D19B6A841AFA5CB69CE7E4E2CC8"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Appeal period</header> <text>After the date an appeal has been filed under Section 207(b) of the National Fishing Enhancement Act of 1984 (as amended), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2101">33 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>, and for 150 days thereafter.</text>
                                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD9665CCCAED48CAA23E9D74F579D575"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply with respect to an inactive structure that the Secretary of the Interior determines poses a substantial and imminent threat to—</text> <clause id="H489DB805500A4CA29BD913A5F9D3304E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>navigational safety; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5186E2394CDC488EB680FAFC4E1D8E7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the marine environment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72A987B03E5E4E30932F5F8F71C13FBB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Existing regulations</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify or supersede existing regulatory procedures for pipeline abandonment or decommissioning under the applicable provisions of the Code of Federal Regulations. Pipeline abandonment in place shall continue to follow established regulatory processes and shall not require additional permitting unless the pipeline is specifically designated for conversion to an Artificial Reef.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

