<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8D4EA14B0A84920B7539001D80B48A2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4199 IH: Modernize the Au Pair Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4199</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify the Department of State’s exclusive regulatory authority over the au pair cultural exchange program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF437C6F689B44F37AC6F378F7EB2DE58" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H825DE7F565D84467A0C95E23B7D1B093" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernize the Au Pair Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8D250A3D126A465590DE53138082C84A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9B5185D9B277419C97CE71C6B3A8BD23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress authorized in the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, (22 U.S.C. 2451 et. seq. (known as the <quote>Fulbright-Hays Act</quote>)) the creation of international educational and cultural exchange programs pursued through private-public partnerships between the Federal agency responsible for foreign affairs (initially the United States Information Agency or <quote>USIA</quote>) and designated sponsoring organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC5D22F31F35417285B6A7F22718DE8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1986, the USIA launched a pilot program referred to as the Federal <quote>au pair exchange program</quote>, whereby young foreign students would travel to the United States to live with and provide childcare to an American family, immerse themselves in American culture, and pursue academic credits at an accredited institution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB771329570B049D0B05D13F7FD5E46A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1994, Congress amended the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/415">Public Law 103–415</external-xref>, 108 Stat. 4299 (1994)) to clarify that the USIA should continue to administer the Federal au pair program consistent with foreign affairs purposes of the Fulbright-Hays Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23303E794B324A578125388122FC7DE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The USIA exercised its regulatory authority over the program to promulgate comprehensive regulations that set requirements for the educational component of the program, specified the eligibility criteria for au pairs, and crafted a nationally uniform weekly stipend formula for host families to provide to their au pairs that was based on an assumed number of weekly hours of childcare, indexed on the Federal minimum wage, and reflected a 40 percent credit for the provided room and board.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDCAB11653C174708A27A3CE6E0B788BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 1997, Congress authorized the Federal au pair program on a permanent basis (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/48">Public Law 105–48</external-xref>, 111 Stat. 1165 (1997)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8537C4A00EA14547A352427BB682873A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1999, the USIA disbanded and Congress transferred regulatory authority for the au pair program to the Department of State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BE55E9E171844A894FD295B00BE4331"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The au pair program is an important public diplomacy tool that furthers foreign policy objectives of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58354F8A1E8D4A3B999EE65A50B4D226"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The au pair program provides a critical source of affordable childcare for tens of thousands of American families at a time when the lack of access to such care costs the economy of the United States an estimated $122,000,000,000 annually in lost earnings, productivity, and revenue.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3472B62827194F94A127958C5C786963"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Studies have shown that over 10 percent of au pair host families are active duty military personnel, and additionally the au pair program has become an essential source of childcare for families of first responders, single parents, and shift workers and others with non-traditional work schedules.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4809616CB1724E48BFADA7C2D8D56EB9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Any and all Federal regulations pertaining to the au pair program must retain the national uniformity and affordability integral to allowing American working families to continue their participation in the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BE69619E5594C74BD5B4AAA07FA9C86"><enum>(11)</enum><text>American families participating in the au pair program must have clarity and confidence in what laws and regulations are applicable to the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507817EC2B80412A84D92359FFAF12EA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>It is clear that, consistent with congressional intent, the au pair program must be exclusively regulated by Federal law to successfully serve a foreign affairs purpose.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3ADD387F04C3455F81131043335BE37A" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of exclusive Federal regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State or political subdivision of a State may not enact or enforce a law, regulation, or other provision having the force or effect of law related to the au pair program administered by the Department of State.</text></section> <section id="HEB4807CEFBC743C09725C1E723CD0F21" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Revised proposed rule on au pair program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a proposed rule that shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FC9B70021904B96B33D2FE93C46F59E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a uniform national modification to the stipend and the educational stipend provided by a host family to an au pair, in a manner that does not make the program prohibitively expensive for and reflects the room, board, and other programmatic costs borne by a host family;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08106BA0A9DA4096B47BD79DC283934F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance flexibility in the au pair program, to accommodate unique work and family scheduling needs of military families, first responders, single parents, shift workers, and other host families with non-traditional work schedules; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE50FC2BBB9A841049FFE0A6F559AF64D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote the immersion of an au pair into the family life of their host family, consistent with the cultural exchange purposes of the au pair program.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

