<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54C0415B87D74AA5A0DA0A3A301777A2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4812 IH: To direct the Secretary of the Air Force to incorporate certain elements regarding depot-level maintenance coordination in at least one multinational exercise conducted in the area of operations of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4812</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Air Force to incorporate certain elements regarding depot-level maintenance coordination in at least one multinational exercise conducted in the area of operations of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BB6EB5D98394013B0832D800C681825" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB0FC3F35E9DB4FA49F9AAE24154A8E2D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Depot-level maintenance coordination in multinational exercises</header>
<subsection id="H23E73717805C4F64A8878A9435868527"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, the Secretary of the Air Force shall incorporate in at least one multinational exercise conducted in the area of operations of the United States Indo-Pacific Command—</text> <paragraph id="H248FFDCB79BC4A0DB2DDA84B4135B039"><enum>(1)</enum><text>depot-level maintenance, repair, and sustainment considerations, including binational or multinational planning sessions with covered nations on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC211E8B745B1426787367BC107B4D290"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to cooperate on depot-level maintenance and repair in ways that minimize transportation requirements in such area of operations and determining the authorities necessary to deliver the necessary joint capabilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93A3019DA159454C9F3B8CD15A764AC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating real-time coordination between the United States and covered nations to maintain munitions stock levels and resupply routes in the such area of operations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3F3B91448C734CC4B5F91CFCE9969527"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mutual recognition of airworthiness and maintenance certification between the United States and covered nations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51318E6B0615435AB092CC3E04FAFAFE"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>emergency tabletop exercises, such as when an aircraft of a covered nation breaks down on United States territory, and vice versa, in a contested logistics environment; and</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC211DB2D0E2F49C0B4EFC961BAC537E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordination with the Air Force Sustainment Center, including the participation of representatives of—</text> <subparagraph id="H12AF5496DAF84EA6ADA249D7741FE147"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Indo-Pacific Command;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCA2986FDDE5A4693909D4D45CC65E57F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States Air Force Pacific;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7751443E235F432693A93D4A432B152E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States Air Mobility Command; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9E8D6675297345C39884870ECCA0E40C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Air Force Sustainment Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H40F4AFFF0C6B468D940ECE6188EFFC21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Air Force shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the lessons learned from carrying out an exercise in accordance with subsection (a) with respect to the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia. Such report shall include each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H2CC4EA0DE2C54B368B19A6275CF7DCA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of candidate systems for co-sustainment with Korea and Australia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65445DC08E3543FCA921A24C2235F11A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of depot-level repair workload opportunities to undertake with Korea and Australia, including testing equipment or line replaceable units.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2ECA854EA4044A4883D607839C5C0DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Opportunities to incorporate Korean and Australian industry partners in depot-level maintenance repair activities, including through public-private partnerships.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F7E4FCB9B6F45A1A930CDF1DBBF4C51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of any potential logistical challenges that could arise with the host country, including with respect to workforce, housing, and location of workload.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7BCDDAEE258F473EB15CF014019D3C37"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An identification of any potential impediments involving intellectual property or data rights between original equipment manufacturers and the Department of the Air Force or between the Department of the Air Force and named partner countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01E354B549F14DB4A09C24836B0FAA3C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An identification of any potential impediments related to International Traffic in Arms Regulations and related statutes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9841FE5E2B0B41B993FB795173AA31C1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any additional recommendations to Congress that would ease the facilitation of depot-level maintenance repair partnerships with Korea and Australia, including changes to existing status of forces agreements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H786B518CE1034338A66334D718EFF1BE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An analysis of current maintenance and repair capabilities and gaps in the organic industrial base of Korea and Australia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6A93ADE72D642BE9E960CA7E2663861"><enum>(9)</enum><text>An assessment of the types of maintenance and repair activities (depot-level, preventative, corrective) that may be most appropriate for partnership with Korea and Australia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0FFCBA2CAF14446971C1F3D494751A5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>An assessment of how partnerships may contribute to allied contingency operations, interoperability, and regional posture resilience in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94E8760F6E6B4697AC2D9253CD1C0D8C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A consideration of planning factors related to the Air Force’s evolving force generation models, future-generation aircraft programs, deployment schedules, statutory maintenance thresholds, and other relevant operational requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD0D4EBC625EC4DBBA9830A61B50AA596"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered nation defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered nation</quote> means any of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H7341811846904C958BD5237985E05A50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Commonwealth of Australia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39B79DA81B6D4CD8BF4716BD7BCB9B57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Canada.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B969085CF8643ADB11D733DCA9270C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Japan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14A6D58A2CA847C09A0F0BB96C7F0552"><enum>(4)</enum><text>New Zealand.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4CFBE96149EC46528363559915C443EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Republic of Korea.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82A3C7362E124C19BBF88A7152D2761A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE4DBA7D03E64098B1E48D39AC7ED3F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other nation as designated as a covered nation for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

