<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25509-D8H-CJ-73J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2739 IS: Reducing Obesity in Youth Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2739</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to promote healthy eating and physical activity among children.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H57EA9ACA89584D9FAEBE917575989525"><section section-type="section-one" id="HBFAB200B4C1548E082E17004B4C69EBC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Obesity in Youth Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H819F190F7E57452C9A3FE9835E1FFE13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="HE05F1A3F3446411AA84CCFB61BF67394"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish a program that will enhance the training and knowledge of early care and education providers and influence practices, policies, and environments in early care and education settings to support healthy eating and physical activity for children ages birth through 5, including by addressing the growing threat of food insecurity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43E8F5AD9C534740A1DD19D82C7FFED9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide support to States on ways to link early care and education programs to nutrition supports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E501AF1647D48099AA0531FD1B3993E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to monitor progress of healthy eating and physical activity promotion in early care and education settings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9462475A826C4882B68152848B437417" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to identify emerging, and expand existing, approaches to engaging families and parents of children ages birth to 5 in healthy eating and physical activity.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB0FE4F544BAC4079ADEF394E08287F77"><enum>3.</enum><header>Healthy Kids Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part Q of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h">42 U.S.C. 280h et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaef6c390ec2f43d3af7d2502cc082bf3"><section id="H80FC2B837B354A4E92412489A7639EFD"><enum>399Z–3.</enum><header>Healthy Kids Grant Program</header><subsection id="HBDA6E3727E854C1A8D6064189182B9DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) and in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, shall award 5-year competitive grants to one or more eligible entities—</text><paragraph id="H2184950207504912A03D921847E464B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve healthy eating and physical activity among children ages birth through 5 years in early care and education settings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79805D12153E48EB96181B2FB9A786CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address food insecurity among such children.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EE754E2F5CF4A0BB7D40EBAB75BD379"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall be—</text><paragraph id="H460F8F273FE747DEA5D501B78ECC4BE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization with expertise in early childhood health and childhood obesity prevention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71041888F9E8429EA43D5E99C10156E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965) or research center that employs faculty with relevant expertise and has expertise in training early care and education providers; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41F6A93336C44841B16517762E7CBF8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in paragraphs (1) and (2) that submit a single application to carry out activities under the grant jointly.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52EA22D073B948FD80402085EDD9FD82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5926EF3DE0244436A2D0FFB332DD7D8A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H43D738953EA941B1BD16E95E8D756907"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity shall use amounts received under a grant under this section to work directly with implementing partners, which may include States, territories, Indian Tribes, municipalities, and nonprofit organizations—</text><subparagraph id="HC47A9A86F86B4FF9882A1CA7B0EEC53E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to create sustainable programs to train early care and education providers through direct coaching and peer-learning, access to quality technical assistance, and professional development opportunities that are focused on healthy eating, physical activity, addressing food insecurity, and other topics that support children’s healthy development, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28C9E78E8DAE4061B2E61FD184AC1EDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to build State capacity through training, technical assistance, and resources to integrate the promotion of healthy eating and physical activity into existing early care and education programs, systems, and initiatives, including linking early care and education programs to new and existing resources for nutrition supports, with a focus on promoting equity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE62C6262004DEBB796FFE2C579C7EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to test innovative or evidence-informed approaches to promoting healthy habits and healthy child development in early care and education settings, which may include linking early care and education and health care providers, enhancing early care and education staff wellness, enhancing access to quality foods in the early care and education settings, and engaging families of children ages birth to 5 years served in the early care and education programs supported by a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H004BC2BC350E4EF0B18F50909B25A3E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementing partners</header><text>In selecting implementing partners under paragraph (1), a recipient of a grant under this section shall ensure that such partners—</text><subparagraph id="H97C9DD4F3F694DDCA698529B6D858FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve populations that are racially, ethnically, socioeconomically, and geographically diverse; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80160C22E7A943AEA9EBBDFF7AC81CC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>represent a mix of rural and urban settings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48356B1F14324B61ACB8CCCCD2BAA72F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National independent evaluator</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, and prior to awarding any grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall enter into a contract with an external entity to create a single, uniform process to—</text><subparagraph id="H212183F24036419FBF5CEC2A28945C52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that entities that receive grants under paragraph (1) comply with the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCEB0C217D9045BBA084036F36819378"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the outcomes of the grant activities carried out by each participating entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0F44DFA3B3B4E42B081F119D7721266"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tracking State progress</header><text>The Secretary may use amounts appropriated under subsection (h)(2) to enter into contracts with, or award grants to, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, or other entities with relevant monitoring and surveillance expertise, for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H8E13A61D7A7D43C691CA78C568E1BE50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>tracking State progress in obesity prevention policies and practices of early care and education programs in States where grantees are present; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA672BD311FC54E38B3B139F49AA5006D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>measuring changes in food security within exposed groups.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8B652900180470CA179C9C18D3D96E1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the completion of the programs and activities (including monitoring and surveillance under subsection (e)) funded under grants awarded under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and all appropriate Federal agencies, a report concerning an evaluation of the results of such programs and activities, including best practices, and lessons derived from the experiences of grantees, with respect to reducing and preventing food insecurity and obesity and overweight among children ages birth through 5 years in the early care and education settings.</text></subsection><subsection id="H76CF484CFE73403383BCB54D6389877D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Early care and education defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>early care and education</term> means programs and activities that serve children ages birth through 5 years either through in-home or out-of-home settings, including childcare programs, Head Start programs, family childcare, and pre-kindergarten programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDA595BA00CC421884FC6AA70B22099D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H265FAD636E2F4B529D251C3204429F0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85A661E92494154B784B3401172F951"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding for tracking State progress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts made available under paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsection (e) $1,700,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

