<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCFBF18FCCA86436FA477D37058E0FA2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2798 IH: High-Quality Charter Schools Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2798</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against tax for charitable donations for the creation or expansion of charter schools.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3A2EE8CD9D0415C9EB2F9A36B45B5A8" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H17BAF2C00C2B4FB3B48CB05CEDFAA110"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>High-Quality Charter Schools Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H76594BBEF7854230A528304AB2AB8969"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax credit for contributions to eligible charter school organizations</header> <subsection id="HEF9F774EB073457B8B19E31FDC4A20B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 25E the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92AD71FCECE8451E88FAD349A677E828"> 
<section id="HFA5B07C0DECC413AA9CCCBDEAEB5F36E"><enum>25F.</enum><header>Contributions to eligible charter school organizations</header> 
<subsection id="HC22514BC6DF34E6DB2C11F897B5F0ADB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>In the case of an individual who is a citizen or resident of the United States (as defined in section 7701(a)(9)), there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 75 percent of the amount of qualified contributions made by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD9B728101160413EB875B7FFBD9E3AD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of credit</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) in any taxable year shall not exceed an amount equal to the greater of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB7669C14AF694FBCB2783B96559241D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>10 percent of the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year, or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83D7C33C5352404FA4E6D7C7C98FE083"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$5,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H141EDD4757404A409610810CC3C5DF1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ACD28CC9CE241F6AC607800DF65A008"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Charter school</header><text>The term <term>charter school</term> has the same meaning given such term in section 4310 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4CF9BBDDA3F24760A2E6B41B81B05702"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible charter school organization</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C6801C8B8A84AC79B49CB9957959393"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible charter school organization</term> means an organization which—</text> <clause id="H7A793BC5A0F04826B53E256DCF09219B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a) and is not a private foundation,</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DE41D51C37B4E1FB3642A2A29CF5935"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a charter management organization (as defined in section 4310 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>)), or a charter school (as defined in section 4310 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>)), that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9FDB368750B4C94928119E1196DE389"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has received, or manages a charter school that has received, a grant for the replication or expansion of high-quality charter schools under section 4305(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221d">20 U.S.C. 7221d(b)</external-xref>), or</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDA0BF43B22E4DF38D8A21974CF34FB3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been selected by a State for eligibility under this section based on a determination by the State that the organization is in the highest 10 percent of charter management organizations (as so defined) or charter schools (as so defined) for student performance in the State,</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA628A97AE5E432DB0077E282CACFC60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separate from any other funds or contributions received by such organization, maintains and accounts for any contributions made by any person for the purpose of the creation or expansion of charter schools operated or managed by such organization, </text></clause> 
<clause id="H3483091673844A8EB564AABB80230E9E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>obtains from an independent certified public accountant annual financial and compliance audits, and</text></clause> <clause id="HBF962C342E74415CA5E68A105A9552B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>certifies to the Secretary (at such time, and in such form and manner, as the Secretary may prescribe) that the audit described in clause (iii) has been completed.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9863E6478C2D45A7BF3EB5B2A17193FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Independent certified public accountant</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>independent certified public accountant</term> means, with respect to an organization, a certified public accountant who is not a person described in section 465(b)(3)(A) with respect to such organization or any employee of such organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10A8577F7C7341989817A8E062741421"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qualified contribution</header><text>The term <term>qualified contribution</term> means a charitable contribution (as defined by section 170(c)) to an eligible charter school organization in the form of cash or marketable securities for the purpose of the creation or expansion of charter schools managed or operated by such organization.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H877C7CAE058B4AD394CF69880F1DD3FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>Any qualified contribution for which a credit is allowed under this section shall not be taken into account as a charitable contribution for purposes of section 170.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34607829E74D48998B1EF42597368726" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Carryforward of unused credit</header> <paragraph id="HAFAB9100D302478796D6AFBC2791CCC1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the credit allowable under subsection (a) for any taxable year exceeds the limitation imposed by section 26(a) for such taxable year reduced by the sum of the credits allowable under this subpart (other than this section, section 23, and section 25D), such excess shall be carried to the succeeding taxable year and added to the credit allowable under subsection (a) for such taxable year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6113670343484A98B9F3DE14F1427700" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No credit may be carried forward under this subsection to any taxable year following the fifth taxable year after the taxable year in which the credit arose. For purposes of the preceding sentence, credits shall be treated as used on a first-in first-out basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC379200D03624867BA8B70824ADA21A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application of volume cap</header><text>A qualified contribution shall be taken into account under this section only if such contribution would not result in aggregate tax credits under this section that are in excess of the volume cap established under section 4 of the <short-title>High-Quality Charter Schools Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBBF305B38EB649668BFBFA8DEFD72015"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25E the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H38458EA911804F90B491DEE464123953"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 25F. Contributions to eligible charter school organizations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HACC75D11E0F54AC68A3B0780A6A16E7E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Failure of eligible charter school organization to make expenditures</header> <subsection id="H72CE4B785FE743AF9CF3805303947C2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/42">Chapter 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCFC174CB74541638CC76FFCFD627A7B"> 
<subchapter id="H2E7B3C51412F4106AC4F1080FCE18BCB"><enum>I</enum><header>Eligible Charter School Organizations</header> 
<toc container-level="subchapter-container" idref="H2E7B3C51412F4106AC4F1080FCE18BCB" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HD2AE7637BDAC42FCB9922F4C40C3EE9B" level="section">Sec. 4969. Failure to expend receipts.</toc-entry></toc> 
<section id="HD2AE7637BDAC42FCB9922F4C40C3EE9B"><enum>4969.</enum><header>Failure to expend receipts</header> 
<subsection id="H6EE5AC6993B8476AA9B7D8D6317DEBE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any eligible charter school organization (as defined in section 25F(c)(2)) which has been determined by the Secretary to have failed to satisfy the requirement under subsection (b) for any taxable year, any contribution made to such organization during the first taxable year beginning after the date of such determination shall not be treated as a qualified contribution (as defined in section 25F(c)(3)) for purposes of section 25F. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9E9CDCA1A944520A096C03FF9D5B453"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The requirement described in this subsection is that the amount of qualified contributions of the eligible charter school organization for the taxable year which are expended before the expenditure deadline with respect to such receipts shall not be less than the required expenditure amount with respect to such taxable year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H114851D388FD4CADA20801B98F2D8078"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H3A3F50239D46458992ABCF7F44A545FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required expenditure amount</header> <subparagraph id="H17312E0BC32E4BB9A98620345B17FBD3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The required expenditure amount with respect to a taxable year is the amount equal to 100 percent of qualified contributions for such taxable year—</text> 
<clause id="H76FA5C47BB834E3F8DF7C7AB17A0CCAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduced by the sum of such qualified contributions that are retained for reasonable administrative expenses for the taxable year or are carried to the succeeding taxable year under subparagraph (C), and</text></clause> <clause id="H34A4B82BE0A0471FB6EEC0BC54D2DFEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increased by the amount of the carryover under subparagraph (C) from the preceding taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0086EDB79DB4B1A8582D4EF462A5960"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Safe harbor for reasonable administrative expenses</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), if the percentage of total qualified contributions to an eligible charter school organization for a taxable year which are used for administrative purposes related to activities for the creation or expansion of charter schools (as defined in section 25F(c)(1)) operated or managed by such organization is equal to or less than 10 percent, such expenses shall be deemed to be reasonable for purposes of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8F38E0581664474BD93F1F790761FD5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>With respect to the amount of the total qualified contributions to an eligible charter school organization with respect to any taxable year, an amount not greater than 15 percent of such amount may, at the election of such organization or school, be carried to the succeeding taxable year. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78DE6BA36DC44C6FA018FA5D9A751EC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text>The term <term>expenditures</term> includes amounts which are formally committed but not expended. A formal commitment described in the preceding sentence may include qualified contributions set aside for the creation or expansion of charter schools operated or managed by such organization for more than one year. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FA0D49FD3E7414D876ECA2F83E8405D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expenditure deadline</header><text>The expenditure deadline with respect to qualified contributions for a taxable year is the first day of the fifth taxable year following the taxable year in which such qualified contributions are received by the eligible charter school organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C876BB0500F49CA816005991A34D57C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified contributions</header><text>The term <quote>qualified contributions</quote> means contributions eligible for the credit under section 25F.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB73F246BD08A4DFA81FFE47872C25731"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 42 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF08210C62DA948CBB5CCF5183B800026"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter I. Eligible Charter School Organizations</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H06ED8DFFE43A4487AFA927D4A4BAE425"><enum>4.</enum><header>Volume cap</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H826D7D1F12ED4760A73F3AF04F542D93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocation</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBD58908F10B240D79005FF69B89F9014"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this Act), the volume cap applicable with respect to such section shall be $5,000,000,000 of tax credits for taxable years beginning in calendar year 2026 and each subsequent year thereafter, with such amount to be allocated as follows:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A586156DE984AD287FB007C9E23C66E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000,000 of tax credits shall be allocated to each State (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(10)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), with such amount to be made available, in the manner described in subsection (b), for any individual residing in such State to claim the credit allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to any qualified contributions (as defined in such section) made by such individual during any taxable year beginning during such calendar year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB9833C1A5BF245B0979DCC787DE32638"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to the amount remaining after the allocation under subparagraph (A), such amount (as adjusted pursuant to paragraph (3)) shall be made available, in the manner described in subsection (b), for any individual to claim the credit allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to any qualified contributions made by such individual during any taxable year beginning during such calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H62C548E03CE444E28410204CF0319DF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>The amount of any allotment to a State under paragraph (1)(A) for any calendar year which is not claimed by taxpayers described in such paragraph during such calendar year shall be added to the allotment provided under paragraph (1)(B) for the subsequent calendar year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1530CAC0CB684C3B9CFDB5D307A39D19"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Increase in nationwide volume cap</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), if the Secretary determines during any calendar year that the amount of tax credits allowable under section 25F with respect to qualified contributions made during such calendar year is equal to or greater than 90 percent of the total amount made available under such paragraph for such calendar year, such amount shall be increased by an amount equal to 5 percent of the total amount made available under such paragraph as of January 1 of such calendar year, with such increase to remain in effect for the subsequent calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HE7EFDECFC9AC40108F4EC2E5570EC178"><enum>(b)</enum><header>First-Come, first-Serve</header><text>For purposes of applying the volume cap under this section, such volume cap shall be applied based on a first-come, first-serve basis, as determined based on the date on which the taxpayer made the qualified contribution.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63A1C270C8404BEAB7E696B51B085ED0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Real-Time information</header><text>For purposes of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall develop a system to track the amount of qualified contributions made during the calendar year for which a credit may be claimed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, with such information to be updated in real time.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H30C20B717060473A9370D0138369AB89"><enum>5.</enum><header>Organizational and parental autonomy</header> <subsection id="H555F899F4B1A4FDB933CDAA7ABEB669C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition of control over eligible charter school organizations</header> <paragraph id="H77673A5C57C04B0A9B26F4FDF6F3E1F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible charter school organization shall not, by virtue of participation under any provision of this Act or any amendment made by this Act, be regarded as acting on behalf of any governmental entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E38898222874A1DB3E65788B6173E20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum freedom</header><text>To the extent permissible by law, this Act, and any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to allow eligible charter school organizations maximum freedom to provide for the needs of the students served by the charter schools operated or managed by the organization without governmental control.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H417926C8A41A473B811078B9B57C2CCD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the terms <term>charter school</term> and <term>eligible charter school organization</term> shall have the same meanings given such terms under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by section 2(a) of this Act). </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA8CE98B7CB8D42D08F280795EE1F2305"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

