<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25378-NDS-WM-6VW">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1569 IS: Fairness in Higher Education Accreditation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1569</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To modify the criteria for recognition of accrediting agencies or
            associations for institutions of higher education.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness in Higher Education Accreditation Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idbdc234aa5279490090280ac6788bfe98">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Criteria for recognition of accrediting agencies or associations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 496 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="idf9ce539f5a324ec9875ab5ad30637f35">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="idff021afbed104e38a4e194d4f6ea7f28"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in paragraph (5)—</text>
                    <clause id="id6a05d193dc0f4a42801bad5573005e55">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="idc3da5ee4320d4962b86196520eccb105">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (J), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id36f2e0a3badb4ca59cf7da12d8c5374f">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (J), and before the flush text, the following:</text>
                        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf888a8ca635d41f1b1011e90c3a858fb">
                            <subparagraph id="id42f8129bb4364e4e92615310578dd915">
                                <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>except in the case of an institution described in subsection (r)(2), success in ensuring a right of free inquiry (as defined in subsection (r)(1));</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idafc3b12f19644cc5978f40fef978c5db">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id107caa4485464f45a116e4b0331526b7">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idc2b8b6dfb64a4260b36c638d37dcc0bf">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0aea09a35e614295a8f94c49f5661968"> <paragraph id="idcfb3f2d121db4e5986a360090615b1f0" commented="no"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>the accrediting agency or association will not impose requirements, establish standards, conduct investigations, or make recommendations concerning—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idf5538da596394c5bb23ee10344a0c8a3" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the race, color, sex, or national origin composition of the student body, faculty, or staff;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id0d0c4e7157d9410faac096a281a40c04" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the race, color, sex, or national origin of the students, faculty members, or staff members who are in leadership roles; or</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id6982f5130afe4bb6bf9116e9e9235526" commented="no">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the race, color, sex, or national origin of the students, faculty members, or staff members who receive honors or special commendations;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id5e50ffe484af4c71bfeb3b69049455ed" commented="no">
                            <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>an accrediting agency or association may only be determined to be a reliable authority as to the quality of education or training offered for the purposes of this Act or for other Federal purposes if the agency or association permits each institution of higher education that the agency or association accredits (and each component or subpart of each institution of higher education that the agency or association accredits) to adopt any lawful policy with regard to the factors described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (9), notwithstanding the particular mission of an institution of higher education (or component or subpart thereof); and</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id8f02a037060648b9b8d158d650002160" commented="no">
                            <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>as part of the accrediting process, an accrediting agency or association may not consider any factor described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (9).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idc6d30d7f305a47fb831de84e1bcd5146">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (p), by striking <quote>Nothing in subsection (a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (a)(9), nothing in subsection (a)(5)</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idd4ee39c3d4d845ff9aa1137da3e1f59c">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0450672183e949e1a89179dcb672202d"> <subsection id="iddb79eae767364ab1b6a9bf42008f7bd3"> <enum>(r)</enum> <header>Free inquiry</header> <paragraph id="id708a2f62c22b4a7a8db02be35e019df1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Free inquiry</header> <text>In this section, the term <term>free inquiry</term> means—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idb98ee13faf614de49e6a501e55431bf1">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a public institution of higher education that is legally required to abide by the First Amendment to the Constitution, compliance with—</text>
                                <clause id="id4903af30446a41e986b5076652bbeee1">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the First Amendment to the Constitution, including protections for freedom of speech, association, press, religion, assembly, and petition; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id27ab9cff92d64468998d0ecc95bae77f">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the institution’s own written policies regarding academic freedom; or</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="ida70baf5103164e66b7033b814ad589a3">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a private institution of higher education, adherence to the institution’s written institutional policies concerning freedom of speech, association, press, religion, assembly, petition, and academic freedom.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ida45cc2b0bf3c4bea92948d8ca7c2708d">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Religious exemption</header>
 <text>An institution described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (F) shall not be subject to the free inquiry requirements of subsection (a)(5)(K). Such exempt institutions shall include an institution—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="ide84632d1eaf9422cb794dcd806c7af02" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that is a school or department of divinity;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id964a9fea28524a79990c8109b9b15456" commented="no"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>that requires its faculty, students, or employees to be members of, or otherwise engage in religious practices of, or espouse a personal belief in, the religion of the organization by which it claims to be controlled;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id007ed24f0dbe46dea502663b08f2986e" commented="no">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>that in its charter or catalog, or other official publication, contains an explicit statement that it is controlled by a religious organization or an organ thereof, or is committed to the doctrines or practices of a particular religion, and the members of its governing body are appointed by the controlling religious organization or an organ thereof, and it receives a significant amount of financial support from the controlling religious organization or an organ thereof;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idc05120f6e59941eb8b6256a2f9aed0a9" commented="no">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>that has a doctrinal statement or a statement of religious practices, along with a statement that members of the institution community must engage in the religious practices of, or espouse a personal belief in, the religion, its practices, or the doctrinal statement or statement of religious practices;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idc9a67caa169e448c9e007d099731da08" commented="no">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>that has a published institutional mission that is approved by the governing body of an educational institution and that includes, refers to, or is predicated upon religious tenets, beliefs, or teachings; or</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idcfa58649746c4821a25af0c9f2ab8500" commented="no">
                                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>with respect to which there is other evidence sufficient to establish that the institution is controlled by a religious organization, pursuant to section 901(a)(3) of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="ideb6b3148623a4b5d957809b17f8b7aab">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Civil action</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">An institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>), and including both public and private institutions as so defined) that is subject to a denial, withdrawal, or termination, or imminent threat of denial, withdrawal, or termination, of accreditation as a result of an accrediting agency or association’s violation of the prohibition established in section 496(a)(10) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(a)</external-xref>), as added by section 2 of this Act, may pursue a civil action in accordance with subsections (e) and (f) of such section 496.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

