<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07A097A54572447B994DFFB03CC863CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5243 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase data transparency for supplemental benefits under Medicare Advantage.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase data transparency for supplemental benefits under Medicare Advantage.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B763CDBB62D4DF29CD30DEC31ED80C4" style="OLC"><section id="H1BEB2E9815E6484D80CF19F977FA9ADC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Increasing data transparency for supplemental benefits under Medicare Advantage</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3258C11E7B194036A79A9FB1125403EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F43485023034E629C696984731404BE"><paragraph id="HCEF064E4104B4FCF96B1E2AD5954F0B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting of enrollee-level data on supplemental benefits</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA2ABD01226C4F04B44F4F81ADAF8793"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2029, a contract under this section with an MA organization shall require the organization to submit to the Secretary, for each MA plan offered by the organization, enrollee-level data on supplemental benefits (by item or service, or category of item or service, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, and national provider identifier), including eligibility for such benefits, the types of benefit categories offered, data on utilization of and payments for such benefits (including the total amount spent by the plan for each enrollee who utilized such benefits and the total out-of-pocket cost per utilization for each enrollee).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41359656ADB043F3A4A2E48C6981B99B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data access</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACFC3E93BB2D4C58A0DDF76A865D8CAD"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>On the first Monday in October of each year (beginning with 2030), the Secretary shall make data submitted under subparagraph (A) available to individuals and entities for the purpose of conducting—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBABC7375AF134C7990E6E52623F5ABC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluations and other analysis to support the program under this title; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D0757A0080646429AD6FD652BDA4770"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other health care related research.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H85205B4C1B0C47F5A554396B990C0313"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Public use data file</header><text>Not later than October 1 of each year (beginning with 2030), the Secretary shall make a public use data file containing the data submitted under subparagraph (A) available on the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7615571949D04F2C80DD6DB9C028A56A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>In making data available under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall have in place procedures to safeguard the privacy of any individually identifiable enrollee information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9048E1264F54EF784153BD22F4284EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by this section shall affect the collection of information as proposed pursuant to the notice entitled <quote>Agency Information Collection Activities: Proposed Collection; Comment Request</quote>, published in the Federal Register on March 14, 2023 (88 Fed. Reg. 15726).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

