<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF67CD83D0FF46B69720A5388B1323A4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 374 IH: Recognizing the disenfranchisement of District of Columbia residents, calling for statehood for the District of Columbia through the enactment of the Washington, D.C. Admission Act, and expressing support for the designation of May 1, 2025, as “D.C. Statehood Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 374</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the disenfranchisement of District of Columbia residents, calling for statehood for the District of Columbia through the enactment of the Washington, D.C. Admission Act, and expressing support for the designation of May 1, 2025, as <quote>D.C. Statehood Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States was founded on the principles of consent of the governed and no taxation without representation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas District of Columbia residents are denied voting representation in Congress and full local self-government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia pays more per capita Federal taxes than any State and pays more Federal taxes than 19 States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas statehood would give District of Columbia residents voting representation in Congress and full local self-government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has the constitutional authority to pass the District of Columbia statehood bill, the Washington, D.C. Admission Act (H.R. 51 and S. 51), which would admit the State of Washington, Douglass Commonwealth, and reduce the size of the Federal district;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Admissions Clause of the Constitution gives Congress the authority to admit new States, and all 37 new States were admitted by Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas no State would have to consent to the admission of the State of Washington, Douglass Commonwealth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District Clause of the Constitution gives Congress plenary authority over the Federal district and establishes a maximum size of the Federal district, but not a minimum size nor a location of the Federal district;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 23d Amendment to the Constitution allows the Federal district to participate in the electoral college, while not establishing a minimum size nor a location of the Federal district;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution does not establish any prerequisites for new States, but Congress has generally considered 3 factors—</text><paragraph id="H22E22AF5E616463A884F36BF787FA53E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>population and resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H987ADADBD40F43D099C55449FA106EE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support for statehood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E671A7B73C8483E82F9E3D0E6F9F82B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commitment to democracy;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has a larger population than 2 States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has a larger gross domestic product than 15 States and a higher per capita gross domestic product than any State;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has a higher per capita personal income than any State;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 86 percent of District of Columbia residents voted for statehood in 2016; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas District of Columbia residents have been fighting for voting representation in Congress and full local self-government for more than 200 years: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HECC6E5C85C384F4CAA344E249267CE12"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6EA621B5108D4FA5B4E6532CAF23AA15"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HA6828B6C76004B629B0E037229C36155"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>D.C. Statehood Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1795272EEFAE47BDB276A903EE4D048C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on Congress to pass the Washington, D.C. Admission Act (H.R. 51 and S. 51).</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

