<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15C0B447126A47AAB240B44DE985A71F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2742 IH: DOGE Accountability and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2742</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent fraud, waste, and abuse by requiring the Administrator of the United States Department of Government Efficiency Service to provide weekly reports to Congress regarding changes DOGE has made to any Federal agency and the realized impacts of such changes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB86521B18D0D40F5B548E9C462098CE8" style="OLC"><section id="H88E079C77BB2401294F44A317636BFF8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOGE Accountability and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H5C67984370DE4727AB05A2F1457C542F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><subsection id="HC8D9E545875049B8988A975E6030630F"><enum/><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H21D66678C65A4BD7A1BC7D08C80A95D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress has a responsibility to review, monitor, supervise, and evaluate the actions of the executive branch to provide effective oversight as a co-equal branch of Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9060FFFCA4A449AEA4729B1FCC76B32F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The authority of the Congress to provide oversight and obtain information from the executive branch is firmly established and essential to its legislative function derived from Article I of the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDAA1708BF54B488E1BA6DF808C9421"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 established that “each standing committee of the Senate and the House of Representatives shall exercise continuous watchfulness of the execution by the administrative agencies concerned of any laws, the subject matter of which is within the jurisdiction of such committee; and, for that purpose, shall study all pertinent reports and data submitted to the Congress by the agencies in the executive branch of the Government.”</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FC2767178904B7BB2DF772B479BED71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On January 20, 2025, President Donald Trump issued an executive order to reorganize the U.S. Digital Service as the U.S. Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) Service and directs DOGE to “implement the President’s DOGE Agenda, by monitoring Federal technology and software to maximize governmental efficiency and productivity.”</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB25AE996CCB2496592F78692E4118046"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">DOGE has pushed for large-scale reductions in force and office closures (often arbitrarily and capriciously), which will have a significant adverse impact on the ability of agencies to serve citizens of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9123A41496BE49039A720E9C6C3A8684"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Reductions in Force (RIFs) and scaling back, or completely eliminating programs at Federal agencies should be based on real and transparent analysis and formal, deliberate program evaluation, not for the purposes of pursuing personal vendettas or yielding personal financial gain for well-connected individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H076F389F8457425F9C5563B7B6DB7B6F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The illogical and erratic, chainsaw approach of DOGE has sown confusion and chaos for employees at Federal agencies and the citizens of the United States alike.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28B7F1E1E65947188810A01FB74C287E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The citizens of the United States expect and deserve ongoing transparency of the actions of the Federal Government, particularly when their personal, private data is concerned.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3F897C9BE1F64661A561F8E43204ADDA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Government Efficiency activity and impact reports</header><subsection id="H8AA71E3095824D6880590D3A3BF462F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Weekly report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 week after the date of the enactment of this Act, and weekly thereafter, the Administrator of the United States Department of Government Efficiency Service shall provide to Congress a report regarding any action DOGE has taken with respect to each Federal agency and the cumulative impact of actions taken to date, including the following:</text><paragraph id="HC8FB78ED19D94463904F946930AE8E0A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each statutory authorization supporting each such change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48CBA8BB207B4F6FB5C3CA803A40F8C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any change in the number of employees at the respective Federal agency, including any employee that has resigned, been removed, or had their position eliminated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D1E3E782A4E4D459E8220F3CD50ADAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of each specific change DOGE has made to the respective Federal agency, including to an office within such agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3871FFD7C3224E4DA4DEFAE1E0B80085"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any cost-saving measure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H134C24E44D734FFDAA2F7952D9FB0ED6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any policy change. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73B92B31B31B41F1B2925AEB3025147E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any physical change to a Federal agency structure or location, including moving a Federal agency to a different building and relocating employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDABB21F374E47DB998A78441188EED9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of any Federal agency data accessed by DOGE, the name of the individual who accessed such data, the purpose for such access, and what was done with such data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDAFD45AF0304E889745313E9789F59D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The realized versus expected benefits of DOGE actions to date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CB66DA8EF1C4A55BCCAC5F0F5434977"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 week after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report of any DOGE activity listed under subsection (a) that occurred between January 20, 2025, and the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBAC9424F5D2F46C39D85DD6A78407BD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9D5081EADFAC455D98B37BD65EB38814"><enum>(1)</enum><header>DOGE</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>DOGE</term> means the United States DOGE Service (commonly referred to as the Department of Government Efficiency).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F589924E02241B6AFD6611ED8D37BD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

