<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFEDE9056C422467DBCC34E647B0C1008" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 200 IH: Expressing support for a comprehensive political reform plan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for a comprehensive political reform plan.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas public trust in the Government has been declining for decades, with nearly 70 percent of Americans indicating distrust in the Government each year since 2007;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas demand for major Government reform has increased to 59 percent of Americans in 2023;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the lack of congressional term limits allows for a steep incumbency advantage—to the extent that each year since 1982, over 75 percent of incumbents in the House and the Senate have won their reelections—preventing true representation and democracy for constituents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 5 out of 6 Americans favor a constitutional amendment to impose term limits on Members of Congress;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas congressional term limits would limit the entrenchment of special interests and the concentration of power within the elected bodies, and allow for a more democratic, representative, and diverse Congress;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Members of Congress should be responsive to the interests of their constituents, rather than the interests of political action committees and wealthy political donors;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 77 percent of the public agrees that there should be limits on the amount of money individuals and organizations can donate to political campaigns;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas banning congressional candidates from accepting campaign contributions from political action committees would give American voters stronger voices in our democracy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Members of Congress should not be able to hold, unless in a blind trust, and trade stocks while retaining access to confidential information or crafting policies, as this leads to conflicts of interest, corruption, and even the possibility of insider trading;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas over 80 percent of Americans across political parties support a ban on Members of Congress holding and trading stocks;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas banning stock trading by requiring Members of Congress to place any investments in blind trusts effectively bans Members of Congress from trading individual stocks, and would prevent corruption;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas over half of the lawmakers who left office in 2019 leveraged their connections on Capitol Hill to land high-paying, influence-peddling roles in the lobbying industry, creating countless possibilities for conflicts of interest;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas almost 1 in 3 Americans believe Members of Congress should never be allowed to lobby their former colleagues, with 65 percent supporting a 5-year-lobbying ban at minimum;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a lifetime ban on lobbying for Members of Congress will reduce the outsized influence that special interests have on policymaking, and will increase transparency and accountability for Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas recent investigations into the Supreme Court have uncovered countless instances of Justices filing deficient financial disclosures, receiving extravagant gifts, misusing staff, and otherwise prioritizing personal gains over behavior fitting for members serving on the Nation’s highest Court;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas confidence in the Supreme Court reached a historic low in 2022, dropping to just 25 percent of American voters;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an enforceable code of conduct for Supreme Court Justices would increase transparency, restore faith in the Court, and prevent conflicts of interest;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas though originally intended to ensure independence and stability, lifetime appointments to the Supreme Court enshrine political bias, inflexibility, and a lack of accountability;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 68 percent of Americans believe Supreme Court Justices should be subject to term limits;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 18-year term limits and regular appointments for Supreme Court Justices will depoliticize, rebalance, and restore judicial independence to the Court; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are existing legislative efforts to address each of these issues;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas H.R. 9134, introduced in the 117th Congress, would prohibit Members of Congress and those running for House or Senate seats from accepting contributions from political action committees;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas multiple bills would institute a lifetime lobbying ban on Members of Congress;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas multiple bills, including H.R. 345, introduced in the 118th Congress, would ban Members of Congress from holding and trading individual stocks during the Member’s tenure;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas multiple bills, including H.J. Res.4, introduced in the 116th Congress, would establish 12-year term limits for Members of Congress;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas multiple bills, including H.R. 4423, introduced in the 118th Congress, would institute 18-year Supreme Court Term Limits and regular appointments; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas multiple bills, including H.R. 3973, introduced in the 118th Congress, would establish a Supreme Court Code of Ethics: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H92A7170F294C42F596463F514C660E9B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H59702A86992C4BA4A0F165C3BEBB4AD2"><text>That the House of Representatives recognizes the importance of a comprehensive plan for political reform which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A2AAADB210D4BC4AD1D69DD4D7AF6DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibits all Members of Congress and those running for a House or Senate seat from accepting contributions from political action committees and lobbyists, and imposes a lifetime lobbying ban on Members of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF869D2389F954E7DAFBC8B0D1182E743"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bans Members of Congress from holding and trading individual stocks during the Member’s tenure and requires Members of Congress, as well as any spouse or dependent child of a Member, to place specified investments into a qualified blind trust until 180 days after the end of their tenure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5E5E1CCBEC34EF2B5FD4ED0FE5B9E82"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishes 12-year term limits for Members of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80F6F93EB2DF4B8EBCC11696E7A8FAAE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>institutes a binding code of ethics for Supreme Court Justices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E9FFC02E8A64D5192121365AB6A0E4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>implements 18-year term limits and regular appointments for Supreme Court Justices.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

