<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H854015BD43654C0D8188C27229C91A5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5368 IH: Pipeline Safety Engagement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5368</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to rename the Community Liaison Services within the Office of Pipeline Safety of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration as the Office of Public Engagement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F9C745D3D54454C89FA677D58E717A9" style="OLC">
<section id="HA98089736894473A82E789DA491B0BD7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pipeline Safety Engagement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1B4C3EB5A9EB48F99642405902BEB6BD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Public Engagement</header> <subsection id="H7C1CA17044B245F68EDD9048F45BA74D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall rename the Community Liaison Services within the Office of Pipeline Safety of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration as the Office of Public Engagement (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA82E06D226784C2E8BFD3B8CCB65BD2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Office are to—</text> <paragraph id="H714A426F94904BC7A20FA957EA5B6F98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proactively engage with pipeline stakeholders, including the public, pipeline operators, public safety organizations, and State, local, and Tribal government officials, to raise awareness of pipeline safety practices;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB628C4F37FF429F89B23A6EEAB798E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote the adoption and increased use of safety programs and activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA4FF40D034644DF9E635EF7E2CE8689"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inform the public of pipeline safety regulations and best practices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08869BDA9E5C4D2FB80B32CA9DAA25CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist the public with inquiries regarding pipeline safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H50756DC505C9411EBB2F3A1A81C29A5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>The Office shall ensure that activities carried out by the Office and information products developed by the Office are accessible to the public.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB13B8C35E494B2496ECAF775D351172"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Community liaisons</header><text>The Office shall incorporate positions known as <quote>community liaisons</quote> under the Community Liaison Services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4FE82AAD6CD946649193FDDA793F5D84"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

