<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25645-3H4-FT-W33"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S774 IS: WHO is Accountable Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 774</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the use of funds to seek membership in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization until certain conditions have been met.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H38D3B7B03B3B43CF97307AB92E175148"><section section-type="section-one" id="H10C160C81DF54CE9901EDD6890BD00B0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>WHO is Accountable Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H346399490616499797A9668FDA2DB76C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds to seek membership in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization</header><subsection id="H0C353E9C5FED450996A50A1CA1BF1503"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to seek membership by the United States in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization until after the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that the World Health Organization meets all of the conditions described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEE652C44C754A589B80BADC57CF143A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions described</header><text>The conditions described in this subsection will be met when the World Health Organization—</text><paragraph id="H2CDC8EBC25AA4869A6312ED0147148CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has adopted meaningful reforms to ensure that humanitarian assistance is not politicized and is being provided to those with the most need;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07B03D05007F468E86E0C8C7E5527B61"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not under the control or significant malign influence of the Chinese Communist Party;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA737D5D9B344D5BC14A4A785E9A33E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not involved in a coverup of the Chinese Communist Party’s response to the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H232CB1C1E95D4B5786D00B841DAB7543"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants observer status to Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78CBB1A96A084D8C94F84B104506D90E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not diverting humanitarian or medical supplies to Iran, North Korea, or Syria;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACD5924F3B2343AA89450943A77444B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has established mechanisms to increase transparency and accountability in its operations and eliminate waste, fraud, and abuse;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FFBDEA07F854619B3FBF3562E0C0010"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has ceased all funding for, engagement in, and messaging with respect to certain controversial and politically charged issues that are non-germane to the World Health Organization’s directive, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7E20E381CD2C4767AFB644182DBEF804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>so-called <quote>gender identity</quote> and harmful rhetoric relating to <quote>gender affirming care</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999FF4159F1A4B44A8D6ECEA41A248E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>climate change; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1568E0E770F04805BD62C22D1538836A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>access to abortion; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA18ABCC253CE489686E65EBE753693C9"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has agreed, as a condition of membership by the United States in the World Health Organization, that no directive issued by the World Health Organization may be considered to be legally binding on any United States citizen or individual State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

