<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25265-2CT-R5-FJ9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 100 IS: Dissenting from the United States delegation’s February 24, 2025, vote at the United Nations General Assembly.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 100</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Dissenting from the United States delegation’s February 24, 2025, vote at the United Nations General Assembly.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas United States cooperation with our allies advances the national security interest of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on February 24, 2025, the United States delegation to the United Nations voted against the Government of Ukraine’s United Nations draft resolution A/ES–11/L.10 entitled <quote>Advancing a comprehensive, just and lasting peace in Ukraine</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the aforementioned vote was cast against Ukraine and the United States’ democratic allies, and aligned the United States with the Russian Federation, Belarus, the Democratic People’s Republic of North Korea, and other autocracies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this was the first instance since 2014 in which the United States voted with Russia at the United Nations on a Ukraine-related resolution, representing a departure from a decade of bipartisan, United States policy on Ukraine and eight decades of alignment with like-minded democratic states at the United Nations; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United Nations Security Council, the United States led a resolution that failed to call out Russia as the invading aggressor and lacked the support of all five European members of the Security Council: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id28cc5e27c3d94bbb88d6051b1eb09562"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the February 24, 2025, United States vote against Ukraine’s resolution at the United Nations General Assembly;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd30c67ffb3f2450e9b4fa7d8c0bec604"><enum>(2)</enum><text>decries the refusal of the United States delegation to continue to identify the Russian Federation as an aggressor or to call for the Government of the Russian Federation to completely withdraw its military forces from the territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id45e67f7e61e44030bc70e1ea0fc4c2f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recalls that the principal purposes of the United Nations Charter are to <quote>maintain peace and security</quote> and suppress <quote>acts of aggression or other breaches of peace</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id001c1dd3f60848f7996b988a57729de4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the United States to work closely with Ukraine and European allies on future efforts at the United Nations related to Ukraine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f3adf8027454ee8979a52c3e9b1ea96"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirms its support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

