<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25725-GJ4-J7-C6K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1928 IS: Gerald E. Connolly Esophageal Cancer Awareness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to submit to
            Congress a report on esophageal cancer with respect to the Federal Employees Health
 Benefits Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8371FA231E0440A3925BB8C1D6F4A688"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8A6B66AC163945CEBD45FD455861BEAA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gerald E. Connolly Esophageal Cancer Awareness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7171FB7F5644426AAC508B67D124C7C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H2734CD1F07794880A5AC36CA5B9C0FA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>esophageal cancer is the fastest increasing cancer among men in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H321B06E76EDD450381CCF12128187C7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>esophageal cancer is one of the fastest growing cancer diagnoses among all people of the United States, with the incidence of esophageal cancer increasing by more than 700 percent in recent decades;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75213D10D7BB47108F476FC3E4D6A9D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>esophageal cancer kills 1 individual in the United States every 36 minutes every day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7E2348401F84FCFA6081CDF99252742"><enum>(4)</enum><text>esophageal cancer is among the deadliest of cancers, with only about 1 in 5 patients surviving 5 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC79CF7AEE32341B686F8DDD4D47D9C91"><enum>(5)</enum><text>esophageal cancer has tripled in incidence among younger people of the United States in recent decades;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H212E28446FB941C2836B1A6B489E8490"><enum>(6)</enum><text>esophageal cancer has low survival rates because it is usually discovered at advanced stages when treatment outcomes are poor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE8C19CB3CB54372993386C94B614D09"><enum>(7)</enum><text>raising awareness about esophageal cancer empowers individuals to seek preventive care, recognize symptoms, and pursue early detection strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6AAA7912E414C7BBB66AF16CB9EE736"><enum>(8)</enum><text>survivors, caregivers, medical professionals, and researchers have made tremendous strides in advancing treatment options and improving the quality of life for those affected by esophageal cancer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3EB20AEB23C4FAE90F41036A57765DE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>esophageal cancer can be prevented through early detection of its precursor, Barrett’s esophagus, which can be eliminated with curative outpatient techniques;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F6E489159DC4619925EE0E7F8FD203C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>research indicates that patients diagnosed with early-stage esophageal cancer have a significantly higher 5-year survival rate (as high as 49 percent) compared to those diagnosed at later stages, underscoring the critical need for enhanced screening and awareness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC936ABB6D0BB4242A788C7A62B3A3373"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of December 2022, the American Gastroenterological Association recommends screening with a standard upper endoscopy in individuals with 3 or more established risk factors for Barrett’s esophagus and esophageal adenocarcinoma, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDA9565425F1649BABDCBBFE0985FC876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>male sex;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H776F6601C85D4CB5A6F8A859039808F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>non-Hispanic White ethnicity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H690720DEECCB42B88190C37C08EE03D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>age of 50 years or older;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H796E6C4A899D4FF0A05F1D87679F2E9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a history of smoking, chronic gastrointestinal reflux disease, or obesity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40B2587900254C0C9FAE0C9C3D1D4164"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a family history of Barrett’s esophagus or esophageal adenocarcinoma.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H4BDC26EDE03B42FABB409A0071BFE86E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report by Comptroller General of the United States</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5919ca213847431193448cf9f72cd01b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Program</term> means the program carried out under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida97624d781ab44a49d235473cd21159b"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes an evaluation of—</text><paragraph id="HBE419AEE79794F65B53A13BEC263CCDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total impact of esophageal cancer-related health care spending under the Program for individuals who are covered under the Program and who are diagnosed with esophageal cancer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE36DDED6B0CA49D3AAFC98CFECD5A807"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how often individuals who are covered under the Program, and who have medical records indicating that those individuals are high-risk for esophageal cancer, undergo screening for esophageal cancer according to established guidelines.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

