<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25045-N99-M1-NF3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S123 IS: Handgun Permit to Purchase Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize for a grant program for handgun licensing programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDB761B5D7FB74CD89AAD92DFCF597B17"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7A32DD13A4BA4DDB8EE872CD98E25775"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Handgun Permit to Purchase Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC4EED3A1E27E4264B824F6A8AE6808F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="idadfcf517641f4c8abe81880744c89278"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 2023, gun violence claimed 46,728 lives, marking the third-highest number of gun-related deaths ever recorded in the United States in a single year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26b1223f01b440f79d13a20e30bbdda6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Between 2018 and 2022, approximately 90 percent of the firearm violence committed in the United States for which a firearm type was specified involved a handgun.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id944c39a1e90c4c099669c5c927b45578"><enum>(3)</enum><text>During the 5-year period described in paragraph (2), 35,959 people in the United States were killed with a handgun.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida020c67ec01149fea87d4a9a515773aa"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Research by top national experts shows that—</text><subparagraph id="id500b265330ee448482170f061d42f07f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the adoption of handgun purchaser licensing laws is associated with significant reductions in firearm-related homicides; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id568bfa5be36d401a9b3d0c6a661cb258"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the repeal of handgun purchaser licensing laws is associated with significant increases in firearm-related homicides.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id954265c33ee54244887a3dbb47325cf1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Research on the effects of the adoption of a handgun purchaser licensing law in Connecticut in 1995 showed—</text><subparagraph id="id6329f11449974796930cbeba1f3552b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a 27.8-percent reduction in the rate of firearm homicide; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7a6b79ca3bf437f8d448b3a8ce3ff98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 32.8-percent reduction in firearm suicide rates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49bdc6d1689948479289cbc11deeadd6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Published research has shown that the repeal of a handgun purchaser licensing law in Missouri in 2007 was associated with—</text><subparagraph id="id0cc7e3c86f5c45ae9c08a2d43afebbb5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a 47.3-percent increase in the rate of firearm homicide; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida65b4feb43d54ac48428effdb0c2eaa9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 23.5-percent increase in firearm suicide rates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0207de8a4fe247388cad10a609dc06cc"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Research on the impact of the adoption of a handgun purchaser licensing law in Maryland in 2013 found—</text><subparagraph id="idf57f55d0ef3c4f99848052bba87931fd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the adoption was associated with an 82-percent reduction in the Baltimore Police Department’s recovery of handguns with key indications of diversion for criminal use; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b203d2452944e33963edb8d652bf2ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that 41 percent of prohibited purchasers surveyed in Baltimore reported greater difficulty in obtaining a handgun.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1bc7e34aaa0487bb4dca531b2cb4329"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Research on the effects of firearm purchaser licensing laws throughout 3 decades found that—</text><subparagraph id="id9861cd3ae0f7469289b9836294ade2f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in urban counties between 1984 and 2015, firearm purchaser licensing laws were associated with an 11 percent reduction in firearm homicides; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id044f0ab94d0949d9ab47c652e122facd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>between 1984 and 2017, States with strong firearm purchaser licensing laws were associated with 56 percent lower rates of fatal mass shooting incidents and 67 percent fewer mass shooting victims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idefc654f7ebb64dcc88dec95a2941c9d6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In States that have had effective handgun purchaser licensing laws for decades, such as Connecticut, Massachusetts, New Jersey, and New York, the vast majority of firearms traced to crimes originated in States that do not have handgun purchaser licensing laws, which supports the need for handgun purchaser licensing laws in every State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f2a4aa7ac534bb68cb0de5dc3b4c126"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Research has shown that States with handgun purchaser licensing laws export far fewer firearms for criminal use in other States than States that lack handgun purchaser licensing laws. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ff6cde887044294883de067253a7ed7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>On January 13, 2025, the Supreme Court of the United States declined to hear a challenge to Maryland’s handgun licensing law, allowing the ruling of the United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, which upheld the constitutionality of the law, to stand.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id9A7B5E2C84BB4110A0322F6169FBC2DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program authorized for handgun licensing</header><subsection id="id4B8E6E3BCEF34A6DA59EA192C5A31956"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF9E664FB2CB44D45A8D9836089307CD1"><part id="id7A019664ADEF442885B0C5B94DC4E7B6" style="OLC"><enum>PP<?LEXA-Enum OO?></enum><header>Handgun licensing grant program</header><section id="H5242E3732AF24DD8AF35C9085E7B38FF"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the term <term>handgun</term> has the meaning given the term in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></section><section id="H5350B5959CF14134867DE51D1CD97D2C"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="HE9141259BFD449049333F9DDF918A987"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may award grants to States, units of local government, and Indian tribes for the development, implementation, and evaluation of handgun purchaser licensing requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2EEDF45A1E3B434FAE19F621A33A5853"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this part, and not later than 90 days after such amounts are appropriated, the Attorney General shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible applicants whose applications are approved under subsection (c) to assist such applicants in implementing and improving handgun purchaser licensing programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF4AE4EB50E142C19B4EBBA392E650C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—</text><paragraph id="HE5E810691F444BE3A3B4915E4055EB8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the law that the applicant has enacted to require a license for any purchase of a handgun, including a description of any exemptions to such law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4137E8CA8D3405CADF2CDAD9F4FDCA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the applicant will use the grant to carry out or improve its handgun purchaser licensing program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2C41E9B022C49CB9A6789AFDDCAAE10"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this part, an applicant shall have in effect a handgun purchaser licensing law that includes the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="id096DAE8A0D614A9181040401E88E7416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to an individual applying for a handgun license or permit—</text><subparagraph id="HA10C93FB8FCC457786F8ACE2914A3356"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual shall be—</text><clause id="id216DF1C3E1294707BA5845DD150BA67C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 21 years old; and</text></clause><clause id="id14824D1457E54866854C631B652A5E59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as those terms are defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>));</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07BC7E18F83E4BC5AE69DD7BEA928B2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual shall apply for the handgun purchaser license or permit at a law enforcement agency in the State in which the individual resides;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C7FAA89F3464C019EB3DFDDF6D5AA0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the individual shall reapply for the handgun purchaser license or permit after a period not longer than 5 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77E4D29F241549AF9DEF9DA114E24637"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the individual shall, in connection with the application for the handgun purchaser license or permit—</text><clause id="idE35911894A77403F8EC120DDA5751A14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to a background investigation and a criminal history check, as established by the State, which shall ensure, at a minimum, that the individual is not prohibited from possessing a firearm under section 922(g) of title 18, United States Code; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A3E40CAA79B4819A0728BC8158F16C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit fingerprints and photographs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF8964571564456866979D9CA026F63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual who is prohibited from possessing a firearm under section 922(g) of title 18, United States Code, may not be issued a handgun purchasing license or permit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0186D5503384BEAB020036D8150D929"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grant funds awarded under this part shall be used to improve the handgun purchaser licensing program of the grant recipient.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H544CF5329E7642ADB5FA3A3AFD16598F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 1001(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0819F71CB647481A9C9B2847006E2BE9"><paragraph id="id2F78384BB5FF471CABDDD5CEF54B23C3" indent="up1"><enum>(29)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out part PP.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

