<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7AB80714FE554E43AB3D941BD9A8CAB0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 509 IH: Expressing support for the designation of June 2025 as “Black Music Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 509</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 2025 as <quote>Black Music Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Black Americans have been creating and uplifting music since the founding of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music transcends genres and styles, but has had particular influence with Negro spirituals, sacred music, folk songs, doo-wop, funk, gospel, blues, classical, rock and roll, ragtime, jazz, rap, rhythm and blues, soul, hip-hop, pop, reggae, and heavy metal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all American music and music around the world has been informed and shaped by Black music in untold ways;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black musicians, artists, songwriters, composers, producers, sound mixers, arrangers, orchestrators, music educators, and personnel throughout the music industry have created some of the most successful and impactful music in the Nation’s history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music has touched the lives of countless people worldwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music will continue to be a treasure of the Nation indefinitely into the future;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music has often been imbued with deeply emotional character related to the discrimination and mistreatment faced by Black Americans dating to the Nation’s founding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music is sewn into the fabric of the Nation, including all its cultural facets, media, cinema and film, art, politics, and theater;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black music has been central to the struggle for Black freedom throughout American history and during the civil rights movement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Jimmy Carter first recognized African-American Music History Month on June 7, 1979;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas music has the capacity to open people’s hearts and minds; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas diversity is the Nation’s strength: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE9E5EFCC27404B65B77FFAB519B9B64B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H334586F26C684D168080F464E6C8861F"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H840CADC2ED3B4F61ACED746904E5DCA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Black Music Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6A838459095426DB4A7C3385D0AF857"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the stirring work of musicians, music creators, other artists, communities, and congregations in creating, uplifting, promoting, and celebrating Black music; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFD23E95D44C4B6E8F4C7CAC3EED5792"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls upon the people of the United States to recognize <quote>Black Music Month</quote> through actions and programs that—</text><subparagraph id="HD043103E11204B46B85C6FDBD84C2F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>elevate the artistry, skill, and talent of Black music and musicians;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0567CCCBF47C4533BA882ED800CE5F60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>perform and partake in Black music;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H113A7157653A4641A734AB16DBAD8CFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote diversity, equity, and inclusion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02A0B58641D64F69AA3E7C291B9E4B5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>spread awareness of Black music’s impact and legacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82210608D60144629C9C6734C662AB53"><enum>(E)</enum><text>honor and observe the deep-rooted history of Black music; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE15A6F390C04FCFA8CAC869E637A52D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>spread joy, awareness, and understanding through Black music.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

