<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3539D94BC1204935B9667479CC7544AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3693 IH: To prohibit the Federal Government from establishing or maintaining a database that contains data collected through, or facilitates, the biometric identity verification of a citizen of the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3693</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Federal Government from establishing or maintaining a database that contains data collected through, or facilitates, the biometric identity verification of a citizen of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC168B17EB9D4659B66BC66E28843284" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H98ABC092F736494AA71B3FCAB195B83E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain Federal Government databases</header> 
<subsection id="H8FFB3502C4A344CC80A5FC0A5778D6AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency of the Federal Government may not establish or maintain a database that contains data collected through, or facilitates, the biometric identity verification of a citizen of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96E6642A54D642A3BA140250891AAB44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biometric identity verification defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>biometric identity verification</quote> means the automated recognition of an individual based on the biological or behavioral characteristics of such individual from which distinguishing, repeatable biometric features are extracted, including fingerprints, iris patterns, or facial features.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

