<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA847608807A24192A6B5714483AD5CBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 597 IH: Pet Food Uniform Regulatory Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 597</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to clarify and update the authority of the Food and Drug Administration to ensure national uniformity in the regulation of the labels, labeling, and advertising of companion animal pet food, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA3306DDD2AA4513848CFBCB9B4D3587" style="OLC"><section id="HB3BF6833B6FE4862BF29C18FFA2E2809" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H454001B367AA400983FD9977E5580ACC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pet Food Uniform Regulatory Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PURR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4821C716A744D01AF26B7333E1D5F6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HB3BF6833B6FE4862BF29C18FFA2E2809" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFE4742458E364DDAB90F1361E6FB51AF" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7203042C8DDD49E7B0E7252478B0CBCE" level="section">Sec. 3. Pet food regulation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4211ABD63646412E80CA268D3112ABAA" level="section">Sec. 4. Responsibilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H94758DFF67854BE9BAB043A49736CDB7" level="section">Sec. 5. Regulations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HFE4742458E364DDAB90F1361E6FB51AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H3506B4BCB6174ADFB620E89E8065455C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The pet food industry is a growing sector in the United States. Pet food exports have increased by double digits over the last few years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H314B530581C846F9BEB956E56A018942"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States pet food manufacturers contribute to the national economy by buying nearly $7,000,000,000 worth of agricultural products from farmers, ranchers, and farm-product processors every year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84E003343B0E4763A9F927A978EDA414"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pet ownership has consistently grown in the United States, resulting in an increase in pet food sales and an accompanying increase in the interest by pet owners in how their companion animals’ food is regulated and produced.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC87B1050DBC4AC48A0D7E88665E0A6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Historically, pet food and livestock feed have been regulated under the same framework. However, as pet owners’ relationships with their pets have changed, so too has their understanding of pets’ nutritional needs and preferences. Pet food is specifically formulated to ensure complete nutrition for the long and healthy lives of companion animals. Owning a companion animal provides profound mental, social, and physical health benefits for pet owners such as reduced blood pressure and stress levels, and research indicates that companion animals can play a role in managing depression. Before the enactment of this Act, the regulatory framework that was originally created for livestock feed no longer met the needs of pets or their owners.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03356C36DB034CC7B35B7EB296CA7622"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Before the enactment of this Act, the regulatory framework governing pet food manufacture and sale, from ingredient approvals to labeling requirements, was multifaceted and wildly inconsistent. Regulatory regimes varied by State, were developed in part by a combination of nongovernmental entities and State government agencies, and were overseen by the Food and Drug Administration’s Center for Veterinary Medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC572A26E5194BE3BD978B2EAC021982"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Creating a more streamlined Federal regulatory process for new pet food ingredients allows for expedited advances for nutrition, greater innovation, and more functionality in a more predictable regulatory environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD36DD5B893148968E780B6B1E7AFB66"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Replacing the patchwork of regulation of pet food with a uniform Federal regulatory framework improves marketplace certainty, allows for more consistent and predictable ingredient review and market introductions, and enhances companion animal nutrition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8587EE285A61445F8DA3CB4B3DD671B1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The nationwide availability of nutritious, safe, and affordable pet food is substantially improved through a unified comprehensive Federal system of oversight of the manufacture and sale of pet food.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FDAE17A86A74CC4B3447EB2F3DA70D2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The manufacture of pet food and its marketing and sale is undertaken throughout the United States and its territories and is interstate commerce.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7203042C8DDD49E7B0E7252478B0CBCE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pet food regulation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter IV of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/341">21 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE332B4684F934928BC94A9715FC73BD2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HBE2C0E999A354E08AEC4E08FB0422514"><enum>425.</enum><header>Pet food</header><subsection id="H645EDA7092474858A8D7BA53FEBD9A6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5EE2ADB92853448EA938062C5440AE27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>companion animal</term> means a domesticated canine or feline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB346DE5CC57B488F8200CCBF03170DD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>generally recognized as safe</term> and <term>GRAS</term> mean generally recognized as safe under section 201(s).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H638B4216F6C34F44BE3A5E58F54203BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>pet food</term> means any food manufactured and distributed for consumption by companion animals, including treats, nutritional supplements, and pet food ingredients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6C0EB70CB2F47D6847FA681CA105486"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>pet food ingredient</term> means an ingredient intended for use in pet food.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AEE7199CB0B4F32897348817A50CB88"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pet food ingredient submission</term> means a submission to the Food and Drug Administration for a pet food ingredient that is a petition under section 409 for any food additive, a petition under section 721 for a color additive, or a GRAS ingredient notification under subpart E of part 570 of subchapter E of chapter I of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25D5F3C00AAD419DAB55D730F368BDC7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preemption</header><paragraph id="H2201322A7E584E5FA1D5EC3DD404753C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No State or a political subdivision of a State may directly or indirectly establish, maintain, implement, or enforce any authority or requirement relating to the labels, labeling, and advertising of pet food.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAA328100EA843C38FE19598B99D386F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict State food safety oversight activities, including any such activities relating to implementation of the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act, outbreak investigations, surveillance sampling, or investigations of consumer complaints.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C81F883DAC642088248194E5CBA054E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GRAS ingredients</header><paragraph id="H082B6366EE66421C828220BDF7431294"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ingredients deemed GRAS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ingredients that are intended for use in pet food, and are not specifically authorized for such use by the Food and Drug Administration as a food additive, a color additive, or otherwise as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>PURR Act of 2025</short-title>, are deemed to be GRAS if—</text><subparagraph id="H648B92E263084FD3B9D360A7666FFDF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such ingredients are identified in chapter 6 of the 2024 edition of the <quote>AAFCO Official Publication</quote> (or any subsequent amendments thereto or editions thereof) as acceptable for use in pet food (whether specifically for use in dog or cat food, or for use in animal food without restriction to species); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19636C3FBAF64405BEC54BF357B679F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is no finding by the Food and Drug Administration that such ingredients are not GRAS.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF923225CA82C4B93ADE0DFD8DC04C79F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voluntary notification</header><text>A pet food manufacturer is not required to notify the Food and Drug Administration of GRAS ingredients used in pet food, but may voluntarily notify the Food and Drug Administration of such GRAS ingredients that have not previously been recognized by the Food and Drug Administration as GRAS for use in pet food.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CBA5DC2E5B44B62A2669CF5ED08418F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timely review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receipt of a pet food ingredient submission, the Secretary shall review such submission and issue an action letter that—</text><paragraph id="HC31FCFFCC29248BCA842173C19513201"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approves such submission or, in the case of a GRAS ingredient notification, does not object to use; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC77B302743A46A281E7C9437A136E4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sets forth—</text><subparagraph id="HBF03521454AC46CEAC9373BBD0851A8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specific deficiencies in such submission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8590AF99ED4944CE96AAD2391D658A20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where appropriate, the actions necessary—</text><clause id="HE39AC1DAF795493F96FFF1E2ED1ED483"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for such submission to be approved; or</text></clause><clause id="HD3BE601504464A3C902C899F08396A97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a GRAS ingredient notification, to resolve any concerns of the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE092D20BFBD40C2BC1F144641D6BC11" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ingredients sometimes present</header><paragraph id="H2B43442E3139434D9152EF4C201A62AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pet food shall not be treated as misbranded by reason of stating in the pet food ingredient list on the product label that an ingredient of a type described in paragraph (2) is sometimes, but not always, present in the pet food.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEC34811C62A432682B0E5CF745ADA20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of ingredients</header><text>Paragraph (1) applies with respect to the following types of ingredients:</text><subparagraph id="HED31FD51015745F59CB6B9F2F6949CDF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fat or oil ingredients.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDA9473D3EA94F99BD348D8897428287" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Flavor ingredients.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFD9226210AE4E3FB63EEE76C16FE289" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Grain ingredients (including grain protein ingredients).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAD15C2F5394418EBD1E781A3C6819A7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Language to be used</header><text>For an ingredient in pet food to be labeled as sometimes present for purposes of paragraph (1), such ingredient shall be identified by—</text><subparagraph id="HAD5889F650724531A6E29B4EA19C5FEA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>words such as <quote>or</quote>, <quote>and/or</quote>, or <quote>contains one or more of the following:</quote>; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82072D2FE23C4B448F9281DDCC208DA8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other words indicating that the ingredient may not be present.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB5147812025447F89B092BDDE6E39D9" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Order of ingredient listing</header><paragraph id="H7ED3F81EB25F4694B7E065AE5C0A5A71" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pet food shall be treated as misbranded unless the ingredients required to be declared on the labeling of a pet food are listed by common or usual name in descending order of predominance by weight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H765CA15ECC1742C4BCB9935757D68EE5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If an ingredient in pet food is present in amounts of 2 percent or less by weight, then instead of identifying the ingredient in the order required by paragraph (1), the ingredient may be placed at the end of the pet food ingredient list following an appropriate quantifying statement, such as <quote>Contains __ percent or less of ______</quote> or <quote>Less than __ percent of ______</quote>, with the blank percentage filled in with a threshold level of 2 percent, or, if desired, 1.5 percent, 1.0 percent, or 0.5 percent, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CFB4CF801C744B0B6518D651ABC5A0F" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Permissible marketing claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pet food shall not be treated as misbranded by reason of the following claims on labels and labeling and in advertising for pet food, without premarket approval of such claims by the Food and Drug Administration, if truthful, nonmisleading, and adequately substantiated:</text><paragraph id="H3860DAE109234D02B51E76A8DD7B1508" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Claims regarding hairball control.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D76F2D4091C4FFBBCA25D2EC79BD45A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Claims regarding tartar control, plaque removal, and bad breath odor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H985C9379931842D2B846E30C23FF9655" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Claims regarding the ability of pet food to support general urinary tract health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC9DC1D52BD84469BE33B20134C0F534" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text><quote>Human grade</quote> claims for finished pet food (not for individual ingredients) if all of the following circumstances are met:</text><subparagraph id="H2D05C5454A754DB39FD2937A38EDAF3C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every ingredient in the pet food and the finished product is—</text><clause id="H9F22AB09EE514260B8F2D163C0457572" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stored, handled, processed, and transported in accordance with—</text><subclause id="H90F6E644DBA449E0B90815FD34E47FDA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>section 117 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2560DF85512F4364B82EC9B6FC134F40" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the laws applicable to food for human consumption, including such laws relating to ingredients, process, or facility type; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF5218F29EAF842DA8A65B4C081271FFB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manufactured in accordance with section 507 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9BC9453EAA548B89A832550B9B23C49" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each facility that manufactures the finished pet food or an ingredient in the finished pet food is registered pursuant to section 415 as a human food facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1359A45E7A43C6B8894678A318E01F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The <quote>human grade</quote> claims clearly indicate that the food is pet food, such as by stating <quote>dog food</quote> or <quote>cat treats</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCB9C841BCFE40F7A6569DFE4D2AF022" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text><quote>Natural</quote> claims if all of the following circumstances are met:</text><subparagraph id="HC4A6E90CFBF840C99F36A100441BEDF6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the term <term>natural</term> refers to a food or ingredient derived solely from plant, animal, or mined sources—</text><clause id="H27691EA45CC34FA0B41D17FA935EBE74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in its unprocessed state; or</text></clause><clause id="HBB72DFD3C0CC42218D4FF5291C9780DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>having been subject to physical processing, heat processing, rendering, purification, extraction, hydrolysis, enzymolysis, or fermentation, but not having been produced by or subject to a chemically synthetic process and not containing any additives or processing aids that are chemically synthetic except in amounts as might occur unavoidably in good manufacturing practices.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42128C8FD00646828061F43B27085EFE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>natural</term> is only used to reference the product as a whole when all of the ingredients and components of ingredients meet the description in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FDF886B42C042BFB0DDE1C86426701C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the food or ingredient contains chemically synthesized vitamins, minerals, or other trace nutrients used as ingredients in pet food, a disclaimer—</text><clause id="HE1E130B8DF59400083ECA2460C5A282F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discloses the addition of such vitamins, minerals, and other trace nutrients by name or category;</text></clause><clause id="HD4106B0A3DCF43718C79A04199103AAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is juxtaposed with the term <term>natural</term>; and</text></clause><clause id="HEA58A14C53964DA384D576E6C4CF509D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>appears with the largest or most prominent use of the term <term>natural</term> on each panel of the label on which the term appears, in the same style and color print and at least one-half the size of the term natural.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4294F73E23CD4F14BD77A3B10F5A5D9F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A disclaimer under subparagraph (C) is not required when the term <term>natural</term> is used in reference to one ingredient and is not referring to the whole product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70A331C3AEC744A88F2F057E9D74763B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Guidance on certain topics</header><paragraph id="HCCADB9C78A284B239B10B82D3A881BC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue guidance with respect to pet food addressing each of the following topics:</text><subparagraph id="HE4C738FD644C41669B4A887DB1BB97A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Methods for substantiating nutritional adequacy of pet foods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7642B62C8D7C4DC6AEABCBB281D1D12C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Pet food metabolizable energy protocols.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08832CDFFB5A4DEA9CB84B6CCF5ECB7B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Affidavits for pet food testing protocol completion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4743E23C274A43DA950C0BA0357270E4" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Data to support a calorie content claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32F900982A754AEDBC053E0DE6FD1DAA" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Analytical variations (Avs).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32DFB6682B5B488383D48A01D3689C69" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Recommendations for use of menadione sodium bisulfite complex (MSBC) in animal feed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06117BA67AA140D996F6C9B997B8DB05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial guidance</header><subparagraph id="H1B516C67F07E4BA69BAC12E137BB2825"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>PURR Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue initial guidance under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78778D94408848E39005E3A0AE4465DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initial guidance under subparagraph (A) shall be based on the guidance contained in the 2024 edition of the <quote>AAFCO Official Publication</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H4211ABD63646412E80CA268D3112ABAA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title X of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/391">21 U.S.C. 391 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C05CAD32CE74F3CAF881488A8DC8668" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HEC1D91A295D34686B61F7FEB3F95385D"><enum>1015.</enum><header>Responsibilities for pet food regulation</header><subsection id="HB8C918A5DA554FE29BF520A3EF6487BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Delegation of responsibility</header><text>The Secretary shall delegate to the Director of the Center for Veterinary Medicine responsibility for carrying out section 425 and, as appropriate, other responsibilities and authorities of the Food and Drug Administration with respect to pet food.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7854EDACA2664177BF7D23FB78CB6249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities of the Director of the Center for Veterinary Medicine shall include—</text><paragraph id="H9FE33D4A2D1D4E099E4B7A974A3588FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conducting and coordinating science-based reviews of pet food ingredient submissions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA851061F934D84928E19A33B5378EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submitting an annual report to the Congress on performance metrics, including performance on—</text><subparagraph id="H490875C61E3F40DD9F759DFEC84A7ABF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the review of submissions and issuance of action letters under section 425(d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8FB4363C1B640BE9E799553E0CC70CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the issuance of initial guidance under section 425(h) and any subsequent revisions to such guidance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75880DB61825404C9CAAE74ED1824957"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposal and finalization of initial regulations under section 5 of the <short-title>PURR Act of 2025</short-title> and any subsequent revisions to such regulations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22452E14C7634D88A8C1EBCA4B7EC57A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>educating pet owners, veterinarians, and the companion animal industry about pet food;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74C56F82D04A45EC8E9EDA1C3C1C32BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>communicating and educating consumers on the safety of pet food; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD37104C2BE5846AA8489A86B980930F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carrying out research to support and improve policies and regulatory decisions regarding pet food.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66362A9F6B034F048C42D5EF748DFE2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>companion animal</term>, <term>pet food</term>, and <term>pet food ingredient submission</term> have the meanings given to those terms in section 425.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H94758DFF67854BE9BAB043A49736CDB7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="H81ECECD807B14B4DB67DA39893ADCE59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text><paragraph id="HD09A0E4460F34F83AC964C703A57E776"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, issue proposed regulations to implement the amendments made by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB4C67E9F53424B97A5D30E838939E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, finalize such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B81203E312B4DF28CA4E5FE2E14606B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initial regulations promulgated to implement the amendments made by this Act shall include PF 1 through PF 12 of the <quote>Model Regulations for Pet Food and Specialty Pet Food Under the Model Bill</quote> in chapter 4 of the 2024 edition of the <quote>AAFCO Official Publication</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

