<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-NEW25233-NYK-G6-9PC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S789 IS: Critical Minerals Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 789</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require reports on critical mineral and rare earth element resources around the world and a strategy for the development of advanced mining, refining, separation, and processing technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idB7BC8EE031C14ABDBB8FADD9D8BA8F27" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Minerals Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf5853efd340d4544aa556a67625f9c1f" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports on critical mineral and rare earth element resources</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id786f6277-0008-4888-b63d-14049781fe55" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="id23061b44-00c4-4842-b40e-04e696491eb3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered nation</header><text>The term <term>covered nation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4872(d) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac9b9947-e0ba-471d-a078-56e0d3345236" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcf25943-8be9-4d84-b43e-6901e203c058" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40207(a) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18741">42 U.S.C. 18741(a)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98e96074-319f-4532-acc2-7e3b2b966211" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rare earth elements</header><text>The term <term>rare earth elements</term> means cerium, dysprosium, erbium, europium, gadolinium, holmium, lanthanum, lutetium, neodymium, praseodymium, promethium, samarium, scandium, terbium, thulium, ytterbium, and yttrium.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="ida951f33be91b4bbdaa29b4dddab74187"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdb31bef-6cb7-4c45-9176-2c928b205e2b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idacafeae6-ee9c-450f-943a-a219a60a4ee4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a4ee37f-6d86-45fc-84b4-b8991e4b160b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bac4728-57b7-45af-8dea-e185b6984b12" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports on critical mineral and rare earth element resources</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id434bc695c2d74b6aa59505b05fb505bc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to Congress a report on all critical mineral and rare earth element resources (including recyclable or recycled materials containing those resources) around the world that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id60979eb0-c63d-4a6f-aef8-a4b770a107ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text><clause id="idb63b21f1-cf9b-46cc-a0c6-10c03a5b1146" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which of those resources are under the control of a foreign entity of concern, including through ownership, contract, or economic or political influence;</text></clause><clause id="ide95bf4ff-39fc-4d90-a09d-97b71d93b3b8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which of those resources are owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of the United States or a country that is an ally or partner of the United States; </text></clause><clause id="id730a22ab-8378-4a19-8d89-bbfe934742e5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which of those resources are not owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign entity of concern or a country described in clause (ii); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1016d77b-9f1e-42f6-878e-04033126a845" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of those resources not undergoing commercial mining, the reasons for the lack of commercial mining;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id917f4e0b-2002-486b-bd17-e3aba30ce843" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each mine from which significant quantities of critical minerals or rare earth elements are being extracted, as of the date that is 1 year before the date of the report—</text><clause id="idd58774a7-14df-42ad-868d-a13435f18b64" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the annual volume of output of the mine as of that date; </text></clause><clause id="iddbcf20dc-24ee-420e-8a00-d8aef8aacc1f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of the total volume of mineral or elements that remain in the mine as of that date; </text></clause><clause id="id67427f7a-8e1b-4f22-9102-39576d7d8c7c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ida0eb1e88-4876-4ae7-bd41-14fbb60f37a4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an identification of the country and entity operating the mine; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="id279b3c94-cef4-4902-8026-0cc1ce8ca55d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the mine is operated by more than 1 country or entity, an estimate of the output of each mineral or element from the mine to which each such country or entity has access; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb4df9669-6699-4e5d-ab5e-dbc4ed7eb50b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an identification of the ultimate beneficial owners of the mine and the percentage of ownership held by each such owner;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9ec7e4c-3b17-46e1-a132-912b41db4792" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each mine not described in subparagraph (B), to the extent practicable—</text><clause id="id75888008-8aa9-416d-bb13-09a4a0b596db" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the aggregate annual volume of output of the mines as of the date that is 1 year before the date of the report;</text></clause><clause id="id3cfb7c0a-7f6c-466b-8f45-2b4e1d318bdb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of the aggregate total volume of mineral or elements that remain in the mines as of that date; and</text></clause><clause id="id4a631dd2-96af-42ed-b36f-cd429ac0cd61" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an estimate of the aggregate total output of each mineral or element from the mine to which a foreign entity of concern has access;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idff370e24-da12-45d0-aa4a-16bb1abecbfa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0e0ef058-9dd6-4644-a95d-4d76dc79dc3e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of key foreign entities of concern involved in mining critical minerals and rare earth elements;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id0944db75-3b30-4d1f-981c-4d4c23acff2a" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of key entities in the United States and countries that are allies or partners of the United States involved in mining critical minerals and rare earth elements; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" indent="up1" id="idbdeaace6-f871-455d-8818-802b521877b8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an assessment of the technical feasibility of entities listed under clauses (i) and (ii) mining and processing resources identified under subparagraph (A)(iii) using existing advanced technology;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cf9e525-93d2-4d41-b730-537fe5450284" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment, prepared in consultation with the Secretary of State, of ways to collaborate with countries in which mines, mineral processing operations, or recycling operations (or any combination thereof) are located that are operated by other countries, or are operated by entities from other countries, to ensure ongoing access by the United States and countries that are allies and partners of the United States to those mines and processing or recycling operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55433ac3-4cc2-494f-b602-163c2b863440" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list, prepared in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, identifying, to the maximum extent practicable, all cases in which entities were forced to divest stock in mining, processing, or recycling operations (or any combination thereof) for critical minerals and rare earth elements based on—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2427f520-3709-45e0-978f-42b94ead4012" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulatory rulings of the government of a covered nation;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6524bfc0-c885-4f92-8b58-052e4c4d4a70" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">joint regulatory rulings of the government of a covered nation and the government of another country; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73cfae0c-5ceb-4536-baba-9b36931ec1de" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rulings of a relevant tribunal or other entity authorized to render binding decisions on divestiture; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf05b7a2-8dec-4474-bef0-4aa6be3516c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a list of all cases in which the government of a covered nation purchased an entity that was forced to divest stock as described in subparagraph (F); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf23e4ad9-60f2-4c6e-97b9-833b9e87fe59" changed="not-changed"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a list of all cases in which mining, processing, or recycling operations (or any combination thereof) for critical minerals and rare earth elements that were not subject to a ruling described in subparagraph (F) were taken over by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae2ac00a-8bb6-4bd6-b685-f6dc5a114df6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of a covered nation; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01cd7dfd-80e2-4c50-b04d-18dca71ea2a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity located in, or influenced or controlled by, the government of a covered nation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4aebc47b-c1c3-48eb-a0ab-bcd59922adb4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex, if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0b90d1ef-73ee-4c23-95e3-b68cd3f36819" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Process for notifying United States Government of divestment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish a process under which—</text><paragraph id="id3dc3ce94-b697-430d-a4fa-63c0bbaf053a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States person seeking to divest stock in mining, processing, or recycling operations for critical minerals and rare earth elements in a foreign country may notify the Secretary of the intention of the person to divest the stock; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7ee72f9-46cc-46b0-9110-c00d24585256" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary may provide assistance to the person to find a purchaser that is not under the control of the government of a covered nation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idee0ea52a-0411-4746-bb4d-d7d56cce0229" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategy on development of advanced mining, refining, separation, processing, and recycling technologies</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4535247-fcda-4386-b556-e17d0d977a2b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall develop—</text><subparagraph id="id50a684af-ca5c-4708-8225-7482f334b448" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strategy to collaborate with the governments of countries that are allies and partners of the United States to develop advanced mining, refining, separation, processing, and recycling technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c18940c-2151-4315-9664-b2731af85c90" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a method for sharing the intellectual property resulting from the development of advanced mining, refining, separation, processing, and recycling technologies with the governments of countries that are allies and partners of the United States to enable those countries to license those technologies and mine, refine, separate, process, and recycle the resources of those countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc8370c9-1908-4b8f-80b8-f7cbb75d6274" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the progress made in developing the strategy and method described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

