<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48BD3F14C1FF46E48A454CE8F94E739F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1611 IH: Respect, Advancement, and Increasing Support for Educators Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a refundable tax credit for certain teachers as a supplement to State efforts to provide teachers with a livable wage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7FF82F60E8BA459D9B80348B5F4AA53A" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9ED45FB0966C45FB94EE96BAD7051E91"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respect, Advancement, and Increasing Support for Educators Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAISE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HEC6C796CF4CE4629ABD24A2C0AAB5B02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Refundable teacher tax credit</header><subsection id="H5FCD5863D86B4429AF84C5C7CA2D933D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of tax credit</header><paragraph id="H1E334E0FAA034BD7B22900196805549C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 36B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H065D0D4728784506A2761943B7D6B4E1"><section id="HC3428CE600164F62A544FF8156F5C2C7"><enum>36C.</enum><header>Teacher tax credit</header><subsection id="H5930E343B9964FC483D6BC275F84B269"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Credit allowed</header><text>In the case of an individual who is an eligible educator during school years ending with or within the taxable year, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter an amount equal to the sum of—</text><paragraph id="HD7AD553BA4754B7A9E9E37D873094F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,000, plus</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA14A656A16E040BDA264612666CA7AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible educator who is employed at a qualifying school, the applicable amount.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55FF3B9341044BE7BDE3F6CFD1CC36F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable amount</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the applicable amount is the amount which bears the same ratio (not to exceed one) to $14,000 ($9,000, in the case of any early childhood educator without a bachelor's degree) as—</text><paragraph id="H291345F30D6B4C94AFB0CBD258DD7CE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of percentage points by which the student poverty ratio for such qualifying school exceeds 39 percent, bears to</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD70026612344FE380A67F55A17E9DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>36 percentage points.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4EA87A1F47046CEB129EBF771BCC705"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible educator</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H60D06706884F46E88A105C783A288AF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible educator</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD9567B053E5D41FE9BCF44EBA3E90863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any elementary or secondary teacher, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F0F0C973FF84E75BD4ADE7BC2844C66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any early childhood educator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8F1041ECD94FC48E87E3A82AC53578"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elementary or secondary teacher</header><subparagraph id="H3DF7E4974A3947C0BA13043D496BC612"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>elementary or secondary teacher</term> means an individual who—</text><clause id="H9732F99A4E1C47C1832A460D94CD4544"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a teacher of record who provides direct classroom teaching (or classroom-type teaching in a nonclassroom setting) in a public elementary school or a public secondary school for not less than 75 percent of the normal or statutory number of hours of work for a full-time teacher over a complete school year (as determined by the State in which the school is located),</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD6CFDC37B6FF497BA42CFE9E4BF63C3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the applicable requirements for State certification and licensure in the State in which such school is located in the subject area in which the individual is the teacher of record, and</text></clause><clause id="HE1B5670F428D4BAE8DEF41796DB02D6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has met the requirements of clauses (i) and (ii) for a period of not less than 1 year before the first day of the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H472A07C16A2647538A6AD7AD61EABF05"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Teacher of record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>teacher of record</term> means a teacher who has been assigned the responsibility for specified pupils’ learning in a grade, subject, or course as reflected on the school’s official record of attendance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3E3EBCF4DF540449D0C922731DE0153"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early childhood educator</header><text>The term <term>early childhood educator</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A8BEC618E2B4838BC26C1D257384784"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a Child Development Associate credential (or an equivalent credential), or has an associate's degree or higher, </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D769B6E125E4333882F54626175D9EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the applicable requirements for State certification, licensure, or permitting under State law for early childhood education,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAAF405A27E94002813CD6E3E11EBF19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has primary responsibility for the learning and development of children in an early childhood education program (as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)) for not less than 75 percent of the normal or statutory number of hours of work for a full-time teacher over a complete program year, as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2137619517CB429CACC6D23F64C8918B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has met the requirements of subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) for a period of not less than 1 year before the first day of the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F82EAF58FAD43ACA44F532A24BCDF47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualifying school</header><paragraph id="H2F097EDC6A3C414E939653AE250E45A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualifying school</term> means, with respect to any school year—</text><subparagraph id="HC5C214BFE14047D782D53EED5023DE91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public elementary school or a public secondary school that—</text><clause id="H70FAC36E1EA643449913F9D6CC471EE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is served by a local educational agency that is eligible in such year for assistance pursuant to part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>), or</text></clause><clause id="H5651EC16C9C8477792BA26C82BC1955C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is served by an educational service agency, or a location operated by an educational service agency, that is eligible, for the year in which the determination is made, for assistance under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>),</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H886272B5199840E5A093601FBDD76ABC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an elementary school or secondary school that is funded by the Bureau of Indian Education, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4A6C6C74DE64DF2A870026786628128"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an early childhood education program (as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)) that serves children who receive, or are eligible for, services for which financial assistance is provided in accordance with the Child Care and Development Block Grant of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>) or the child and adult care food program established under section 17 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1766">42 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0BE02ADE5FF4B1E9508821145393C72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the terms <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD58E1A038BE5496CB09F67E007F464DE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Student poverty ratio</header><paragraph id="H411FCC9EA2024E38AE30D0B1FC368EBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>student poverty ratio</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H06CE3A858D414248821CF23899B2E6CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to any qualifying school described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (d)(1), the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text><clause id="HE7C469676E6C4D3DB38236F93CF63FFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number of children served at such qualifying school meeting at least one measure of poverty described in section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6313">20 U.S.C. 6313(a)(5)</external-xref>), to</text></clause><clause id="HF464E51EF9F144ADACB714480AEEC835"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of children served at such qualifying school, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA4579F92EF64159B0060ACA9396CE73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any qualifying school described in subsection (d)(1)(C), the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text><clause id="H042829D6841141728235611BC86ACA6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number of children attending such qualifying school who are eligible for services under the Child Care and Development Block Grant of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>) or for the child and adult care food program established under section 17 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1766">42 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>), to</text></clause><clause id="H6146C7287BA946549A38B829A83E1F89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of children attending such qualifying school.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8A003B8B4A94DE6BFF3444230904083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of ratio</header><text>In determining the student poverty ratio with respect to a qualifying school under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall use the same measure of poverty as is used for purposes of determining the allocation of funds under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to the qualifying school. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H615F5BEB837E4A49857B4DCBF2DF6FF9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><paragraph id="H9B99CA6F0FB643C6B60857DC1D244066"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2026, each of the dollar amounts in subsections (a) and (b) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H7CC345AB7E944C0986D4025CCB846F45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01719F4DB2014403B9DC8742838B7FF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H049DDA4019D24E23A6676EC57E724768"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase determined under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $50, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A1E9B057AE4A4D8275260170086959"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="HA25FD8C8371E4D57B6D2A58D2F991DB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 36B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H607F26A0051445A984EB6873B183473D"><toc><toc-entry idref="HC3428CE600164F62A544FF8156F5C2C7" level="section">Sec. 36C. Teacher tax credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E6E08992D84117BB9315256BE3CBC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 6211(b)(4)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>36C,</quote> after <quote>36B,</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAD8E83EF6D344EE8FB1089C8C8978D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>36C,</quote> after <quote>36B,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2324A994ACE486AB6E3456B7AB973E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><paragraph id="HED34269DA3B24CEEB6044A08BE586937"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3520AA28E50A44379D70B323E1EA2CBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect such information as necessary for purposes of determining whether a school is a qualifying school (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by subsection (a)) and the appropriate amount of tax credit under such section; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA158014143944F709B6614E50F0A02BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide such information to the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1DEF362B61F4FC09FBCD9B3810FCEC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information for the Secretary of Education</header><text>As a condition of receiving Federal funds and if requested by the Secretary of Education, each qualifying school shall collect and submit to the Secretary of Education such information as may be necessary to enable the Secretary of Education to carry out paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEE3A38170A124483A600A9B734651122"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplementation of funds</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H44F683D2EA7443FBAD745B683A511AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elementary and Secondary Education</header><text>A State educational agency or local educational agency (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) shall not reduce or adjust any teacher pay or teacher loan forgiveness program due to the eligibility of teachers within the jurisdiction of such agency for the tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Each State educational agency and local educational agency (as so defined), upon request by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall demonstrate that the methodology used to allocate teacher pay and teacher loan forgiveness (if applicable) to qualifying schools (as defined in section 36C(d) of such Code) ensures that each such school receives the same State and local funds for teacher compensation it would receive if the credit under such section 36C had not been enacted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H893129A98C104D8784D2AEC80AF78054" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early childhood education</header><text>An agency or other entity that funds, licenses, or regulates an early childhood education program (as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)) shall not reduce or adjust any teacher pay or teacher loan forgiveness program, or permit such a reduction or adjustment in the early childhood education program, due to the eligibility of teachers within the jurisdiction of such agency for the tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Each such agency or entity, upon request by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall demonstrate that the methodology used to allocate teacher pay and teacher loan forgiveness (if applicable) to such early childhood education programs ensures that each such program receives the same State and local funds for teacher compensation it would receive if the credit under such section 36C had not been enacted. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF43DC1BBAEC7463BB2D65C13F67B017A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employer limitations</header><paragraph id="H4426CEC085BA4EA8B7F52F122ED291E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition of use in collective bargaining</header><text>An employer that engages in collective bargaining with employees who are eligible educators, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, shall not include the amount of the teacher tax credit under section 36C of such Code in determining the amount of salary or other compensation provided to any employee under the collective bargaining agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H616D3ED6698846CFADC9DDF34587C2D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of use as punishment or retribution</header><text>An employer of an eligible educator, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, shall not change the work assignment or location of the eligible educator if one of the primary reasons for the change is to—</text><subparagraph id="HDE0F65E75E884E298063B5C552866097"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent the eligible educator from receiving a teacher tax credit under section 36C of such Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB37142F359440A897895F283C6BCF26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the amount of the teacher tax credit that the eligible educator will receive.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD85795A5F17443D8AC4CC2020CEC0287"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall have the authority to investigate and enforce any alleged violation of this section in the same manner, and subject to the same procedures, as would apply to an allegation of an unfair labor practice under section 7118 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E16CDA6F53047E98AB6F11337DF6C99"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H08D5423459674C4EA702F081B74E06A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>affecting commerce</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H600F2508FC90451FB72D84E1827A170E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>employee</term> means an employee of an employer who is employed in a business of an employer that affects commerce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BFBD9F15E2E4852B8AB2DC3E07B1F6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>employer</term> means a person, including a State or political subdivision of a State, engaged in a business affecting commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DB7090CB8544989935A3F177649FA5D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0DABC5D3FD97418BB2BE35AEEA1C47F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increase in and expansion of deduction for expenses of elementary and secondary school teachers</header><subsection id="H5AF0B866680C4FAFAC910AD7EE3656BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase</header><paragraph id="HA652BC5E87F144299148062F4BDFA4DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (D) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>$250</quote> and inserting <quote>$500</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H726267D119AD4589B6DED61D8093A31A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>Section 62(d)(3) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HF9112A311F1F4823A65CE037B7113D7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2015</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H233C8D512068423AA1335108A8116679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the $250 amount</quote> and inserting <quote>each of the dollar amounts</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H889FA94CD7634D25B2D2D76138C99D91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2014</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE6ED5562EB2B4A54BEC5065894E1C34B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion to early childhood educators</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">Section 62(d)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H6E0AEF04BF644916944C618A2070E34B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who is a kindergarten</quote> and inserting</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4606974543FF485182952E50C86D4CBC"><text>who is—</text><clause commented="no" id="HFC360953FA2F43A3AA11B9244E439B63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a kindergarten</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H554DB0A31E0144F19F8969B4525A549B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAF8A33290FF34A38AC118604F66902C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82F386DD4D104804B9C22DEC3F1D9DCB"><clause commented="no" id="H230AF485D02845B4BA4E5CE290C7726B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an early childhood educator (as defined in section 200 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1021">20 U.S.C. 1021</external-xref>)) in an early childhood education program (as defined in section 103 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)) for at least 1,020 hours during a year.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5A3054540E4347876002EF8F40A84E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="HC478C383C3584E57BE5416CB853D3984"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mandatory funding to support local educational agencies that maintain or increase teacher salaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2003 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6603">20 U.S.C. 6603</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF28EB1588FBA432FA399DF0F20D811A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Authorization of appropriations</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Funding</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCADF930372543AB9D10ECE88672B4FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE62D9E456647493BAEC2480104FC2450" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="HBDC9F6FCBEB84C0DBD14DEDB4559CBFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriations for part A</header><paragraph id="HD3938F69341E4BDE90D58180250FA3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated, out of any funds not otherwise appropriated—</text><subparagraph id="H1F2A35857CC6457189EE38BE2986CDA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2026, $5,200,000,000 to carry out part A; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12EB1512E5F34ACBBF81C5CCBAB7EE7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027 and each succeeding fiscal year, the amount appropriated under this paragraph for the preceding year, increased by a percentage equal to the annual percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor for the most recent calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB22B3FAA84B945CBA043A6511FE546F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation for teacher salary incentive grants</header><subparagraph id="HB791105670F94A7091CFB2854B4EE861"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE957AD3515049B88138194D02E876D6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligible local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>eligible local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that, for the preceding school year, maintained or increased the salary schedule for all teachers employed by the local educational agency.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB642CBF0D7546DABBACF0BF292C7354"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Teacher salary incentive reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>teacher salary incentive reservation</term> means, for each fiscal year, the amount that is 20 percent of the amount by which the funds appropriated under paragraph (1) for the fiscal year exceeds $2,200,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB943CC3C0B3143B1B9176620F15C2FEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year for which the total amount appropriated under paragraph (1) is greater than $2,200,000,000, the Secretary shall, after making any reservations under section 2101(a), reserve and use the teacher salary incentive reservation to award grants, based on allotments under subparagraph (C), to eligible local educational agencies for purposes described in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D5C6009012346B496BEE6BF939E3B9C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allotments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An allotment under this subparagraph for a fiscal year to an eligible local educational agency shall bear the same relationship to the teacher salary incentive reservation as the number of children counted under section 1124(c) who are served by the local educational agency bears to the total number of such children counted under such section served by all eligible local educational agencies that submitted an application under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE6BDF5EAAC640739E43D0FC7FBFBA1B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible local educational agency desiring an allotment under this paragraph shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C784DEB401F4469BED11EB8F9717D4E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A local educational agency receiving an allotment under subparagraph (C) may use the allotment to carry out one or more of the following:</text><clause id="HC078A28164744FD08E0739684C342CA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Comprehensive teacher or school leader preparation programs described subsection (d), (e), or (f) of section 202 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></clause><clause id="H59C596CA89504237B1E903583EE3C598"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Support for teachers to earn certifications or credentials in high-need fields or advanced credentials, such as certification or credentialing by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards.</text></clause><clause id="HFB23F6C8BEEB4525A654AC51820B5418"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Teacher leadership programs.</text></clause><clause id="H47527BDBF8D14FC3A71D9C0028B45FF3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Induction or mentoring programs for new teachers, principals, or other school leaders.</text></clause><clause id="H0224E964CEBC45AAA0A13498B9A82184"><enum>(v)</enum><text>High-quality research-based professional development.</text></clause><clause id="H3B78658A5E484C46A32670F94FE8F3A9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Other activities approved by the Secretary that—</text><subclause id="H32D6A37B345C4085AEB2D7E7E7F63E73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>promote and strengthen the teaching profession;</text></subclause><subclause id="H271EDDF2D06F48D0B59DE74D9D2CBFCC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>attract, retain, and diversify the educator workforce; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1CB261A12A114175A1209DD0A12E2FA9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>advance the skills and efficacy of the educator workforce. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7973DA61A12142CB954728BFF4C0EBA1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>A local educational agency receiving an allotment under subparagraph (C) shall use the allotment to supplement, and not supplant, any State funds or efforts to raise teacher pay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

