<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25310-NNL-3F-GRL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1218 IS: Transportation Assistance for Olympic and World Cup Cities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1218</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250401" legis-day="20250331">April 1 (legislative day, March 31), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide assistance for cities hosting international sporting events taking place in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation Assistance for Olympic and World Cup Cities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a68392b4e8b47fbaa3d99443a1ce990"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transportation assistance for international sporting events</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7376f16d90d54e14bde7c569e064c49a"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5501">section 5501</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83092A817B2942399B574E01639D1D2A"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id464fb53a5955479c8304a5487397dbad"><enum>5502.</enum><header>Transportation assistance for international sporting events</header><subsection id="id708e7eb875184f1287d2f69980c9ab3b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to support State, Tribal, and local efforts on transportation issues necessary to obtain the national recognition and economic benefits of hosting international sporting events in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8351ac0033c74c4288c12e0baa650383"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id2dd719d7813c408e8ecd4716d95d5c73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered event</header><subparagraph id="idf8c272acb8c449bfb46e02f3e81bc3e7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered event</term> means an Olympic event, Paralympic event, Special Olympics event, FIFA Men’s World Cup event, or FIFA Women’s World Cup event that is held at a site within the United States (including any territory of the United States) that has been selected by the International Olympic Committee or the International Federation of Association Football to hold such event.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb839a6c07a7745f5b1702d457d3f5fcd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grouping</header><text>Multiple events described in subparagraph (A) occurring in the same stadium, city, metropolitan planning area (as defined in section 134(b) of title 23), or metropolitan statistical area (as designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget) as part of the same overall competition, sporting event, or grouping of competitions or sporting events shall be considered to be 1 covered event.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d47581aa25a424081c44a521d9c867b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered event</term> does not include activities relating to preparing or submitting a bid to be selected to hold an event described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida02feb9ba31746d3aef9998b2b350da8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id697a2dc7483e4761857896de60853b1b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government (including a port authority or transit agency) hosting a covered event;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4709669136a425684804d9ca680a993"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government (including a port authority or transit agency) that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2649f95a3374bbbb4b439eb3e98c24e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is supporting a covered event; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71631b2e13a3457aad64746e346e463c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owns a transportation facility or provides a transportation service that is located not more than 100 miles from the location in which the applicable covered event is or will be held;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa9e8f843ff944769e1164ec0050ef4f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization that serves an area that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03fc32991fba427cbf8793fb345b02e0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is under the jurisdiction of a State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government described in subparagraph (A) or (B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida854f1c13f2a4926baa748982d498980"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is located not more than 100 miles from the location in which the applicable covered event is or will be held;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf0ebe2825d249979fa242f11ab691d7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity eligible to receive a grant under section 5339 for services provided within 100 miles of the location in which the applicable covered event is or will be held; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc241c8763d84b23a6ff4d972bc40ba4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a nonprofit entity established for execution of a covered event.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida86fead0e386439ebe7558d92ddb2789"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Host metropolitan planning organization</header><text>The term <term>host metropolitan planning organization</term> means a metropolitan planning organization for an urbanized area (as defined in section 134(b) of title 23) within which a covered event is or will be held.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID569E39A7AE294A8BB8194A9568303F9E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfde83e2071c54885ac94a92349ebbe96"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Metropolitan planning organization</header><text>The term <term>metropolitan planning organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 134(b) of title 23.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0822630f8744371b8c60cdd351116a6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1e7006e74e8b4795b25848f4b7ab95ef"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants for transportation projects relating to international games</header><paragraph id="idc6f7783dccfa4b4e9cbf7250578dc0f7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allocate the amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out this subsection as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06116316d00e4503ae8c193aa1eeb2f2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>First, the Secretary shall allocate those amounts equally among the host metropolitan planning organizations for the most imminent covered event and any other covered events occurring during the same fiscal year, subject to the condition that a host metropolitan planning organization may not receive more than $10,000,000 under this subparagraph for a single covered event.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2d70874a783455dbb654e8f72379679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Once the host metropolitan planning organizations described in subparagraph (A) have each been allocated a total of $10,000,000 under this subsection for each covered event described in that subparagraph, including any amounts for previous fiscal years allocated for the same covered event, the Secretary shall allocate any remaining amounts—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b6406a1bd924da196ab7a0e8a0df196"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">first, equally among all host metropolitan planning organizations eligible to receive assistance under this subsection for a covered event not described in subparagraph (A), subject to the condition that a host metropolitan planning organization may not receive more than $10,000,000 under this clause for a single covered event; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77b3500bf75e4cc6b66949beb081d6ec"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>once the host metropolitan planning organizations described in clause (i) have each been allocated a total of $10,000,000 under this subsection for each covered event described in that clause, including any amounts for previous fiscal years allocated for the same covered event, equally among all host metropolitan planning organizations eligible to receive assistance under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c068efe332b44c29d46b72923826a6e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a13d6de433844efa48c62d64c79c664"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A host metropolitan planning organization receiving amounts under paragraph (1) may use the amounts to provide funding to eligible entities to carry out projects described in subparagraph (B) that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44687c5d103a4f72b5d50e78a28b3f2a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are located not more than 100 miles from the location in which the applicable covered event is or will be held; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d4fe7c876154ddfb4e56ec4fdb75f92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the determination of the host metropolitan planning organization, are not temporary infrastructure needed for hosting the covered event.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d9e39084a5044e2bc9cdc771f165b34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Project described</header><text>A project referred to in subparagraph (A) is any of the following:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56d4a8cc62ac423db6e2631892c4dc0e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A transportation project that—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6b802104c964a6d8bd8400d05bba1c5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is eligible for assistance under any provision of this title or title 23; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddaccbc7024694f068545bab6b5d47730"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the determination of the host metropolitan planning organization, will assist with the movement of people or goods related to the applicable covered event.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc50803b76a7347b5878ad18d7ec55134"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A transportation planning activity that, in the determination of the host metropolitan planning organization, will assist with the movement of people and goods for the applicable covered event.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id940fda132f944131b82474a812d77701"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements described in section 6701 (n) shall apply to a project described in paragraph (2) that is funded by a grant under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c050d92ae5f4ae4bf88ae4ff7f274ae"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitations</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90861bdab87c424296271173108d1599"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Allocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the allocation of amounts under paragraph (1), a host metropolitan planning organization is eligible to receive assistance under this subsection only during the period beginning on the date that is 5 years before the date on which a covered event begins and ending on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the covered event ends.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04921835adb34060aebc3f4884a70e5e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reimbursements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), but subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall provide, from amounts allocated to the applicable host metropolitan planning organization under paragraph (1), reimbursements for activities described in paragraph (2) that are carried out during the period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ea017e0bd8a46e3a6bad51fb14b9b56"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Release of funds</header><text>Any amounts allocated under paragraph (1) that are not expended by the date that is 1 year after the date on which the applicable covered event ends shall be reallocated in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd96c74acdd5c405697f83a5c5f90bb53"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $50,000,000 for each fiscal year, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4b6f1a4d01234e1085a9ec6f501ceb33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transportation planning activities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida73bcbf0bea8459da0702048c11a931a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, on request, shall provide technical and planning assistance to eligible entities, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3fa45d6edb134f2288cebe6b2e0b69cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by providing technical assistance for planning activities of States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, and metropolitan planning organizations under sections 134 and 135 of title 23 and sections 5303, 5304, and 5305 of this title for transportation projects relating to a covered event;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f804f6a2a374f839277b6f7ad7c5e8b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by assisting States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, and metropolitan planning organizations with the development of intermodal transportation plans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0033b651821649d1bca3e00f89b3dc0d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by facilitating programs or providing incentives to temporarily pool and share, for the duration of a covered event, buses and related equipment among—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1219993c8d34aa2be62c3c2d2b82f93"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States, Indian Tribes, and units of local government hosting or supporting a covered event; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98affba170634051bedc18cc167c8436"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States, Indian Tribes, and units of local government not hosting or supporting a covered event;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8da0e0c8e594f1bb2b03b7a9bd62d1e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by expediting review and comment of any required submissions to the Secretary relating to a covered event;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c6456b855174200a77ea35b6d8d8472"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by assisting with the coordination of transportation planning efforts between governments or the private sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf17ae67e29284cde9cd12fcbf82ca052"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by providing any other technical or planning assistance the Secretary determines to be necessary for advancing the purpose of this section described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fd5baa43fcf44f98d419645a3e2ab8f"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide assistance under this subsection for a covered event only during the period beginning on the date that is 5 years before the date on which the covered event begins and ending on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the covered event ends.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc331b66a9b45461cace35cf2567d44b0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5501">section 5501</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0EDCFC8C25B949AAA8840AD502D9B798"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5502. Transportation assistance for international sporting events.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b65502148064f828d81c294b8f13025"><enum>3.</enum><header>Studies on the effects of hosting the Olympics and World Cup on the travel and tourism industry in the United States</header><subsection id="ida6a636059fd14d51b14ec62a5b31189b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id41838a2e04cd4c7bab6ffaa5637c2e96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local Planning Committees</header><text>The term <term>Local Planning Committees</term> means the World Cup planning committees specific to each World Cup host city.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01b6772d19644ffb9f9b8388f8f201a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Olympics</header><text>The term <term>Olympics</term> means the 2028 Summer Olympics and 2028 Paralympics, both hosted by Los Angeles, California.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd335f4c219f64095a61794698c858126"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27d03a4b668a4955b62e59dc4ff8326d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Travel and tourism industry</header><text>The term <term>travel and tourism industry</term> means the travel and tourism industry in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9578893799e3470995388c97943c7918"><enum>(5)</enum><header>World cup</header><text>The term <term>World Cup</term> means the 2026 Men’s FIFA World Cup, hosted by the United States, Mexico, and Canada. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0d70d56629a46208792595cb294f914"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Commerce study and report on effects on travel and tourism of hosting the Olympics</header><paragraph id="id9e2325997b664a5a9addf7554a57ee8a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and after consultation with the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board and the United States Olympic Planning Committee, the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, commence a study to examine the impact of the Olympics on the travel and tourism industry, including—</text><subparagraph id="id93b6ac4600444c5bb99e15bb9e722aee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes in the frequency of international travel to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c3a831cdbc746178517fdaaf9b346f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes in the frequency of domestic travel within the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7cde7aeaed24b54b6671113683f324d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changes in the revenues of businesses in the travel and tourism industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb72459b1eb134574b667a5e7fdb177dd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>changes in employment rates in the travel and tourism industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idea0ab832101e405a9ff2d4e29dc69d51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a99334cb0344fba9f5f92eab5715e12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the Olympics, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2ef262b3c274e8298ca32c2e7977e11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report described in subparagraph (A) publicly available on the website of the Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4064c9af8b674062aac5f060a13a7457"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Department of Commerce study and report on effects on travel and tourism of hosting the World Cup</header><paragraph id="id076b5e9813f3487294eab438ed52608d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and after consultation with the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board and Local Planning Committees, the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, commence a study to examine the impact of the World Cup on the travel and tourism industry, including—</text><subparagraph id="id7a8acc224c0944f5a645b69661a2bf4c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes in the frequency of international travel to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1f5b95684c7497fb9a1043b547bdad0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes in the frequency of domestic travel within the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8532f6365135408cbb42905c09affdf4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changes in the revenues of businesses in the travel and tourism industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2169eb1bc4d34001902bc4b5f514390d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>changes in employment rates in the travel and tourism industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3dfef6ab719041a9a6c62b5242174897"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73b5cb19add04de19e8dccc8bf31415b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the World Cup, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fa949465f79422299bb92fbfb2aa8ba"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report described in subparagraph (A) publicly available on the website of the Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

