<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H102F3E2ADA3A4031B08E20527C6E07CD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 153 EH: Expressing condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of the crash of American Eagle Flight 5342 and PAT 25, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 153</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Expressing condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of the crash of American Eagle Flight 5342 and PAT 25, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of Wichita, Kansas, and the people of the National Capital Region have experienced a terrible tragedy with the loss of 67 lives in the crash of American Eagle Flight 5342 and U.S. Army flight callsign <quote>PAT 25</quote> near Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport outside of Washington, District of Columbia, on January 29, 2025;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many of the victims of the crash were residents of, or connected to, Wichita, Kansas, colloquially known as the <quote>Air Capital of the World</quote> for the city’s historic role in aviation; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas many Federal, State, and local officials have cooperated to respond to the emergency, investigate the accident, and provide assistance to families devastated by the loss of loved ones: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB7001385330B48F8B6AD913B581F70CB"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H538E1D9BFC8749C9B1FEC51BBCF13D77"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H8DE39010ACBF45BB94FEC88E42F4A018"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of the crash of American Eagle Flight 5342 and PAT 25;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D07809FA57B4A49966A54AC8D740246"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors those who lost their lives, including Franco Aparicio, Luciano Aparicio, Sarah Lee Best, Brielle Beyer, Justyna Beyer, Jonathan D. Boyd, Jonathan Jay Campos, James “Tommy” Thomas Clagett Jr., Chris Collins, Casey Laurance Crafton, Pete "PJ" Diaz, Kiah Duggins, Chief Warrant Officer Andrew Loyd Eaves, Danasia Brown Elder, James “Brian” Ellis, Ian Douglas Epstein, Lindsey Denae Fields, Jinna Han, Jin Han, Cory Haynos, Stephanie Haynos, Roger Haynos, Alexander “Alex” Gordon Huffman, Asra Hussain-Raza, Steve Johnson, Julia Kay, Sean Kay, Elizabeth Anne Keys, Alexandr “Sasha” Kirsanov, Spencer Lane, Christine Conrad Lane, Samuel “Sam” Walter Lilley, Alydia Steele Livingston, Everly Pearl Livingston, Donna Livingston, Peter Livingston, Captain Rebecca M. Lobach, Pergentino Noble Malabed Jr., Grace Maxwell, Charles Douglas McDaniel, Dustin Michael Miller, Melissa Jane Nicandri, Staff Sergeant Ryan Austin O’Hara, Vikesh Patel, Jesse Jameson Pitcher, Robert “Rob” Alan Prewitt, Lori Ann Girard Schrock, Robert “Bob” Ryan Schrock, Wendy Jo Shaffer, Evgenia Shishkova, Vadim Naumov, Michael “Mikey” Bret Stovall, Olesya Taylor, Olivia Ter, Inna Volyanskaya, Angela Yang, Zheheng “Lily” Li, Edward Zhou, Yu Zhou, Kaiyan Mao, and 7 others. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEA0CE723E06545B684237E92C6403E39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses sympathies to the people of Wichita, the entire state of Kansas, the National Capital Region, the Nation, and the multiple countries who grieve for the victims; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA0AFEBC2A4842D4A7CA00088D82CF90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the heroic actions of the first responders, emergency services personnel, and all those who aided in the recovery efforts in freezing waters.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


