<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEFBD67D9F0F044A6B6F55412BAF137E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3596 IH: Rape Shield Enhancement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Judicial Conference to submit a report examining an amendment to the Federal Rules of Evidence to further limit admissibility of evidence regarding an alleged victim’s sexual behavior or predisposition and to improve privacy protections for admissible evidence.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCEC3477155C943B8B97820521AD057A0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC2F02281AC494616B8F921B64EF90EBA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rape Shield Enhancement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0972866B5DA84117BC3200FD47C945A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on amendment to the rules of evidence to further limit admissibility of evidence regarding an alleged victim’s sexual behavior or predisposition and to improve privacy protections for admissible evidence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Judicial Conference shall submit to Congress—</text>
<paragraph id="HB75C6E013E064EDB968BBE853C62B33A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a report reviewing Rule 412 of the Federal Rules of Evidence, and identify amendments, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, limited in scope to—</text> <subparagraph id="H2621FC9F502040EC893AC541A250595E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>further limiting the admissibility of evidence regarding the sexual behavior or predisposition of an alleged victim of sexual assault; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0AD86C3EDCC47B0A993C51B2AB61016"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving privacy protections for admissible evidence related to the sexual behavior or predisposition of an alleged victim of sexual assault, including the subsequent disclosure of such evidence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EE5F1E1E70D4F07A8BAC1636CE02DA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a report reviewing Rule 26 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, and identify amendments, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, that would—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1FAF369C64CC41FF97CF0705899DE260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>narrow the scope of permissible discovery requests to limit inquiries into the personal, financial, social, psychological, sexual, medical, or other private or confidential records or history of an alleged victim of sexual assault, unless directly relevant to the case;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD381BAE9584A413A83E4993B12FEFA5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish clearer protections for the privacy of such an alleged victim, including limitations on subsequent disclosures of personal, financial, social, psychological, sexual, medical, or other private or confidential records or history of an alleged victim of sexual assault; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H686AB2B917874A7CA783A911EE5D7113"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that discovery practices are consistent with Federal law protecting the rights of such an alleged victim; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H984473E50BA84A9CB3C59ABBED53ACA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a report reviewing Rule 16 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, and identify amendments, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, that would—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4BBB304854394FA3A1CD78BB37E61399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>narrow the scope of permissible discovery requests to limit inquiries into the personal, financial, social, psychological, sexual, medical, or other private or confidential records or history of an alleged victim of sexual assault, unless directly relevant to the case;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H779892D5EC7141CCAAAAB5CD3E1B1DBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish clearer protections for the privacy of such an alleged victim, including limitations on subsequent disclosures of personal, financial, social, psychological, sexual, medical, or other private or confidential records or history of an alleged victim of sexual assault; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8202D418A78B4B799073C9D71AE2D42F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that discovery practices are consistent with Federal law protecting the rights of such an alleged victim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

