<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73F48955B325484392CBBB2EEA22FCF6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2310 IH: China’s Odious and Brutally Atrocious Labor Trafficking Supply Chain Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2310</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that goods made using or containing cobalt refined in the People’s Republic of China do not enter the United States market under the presumption that the cobalt is extracted or processed with the use of child and forced labor in the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86A88C6871054308800F37DB95C6A772" style="OLC"><section id="H519782C19C7846D7ABAB34404A2E0BB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>China’s Odious and Brutally Atrocious Labor Trafficking Supply Chain Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COBALT Supply Chain Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB18BCD45F8154D468CC74D84FE44EE82"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HFE4943FB0BB1436384B04A2FB338CD65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cobalt is an essential component of lithium-ion batteries, which are predominantly used for electric vehicles, smartphones, and laptops, among other electronic devices. According to the International Energy Agency, the world is expected to see a forty-fold increase in lithium demand and a twenty-fold increase in cobalt demand by 2040, as the demand for electric vehicles is expected to grow significantly during this period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56F58613914A4C07A313ECD404DAD94B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>More than one-half of the world’s cobalt resources are in the DRC, which supplied approximately 70 percent of the global cobalt mine production in 2021. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD99ECBCB853E4B4090C64B90F4A80389"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fifteen of the DRC’s 19 cobalt mines were owned or financed by PRC companies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5894F9C49FE4589A6AF95F7E826265A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firms based in the PRC hold a near monopoly in the DRC’s cobalt sector, according to the Biden Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82777DAD91AD4FCE8079B5E859E85A14"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mining industry in the DRC is beset with child labor and forced labor, disregard for worker safety, and environmental degradation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98A80915D8324BC48EC2E73D3BBCE41F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Approximately 15 to 30 percent of cobalt produced in the DRC comes from artisanal and small-scale mining. An estimated 255,000 miners work in artisanal and small-scale mining in the DRC, of whom at least 40,000 are children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E9A5522DAB84CAEBB658D5988CA0A8E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artisanal production was chiefly exported to the PRC or processed within the DRC by PRC firms, according to an article “China, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and artisanal cobalt mining from 2000 through 2020” published in Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS), a peer-reviewed journal of the National Academy of Sciences (NAS).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C7773DF3ACB48238483A7ED08C424D5"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2024 Trafficking in Persons Report, the Department of State ranked the DRC with a Tier 2 for the second year in a row and emphasized that ‘‘In 2020, the Minister of Human Rights issued a decree increasing oversight of mining communities, including a zero-tolerance policy for forced child labor in the mining sector’’, noting further that ‘‘As part of this effort, the government, in partnership with an NGO, certified mining sites in eastern DRC as conflict-free and child labor-free … However, the government did not report certifying any mines or identifying any potential victims during the reporting period.’’ The government also “did not report providing anti-trafficking training to labor inspectors.”.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60669F8EFB524EE8BB08015060EB0675"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>) states that it is illegal to import into the United States <quote>goods, wares, articles, and merchandise mined, produced, or manufactured wholly or in part</quote> by forced labor, including forced or indentured child labor. Such merchandise is subject to exclusion or seizure and may lead to criminal investigation of the importer. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9E812D32780F42FF95E57BAA764D1441"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="H31B9AABE486B4906A74F2A92B119A644"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that the PRC does not undermine the effective enforcement of section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF2979CA150C4F3797F567505A9DE33F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>lead the international community in ending child labor and forced labor practices wherever such practices occur through all means available to the United States Government, including by prohibiting the importation of goods made with cobalt or containing cobalt extracted from the DRC by companies from the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9908313BBC444B9AEC64620FB3720AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognize that the PRC’s dominance in DRC’s cobalt extraction and the processing and refining of cobalt is a national security concern of the United States that requires a strategy developed jointly by the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67526FA796A049DF96B059A050D0E073"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with Mexico and Canada to effectively implement Article 23.6 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement to prohibit the importation of goods produced in whole or in part by forced labor or compulsory labor, including those goods produced in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR), including the processing of cobalt and goods made with cobalt.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA47F3CF7234E4511963FAF0434ABEF21"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption that covered goods are goods that are made wholly or in part with forced labor or child labor</header><subsection id="HF745CF81CB0C4264BE66014D771C6578"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</text><paragraph id="HAFFA259B876049ECA7EBF9D72F0CE877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall apply a presumption that covered goods are goods that are made wholly or in part with forced labor or child labor; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05D5B423960847379F5BFBB4213F10D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall prohibit the entry of such goods at any of the ports and the United States, and shall otherwise prohibit the importation of such goods, in accordance with section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5F89B8A666745F88F22C98A75B8AC16" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to covered goods if the Commissioner determines that the importer of record of the covered goods has demonstrated by clear and convincing evidence that such goods do not contain cobalt refined in the PRC.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6924828FB72D484D8054152AB2E09A3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>The Commissioner shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make available to the public, not later than 30 days after making a determination to apply the exception under subsection (b) with respect to any covered goods, a report identifying the evidence for such determination.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2BD29CE554F94917BF9275902A176EB2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commissioner may prescribe regulations—</text><paragraph id="H834F6220698B42C3A0EAFFF4481C5FAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to implement subsection (b); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E01A2EBEE6F434F81AD1FC31C265933"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to amend any other regulations in order to implement this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94A811B9D6CF4433A49C9D9F7273C290"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section takes effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0B56D242826041C991FE0FC6B2F3ABFC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the application of regulations in effect on, or measures taken before, the date of the enactment of this Act to prevent the importation of goods mined, produced, or manufactured, wholly or in part, with forced labor into the United States, including withhold release orders issued before such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFCDF50EC94C74FCB8FA845765649C81B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement strategy to address child labor and forced labor relating to covered goods</header><subsection id="H78109A10C00247D99B157B0F6C8A5873"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force, established under section 741 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4681">19 U.S.C. 4681</external-xref>), in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text><paragraph id="HE97595164FFF427C91AAF20C201D5DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contains an enforcement strategy of the United States Government to effectively address enforcement of section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>) to prevent the importation into the United States of covered goods that includes measures that—</text><subparagraph id="H49189FEB65E14A8595CC663B29C3CE66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>can be taken to trace the origin of goods, offer greater supply chain transparency, and identify third country supply chain routes for the covered goods; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9141C9FE22B8427090F92A9757BC8942"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that covered goods do not enter the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B32E6672FA4E938D0B1F0D5A7918C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains a strategy to ensure that covered goods do not enter the United States market as goods imported from third countries, including from Canada or Mexico;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB23FCAFB54A14109852C7AC959AE0533"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contains a strategy to ensure that covered goods denied entry to the United States market do not later enter the United States market through third countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02BAC979560E4E9AA58B14BA796B64AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes authorities to seize or destroy covered goods denied entry to the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD088F0761724797BA1BF43B30B15750"><enum>(5)</enum><text>describes measures to address child labor and forced labor in the mining, production, smelting, or processing of metals or minerals, in particular cobalt and lithium and their derivatives, in the DRC.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64DAA4461F904E698DDA18DD73C48935"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H76DA0D4E427C42E2AB7629C04427FB8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of—</text><subparagraph id="HD58BE90BFB544080909968557CE31D9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>covered goods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5B36B11D79E4A629B554718A6A517BD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities that refine cobalt in the PRC;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94D1530A216D43DFAE38CB08854F387C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities that mine cobalt in the PRC and whether any of these entities operate in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763CB8B0BAD4422E9D7A12EBC9DD5706"><enum>(D)</enum><text>entities that import covered goods in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H869B61B087644529A66B701F8DB8460C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>entities, in the DRC, owned or controlled by PRC entities, or financed by PRC state-owned banks or institutions that mine or process cobalt; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H276E9892C0D44CD2BC1DA229A0665D4E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>priority sectors for enforcement of imports made with covered PRC goods, with a sector-specific enforcement plan for each priority sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A83577DC14D40EEB463C27786F7BED2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations for efforts, initiatives, and tools and technologies to be adopted to ensure that U.S. Customs and Border Protection can accurately identify and trace covered goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F74BA92062B45A7BB59C7F6E59FFAAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the additional resources necessary for U.S. Customs and Border Protection and other Federal entities, including the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force, to effectively implement the strategy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C33C451B8D4C9D947416E38DE7585D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of how the list of entities required by subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of paragraph (1) shall be regularly updated and reported to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06EE3BF82C0C4228901C58DCFBC55618"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A strategy to coordinate and collaborate with appropriate nongovernmental organizations and private sector entities to implement the enforcement strategy for covered goods and to create and update the list of entities required in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H385ADEF4E56045A79BDB8D61CCCF1A26"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) and any publicly published updates described by subsection (d) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex, if necessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB69024D8C32D48AEAC930847F9BBC39A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>After the submission of the strategy required by subsection (a), the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force shall provide briefings to the appropriate congressional committees on a quarterly basis and, as applicable, on any updates to the strategy required by subsection (a) or additional actions taken to address the importation of covered goods, including actions described in this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFDD70E838663416BB41FA6FA1D229172"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have effect on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H54C51809BD4E4B05AF2CADC2442C5A38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 8 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01CD453BCD784B2CB7B2686F735660FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a determination that child labor and forced labor in the mining industry of the DRC has ended, including artisanal and small-scale mining sectors. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCBC43A777EFC416A9FE09D6AED389A45" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Certification that Federal vehicle purchases are free of parts made or mined with child labor or forced labor</header><subsection id="H9A2E75EF721847C2ABB57775F171C7AF" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall certify whether all vehicles purchased in the prior year by the United States Government are completely free of parts made or mined, wholly or in part, with child labor or forced labor in the DRC or the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD409E97EB8D84BCA98C4712B0233017F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The certification required by subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to vehicles purchased in the prior year by the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C734A6907EA43D5912A1884810E4050" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission to Congress; publication in Federal Register</header><text>The President shall—</text><paragraph id="H4EE0F301A14847F7A543148C18B87DC6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit the certification required by subsection (a) to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF9556B82B3474997B31374D91311E5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish such certification in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE3A45E2E1BE48A4AF3FC118598BE5E0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Documentation for certification</header><text>Documentation mapping the supply chains of all the vehicles and their parts, procured in the prior year by the United States Government, shall be available upon request by Members of Congress from the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE72CC0B2F0914FD7B6A6445DDE66CC8D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HAE98AA650A0E444BA0F09219DBCCE395"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H58086920790745F38692CFAA5925227D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9CC9B8623AE4CE4A9916E4F2BF47F53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74F47C13A2554DF394841AB0E1538898"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artisanal and small-scale mining</header><text>The term <term>artisanal and small-scale mining</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H0DE843409CB749E390ABA3CD3DBEF3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means mining with minimal to no mechanization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCBDC4435849462C9E5548CBC29444A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the use of intensive handtools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD8300CB34234C46BD015E20FE59A3AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term “child labor” means work that deprives children of their childhood, their potential, and their dignity, including work that is harmful to the health, safety, and morals of children as such term is commonly used by the International Labour Organization. In this paragraph, the term “children” means individuals who have not obtained the age of 18. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA760A393BB14411C87CA5E0860DA127D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered goods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered goods</term> means goods, wares, articles, or merchandise that contain cobalt refined in the PRC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2973066B064C9F947969A62452175A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>D<enum-in-header>RC</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <term>DRC</term> means the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB459096425A742DF9F338528F99DF0EF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Forced labor</header><text>The term <term>forced labor</term> has the meaning given that term in section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5C94BA3C324B038E1B2E2C9615D0F9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>P<enum-in-header>RC</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <term>PRC</term> means the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

