<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA25213-GK7-HX-9MR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1113 IS: China Financial Threat Mitigation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1113</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a study and prepare a report on the exposure of the United States to the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8FFFA4F7B855497CA2558F210BD12E0A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H91C5C22C1C8B430FA79EF1BCCE288148"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>China Financial Threat Mitigation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0E25858F055243448A36C2BF56540DC6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and report on financial threat mitigation with respect to People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="H23CF4DFFF64F4F5E9F90503F999FD817"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Secretary of State, shall conduct a study and prepare a report on the exposure of the United States to the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China that includes—</text><paragraph id="H5E82292F66F54B4E81BD48EB73D42F24"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the effects of significant risks in the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China on the United States and global financial systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C32228201B949A6916EC1A979D125E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the policies the United States Government is adopting to protect the financial stability of the United States and the global economy from any risks assessed under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2537ABBA894E455FB017753D12C3E08C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and evaluation of the transparency, completeness, and reliability of economic data from the People's Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDC77AF191C0419AAFF7F2719F36C3A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for additional actions the United States Government, including United States representatives at relevant international organizations, should take to strengthen international cooperation to monitor and mitigate financial stability risks from the People's Republic of China and to protect the interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4AC87D956A24335896B7C11165CC362"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transmission of Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transmit the report required under subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8b6a81cfd344defba6a0e03dcd8f907"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5e5d5865cb54a1aa124296693589f44"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf735d4caa05d4c5b953a1b2f07415a4a"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the representatives of the United States at relevant international organizations, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id924f51e6acb447e8919c900c1fa5a265"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classification of report</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be unclassified, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF2A6E157E4D43EF90CD20A3806EA585"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall publish the report required under subsection (a) (other than any classified annex) on the website of the Department of the Treasury.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

