<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25269-F42-RW-RK2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S802 IS: Pay Our Coast Guard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 802</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 14, United States Code, to make appropriations for Coast Guard pay in the event an appropriations Act expires before the enactment of a new appropriations Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HCDC4D64D497B4E96A5C03E20E348F2D9"><section section-type="section-one" id="HDE6985BF40364EF384FB6D92E432E214"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay Our Coast Guard Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2DB01471E58344DDB694D390DD068579"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H49D63FD3F97944429CA695CC5E378E41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Coast Guard is a military service and a branch of the Armed Forces of the United States at all times regardless of whether it operates as a service in the Department of Homeland Security or as a service in the Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C00D12478B24FBC9618124DE0E8E3D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding respective appropriations and except as otherwise provided in law, members of the Coast Guard should receive treatment equitable to that of other members of the Armed Forces with regard to pay and benefits.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7192351AD3BD4D56A3B8BF08821D3298"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coast Guard pay; continuation</header><subsection id="H3D1692C1764F4262AF48579619C41DFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/27">Chapter 27</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H187AD685F50E45BAB58B15C186371E33"><section id="H5D95D05D7F6F42CC9A21076956FC09E7"><enum>2780.</enum><header>Pay; continuation during lapse in appropriations</header><subsection id="H20A6ED9A90A84653B60FF846635DFDD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any period in which there is a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse, there are appropriated such sums as may be necessary—</text><paragraph id="H54FB10ACC40E493C90E8A59768942B40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide pay and allowances to military members of the Coast Guard, including the reserve component thereof, who perform active service or in-active-duty training during such period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C66EF1046EC4747BCCE595902228CED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide pay and benefits to qualified civilian employees of the Coast Guard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7504D936450048819CE033D4ED2EFADA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide pay and benefits to qualified contract employees of the Coast Guard; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE68F150A622149AD9B1FF11BD9C2AE55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide for—</text><subparagraph id="H8F9BD0196F3D4608A06CF14CDC83268D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the payment of a death gratuity under sections 1475 through 1477 and 1489 of title 10, with respect to members of the Coast Guard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H322FE930093C4AE3AD4D19FD3B2F9E6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the payment or reimbursement of authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services under section 481f of title 37, with respect to members of the Coast Guard; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4EA87774B5A42BDABEB32822E7285EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for dependents of members of the Coast Guard dying on active duty, as authorized by section 403(l) of title 37.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A34106CA0024991A46674F6BB12242A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coast Guard-Specific funding lapse</header><text>For purposes of this section, a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse occurs in any case in which—</text><paragraph id="H532C1E10852E41E5B940BA409E05EB95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a general appropriation bill providing appropriations for the Coast Guard for a fiscal year is not enacted before the beginning of such fiscal year (and no joint resolution making continuing appropriations for the Coast Guard is in effect); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B64FC1A5C3A44D3B53D9FD2C3A9C3DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a general appropriation bill providing appropriations for the Department of Defense for such fiscal year is enacted before the beginning of such fiscal year (or a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for the Department of Defense is in effect).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCA39E7019A94206B1A85212D38829A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted for any fiscal year for any purpose under subsection (a) shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text><paragraph id="H5A8460413884482FA0A00C4573DDC7E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CE8ADDBA21546038A0394FD26F36441"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F41F323FD2B4E8DB2C40360A581C611"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The termination of availability of appropriations for the Department of Defense. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5BA18C88ABF4F2AA17836BABD480C9B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rate for operations; applicability to appropriations Acts</header><text>Appropriations made pursuant to this section shall be at a rate for operations and to the extent and manner that would be provided by the pertinent appropriations Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB79021A3AC884486A2A166BD0CF72D46"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Charge to future appropriations</header><text>Expenditures made pursuant to this section shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is enacted into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF2254A2E6BA4E8791C4228EE9E0EAD5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Apportionment</header><text>Appropriations and funds made available by or authority granted under this section may be used without regard to the time limitations for submission and approval of apportionments set forth in section 1513 of title 31, but nothing in this section may be construed to waive any other provision of law governing the apportionment of funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC6917328E1049D3B659B6AAB5C9EA2A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4078B46C6E534C98B09DE8E57E2481C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified civilian employee</header><text>The term <quote>qualified civilian employee</quote> means a civilian employee of the Coast Guard who the Commandant determines is—</text><subparagraph id="H5A4CD89DFEC84C759DA341F35542569D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing support to members of the Coast Guard or another Armed Force; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9203EC7AAD1C4B6CB0C4C2D0C4406500"><enum>(B)</enum><text>performing work as an excepted employee or an employee performing emergency work, as such terms are defined by the Office of Personnel Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D799519CCD943C1A08511FF417464A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified contract employee of the Coast Guard</header><text>The term <quote>qualified contract employee of the Coast Guard</quote> means an individual performing work under a contract who the Commandant determines is—</text><subparagraph id="H5B9AABED21004024B56E25CCE2516F37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing support to military members or qualified civilian employees of the Coast Guard or another Armed Force; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EE9418830F54F08A19D31B84C2F2BE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>required to perform work during a lapse in appropriations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEB076CD81EC64EEBA8475608359F759D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/27">chapter 27</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC26EE197D839463DBF72BA756D77F74B"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2780. Pay; continuation during lapse in appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

