<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H68F4A932BA6B40E48739B225443F1C0F" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1326 : DOE and USDA Interagency Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1326</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for Department of Energy and Department of Agriculture joint research and development activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C92EC96DD974447AE1D3A655B14CFD3" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H607DBB945CFD4370AA4723FF18F7E390" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOE and USDA Interagency Research Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H4CD9488CA8F5445B9534525D957E5F5D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Energy and Department of Agriculture joint research and development activities</header><subsection id="HE7FDEFCEB5DB4A559E4694B6053BFACF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretaries</quote>) shall carry out cross-cutting and collaborative research and development activities focused on the joint advancement of Department of Energy and Department of Agriculture mission requirements and priorities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE87F90899D9B4A82BAB2EA1C4CD3636B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The Secretaries shall carry out and coordinate the activities under subsection (a) through the establishment of a memorandum of understanding, or other appropriate interagency agreement. Such memorandum or agreement shall require the use of a competitive, merit-reviewed process, which considers applications from Federal agencies, National Laboratories, institutions of higher education, nonprofit institutions, and other appropriate entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC4847DEE53943E5BABB4FEF5C063F02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Secretaries may carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="H965F15D56EEE4A008E99994E7368D6BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conduct collaborative research over a variety of focus areas, such as the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0D9B6C23B11E42A3BB54433733B690DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Modeling and simulation, machine learning, artificial intelligence, data assimilation, large scale data analytics, and predictive analysis in order to optimize algorithms for purposes related to agriculture and energy, such as life cycle analysis of agricultural or energy systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC573AD9CFAE94FB2BCC3055DF3B45E75"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fundamental agricultural, biological, computational, and environmental science and engineering, including advanced crop science, crop protection, breeding, and biological pest control, in collaboration with the program authorized under section 306 of the Department of Energy Research and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18644">42 U.S.C. 18644</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C0F05507807477FAD5EA1B3CBB6B127" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Integrated natural resources and the energy-water nexus, including in collaboration with the program authorized under section 1010 of the Energy Act of 2020 (enacted as division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16183">42 U.S.C. 16183</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57680843C1E74DB09C909125AB0C4CD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Advanced biomass, biobased products, and biofuels, including in collaboration with the activities authorized under section 9008(b) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8108">7 U.S.C. 8108(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A1D5DDEE349474EAF6969FF8AE43046"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Diverse feedstocks for economically and environmentally sustainable fuels, including aviation and naval fuels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC67564C147684D04923AE853B1D4A3F8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Colocation of agricultural resources and activities and ecosystem services with diverse energy technologies and resources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEA1FBD20F5A494394AD1D2E94BA0F5A" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Colocation of agricultural resources and activities with carbon storage and utilization technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67A70648FFA84FB7AD57FAF98EE10CB0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Invasive species management to further the work done by the Federal Interagency Committee for the Management of Noxious and Exotic Weeds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD86303A69C9D41E1B6C6728131489006"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Long-term and high-risk technological barriers in the development of transformative science and technology solutions in the agriculture and energy sectors, including in collaboration with the program authorized under section 5012 of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16538">42 U.S.C. 16538</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91A2E90FCF7B4870B3EFD8990C9EDD9C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Grid modernization and grid security. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9672CFAF91474B73AE3B9722B29B25EE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Rural technology development, including manufacturing, precision agriculture technologies, and mechanization and automation technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B459D7C758546F2BAB8326F6A8DDD1C"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wildfire risks and prevention, including the power sector’s role in fire prevention and mitigation and wildfire impacts on energy infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H306D4B11D5264565B279879BB57F48A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop methods to accommodate large voluntary standardized and integrated data sets on agricultural, environmental, supply chain, and economic information with variable accuracy and scale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H656564521D5341F6BDB5932704B051C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Promote collaboration, open community-based development, and data and information sharing between Federal agencies, National Laboratories, institutions of higher education, nonprofit institutions, industry partners, and other appropriate entities by providing reliable access to secure data and information that are in compliance with Federal rules and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85BD3328B5B04508A928410C0E37380C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support research infrastructure and workforce development as the Secretaries determine necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63A23AAD4A54438790B0C097B017A85D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conduct collaborative research, development, and demonstration of methods and technologies to accomplish the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFDFD314ABF8E485B86C0A4C4D54F7288"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Improve the efficiency of agriculture operations and processing of agricultural products.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H657F862D70E74DA688452586CFF0B882"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reduce greenhouse gas emissions associated with such operations and such processing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B92B7E8CF3F4F46AB6D03E861456541"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Secretaries are authorized to—</text><paragraph id="HF9EA0BB07C9F4604B68BABE455368F0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out reimbursable agreements between the Department of Energy, the Department of Agriculture, and other entities in order to maximize the effectiveness of research and development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D7D03E7F5734C95A42EB5B582E64550"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with other Federal agencies as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BDFE395168F47F89FC735F8F3301831"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, a report detailing the following:</text><paragraph id="H8C9702A1AE4A4862A410CB035BC0F22E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Interagency coordination between each Federal agency involved in the research and development activities carried out under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49893F3EDDF34A58B457E4769A7E75D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Potential opportunities to expand the technical capabilities of the Department of Energy and the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9D6900208BB4257A722EA054F42423A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Collaborative research achievements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE80AFAD5CC0458DBBE27291C0A31720"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Areas of future mutually beneficial successes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13AF9A4BA1324D96BA9C7455D6E7BAA4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Continuation of coordination activities between the Department of Energy and the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DBEC548CA4A43E38957689AD8F213BF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities authorized under this section shall be applied in a manner consistent with subtitle D of title VI of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19231">42 U.S.C. 19231 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250324" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 24, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

