<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25022-5TX-9D-TRJ">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2618 IS: More Opportunities for Rural Economies from USDA Grants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2618</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr.
                    Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and
                Forestry</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To improve the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the
            Department of Agriculture to certain counties in which the majority of land is owned or
            managed by the Federal Government and to other units of local government and Tribal
            governments in those counties, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>More Opportunities for Rural Economies from USDA Grants Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MORE USDA Grants Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idC3F81103AB8B499B90D2167BDD57B249">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id767DC3C3F5C84F0988520558889882AD"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>High-Density Public Land County</header> <text>The term <term>High-Density Public Land County</term> means a county (or equivalent jurisdiction) of a State or territory of the United States—</text>
                <subparagraph id="idFCF616312463467A9C7F12A063B96D6C">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that has a population of not more than 100,000 people, according to the most recent annual estimates of population by the Bureau of the Census; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id92C855B8B6B7471082F03CEDD2E33715">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in which more than 50 percent of the land is owned or managed by the Federal Government.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idDC97B1DA574E41289D514D69ED23DEE0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Qualifying grant program</header>
 <text>The term <term>qualifying grant program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idA8E8B3E45A2040408EF17002D1E3C861"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the Rural Business Development grant program established under section 310B(c) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1932">7 U.S.C. 1932(c)</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idE593AE19920D421FA3C158A25E1836BA">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the community facilities grant program established under section 306(a)(19) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926">7 U.S.C. 1926(a)(19)</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id7430F5FCEA5A47F0AE07E763684F4AEC">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the Economic Impact Initiative grant program established under section 306(a)(20)(B) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926">7 U.S.C. 1926(a)(20)(B)</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id38B758DF8D2B4BF48F5C18A466742A19">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Telemedicine and Distance Learning Services grant program established under chapter 1 of subtitle D of title XXIII of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950aaa">7 U.S.C. 950aaa et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idF189BE1988CD47DD96335FED5847775F">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Community Connect Grant Program established under section 604 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950bb-3">7 U.S.C. 950bb–3</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idB03606CE9E0C4B01BF6808DF9BF7B3E5">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>the broadband loan and grant pilot program known as the <quote>Rural eConnectivity Pilot Program</quote> or the <quote>ReConnect Program</quote>, authorized under section 779 of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 399);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id039A4397C15C4907A6A362D61324F184">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>any discretionary grant program of the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, the Rural Housing Service, the Rural Utilities Service, or any other rural development agency of the Department of Agriculture under which grants are awarded to—</text>
                    <clause id="id3DA0DE4B867943298F4C276CEF22ADEB">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>counties;</text> </clause> <clause id="idC0682AD7F81C460CA08EB42362667606"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>other units of local government; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15E84741507A49719514422F4B74A8A5">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Tribal governments; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idE65753A722F24211A8386A6AC7803FE0"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>any other discretionary grant program of the Department of Agriculture under which grants for rural development or energy are awarded to—</text>
                    <clause id="id2775BB34BCE644E4B9268B4896BC62DC">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>counties;</text> </clause> <clause id="id3460157BA25B49299B48574872FA4742"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>other units of local government; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="idBFA1EE68DD7A4E7280D4714208C16FB9">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Tribal governments.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id5618BA09709847628B76FD3015C26A6B"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Secretary</header> <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="idA7D22167709E4C5C8691665577664221">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Tribal government</header>
 <text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id8D1F63AFAC214262A0EC78FFC4431DD5">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Grants</header>
            <subsection id="id2788B37EF9FB4E78B024570EEBF89773">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Reduction in local matching requirements</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to a High-Density Public Land County and any unit of local government or Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County, any requirement for local matching funds under a qualifying grant program shall be reduced by 50 percent.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1EED0A709723485CB7D10A596E92973B">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Technical assistance</header>
 <text>On request of a High-Density Public Land County or any unit of local government or Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County, the Secretary shall provide additional technical assistance to the High-Density Public Land County, unit of local government, or Tribal government before and during the annual application period for each qualifying grant program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7CAEB5A0A1634D34A827EE0BF6113387">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Priority</header>
                <paragraph id="idC9C30B73C122448AB8BC3B84416FB91C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Application approval</header>
 <text>In approving applications for a qualifying grant program, the Secretary shall give priority to an application from a High-Density Public Land County, unit of local government within a High-Density Public Land County, or Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County that has not received support under the qualifying grant program during the 10-year period preceding the date of the application.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id2B7D2E96E7D54909B1F61F63971510C8">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Technical assistance and other support</header>
 <text>In carrying out subsections (b) and (d), the Secretary may give priority to a Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id4963B6573020443B9111AD43218C4808">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Other support</header>
 <text>The Secretary may provide additional support, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, for a High-Density Public Land County or a unit of local government or Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County, including by considering and, if appropriate, offering flexibility with respect to any requirement of, or barrier to applying for or receiving assistance under, a qualifying grant program if the requirement or barrier relates to—</text>
                <paragraph id="id34FAFA3DD4804B44AD0B014F4BE3C44F">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>scoring criteria relating to numerical size and impact, such as the number of jobs created or the number of people served, which disadvantage small and isolated communities;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idD7C3B04C904C42EAABF3E9443B0FC427">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>any requirement that an applicant for a qualifying grant program partner with other institutions, such as community colleges or foundations, which may not operate in the jurisdiction of the High-Density Public Land County, unit of local government, or Tribal government seeking assistance under the qualifying grant program;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida7059ecf08fe4d0a88b6274e359ad29c">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>any financial or cash-on-hand requirement that a High-Density Public Land County or a unit of local government or Tribal government within a High-Density Public Land County cannot meet for reasons other than any financial constraints to which the High-Density Public Land County, unit of local government, or Tribal government is subject; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id656CE9A699EE4E1FA8AC86FF3B9E77A3">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>an overly complicated or overly technical application for a qualifying grant program that deters High-Density Public Land Counties or units of local government or Tribal governments within High-Density Public Land Counties from applying for the qualifying grant program.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

