<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HF0886061524D410CB7EBBFE7E48B173B"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3403 IH: Supporting Equal Access to Tables Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit third-party restaurant reservation services from offering or arranging unauthorized reservations for food service establishments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA5370053DDF499B8E63DAC0A1E2C4EF"><section id="H0DDB01EFD6694302873065740536AD44" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Equal Access to Tables Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SEAT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4188693E7F5A48FE80EF3F3CA58C288B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on third-party restaurant reservation services</header><subsection id="H4308D879810144CA9CCDF0316A4E64AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A provider of a third-party restaurant reservation service may only list, promote, sell, or otherwise advertise or make available a reservation for a food service establishment if there is a written agreement between such service and such establishment, or a contractual designee of such establishment who obtained reservation distribution rights directly from the establishment, that permits such service to list, promote, sell, or otherwise advertise or make available such reservation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C5653F997E24C3DA8CBE270266BEB25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by commission</header><paragraph id="H7CF45D33D7154762B048DBF412C58D9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A9A272248F24122806592D4210875F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4148D44833A34B00944A6050B78F48DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to a provider of a third-party restaurant reservation service beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA5A8216B3C914A2092F3D8412993F8F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Indemnification provisions</header><text>An agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a) may not include a provision that requires a food service establishment to indemnify a third-party restaurant reservation service, any independent contractor acting on behalf of such third-party restaurant reservation service, or any registered agent of such third-party restaurant reservation service for any damages or harm by an act or omission initiated by the third-party restaurant reservation service. If an agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a) contains such a provision, such provision shall be deemed void and unenforceable.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD74704A63693414A81DBA09363361003"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H49F1CA28D79F4BDBA8FEA492B150CD87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C8BF235374047F0A0D9C097DF191EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Food service establishment</header><text>The term <quote>food service establishment</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HB2308515C2E8498183769A8FC8324059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a restaurant, food stand, food truck, food cart, saloon, inn, tavern, bar, lounge, brewpub, tasting room, taproom, licensed facility or premise of a beverage alcohol producer where the public may taste, sample, or purchase products, or other similar place of business in or at which the public or patrons assemble for the primary purpose of being served food or drink; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H539F71F298814A76B339342542EC6390"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an entity described in subparagraph (A) that is located in a larger establishment or complex, including an airport terminal or other transportation facility, amusement park, sports stadium, entertainment venue, hotel or hotel complex, or retail store or retail complex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6BBD8512379422EB59A948F530F2778"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Third-party restaurant reservation service</header><text>The term <quote>third-party restaurant reservation service</quote> means any website, mobile application, or other internet-based service that—</text><subparagraph id="HA29AD0AEFF1C426DB149D14CD7E8C44B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lists, promotes, sells, or otherwise advertises or makes available reservations for on-premises service for a customer at a food service establishment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74CA4D38135042D7B5A8E21CABFE24D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is provided by a person other than the person who provides such food service establishment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

