<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9B2243B7D504EF08FE4BFBFBF855B5B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 256 IH: Supporting the designation of March 2025 as Endometriosis Awareness Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 256</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of March 2025 as Endometriosis Awareness Month.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas endometriosis is a disease in which the type of tissue that normally grows in the uterus (the endometrium) also grows outside of the uterus;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas endometriosis is one of the most common gynecological diseases in women, and occurs in 1 in 10 women of reproductive age;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the cause of endometriosis is not known, but risk factors include—</text><paragraph id="H9084D79DEE00410B833D27D4D7DAD92D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">having a mother, sister, or daughter with endometriosis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5198522700D743B9A61EF7BE4ECE27A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>menstrual cycles that started at an early age;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE82DC51B9A12462EA8FDC2BCF7F9D52E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>menstrual cycles that are short; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B41FB3AA4BD48A38C0B740708F68A93"><enum>(4)</enum><text>periods that are heavy and last more than 7 days;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for many women, the only way currently available to be certain of an endometriosis diagnosis is to have a surgical procedure known as a laparoscopy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women experience a delay from three to eleven years between the first symptoms of pain and the final endometriosis diagnosis, which can lead to lower quality of life and high medical costs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for many girls and women, endometriosis is a lifelong chronic disease that can affect relationships, school, work, fertility, and daily life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the primary symptoms of endometriosis include pain and infertility, and many with endometriosis live with debilitating, chronic pain;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, approximately 75 percent of women with endometriosis experience a misdiagnosis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the management of symptoms of endometriosis may include surgery, gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) antagonists, and many other medical treatments;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas endometriosis is associated with increased health care costs and poses a substantial burden to patients in the health care system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, the estimated average direct health care cost associated with endometriosis per patient is more than $13,000 per year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 40 percent of women with endometriosis report impaired career growth due to endometriosis, and approximately 50 percent of women with endometriosis experience a decreased ability to work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention found that the average number of <quote>bed days</quote> for patients with endometriosis was 18 days per year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women with endometriosis can lose 11 hours per workweek through lost productivity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the physical and psychological impact of endometriosis affects all domains of life, including social life, relationships, and work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas medical societies and patient groups have expressed the need for greater public attention and updated resources targeted to public education about this unmet health need for women;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a need for more research and updated guidelines to treat endometriosis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is an ongoing need for additional clinical research and treatment options to manage this debilitating disease; and </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is no known cure for endometriosis: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA716B494A3514744BCB2C9933D3C6D26"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6A601FE7C01E4ED2952011A50FB9F9FF"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H76C456ADDD4F4029AAF22BC275B8B12C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strongly supports the goals and ideals of Endometriosis Awareness Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0110DC69170E4E7AA7411CDCB885FB0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the need for early detection and treatment of endometriosis, increased education for health care providers, and more culturally competent care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B1E89DCD29B461BB30FEE6399D3E75F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>remains committed to supporting and funding endometriosis research for more effective treatments, increasing fertility, and, ultimately, a cure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H501CB1CFE5B6487F837BC52B55D4CEB8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate awareness and educational activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

