<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25J21-XRR-R6-JDX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2950 IS: Scam Compound Accountability and Mobilization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2950</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State and relevant executive branch agencies to address international scam compounds defrauding people in the United States, to hold significant transnational criminal organizations accountable, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Scam Compound Accountability and Mobilization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id758b823eee394193ae5439d52772c543"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id0e0194a16cd343369223a687cfa98484"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transnational cyber-enabled fraud, particularly perpetrated from scam compounds in Southeast Asia, is a growing threat to citizens of the United States, national security, and economic interests globally, with the Federal Bureau of Investigation reporting $13,700,000,000 in losses in the United States due to cyber-enabled fraud in 2024, including schemes commonly perpetrated by significant transnational criminal organizations operating scam compounds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb99282a061d4985917568b9d4f4d00e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>significant transnational criminal organizations responsible for a large proportion of these scam compounds are affiliated with the People’s Republic of China (PRC), actively spread PRC propaganda, promote unification with Taiwan, and have brokered projects for the Belt and Road Initiative;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d47b102640d4333add557c1b556cc4d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>significant transnational criminal organizations have lured hundreds of thousands of human trafficking victims from over 40 countries to scam compounds, primarily in Burma, Cambodia, and Laos, for purposes of forced criminality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaee58ac767f04823958c9fc9b8f1cd35"><enum>(4)</enum><text>significant transnational criminal organizations are expanding scam compounds internationally including in Africa, the Middle East, South Asia, and the Pacific Islands, and related money laundering, human trafficking and recruitment fraud have occurred in Europe, North America, and South America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd6131bb43ad428eb556c6cca6282c48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States should redouble efforts to hold the perpetrators and enablers of scam compound operations accountable, including those involved in related money laundering, human trafficking, and recruitment fraud, by employing tools, such as targeted financial sanctions, visa restrictions, asset seizures, and forfeiture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d077a1831cd4a57a537c701a0b78dee"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to effectively address cyber-enabled fraud originating from scam compounds internationally, the United States Government should work with partner governments, multilateral institutions, civil society experts, and private sector stakeholders to improve information sharing, strengthen preventative measures, raise public awareness, and increase coordination on law enforcement investigations and regulatory actions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd01ee7699db2434f83ea8da27cdc1b68"><enum>(7)</enum><text>survivors of human trafficking, including forced criminality, require victim-centered support to ensure they are not punished for offenses committed under duress.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ideacc5819e3044a17a262748691d9b124"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ff69c1a3ddf4658959d248ed1240c12"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id7b764a0b91a04cb4aa0ee6f6c88a2c83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd42fbeffc202448b97fa83a7ff783120"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb66e01d57d44b7ba20222e2854958bc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a3b7001434f411e948a3f473d2a2dd1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id946089d924a641d7be5cfc3a0a72080c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide9180266701f49cdb8f600ac1fc529b6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59d0c50c2c9246d985980a0bd5c4e944"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd72c1914d02a4b63a0ad312c1ec4283b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e1cbbd542dc4d46a2cfa14aa2adcc91"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b3ebd4f0a174c1ea91cca8993104433"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cyber-enabled fraud</header><text>The term <term>cyber-enabled fraud</term> means the use of the internet or other technology to commit fraudulent activity, including illicitly obtaining money, property, data, identification documents, or authentication features, or creating counterfeit goods or services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb18f9d4b66334c819ceab47a5b064b25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enabling country</header><text>The term <term>enabling country</term> means a country where—</text><subparagraph id="id15a4df2960f347ca8065c4d2ba1a2433"><enum>(A)</enum><text>government authorities actively or implicitly permit, enable, or perpetuate scam compound operations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ed0e284b94f4b12b583003ea16dc224" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineffective law enforcement or a failure to enact legislation intended to prevent facilitating services from reaching scam compounds or significant transnational criminal organizations enables scam compound operators to obtain facilitating services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd03b95e0106b44b98dcae3d52968e1bb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Forced criminality</header><text>The term <term>forced criminality</term> means a form of forced labor for the purpose of causing the victim to engage in criminal activity, which may include cyber-enabled fraud.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbf63dbbce18464394d70efa7539b64e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Forced labor</header><text>The term <term>forced labor</term> has the meaning given the term severe form of trafficking in persons in section 103(11)(B) of the <short-title>Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bc2d81320b54329b802965c2e542d39"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relevant foreign assistance programs and diplomatic efforts</header><text>The term <term>relevant foreign assistance programs and diplomatic efforts</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id352d0a1a4aa448038c679eae633aa4e8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means unclassified voluntary support programs funded directly by the United States Government that provide assistance to one or more foreign countries for the purpose of combating scam compound operations and related significant transnational criminal organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id292094d7091a480390d689e19723a23c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes intelligence activities, including activities authorized by the President and reported to Congress in accordance with section 503 of the <short-title>National Security Act of 1947</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3093">50 U.S.C. 3093</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaec6f7d3c2cf412f978170b5a759107b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Human trafficking</header><text>The term <term>human trafficking</term> has the meaning given the term severe form of trafficking in persons in section 103(11) of the <short-title>Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida58eb9cabd444230ac530f584499b2ec"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Human trafficking victim</header><text>The terms <term>human trafficking victim</term> and <term>victim of human trafficking</term> mean a person subject to an act or practice described in section 103(11) of the <short-title>Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b4319c8834b4909bbd77b64a415225d"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Impacted country</header><text>The term <term>impacted country</term> means a country that is a significant—</text><subparagraph id="idfe100edff4f84382a7016a5bea3c25f4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transit location for victims of human trafficking to scam compounds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id471b51fa3fce46e980b9fcac1b3a3f12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>source location for victims of human trafficking for scam compounds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93dc1057dac24ba3be641daba98fd3fb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>target of cyber-enabled fraud originating from scam compounds internationally.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a8334e89c724d44b18d58adda6ccd34"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Scam compound</header><text>The term <term>scam compound</term> means a physical installation where a significant transnational criminal organization carries out cyber-enabled fraud operations, frequently using victims of human trafficking and forced criminality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id747d506c7e0049a790897092b455a589"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Significant transnational criminal organization</header><text>The term <term>significant transnational criminal organization</term> means a group of persons that—</text><subparagraph id="idbef3d86a349642738a8eb2ca01ddce48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes one or more foreign person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07594d074d9a43dbb81582362a0d3e2e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engages in or facilitates an ongoing pattern of serious criminal activity involving the jurisdictions of at least two foreign states or one foreign state and the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a3954b6fd214408824c0af1f2d574cc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>threatens the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id03398a6f5d0e4f6b9120dab46773465f"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <term>Strategy</term> means the strategy to counter scam compounds and hold significant transnational criminal organizations accountable required under section 4.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id444b735ed3584e06ac14cbfc384112e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The definitions under this section are exclusive to this Act and may not be construed to affect any other provision of United States law.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6a5d0bd6c6744e3892128d1ca1b8ec9e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to counter scam compounds and hold significant transnational criminal organizations accountable</header><subsection id="idfa2ad75b8660487cac868839472e5bc5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74e1ecbb0ac24ec99b7eb50cb3f5b5ec"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed to counter scam compounds and hold significant transnational criminal organizations accountable;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b48a2345d444b7ab4d2b8b7af658ee4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is global in scope; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96ad368c410f4638b5c653263d99b84e"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may prioritize efforts focused on Southeast Asian countries where scam compound operations are most prevalent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id81ced7eecd164591855bf9d1bf12406b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Strategy shall—</text><paragraph id="ida090378a87b9487aa2ea3ef6e4d8ccdf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>articulate a comprehensive problem statement identifying the structural vulnerabilities exploited by significant transnational criminal organizations operating scam compounds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47c1ba3a62a24f71b1fdec58a2bfd80d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a comprehensive list of enabling countries and impacted countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide13ab79ac0644dfd834322fefcaf677c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify all active executive branch relevant foreign assistance programs and diplomatic efforts underway to address scam compounds, significant transnational criminal organizations connected to scam compounds, and related money laundering, human trafficking and forced criminality, including efforts with enabling countries and impacted countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id502a2920dc6f4582b7250498c5efb1db"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify relevant foreign assistance resources needed to fully implement the Strategy and any obstacles to the response of the Federal Government to scam compounds, including coordination with partner governments, to address the human trafficking, including forced criminality, and money laundering that facilitates and sustains scam compound operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e1a408fb7a148fab641794bcb1213c3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include objectives, activities, and performance indicators regarding the response of the Federal Government to scam compounds, including—</text><subparagraph id="id82d640ef0f404be98845ba4a9b1fae72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prevention of recruitment fraud and human trafficking, including by—</text><clause id="id8034dbdc4c2f41f8847ce0b481bad6c8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engaging private sector entities operating internet platforms or other services that can be abused or exploited to perpetrate recruitment fraud, human trafficking or cyber-enabled fraud;</text></clause><clause id="id09b4cd5935d94edba640d3adf397422c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>raising awareness among at-risk populations to identify common recruitment fraud strategies and improve due diligence and self-protection measures;</text></clause><clause id="id1574eb70fd7b473390367caaf95dc752"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>urging governments to monitor and enforce laws against fraudulent and unlawful recruitment practices; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id214ed0ce802345c48a2e99a883756bca"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sharing information and building awareness among foreign counterparts, including law enforcement and border officials, to identify potential human trafficking victims;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f21e8e8b7ba4e1d8c1b66fa631bd900"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the support for survivors of human trafficking and forced criminality under the direction of the Ambassador at Large to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd13a3d1b64ec43cfa3de74cce176b41b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the enhancement of coordination and strengthening the capabilities of partner governments and law enforcement agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47e100c985434dc08f4ee723cae9f4c1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the use of sanctions, visa restrictions, and other accountability measures against enabling countries, significant transnational criminal organizations, and related third-party facilitators of scam compound operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd06180cdde1041f096474a860de40bf5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the support of partner governments in countering corruption and money laundering related to scam compound operations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7836ddf1099436dbda36d1893a58864"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the investigation of PRC connections to significant transnational criminal organizations operating scam compounds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3ac357a94c74f16972851f015fe4506"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in the Strategy may affect, apply to, or create obligations related to past, present, or future criminal or civil law enforcement or intelligence activities of the United States or the law enforcement activities of any State or subdivision of a State.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide54d1a8b11004a4d83cdb3a46e23f792"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishing a task force to implement the strategy</header><subsection id="id0cb83af311af4e718f5e28931fcc5d61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after submitting the Strategy pursuant to section 4(a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, shall establish an interagency task force (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>)—</text><paragraph id="id8f893d0e1a274e4799d9b86f12ca655e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to coordinate the implementation of the Strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c7c25499c94475ca9e9cd695faf3391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conduct regular monitoring and analysis of scam compound operations internationally;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46b6391089f74e478affc4ae2061f918"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to track and evaluate progress toward the objectives, activities, and performance indicators of the Strategy described in section 4(b)(5); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad1e373323b94f05bfa8ec09dba44c6a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to update the Strategy, in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, as needed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id90d5843c959742849e5d28ea4bfa45da"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual reviews and reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the establishment of the Task Force, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, shall—</text><paragraph id="id34e10e53f3a24550aaa50287dd19d5b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a status review of the Strategy and the overall state of scam compounds operated by significant transnational criminal organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id013dcde92bcc41eb92d53de7060ea9fb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a list of enabling countries and impacted countries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id764c2505c8fd4ad8b641d1573967521f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit the results of such review in a public report to the appropriate congressional committees, which may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc068cadfa90f4fa986e6ce2dc5421ddf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Task force termination</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is six years after the date on which it is established.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0c66df7d1e084ed9a12fe60c8f114a88"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strengthening tools to dismantle scam compounds and hold significant transnational criminal organizations accountable</header><subsection id="id290c1b12b9744a47ad258e57e905003d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to significant actors in scam compound operations</header><text>Beginning on and after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines—</text><paragraph id="id4bb73a59b6c9499ea7bb51d8a8883d5b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has materially assisted in, or provided significant financial or technological support to, or provided significant goods or services in support of, the activities of international scam compounds or enabling services, including recruitment fraud, human trafficking (including forced criminality), cyber-enabled fraud, or money laundering; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77299ccdac3b46b0a83c66b53b40848a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>owned, controlled, directed, or acted for, or on behalf of, a significant scam compound operation or enabling service, including recruitment fraud, human trafficking (including forced criminality), cyber-enabled fraud, or money laundering.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbdaae505b8bc43bfb5c7ff5e8f87008e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The President may exercise of all powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (a), including, to the extent appropriate, the vessel of which the person is the beneficial owner, if such property or interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfa98f5b5c63543fb8c3bacd6e364eedb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb87ab9398b7644e681008b763179a1d3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc576f01deaa34d09a7c58206beed1094"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to any person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any prohibition of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under this section, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddea5036bbd06472997a38c628e1b8502"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Intelligence and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions authorized under this section shall not apply with respect to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94537e4dd2a945268c9105b2533e6610"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7b81a781c774fe6ab82b27e07d9cf81"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5bb0999787da480b95f45b5edbeae917"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Semiannual report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph id="id95ce5d2f08234b30ac581674ef4980b2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies all foreign persons the President has sanctioned pursuant to the authorities under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88ad7dffc6f94d2cafd265d523063e6d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dates on which sanctions were imposed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddf33c518543b4296a9d68baaf3342432" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd25a4392648142f99cddc729b6b0cbd0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A requirement to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property pursuant to subsection (b) shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5927d2f7dc9f449ca0c1668b9644819a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8cf6cddfde42493d8da6978c7dc25a45"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="idbea4320a103c40d3811faf8e7143a757"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person or a foreign financial institution if the President determines that such waiver is in the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida29be6b992104a88836038c838f1f67a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 days before granting a waiver pursuant to paragraph (1), the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id7fc05882958148488a2d9f4fc027034b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the individual or institution that is benefitting from such waiver; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bbf7da9d75f402596151a26f1b02a6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the beneficiary is an individual, a detailed justification explaining how the waiver serves the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idda127e70bc914efd82cc5d0015c95888"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

