<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25272-06V-VG-DX7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1149 IS: SEC Whistleblower Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1149</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to further enhance anti-retaliation protections for whistleblowers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SEC Whistleblower Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF2143279CC6A4A54877A9B6802F16772"><enum>2.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections for internal disclosures</header><subsection id="id768661CDCC3143629E98C9734163D666"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21F of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H75BF0E4D49044E73B6EB14534ED3B822"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(6)—</text><subparagraph id="idA7ACE91788654ADB96A5DE6363FD44A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The term</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAC806DAC752E4B83B910FD8037B7D2FC"><subparagraph id="id0456EAB7E1FB4BDE94B0F17A0179136A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C3F6325AE0A4C2A8A209B8437FA3317"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id240111B1E21846ADB71BA46AB8ECDE37"><subparagraph id="id9352A2A49CFD4CFA99EC466E861FA008"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely for the purposes of subsection (h)(1), the term <term>whistleblower</term> includes any individual who takes, or 2 or more individuals acting jointly who take, an action described in subsection (h)(1)(A), that the individual or 2 or more individuals reasonably believe relates to a violation of any law, rule, or regulation subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board, the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board, or a self-regulatory organization.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id92D811CD3C1C4CAEB2797256E6B295EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="id7C7ADA849CD74A6C9F4AE3850A68E717"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="idEDC93CE706A549E5894351D7BCB9FF21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>or post-employment</quote> after <quote>of employment</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="id29A480A124274DDBB83DB9EBE5E49EE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>, in writing or orally if the oral report is documented,</quote> after <quote>to the Commission</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="id13056B6B79A64C7B97D4E3C0B5A605D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="id27A5F0F7C88548B7B588B02A209DAF59"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id0634B94E2AEB44FEB91DD3EA5715634E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id226F940DB25849EBA7892351495D5247"><clause id="id2350FEEB161E4930BDBE41ED9EFEA274"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in providing information regarding any conduct that the whistleblower reasonably believes constitutes a violation of any law, rule, or regulation subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission to—</text><subclause id="id0AD1093AF7ED445EBE445568DDAF2678"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a person with supervisory authority over the whistleblower at the employer of the whistleblower, if that employer is an entity registered with, or required to be registered with, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Commission, the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board, a self-regulatory organization, or a State securities commission or office performing like functions; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idA76803F7ABA34A36870A80D55F9979F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>another individual working for the employer described in subclause (I) who the whistleblower reasonably believes has the authority to—</text><item id="id69612329A7BD4C9B9F5AEC963ED13925"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>investigate, discover, or terminate the misconduct; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0A42DD127DBA47C18FE254F4AA12B60D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>take any other action to address the misconduct.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id929BC76741354D69AFC4514DA417BE84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idE919E876F8DA404D83565BB745A34005" act-name=""><clause id="idDF532811876D418BB0B5F767C47EEFDE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Jury trial</header><text>A person against which an action is brought under this subsection shall be entitled to a jury trial.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ADC90F8DC1B4286AD69C12949CA4B9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to any claim involving a violation of section 21F(h)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6(h)(1)</external-xref>), including a claim in an enforcement action or proceeding brought by the Securities and Exchange Commission, that is—</text><paragraph id="id5601B4B928134A83B98BF2556000F74E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pending in any appropriate judicial or administrative forum, as of the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8EF09EA412A743E78D2A99AF63B86CF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>filed after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id21DA503D05F041869EE7367FE5CB11B0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prompt payment of awards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21F(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" act-name="" id="id2D53FBC0855B48CE9B5FD95D2955D0D2"><paragraph id="id7CDFED9616B441CDBD9229FE18C3BA98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timely processing of claims</header><subparagraph id="id3E51AC74A7364C34BFD363F1F1375AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial disposition</header><clause id="id062FD925087D41618DBFB07E3372547E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Commission shall make an initial disposition with respect to a claim submitted by a whistleblower for an award under this section (referred to in this paragraph as an <quote>award claim</quote>) not later than the later of—</text><subclause id="id8388D08771514492A28A92CBAC4AE9C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the deadline established by the Commission, by rule, for the whistleblower to file the award claim; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idADE7A692EDD04AD3B1C86CB2E221579C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the final resolution of all litigation, including any appeals, concerning the covered action or related action. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6B0C26AC65024FE9AABA8FA73D27AC8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Multiple actions</header><text>If an award claim involves 1 or more related actions, the requirement under clause (i) shall apply with respect to the latest deadline with respect to the actions.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F7E947D3B7C42ABBF9188120BC4CBA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><clause id="idFC474A0C6DEE45F692088E8836689B7F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial extension</header><text>If the Director of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Director</quote>), or the designee of the Director, determines that an award claim is sufficiently complex or involves more than 1 whistleblower, or if other good cause exists such that the Commission cannot reasonably satisfy the requirements under subparagraph (A), as determined by the Director or the designee, as applicable, the Director or the designee, after providing notice to the Chairman of the Commission (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Chairman</quote>), may extend the deadline with respect to the satisfaction of those requirements by not more than 180 days.</text></clause><clause id="idC38829EC202C4D6C809DE5DC75BE95F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional extensions</header><text>If, after providing an extension under clause (i), the Director, or the designee of the Director, determines that good cause exists such that the Commission cannot reasonably satisfy the requirement under subparagraph (A), the Director or the designee of the Director, may extend the deadline described in clause (i) as needed for 1 or more additional successive 180-day periods only after providing notice to and receiving approval from the Commission. </text></clause><clause id="idC5C8AEC8F0AD4565A563B20F0B6074FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice to whistleblower required</header><text>If the Director, or the designee of the Director, exercises authority under clause (i) or (ii), the Director or the designee, as applicable, shall submit to the whistleblower who filed the award claim that is subject to that action by the Director or the designee a written notification of that action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA9ACEDE9CB584F229BE0691D48C0B485"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This paragraph shall apply only to an award claim that the Director of the designee of the Director determines is timely submitted under a deadline established by the Commission after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id665082C38F884C23902CAFEB424811DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nonenforceability of certain provisions</header><subsection id="idB5489C77CD644911BBCCF36A5467255F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21F of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" act-name="" id="idB1E755AAED07435EB5156511285E7726"><subsection id="id7CE6A053DE7640FCB4E9A91B52667251"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Nonenforceability of certain provisions waiving rights and remedies or requiring arbitration</header><paragraph id="idAF9F298F32364EF5B465AAEDD44A515B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver of rights and remedies</header><text>The rights and remedies provided in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy form, or condition of employment, including by a predispute arbitration agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDC3EF12029D6400D94DFB884D12C3184"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header><text>No predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable if the agreement requires the arbitration of a dispute arising under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE2A60E963A8B4AA2B55A4B4A36E30ADD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (k) of section 21F of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to any action that is filed on or after, or that is pending as of, the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id26fd684c326f4cf99283fe63fedb8e53"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission may issue any rules that are necessary or appropriate to carry out this Act consistent with the purposes of section 21F of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-6">15 U.S.C. 78u–6</external-xref>), as amended by this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

