<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9604F25196074437822C2173A8AADDD7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2770 IH: Transformational Artificial intelligence to Modernize the Economy against Extreme Weather and Wildfires Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the use of artificial intelligence by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to adapt to extreme weather, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6160D8E18C6E4B1ABF6681BDA2E2304C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA55878DD671A4B95B13C6180658BA885" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABF2593C332D4E1D947545F9D0BD3A93"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transformational Artificial intelligence to Modernize the Economy against Extreme Weather and Wildfires Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TAME Extreme Weather and Wildfires Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB8B7CEE0E06D4C7DB495BC7A7A9BD817"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HA55878DD671A4B95B13C6180658BA885" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBC303B95DC2540E9B4FC9E75FA5B8572" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H17A9A61F5D994DB88D36D7278A42460C" level="section">Sec. 3. Earth system forecasting and information delivery.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H1BD2C4864C7C4A1F8C921F2E60B28332" level="section">Sec. 4. Advanced artificial intelligence applications for weather and information delivery.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HEF1A78A69DAB42FAB342BE09FE285171" level="section">Sec. 5. Technical assistance on use of artificial intelligence weather models.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H868032EE3CAC419E8B9DB85C8DFCCEC4" level="section">Sec. 6. Fire environment modeling program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB2E77474905B44EC99D20CC8415DF662" level="section">Sec. 7. Partnerships for transformational innovation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H80B03F297EAF416588C79C77159240CC" level="section">Sec. 8. Federal Government workforce expertise.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7B757F69F41F414EB6EE289085997807" level="section">Sec. 9. Data access.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBC303B95DC2540E9B4FC9E75FA5B8572"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H5037B5008DDC4FF98D735DDED146355D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header> <subparagraph id="H9E913559C6694E2CBB70B8E6C06454B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> means a machine-based system that can, for a given set of human-defined objectives, make predictions, recommendations, or decisions influencing real or virtual environments, including by using machine-based and human-based inputs—</text> 
<clause id="HCDB1E3AAF1D04FE5B0DE6485721F4C30" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to abstract such objectives into models through analysis in an automated manner; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5EE32DD4CFE8431B87B3C2622B443D0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use model inferences to generate information or formulate options for action.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD960541C34674E2EA9A3BED7733DEBFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> includes machine learning, neural networks, and natural language processing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9D7BCB02C96489EAAFEB984E4004E9D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence weather model</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence weather model</term> means a weather model based primarily on artificial intelligence to project future Earth system conditions based on machine learning from an Earth system reanalysis dataset.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60E7975B32B64803AAF67D61E70EA0ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Curate</header><text>The term <term>curate</term> means to collect, maintain, and update periodically a dataset—</text> <subparagraph id="HD96BA2349089498A8E078A86A36B2CCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure and document its quality; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15BBE934350B4804B4799B9D5ED66A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide metadata on its provenance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09A0DDECA3AE45D1AEE171B84F3311B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Numerical weather model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>numerical weather model</term> means a weather model based primarily on coupled Earth system processes and that uses numerical computation to forecast future Earth system conditions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5854B9296B0A4121BA57A0611B95C2CF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Observational data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>observational data</term> means data from actual observations of environmental conditions, including remote sensing and in situ platforms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF8FBB0EC1D14DC986F129ABA5D1C623"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Open license</header><text>The term <term>open license</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502(21) of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEED5F1E73FDF4DD586F227DCBD01F6D5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reforecast analysis</header><text>The term <term>reforecast analysis</term> means the assessment of a numerical weather model or artificial intelligence weather model by comparing model output and observational data over a period of time in the past.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17208438C78744B7AC6E26902BB051FD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Synthetic data</header><text>The term <term>synthetic data</term> means data produced from a model or statistical method in order to fill gaps in observational data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7589261951D648B2BE6B91986F5F9A9E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Training dataset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>training dataset</term> means a dataset used to train an artificial intelligence model.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A086B57E4EE42338062751E700EA489"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Under Secretary</quote> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2B538E746E14767940C953123D746D0"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Weather enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>weather enterprise</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H17A9A61F5D994DB88D36D7278A42460C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Earth system forecasting and information delivery</header> <subsection id="H629F25DBF1FB404D96DC46512D7764CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Director of the National Science Foundation, any appropriate Federal Advisory Committee, and such other technical experts as the Under Secretary considers appropriate, shall develop and curate comprehensive weather forecasting training datasets with relevant Earth system data, quality information, and metadata necessary for weather forecasting dataset that develops a long-term record of past weather in support of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H27C4E90C7EC6499E922738B317EC0F48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Furthering the understanding of weather, water, and space weather modeling and data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BCD128571F8485F87FCD267E4D8701F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Advancing the science of weather forecasting, including seasonal and subseasonal forecasting.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2ACB35C32A6F48B286C29DA76F3AACE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing artificial intelligence weather forecasting applications.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A01B891195D4207BF1E3DDF98B5D80D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of existing datasets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to speed the development of the weather forecasting training dataset required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall assess, and to the greatest extent practicable build on, existing weather forecasting training datasets of the Federal Government.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01420712041F4674BD022369FD3C0357"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence weather model</header> 
<paragraph id="HB30DF87555E741C1AD11CCBB5FC523A6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary, in consultation with any appropriate Federal Advisory Committees, may develop and test a global weather model based on artificial intelligence, to be referred to as an <quote>artificial intelligence weather model</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97B21970B6234254BA4930737E0B6DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Weather ready nation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In coordination with the activities carried out under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary may explore using artificial intelligence to enhance the dissemination of information and evaluation of effectiveness for improved public understanding, preparedness, and resilience.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3637280D56604F6B96BD9E481F7D90C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Under Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the activities conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H282343F2A20A47A699807371607A970F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative institutes and contracting authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, subject to the availability of appropriations, the Under Secretary may competitively award contracts and funding opportunities, increase the scope of existing cooperative institutes of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or competitively award a new cooperative institute.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF2CC3A4EF102467C93D8A02065CE5F95" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Environmental impact</header><text>The Under Secretary shall develop and disseminate best practices to minimize environmental impacts from the use of artificial intelligence to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF56C9E5219224018900748B69FFD8860"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Continued support for observations, basic research, and numerical weather models</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of this section, the Under Secretary shall continue to support and advance the activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7F8A4595FC5E4CC09704F894CFBF8586" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collect and acquire traditional and novel observational data relevant for artificial intelligence and numerical weather models.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47C76E56B57F47A3A1F0760031005BA7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Advance research on the Earth system and numerical weather models.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24E2AE62F83D4E58B1DB9CE3DB34E943" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop and advance numerical Earth system modeling for predictions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDCFC174DE81434487A3493024EBC87A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop weather model data post-processing techniques.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A9F96732C4A49009CACA45639859DE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Improve data assimilation techniques.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1BD2C4864C7C4A1F8C921F2E60B28332"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advanced artificial intelligence applications for weather and information delivery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall explore advanced applications of artificial intelligence to improve weather forecasts and information delivery, such as by carrying out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF6D5BC4D0722488284CD49F8402B27C7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Improving data assimilation techniques.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6415700DB645B6A4ACE8402F08F4BC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using artificial intelligence weather models to quickly emulate running numerical weather models to assess and improve the confidence in and reliability of weather forecasts and information delivery.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4E7F7529EBC4898A325F4AF2C25B595"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving impact-based decision support to communities for greater societal benefits based on weather forecasts.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEF1A78A69DAB42FAB342BE09FE285171"><enum>5.</enum><header>Technical assistance on use of artificial intelligence weather models</header> <subsection id="HD18B3B626E5D413C85840B1AC6027A42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall regularly inventory and assess major non-Federal Government artificial intelligence weather models in order to provide the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6249FD35254F4E27B8686C5AD22B2351"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical evaluation and assistance on using such models.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H386B14B7BF164C329E7D61C94A79E733"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Best practices on providing forecasts based on outputs from both artificial intelligence weather models and numerical weather models, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBE679C427E04B33A8DA49EF6F129005"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support for forecasters and social scientists to test and evaluate the use and effectiveness of artificial intelligence models, including within National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration testbeds.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70422D4F10234AAF8851410A119177F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support for emergency managers to make operational decisions based on outputs from both artificial intelligence weather models and numerical weather models, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D6D3FF34F2C4343BE617A1BD83E2E3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reforecast analysis</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8ED6ABC79224066AD9D9879D8E4E901"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall support the development of a common framework for the assessment of numerical weather models and artificial intelligence weather models through reforecast analysis and related methodologies as the Under Secretary considers appropriate. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H245404B69E184102993EE7E1959BD06D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Under Secretary may develop and disseminate best practices in collaboration with the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H904811EBBAE94198BE5FE0B20C9D3D6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The National Institute for Standards and Technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA53A136B69AE408DB68F511A443B91E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B064C1BDA1D4B599D264E03144F0702"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The National Science Foundation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2D73A078CF7432CBD965F1A8FFA2929"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE63BFC118A204F83BA8CA6A4BB176231"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Academic and research institutions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7A51AB6DA24406987441EFF515C41F4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The private sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6962B45B01B54B5BA471A8A2149C0872"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on use of analysis to improve models</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the feasibility of using reforecast analysis techniques to improve seasonal and subseasonal models.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H549EDF04FEC2469EBB33552D8B5885A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Weather forecast offices</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary shall provide technical assistance, best practices, and support required under subsection (a) through weather forecast offices of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C2C636828A2412184ACCB7802AB0687" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Independent study on the impacts of artificial intelligence weather, water, and space weather models</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary may enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences or any other entity determined appropriate by the Under Secretary to assess the impacts of artificial intelligence weather models on the weather enterprise and make recommendations to improve the integration of such models in operational forecasting.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H868032EE3CAC419E8B9DB85C8DFCCEC4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Fire environment modeling program</header> <subsection id="H2CC157D1166B409899B8006F5D5A7543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, and in consultation with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of Energy, the Director of the National Science Foundation, any appropriate Federal advisory committees, and such other technical experts as the Under Secretary considers appropriate, shall develop a program to use artificial intelligence to analyze available observational data and synthetic data on the built and natural environments in order to carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6704B301F2F7449FBC72A4A01ECFC2CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Warn at-risk communities, firefighters, and other responders, including by integrating social science informed research and development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE276BF33259647C588591F27ABE820D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Predict and detect wildfires to the maximum extent practicable.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DE977371EFA43C78BF766FD37B52716"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Forecast wildland and built environment fire propagation and potential impacts based on an analysis of the elements influencing fire behavior, weather conditions, terrain, and observations of the fire environment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BD91E7454464338A69FE58A3FD4070D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Detect, monitor, and forecast smoke and other hazards associated with wildfires.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC056C0BE056249AAAF3F45C7F428CF9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training dataset</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary may acquire observational data and synthetic data on the built and natural environments collected across the United States to develop and curate a related artificial intelligence-ready training dataset for purposes of training the artificial intelligence used in furtherance of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE5E55B323A3E4C659A9E83236D0BA656"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data acquisition</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary may enter into contracts to acquire relevant data referred to in this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB6CF0B017F54189B37CBD053B3E5B3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Weather integration</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary shall integrate outputs from weather and other environmental models and observational data and synthetic data referred to in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H00CA1D2B16AC4377A7E62B4930577C9B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Environmental impact</header><text>The Under Secretary shall develop and disseminate best practices to minimize environmental impacts from the use of artificial intelligence to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB2E77474905B44EC99D20CC8415DF662"><enum>7.</enum><header>Partnerships for transformational innovation</header> 
<subsection id="H45AF53CB757B47468BBBBA43EE895337"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall explore novel structures for partnerships with private entities and academic entities for transformative innovation in weather forecasting and other environmental forecasts in order to carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H67C760EF5A2F4FF1A124A02758B116C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further the understanding of weather, water, wildfires, and space weather, and associated societal impact.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98C9D8C9218A41829C97888E398E407B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Advance the science of weather and water forecasting, including seasonal and subseasonal forecasting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A10394799154E9E8E9368C958553F1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop, evaluate, and transition artificial intelligence weather, water, and hazard forecasting applications for operations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29A229541A2842ACA37AA34066E42BF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Co-Investment</header><text>In carrying out this section, subject to applicable law, the Under Secretary shall consider and adopt novel co-investment strategies with the private sector and academic sector, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCFEE21C52E924689B407C63905A32C79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Non-Federal Government contributions to resource and support high-risk, high-return research and development in environmental forecasting, data science, artificial intelligence, and related fields.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF85D1F7099224441B9684BAE9BECA151"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Shared rights to intellectual property from research and development activities under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H510AC97D0E6D46F298469F4055AF8A8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other approaches to sharing resources and results under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H80B03F297EAF416588C79C77159240CC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Federal Government workforce expertise</header> 
<subsection id="HD2E71A0A44BD443CB4D7265ED8A400A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall develop, recruit, and sustain a professional workforce for weather forecasting applications of artificial intelligence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE98328BEC2D744CE85468E6B00AD1245"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Under Secretary shall leverage robust public-private partnership models to collaborate with private sector experts and provide employees with access to training, experience, and long-term development of workforce and infrastructure in order to utilize artificial intelligence to improve weather forecasts.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7B757F69F41F414EB6EE289085997807"><enum>9.</enum><header>Data access</header> 
<subsection id="H7499C2C0AB9048BFB8F896C6C8E5E9E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary may make available to the public, as the Under Secretary determines appropriate, at no cost and with no restrictions on copying, publishing, distributing, citing, adapting, or otherwise using under an open license, any data or code developed under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF4F3A8AD553A483887BC416AD69EBB28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accommodations</header><text>The Under Secretary may make such accommodations as the Under Secretary considers appropriate to ensure that the public release of any model, information, documentation, or data pursuant to this Act does not jeopardize any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H06FB4B1DE81048029D243F4B1812D313"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA6D95CF1957489EB913737FE5AD8E70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Intellectual property or redistribution rights, including under titles 17 and 35, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC28C00E6FE4A4B64ABB5BF231CB2FED3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any trade secret or commercial or financial information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD9E0C6E352F423CBD8B663E86D51565"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any models or data that are otherwise restricted by contract or other written agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4A04313A5D0404D83F619C8ED590FF1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The mission of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to protect lives and property.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H726362D0BCE04E6AA009F4093F00BF42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to supersede any other provision of law governing the protection of the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

