<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H17995ADCACBA4B678F495F21301FAB04" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1568 IH: African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1568</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center in New York, New York, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9B084DC021B4CF9A0FC43D87735DD86" style="OLC"><section id="H8E14DDBB15E849A38D430ED1909E15DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1C2AAE5310874F92B54B10EC0698C0D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HAC811AC8C59F477FB0BF984BA3AB27F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the African Burial Ground National Historic Landmark in New York, New York, holds the remains of up to 20,000 enslaved Africans and early-generation African Americans from the colonial era;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2ADBE061114E96B9D9355945BE3ED7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Africans and African Americans that suffered under slavery show us the strength of the human character and provide us with a model of courage, commitment, and perseverance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFA34A394844F1DA2BC8150A174055B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as President George W. Bush stated on July 8, 2003, during his remarks at Goree Island, Senegal: <quote>For 250 years the captives endured an assault on their culture and their dignity. The spirit of Africans in America did not break. . . . All the generations of oppression under the laws of man could not crush the hope of freedom and defeat the purposes of God.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD10093EA6CC547AEACA115C5177E5D79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on February 27, 2006, President George W. Bush established the National Monument, which was comprised of the approximately 15,000-square foot parcel of the National Historic Landmark that was bounded by Duane and Elk Streets in Lower Manhattan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AAC1BC452984BBCB382FE9A0CF6F50E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an international memorial museum facility dedicated to those individuals who suffered the grave injustice of slavery in the United States, while at the same time helping to build the country, would—</text><subparagraph id="H97E1E8D7159540DF87A76C314B1D785E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect the significance of the African Burial Ground; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B226B328AB4B4BA22564ECE529151F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>help the people of the United States understand the past and honor the history of all people in the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D7131DCEBFE4245BEA573E20BA3694B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in 1998, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution—</text><subparagraph id="H0E546C65EF4D400F8255AC11F7D5AB9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stated that the African Burial Ground affords the perfect opportunity to gain insight into—</text><clause id="HF8E6831BF0314B558E4E07632393A0C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the institution of slavery, as practiced in urban, rural, northern, and southern parts of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H43EBB93A5D8B4E4BA35EAA1FB1F0B187"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the international slave trade; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC04BC0389D643F1B6E537468F3C6AD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proposed that a partnership be formed among the Smithsonian, the National Park Service, and the General Services Administration to further develop the African Burial Ground;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE400EB8DABA4DDDA1DFB63897798756"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the National Museum of African American History and Culture Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80r">20 U.S.C. 80r et seq.</external-xref>), which authorized construction of a museum in Washington, DC, identified the period of slavery as one of the periods of the African-American diaspora that would be encompassed by the museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACFC6045D3F34061AD85EF05084226F6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the African Burial Ground—</text><subparagraph id="HBB086FA9094F403893BBB54AD1D6DCE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is unlike any other anthropological and symbolic site in the United States or the world;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E872EE448C4EA5A76D76171C305BA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes DNA samples from the remarkably well-preserved human remains that will enable researchers to trace the home <quote>roots</quote> in Africa of those individuals buried at the African Burial Ground; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E329FE630504BA0A75C94B5E3809022"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides a fitting location for a national memorial facility, relating to the National Museum of African American History and Culture that would—</text><clause id="H878106744E584101BBE54DB07694A313"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pay special tribute to—</text><subclause id="H90E565BE84524471A7D1DC0B4D6FC3F9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the thousands of enslaved individuals who are buried at the African Burial Ground; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6761586DC8D64AE69F34C4CB56DB9472"><enum>(II)</enum><text>all of the individuals who were enslaved during the history of the United States;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9CF4D7AFF863419E96883AFD3A25703B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>examine the African cultural traditions brought to the United States by the enslaved; and</text></clause><clause id="HFB445412243241B78F44CF9C3CC749C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>explore in-depth the institution of slavery;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14907B4286FF42878FAEE8904EC08AE8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a memorial museum at the site of the African Burial Ground—</text><subparagraph id="H023F37F8625F4434BF57AF71B8F91811"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was first recommended by a Federal steering committee in 1992; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8521BE0A5B94400889807787412013EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in conjunction with the World Trade Center memorial and other nearby sites, would attract millions of visitors from the United States and abroad, making a substantial contribution to the development and revitalization of Lower Manhattan in response to the attacks on the World Trade Center of September 11, 2001;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC790DC3858349BD8BBD8808AFC42B6C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Public Law 99–511 (100 Stat. 2080) encouraged support for the establishment of a commemorative structure within the National Park System or on other Federal land that is dedicated to the promotion of understanding, knowledge, opportunity, and equality for all people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FCFB938B5B34BB9B2F18FBB38074A4B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>similar to the National Museum of the Native American that was established by section 3(a) of the National Museum of the American Indian Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80q-1">20 U.S.C. 80q–1(a)</external-xref>), a memorial museum at the site of the African Burial Ground would benefit from a partnership among—</text><subparagraph id="HCD53C7F1D68941D9A13B9D9C8A9AEF1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB19D971EB9D247ABBEDE9A84EC50EC19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State of New York;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB204B52876544137BC3EEACF3DF28BCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the city of New York; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC94DEED62D184ECE9C6211E7743684BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>members of the private sector;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62D8F0751CFA4288897FF4741581A87F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the African Burial Ground—</text><subparagraph id="HA636F9D944C04C5594986BAD66425E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been determined to be nationally significant as—</text><clause id="HBD6A0AD20BBC4763BDA1EB4FA8F7FBEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a National Historic Landmark; and</text></clause><clause id="HF164E288776A4F97AF8F00F32D1A23C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a National Monument; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA53807DB8550439A9F84E5FECF3E0B06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an important opportunity for interpretation, understanding, partnership, and pride; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD786EA4C76DF45FE955CA4F7EA04BD54"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the National Park Service—</text><subparagraph id="HB4E83D40A69C4E5A8CB5CB286C63004A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has played an important role in the development of the African Burial Ground (including the designation of the African Burial Ground as a National Monument);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8AC9A6E56804941997482CBB6C92C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>successfully operates other national facilities in the city of New York that symbolize freedom and the quest for freedom in America, including—</text><clause id="H572AADE7162545AA90BBE0955359A1E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Statue of Liberty National Monument; and</text></clause><clause id="HF4D0B70DCDB0495685B7DED045184F57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Ellis Island National Monument;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFA72EBD56AD4ACFBBFB37CE7AFDBE53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provided key support to the Presidential Study Commission for the National Museum of African American History and Culture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3DDA41A91A94CF8B7DBFEE9C355ED01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is well-suited to assume a leadership role with respect to the creation of the Museum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H43E4F0AD20DF44078BC1096EDF671E43"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6DE95D740C534F788512E2DE51DF866E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the General Services Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A31C40B764408FBD5462C2F6BA3598"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the African Burial Ground Advisory Council established by section 7(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD43613140D85496AA7D8FB1DFDE67529"><enum>(3)</enum><header>City</header><text>The term <term>City</term> means the city of New York, New York.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE963C9F84E9645A8B766D7A52A83BA16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expansion property</header><text>The term <term>expansion property</term> means the property that is acquired by the Secretary under section 5(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA863B32CFEC4BFD823760778586F328"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Museum</header><text>The term <term>Museum</term> means the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center established by section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1157927F576F49559389D3EF18398B5A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>National landmark</header><text>The term <term>National Landmark</term> means the African Burial Ground National Historic Landmark in the City.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD98630EE281486693A4C92246646166"><enum>(7)</enum><header>National monument</header><text>The term <term>National Monument</term> means the African Burial Ground National Monument in the City.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51C42BE23D447F9A54F1F2119B625D1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A7290E95328487B9AC3799A36F102B9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of New York.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC086CA75F3C445438D7EEDD62FEBDCD3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of museum</header><subsection id="HC4D7EA733D644BFBA915E2647461D15C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established at the National Monument a memorial museum and educational center, to be known as the <quote>African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4A218C0DF13146668C08907ADB7C9CFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Museum are—</text><paragraph id="HE1CF2A9FB1B94112BC24E2792CF28299"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to serve as a permanent living memorial—</text><subparagraph id="HFA8FAF92C9E84A9DA0095AA5788FB520"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the enslaved who are buried at the African Burial Ground; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16AC800329C84C8595272C54CDB1CDB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to other Africans and African Americans who were enslaved;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7282BC5FE00F483AA11AF2604114F866"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to examine the African cultural traditions brought to the United States by the enslaved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E86170604644FCAA5657D73AEAB4E37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to explore in-depth the institution of slavery in the United States and other parts of the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9E629DF327B4475BBF3A100384393B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide a space for—</text><subparagraph id="H7E855B14DD2F4C658043B770B36C0EAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permanent and temporary exhibits; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C8DF71733B44B0CAC85EC43D242C083"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the collection and study of artifacts and documents; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD20B894B66E4AFCB735741235F7F432"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to encourage collaboration between the Museum and the National Museum of African American History and Culture, other museums, historically Black colleges and universities, historical societies, educational institutions, and other appropriate entities and organizations, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation, including collaboration with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HB135DC131E184807A25AC4EBBF68D801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of cooperative programs and exhibitions, including through digital, electronic, and interactive technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413254CE20D24D438F7302FD3D0B8D65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identification, management, and care of Museum collections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9AE03FE5BDD4B6AAE7F29A77FDC27DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the training of Museum and National Park Service professionals and other persons concerned with heritage preservation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31282782D1624C46BFD047828B322CE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Association with national museum</header><text>The Museum shall become associated with the National Museum of African American History and Culture, in a manner to be determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Council and the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</text></subsection></section><section id="H699062529EDC488099AF4CD94D07C5EC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Site acquisition and development</header><subsection id="H647DA8108C2C493FBF38FC602F090FDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, the Advisory Council, and other appropriate entities or organizations, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation, shall—</text><paragraph id="HE70500770B53478593079EA073F8752A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquire for the Museum property that is located at—</text><subparagraph id="H1148948DAA38412E8741E7DAA9AE127A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>22 Reade Street, which is adjacent to the National Monument; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF46226FC1DB491587E4A9B82B89EA89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in any other area of the National Landmark other than the location described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E3408B3B454EB9A85E51AD427DC95E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>plan, design, and construct the Museum on the property acquired under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED67CF78B8894A9AA74D4BBE9D6D62F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Secretary shall pay <fraction>2/3 </fraction>of the total costs of—</text><paragraph id="HC582A742819147E4864ED9013A33668A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquiring property for the Museum; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3356B431DB834D14AAC8BC00DC60D5C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>planning, designing, constructing, reconstructing, and renovating, as applicable, the Museum.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FA4608E88BB4FF79E1C1855A397E01C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><paragraph id="HE49EB73541D34AE381F214BACA8438C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator may enter into any agreements with each other, the City, the State, and other parties, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation, that are necessary for the acquisition, by donation or other means, of property for—</text><subparagraph id="H421F736180D040FD95E1F48A5555D903"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing the Museum; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA70AF4A0C74B72A2C6AA5495809173"><enum>(B)</enum><text>planning, designing, constructing, reconstructing, and renovating, as applicable, the Museum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA8AA88F6844D928336203AC296D2FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Site acquisition</header><text>The Secretary may acquire property under subsection (a)(1) by purchase, long-term lease, or any other appropriate means of acquisition, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE452E1BEC0CB45CEA3A5E12356FCA5F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expansion of national monument</header><text>The expansion property is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the National Monument.</text></subsection></section><section id="H28A20574A5C14EB88AF5004A6FB31D2D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Operation of the museum</header><subsection id="H63195465C4BA4A9EA0163427BA8620EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Council and the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation, shall operate the Museum.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB74FB907FD4446E2A2C0B089A5DC6DDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Council, may—</text><paragraph id="H9A0A5C8D8608406D831B308006B6B9CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchase, accept, borrow, and otherwise acquire artifacts for the collections of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC134917EC0594B14AC9F65E3819DD120"><enum>(2)</enum><text>loan, exchange, sell, and otherwise dispose of any part of the collections of the Museum, if the proceeds of the disposition are used for additions to the collections of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCB074AB17EF4FC6BAB5B2D5321BF77B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>specify criteria with respect to the use of the collections and resources of the Museum, including policies on programming, education, exhibitions, and research;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H308A37C2D07B47F0ACD17A89359CEBE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide for preservation, restoration, and maintenance of the collections of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0E3174D1F6F4BE1855E3664B6CDB4FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, and devises of real and personal property for the purpose of facilitating the work of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68EF93B28954759A5EE581A5C379A60"><enum>(6)</enum><text>contract with such parties as may be necessary to facilitate the operation of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C4F196A1DF74F84A67AF730D656C621"><enum>(7)</enum><text>administer the National Monument as a unit of the National Park System in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="HBFA874D8C43C41FEA4D1D7AA78EE193C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E924BB81224C21BBBD60983EDF630A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including applicable provisions of division A of subtitle I of title 54, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E096C553DA4D678A1F660E6F9303CE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>conduct any other activities that are necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H13E0A14A0F9740AFA72370FC08B19FEE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Advisory council</header><subsection id="HFF7310B5DDD344EABBB50C16FAC766F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Department of the Interior an advisory council to be known as the <quote>African Burial Ground Advisory Council</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6ECC2C304C3A4823B9095AFDE4C5B8E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H86F4D0AFA39F43C496FAB78121F3C48A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be composed of the following members or their designees:</text><subparagraph id="H1C44D364F00A479099196438BC7C9B6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary, who shall serve as Chairperson of the Advisory Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BFD712A359944FA8A83A4723905B7D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the National Park Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE81E28AC87334971835FEB4C51029463"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70FCC923DC7548E0A6053C6E3C5C2570"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Administrator.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0F3302E7D46493A8C9BBF8BA435784A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Governor of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833B1AC9120E489586896905ABD56F0E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Mayor of the City.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DD8E2BCDF124666B30B42A9F1046E69"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The President of the Borough of Manhattan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CD31ED12F76462CA03CF131788772F2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Fourteen members, to be appointed by the Secretary, taking into consideration—</text><clause id="HC5DFD6A020EB4948B9978DCA9F8F3F7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations from organizations and entities that are committed to the legacy of the African Burial Ground, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation; and</text></clause><clause id="HA367785E1A794454ACF2625C1E7D22A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations from the members of the Advisory Council.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4323FA5FF6411C8473D05E8D0005D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonvoting members</header><text>The Secretary may appoint as nonvoting members of the Advisory Council—</text><subparagraph id="H25F4F37F1DCB4A9BB90D99FA25101150"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the United States Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7151A0B9B2614125BC9A5A9032365B06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA95ED44CE35A4159A249C24B3F650D5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>officials representing the City;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49ED3A835D1B4521B6302B8CB2CBB3D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>officials representing the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C5EEEC317B6408093DD32B8CF2EC58D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other individuals that the Secretary, in consultation with the members of the Advisory Council, determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32AD71B78F054458BC73D9C70D35B681"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Date of appointments</header><text>The initial appointment of a member under paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8029F7AEDC934CFB8AFFB3A66A2E4524"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms</header><paragraph id="HF0CA3B239ABC4795A540953DC24B78E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), each member of the Advisory Council shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FB29E973B548E7A698F1A216647D0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial appointees</header><text>Of the members first appointed under subsection (b)(1)(H)—</text><subparagraph id="H59F9C5EBF03C49C3A1E593DB3A50752C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4B893B1A9BF46A7BBEAF6C89BEE629C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257BAEDF9EAA4F32902ADB4612532335"><enum>(C)</enum><text>4 members shall be appointed for a terms of 3 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H962DAEC3007A4614A8FC662C8B0B9674"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><subparagraph id="HC85C0569596044A0B52631D7BDAF8326"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Advisory Council may be reappointed, except that no individual may serve on the Advisory Council for a total of more than 2 terms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C876C823FB64F099ED7F20A06D72F40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancy appointments</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the number of terms an individual serves on the Advisory Council shall not include any portion of a term for which an individual is appointed to fill a vacancy under paragraph (4)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H804FACE508A14E2CBF8D2D397CFD7649"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="H17524DD2D91C4024A47DA79C92377719"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Advisory Council—</text><clause id="HCACE4DFCC2484D699E24525D45305753"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Advisory Council; and</text></clause><clause id="HC29DF0CCFB0340528B4159390F2E7873"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H848354B5360E4C8DAF63B59DF64820BE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Any member of the Advisory Council appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B71D6AF8EB24B068FCA87FEDDEC99F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text><paragraph id="HA7C9BFD9BC024E46A7708AA39A6C06C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary on the planning, design, and construction of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55576F55FA5B418BB4821B7A8BA38C73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advise and assist the Secretary on all matters relating to the administration, operation, maintenance, and preservation of the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0820B9801B114840AD336F3872C17CCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide significant opportunities for public input with respect to carrying out the duties under paragraphs (1) and (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H367A662F4014429A9061AC5A80EE7734"><enum>(4)</enum><text>adopt bylaws for the operation of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5527105EF3BD4D9FA09456B562546B20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation</header><paragraph id="H304A49CBB39342A8A88AACE9F0A6CBB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Advisory Council shall serve without compensation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDFFCAEFC0254A1C9DEFA2B880951F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Council shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5D53CA1D9E9490DB60A0DA5E79A7F55"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="H54FE59DAF8DC4988BABCF12BBDF223A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet at the call of the chairperson or on the written request of a majority of the members of the Advisory Council, but not fewer than 2 times each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB6EBC435A74BAB89349B8A0BD6D6E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meetings</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date of the first meeting of the Advisory Council, the Advisory Council shall meet not fewer than 4 times for the purpose of carrying out the duties of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BF855DDFEDB48E896EE9C475F58E4D4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Advisory Council shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting business, but a lesser number may receive information on behalf of the Advisory Council.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2F5FF92DC64D49179E02B5A4A3ED3275"><enum>8.</enum><header>Director and staff</header><subsection id="H87E249DD4EB34B31BDC83F8BFE80B4D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph id="HC452B5A382704F3DBF639CACE24D8541"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a Director for the Museum, taking into consideration recommendations by the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DE7077A1224452965141285A13C519"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director of the Museum shall manage the Museum, in accordance with any policies established by the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE23C3295B184B9D9D0BCCF580A4C421"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><paragraph id="H205C78C533474FBB9DF9248028A46591"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Secretary may, without regard to the civil service laws, appoint 2 employees to assist the Director of the Museum in carrying out the duties of the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFECEE7AAE7A4B1EA0856C475D4A98D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The employees appointed under subsection (b) may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCA88125256974041A2B3DEF9CCD1D75C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="H3804444FC8884D49BA42775070DACFDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph id="HDA8DD027B20940C9AEF0768931017BEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$15,000,000 for fiscal year 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21EF516DB52F42E6AB0D5FD04FA34450"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for each fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H156F80C197514164BDECE804535608F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition of museum site</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out section 5.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD1AB83E9CCA4C28AE15B24AF042E6B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts made available under subsections (a) and (b) shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="H05F159801CF943EBBA3B0B1E272CEF30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under this section may be used to support the Museum and expand or establish programs that promote and preserve the legacy of the African Burial Ground, including—</text><paragraph id="HB75EDC1EC74D45C385EC4678CAE49048"><enum>(1)</enum><text>using amounts made available under this section to raise funds from private sources to support and promote the Museum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD55F5D17F1D4ABF93BE2156D5736804"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting curriculum development, workshops, and community outreach to deepen public understanding of the historical significance of the African Burial Ground;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F1430F3640E4F4E8CBDBB42BF9F055A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing a dedicated visitor’s center to provide an immersive educational experience, including interactive exhibits and technology-driven tools to enhance public engagement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2359667DBD5484EA32805EC134D1E34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensuring the long-term sustainability of the facilities and organizational objectives of the Museum.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

