<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H985F0B13894F43B2AE4F73E1082C9A2C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4422 IH: Don’t Feed the Bears Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the adoption and enforcement of regulations to prohibit the intentional feeding of bears on Federal public lands in order to end the hunting practice known as <quote>bear baiting</quote> and reduce the number of dangerous interactions between people and bears.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H376E725759364A418659683813E7C9EC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H73B60001B04148F09FDF49EC73D89937" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Don’t Feed the Bears Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F029EAABD514B3DBE390BA88F37D786"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Prohibition on feeding bears on Federal public lands</header> <subsection id="H7CA7BD2823AA44328386E6FE66548110"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Findings</header> <text>Congress finds the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H9CCA8FD8E6E848B79B4D85C4B58EDB49">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Federal land management agencies, including the Forest Service, National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and Bureau of Land Management, publish and distribute materials to the public discouraging any feeding of black bears.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H354AE5344FE0438FA52A111479D56FDA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Even though Federal land managers are in agreement that private citizens should not provide food to bears, several Federal land management agencies do not prohibit licensed hunters from setting out food as bait for bears on Federal lands in States where baiting is permitted by State law.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8CE6D41403014A8C84F2B9AD134DF549">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A typical bait station consists of hundreds of pounds of human-scented foods, often including parts of animal carcasses, pastries, fruits, and grease, that are simply piled on the forest floor or dumped in large drums.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5179E21D491D4BD4B28BE1F879B33E63">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The foods used in a bait station are no different than the human-scented foods that a bear might find in a garbage can, dump, or campground, and after the bear hunting season ends, bait stations are often not removed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5CB95179909F4D608C39500C2F592829">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The presence of bait stations on Federal lands allows bears to increase their food intake and results in higher birth rates, increasing bear populations.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE79CA9CE02C44A00BF21C69A470EEE12">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Wildlife scientists agree that black bears are naturally wary of people, but that feeding bears human-scented foods can cause bears to lose their wariness and become emboldened in approaching people and property in search of food.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E1D15810AFA44059265D806CB0D4123">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Human-fed bears cause millions of dollars in property damage every year.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF06B1400F61041CF8ECB4D3CC5A87209"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>Bears habituated to human food can pose a safety threat, occasionally resulting in attacks on human beings.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E8DE974D6234AF7BAF54251416A103D">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>Bears that come into conflict with people are often labeled as nuisance animals, and are often killed as a means of protecting people and property.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5AF313DCDB1E4BBFA068D4C608928CB3">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>When the National Park Service adopted policies to ban bear feeding and to end the practice of keeping garbage in open-air dumps, units of the National Park System experienced a dramatic decline in bear-human encounters.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H47DFC44CDA1A43AE8E60EE4A24728DB6">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>A majority of the States that allow bear hunting ban baiting, and black bears can be hunted successfully by means other than baiting.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7991FC260A8D4534A7824E2FB59AD80D">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
 <text>It is inconsistent for Federal land management agencies to demand that visitors to the Federal lands not feed bears, but to allow this practice by bear baiters.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H34623C23D4D04E119F27D01635731BD9">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text>The United States already prohibits baiting of migratory birds.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H861E2137D1D34347AB837A9A4E01BA37"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Enforcement of existing nps regulation</header> <text>The Secretary of the Interior shall enforce the regulatory prohibition, contained in section 2.2(a)(2) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, against the feeding of wildlife on National Park System lands to prohibit individuals from intentionally feeding bears for the purpose of enticing bears to a particular area to be hunted, a practice known as <quote>bear baiting</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5CD41467C0E24AE5B67D7816260C6301">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Enforcement of existing fws regulation</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Interior shall enforce the regulatory prohibition, contained in section 32.2(h) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, against bear baiting and the baiting of other wildlife on wildlife refuge areas.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE33C0F7A04454D18A288841D35F2C4D6">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Adoption of regulations for other public lands</header>
        <paragraph id="HE38DECFB27C242C1A52DFEB8BCA2B916">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Regulation required</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Interior, with respect to lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, and the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands, shall each adopt and enforce a regulation to prohibit individuals from intentionally feeding bears, including feeding for the purpose of enticing bears to a particular area to be hunted, a practice known as <quote>bear baiting</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2F3CFC746B9445EEA3443388F9619A41">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Deadline for adoption</header>
 <text>The regulations required by this subsection shall be issued in final form not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H758E3641C9854CCC97D4E4B31F279DFA">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Exception in extraordinary cases</header>
 <text>The regulations referred to in subsections (b) and (c), and the regulations required by subsection (d), shall provide an exception in extraordinary cases when the Secretary concerned determines that bear feeding is required for the welfare of the bear, preservation of public safety, or authorized wildlife research.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

