<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD19FB7D2D78D48A6A8CC4B3223947D7B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3360 IH: Driver Technology and Pedestrian Safety Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to conduct a study on the effect of driver-controlled technology in motor vehicles with respect to severe traffic injuries and traffic fatalities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1484543F7A0043898E41781AC415C4CF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A4A1D9D13E8454DA302291DE8768996" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Driver Technology and Pedestrian Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8AF13CD0809E42ACA72CA74A61FFC184"><enum>2.</enum><header>Driver-controlled technology safety study</header> <subsection id="H0A3F0E037C0D41DD91A98857444EC93A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Driver-Controlled technology safety study agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine—</text>
<paragraph id="H69F5CCB728AC46E785E67F38A36C9C36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct a study on the effect of driver-controlled technology with respect to severe traffic injuries and traffic fatalities, including severe injuries and fatalities of pedestrians, bicyclists, and other vulnerable road users; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H390B848251544F27ABCECFC7680D45F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prepare the recommendations described in section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF0EF5305D9174173B3DC7355E8766696"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period of time To be studied</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the period of time to be studied under subsection (a), which shall be a period of time that began not later than 10 years before the date on which the Secretary enters into the agreement under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6E7450736C2494ABD759D931B8E3505"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study described in subsection (a) shall address the following information:</text>
<paragraph id="H9E52E97E399343C5B95D7A3937C641E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The prevalence and characteristics of touch screen-based systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E727E544CFF4CB290F88EE318D62A2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The impact on driver distraction, property damage, severe traffic injuries, and traffic fatalities as a result of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H0B64EC5529C348C1AA45BA6BB55040C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Replacing tactile motor vehicle controls with touch screen-based systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31E03FC5BB9B40609DC08D50C362F894"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The characteristics of such systems, including brightness and size.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7312B193E8E54B30BEA4F177ECFE1009"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Driver-controlled technology that is not a touch screen-based system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE955DA0E7E8470793239DFF1034B7D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The user interface designs of touch screen-based systems and other driver-controlled technology, and the effect of those designs on driver behavior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CDF17CF6E434EDDB309957E64E08021"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA178E1C96C84823A16B86644D256597" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which viewing or manipulating a touch screen-based system while driving a motor vehicle results in a severe traffic injury or a traffic fatality; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87B56DF1B3994CDB8C4DE8ABAF32AE81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which viewing or manipulating a smartphone, other than a smartphone that is projecting a user interface to a touch screen-based system, while driving a motor vehicle results in a severe traffic injury or a traffic fatality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3EA168292FF4A4DBBCE627576EA86C8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whether the time of day and other road conditions, including traffic, weather, and the number of commercial motor vehicles on a road, have a significant effect on the incidence of severe traffic injuries and traffic fatalities, the extent of any effect, the likely reasons for any effect, whether any effect varies between the United States and other countries, and any changes to touch screen-based systems and other driver-controlled technology that may help mitigate any effect.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF8895DFA99C643CE815BFC8FC19FC219"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other information that is relevant to the study, which may include a previous study.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H68963A1B5B9F4160973E801DE5502E64"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report and recommendations</header> <subsection id="HA246D4D2ED9B486587558A3BC2CA8DD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date on which the Secretary of Transportation enters into an agreement under section 2, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H63FED1A5947E4599A4FECE2D32F3C5F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that includes the findings of the study under section 2; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC93BB6CE5EA04C7B8C3E59081659A9A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish the report on the public website of the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDF51DFA77D2D43F2A689611F6E4C7588"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 months after the date on which the Secretary of Transportation satisfies the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress recommendations that are based on the findings of the study under section 2, including recommendations—</text> <paragraph id="H739FCC84A4314624B06211751E8F1ACF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce severe traffic injuries and traffic fatalities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43A5CC77C92C45389150601B662AB052"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to change the Fatality Analysis Reporting System, the National Occupant Protection Use Surveys, and the Model Minimum Uniform Crash Criteria of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, or another set of Federal surveys, to collect as much data as practicable with respect to the use of a touch screen-based system while driving a motor vehicle and the use of a smartphone while driving a motor vehicle, given the variation in the methods of data collection by States and units of local government.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7F8BAFF8DE15484793D2A767597C2C64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In submitting the recommendations described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Transportation—</text>
<paragraph id="H3A94FF7102D94210A459898F42D052A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not include a recommendation that only restates an existing requirement for a department or agency of the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6D0617226684936A296A40AF47DE6FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall divide the recommendations into the following categories:</text>
<subparagraph id="HBBF4135D08FD4FB4A8A4584482CE7B61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any recommendations that a department or agency of the Federal Government, including the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, may implement under the existing authority of the department or agency, including any authority of the department or agency to develop or update guidance or standards on motor vehicle technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEAE101975484FB99C91992F170CAA6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any recommendations that would require the enactment of Federal law for a department or agency of the Federal Government, including the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, to implement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H8BADFF09B60C44838CFF9DDDA7292FAF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HFDFB8030E11F4665996EE29A9020D080"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>commercial motor vehicle</term> means any of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HF8D0C7E5D1C743CEA1589DC565584570"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A commercial motor vehicle, as that term is defined under section 31132 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8B47C9435C048ED8D1A8A6310C14919"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vehicle owned or operated by a transportation network company, as that term is defined under section 346 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF1AF21FD104460897F31221034134EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Driver-controlled technology</header><text>The term <term>driver-controlled technology</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F9D99E5ACEA4556B9259C566B4B83A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the controls and functions of a motor vehicle that are engaged at the option of a driver of the motor vehicle;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87A10364AF9843CE9B59ECBEDCB9EB76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the functions that are related to driving, are not related to the safe operation of the motor vehicle, and do not involve the use of a system that is required by law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C903574B566479FA87CA7F02ABE8F14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes a touch screen-based system; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD187880C9C894DE1822E79F883CB6D87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not include any functions that are engaged by default as the motor vehicle is driven, such as automatic braking, cameras, and dynamic lighting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1943F262EDC14F68A38211BA83FB1346"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motor vehicle</term> means a passenger motor vehicle, as that term is defined under section 32101 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC0B7AE692AD949549B3A30263269CCC7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tactile motor vehicle control</header><text>The term <term>tactile motor vehicle control</term> means a knob, a switch, a trackpad, or another physical control, that is in a motor vehicle and is not a touch screen.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85ECC5A0E91642E98AD904D20A426D2D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Touch screen-based system</header><text>The term <term>touch screen-based system</term> means a computer that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9A9CB4B2405D4B2A97EEDB29B9AE2090"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in a motor vehicle;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06A3CBB6036F47A3AA261C1DD9F2D017"><enum>(B)</enum><text>controls the functions of the motor vehicle, including the infotainment functions of the motor vehicle;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF0A796F0183643CCBDF1DABCB8C851E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a primary user interface that consists of a touch screen and on-screen software controls;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC34AE68F788F46F881FB7DBDC6942024"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may be able to be manipulated by tactile motor vehicle controls; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAC45B8CB584B47EE8AE49FFAE65C0ABF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may be able to display a user interface that is projected from a smartphone.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H72AF258FCAD54C04BC04917DC29518A4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <subsection id="HA665A595C6EF4E74906E22A94F69D35B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall not be construed to preclude or delay the promulgation of any regulation required or authorized by law.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8D076A2950CB4EE3B3D0E6F0AB3DA972"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deference</header><text>If a court finds that a term used in this Act is ambiguous, the court shall defer to a reasonable interpretation of the term by the Secretary of Transportation.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

