<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADCCD66800C44BC2A33EC83226296879" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 646 IH: Calling on the Senate to remove the name of Richard B. Russell from the Russell Senate Office Building.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 646</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling on the Senate to remove the name of Richard B. Russell from the Russell Senate Office Building.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this resolution may be cited as the original resolution calling on the Senate to remove the name of Richard B. Russell from the Russell Senate Office Building;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Senator Richard B. Russell opposed civil rights as <quote>unconstitutional and unwise</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1935, Senator Russell participated in his first filibuster of a civil rights bill, when he and his colleagues in the Senate stopped an anti-lynching bill with 6 days of nonstop talking;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1936, Senator Russell stated in a re-election campaign speech that <quote>as one who was born and reared in the atmosphere of the Old South, with 6 generations of my forebears now resting beneath Southern soil, I am willing to go as far and make as great a sacrifice to preserve and insure White supremacy in the social, economic, and political life of our state as any man who lives within her borders</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1956, Senator Russell wrote an initial draft of the Southern Manifesto, the bicameral resolution stating support for segregation and refusal to observe Brown v. Board of Education;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, because President Lyndon B. Johnson signed the Civil Rights Act of 1964, Senator Russell, along with more than a dozen other Senators, including Herman Talmadge, boycotted the 1964 Democratic National Convention in Atlantic City;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 17, 1964, the New York Times published an article entitled, <quote>Relocate Negroes Evenly in States</quote>, in which Senator Russell proposed a voluntary <quote>racial relocation</quote> program to adjust the imbalance of the African-American population between the 11 States of the old Confederacy and the rest of the Union;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1972, shortly after Senator Russell’s death, the Senate voted in an overwhelming majority (99–1) that the Old Senate Office Building be named the Russell Senate Office Building;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas historian Gilbert C. Fite wrote at the conclusion of his biography of Senator Russell, <quote>White supremacy and racial segregation were to him cardinal principles for good and workable human relationships</quote>; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/58">Public Law 115–58</external-xref>, a joint resolution signed into law on September 14, 2017, rejects <quote>White nationalism, White supremacy, and neoNazism</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD5220016D980417EB6CC171500843D7F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H59D37983069848BAAE72CFA18BE8448B"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H3F055125F98A4ED1ACC90860544FE001"><enum>(1)</enum><text>once again rejects White nationalism and White supremacy as hateful expressions of intolerance that are contradictory to the values that define the people of the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67FCBED33A384DCEB1B3DD687D05DE6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns the use of captions, statutes, memorials, and artwork used or erected to memorialize Senator Richard B. Russell, or any other lawmaker who intentionally disavowed the Declaration of Independence’s exhortation that all persons are created equal; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C56D04DFD844DE69F08A507247C7802"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the Senate to remove the name of Richard B. Russell from the Russell Senate Office Building and to revert to using the building’s original name, the Old Senate Office Building, until the Senate finds a suitable honoree.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

