<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE87A092A6D24F08B6D23235AEA8B92A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3930 IH: Roadless Area Conservation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide lasting protection for inventoried roadless areas within the National Forest System.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD3D6BF3ADDCA48008D070FB7BB1E9E41" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0CEDD8A79F7746E9A2AF79CF3961AA02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Roadless Area Conservation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H772533B4918741CE8DF07AEA33F23C87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H93BBDDB55C664B3C94744981D522FC06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H35BC6D4D7EF94ED1BD7AC30FF4A8780C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there is a compelling need to establish national protection for inventoried roadless areas of the National Forest System in order to protect the unique social and ecological values of those irreplaceable resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1B87849D22243C8A364B3DA9427264A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>roadless areas protect healthy watersheds and the numerous benefits of healthy watersheds, which include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4B427D083C1141419789A2A2FEF6323E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing the setting for many forms of outdoor recreation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38797DF95ADF45DF9A74FA5AC306D73A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring a supply of clean water for domestic, agricultural, and industrial uses;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3FE420BC0170451FAF184D807BB3D9B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing drinking water to tens of millions of citizens of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H686E6E99A263413383567BA8D6E58CE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>helping maintain abundant and healthy fish and wildlife populations and habitats;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB47556ED10DD4F7DB18F78049821D4E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintaining roadless areas in a relatively undisturbed condition—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4BF93FD7BAA4D8EAF0FA3C4FF5AC682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>saves downstream communities millions of dollars in water filtration costs; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9D119A5E5ED1422D93E82E9F7E4BDE6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is crucial to preserve the flow of affordable, clean water to a growing population;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD6A3E78013F438B8598BD049F3E253C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the protection of roadless areas can maintain biological strongholds and refuges for many imperiled species by halting the ongoing fragmentation of the landscape into smaller and smaller parcels of land divided by road corridors;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6362AC50E81442C8ACAFCE3D095CC7C8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>roadless areas conserve native biodiversity by serving as a bulwark against the spread of nonnative invasive species;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B6C604310104DE38B32234F7C7CFBE1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>roadless areas provide important back­country fish and game habitat, creating opportunities for hunting and commercial and sport fishing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9131B216CB914B45A49E0E97C2D131EA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>roadless areas provide unparalleled opportunities for outdoor recreation, including hiking, camping, picnicking, wildlife viewing, hunting, fishing, cross-country skiing, canoeing, mountain biking, and similar activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15777C5F3A224292A6FFB17438EA2492"><enum>(8)</enum><text>while roadless areas may have many wilderness-like attributes, unlike wilderness areas, the use of mechanized means of travel is allowed in many roadless areas;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H189804EFCBB34294BD5959037D734D34"><enum>(9)</enum><text>roadless areas contain many sites sacred to Native Americans, Alaska Natives, and other groups that use roadless areas for spiritual and religious practices and access, including customary and traditional uses and activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA36401EB303D42B395D0FD13252E13CA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>from the inception of Federal land management, the mission of the Forest Service has been to manage the National Forest System for multiple uses, including resource utilization, conservation, and other uses;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D004D6D53C844B4A3AF59BE3C5E1C2B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>consistent with the multiple-use mission described in paragraph (10), this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FA6317B92A54E478E995891873E7323"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures the continued protection of social and ecological values, while allowing for many multiple uses of inventoried roadless areas; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E9713CC7FEE4DCB8B6DD468F0A7FD51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not impose any new limitations on—</text> <clause id="HEA601BBEB8A446288A4587687DCF4E18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inventoried roadless areas; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HA90FDC41F1344586964C53924E4FD65F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of, or access to, National Forest System, State, or private land outside inventoried roadless areas;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDF50ABD888D470C9ADAF6BFAB550C47"><enum>(12)</enum><text>enacting a law for the protection of inventoried roadless areas—</text>
<subparagraph id="H932AA84D96454162A25DD8224CE4A41A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides additional reliability to areas with recreation-based economies that depend on public land without roads for jobs, revenue, and consumer spending; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4747FA563EB4F87ABC25BE6B1CF5EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourages forest managers to continue giving priority to conducting fuel reduction treatments in the areas in which the treatments will have the most impact;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H39437ADD40BE42D0A8EB595099667E23"><enum>(13)</enum><text>wildfires are almost twice as likely to occur in roaded areas as in roadless areas, because road­less areas are generally located further away from communities and are harder to access;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48C8146FB3EE4B43BAD972AC07412B84"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the Forest Service has an enormous backlog of maintenance needs for the existing 368,102-mile road system of the Forest Service that will cost $5,980,000,000 to eliminate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C22EFC7BC6342CE921457DC969C00A2"><enum>(15)</enum><text>continued protection of roadless areas will continue to allow for the development of hydropower projects.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H370D1366392943B1BDF305B082AD396E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to provide, within the context of multiple-use management, lasting protection for inventoried roadless areas within the National Forest System.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HEB70B473455342A6935C1786313D51B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HCF05E24B66714D92B560976EC71ADD41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inventoried roadless area</header><text>The term <term>inventoried roadless area</term> means any area in which road construction, road reconstruction, or logging is subject to regulation under the Roadless Rule.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF29FDF99EFDB490B811155B9AA464666"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Roadless Rule</header><text>The term <term>Roadless Rule</term> means part 294 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, as adopted on January 12, 2001, and modified for Idaho on October 16, 2008, and for Colorado on July 3, 2012, and December 19, 2016.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A64D49F4E114AB4834971B188004C54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H2509A201E2904316AA6D7ABC1B662586"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of inventoried roadless areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall not allow road construction, road reconstruction, or logging in an inventoried roadless area where those activities are prohibited by the Roadless Rule.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

