<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H8C98F0A0F26A464193CA29455306A15E">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4681 IH: Specialty Physicians Advancing Rural Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4681</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a loan repayment program to encourage specialty medicine physicians to serve in rural communities experiencing a shortage of specialty medicine physicians, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3D44546B0537494EB6F8B32CE29AD219">
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA9B6841D13554F6AB9F35D9FEB489949"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Specialty Physicians Advancing Rural Care Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPARC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H40B80EAEF232492B81C2260063A58EE3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Specialty medical practitioners workforce in rural communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H42854FBD597E46F1A12448C17E6B9382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating part G (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/795j">42 U.S.C. 795j et seq.</external-xref>) as part H; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D7396212395477EA940721FFAAD401A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after part F (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295h">42 U.S.C. 295h</external-xref>) the following new part:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D7785C732B3451794FFCFFF129F9613">
<part id="H36AE7BE5AD244C7683C3B90C0217C402" style="OLC"><enum>G</enum><header>Specialty medicine workforce in rural communities</header>
<section id="HDD0304B0A0D04F30B8C54182BC055C05"><enum>782.</enum><header>Loan repayment program</header>
<subsection id="H0E35B87205CB4AFF80795F04DE81EDBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
<paragraph id="HA6696DACCC4442028C1918292DA4C9AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program for specialty medicine physicians</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall carry out a program under which—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CAA1655E12F4E62916E4903DC50ADED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary enters into agreements with specialty medicine physicians to make payments in accordance with subsection (b) on the principal of and interest on any eligible loans described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2659E21A1B3D473F9DC486BFB2D3AA1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specialty medicine physicians each agree to complete a period of obligated service described in subsection (d) as a specialty medicine physician in the United States in a rural community experiencing a shortage of specialty medicine physicians.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A923C3344554AFF83D9FDD245724980"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program for non-physician specialty health care providers</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may carry out a program under which—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB0B05B26E48348A285D6FE17001C78CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary enters into agreements with non-physician specialty health care providers to make payments in accordance with subsection (b) on the principal of and interest on any eligible loans described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D6F28588DEF4F9DAC2219764AC21B1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the non-physician specialty health care providers each agree to complete a period of obligated service described in subsection (d) as a non-physician specialty health care provider in the United States in a rural community experiencing a shortage of such providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC6F9CFA8C6674BEDB07EF4861CCDB9EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>For each year of obligated service by a specialty medicine physician pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a)(1) or by a non-physician specialty health care provider pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall make a payment to such physician or provider as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA98EAE5F50C140B299723EC713FA4065"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service in shortage area</header><text>The Secretary shall pay—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB188760D78704CB5A8A77E784CA9E130"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each year of obligated service by a specialty medicine physician or non-physician specialty health care provider pursuant to an agreement under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a), <fraction>1/6</fraction> of the principal of and interest on each eligible loan of the physician or provider which is outstanding on the date the physician or provider began service pursuant to the agreement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4185858039AA454798779088455448FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for completion of the sixth and final year of such service, the remainder of such principal and interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B3153E5A66C4BDDA8ABB2DAD24D9395"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The total amount of payments under this section to any specialty medicine physician or non-physician specialty health care provider shall not exceed $250,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1C8E7A782562455989A84ECD9846F0BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible loans</header><text>The loans eligible for repayment under this section are each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF217E09F7FA7456A94E0B8E72099CBE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any loan for education in specialty medicine or specialty health care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6270CE7FD7742CFAB1DEFEAB289BB31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan (as such terms are used in section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAA1D58AE1EF4AA6BE024A3193C6110C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any Federal Perkins Loan under part E of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1DA900C56DF4D239056950E819E0111"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other Federal loan as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB7EAA73C7561438CA4768EA972265B93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of obligated service</header><text>Any specialty medicine physician or non-physician specialty health care provider receiving payments under this section as required by an agreement under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall agree to a 6-year commitment to full-time employment, with no more than 1 year passing between any 2 years of covered employment, as a specialty medicine physician or non-physician specialty health care provider, as applicable, in the United States in a rural community experiencing a shortage of specialty medicine physicians or non-physician specialty health care providers, as applicable.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8A72061195D642CB9861501D990FF12D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ineligibility for double benefits</header><text>No borrower may, for the same service, receive a reduction of loan obligations or a loan repayment under both—</text>
<paragraph id="HEC66964DC4A64413892823D3D3C01FB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA850F32511B74FA89D7B694F6CD2379A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any federally supported loan forgiveness program, including under section 338B, 338I, or 846 of this Act, or section 428J, 428L, 455(m), or 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4416C81191EA40ECA720346712213D4E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Breach</header>
<paragraph id="H3E70C0FA77054048909EC998C7CCFF2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liquidated damages formula</header><text>The Secretary may establish a liquidated damages formula to be used in the event of a breach of an agreement entered into under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54BDBEF8A5C0420D9C1C4A061C95FE94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The failure by a specialty medicine physician or a non-physician specialty health care provider to complete the full period of service obligated pursuant to such an agreement, taken alone, shall not constitute a breach of the agreement, so long as the physician or provider completed in good faith the years of service for which payments were made to the physician or provider under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H526D9C18A4734DC9B72696ED2C00F7E9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules for non-Physician specialty health care providers</header><text>Non-physician specialty health care providers participating in the program under this section are not eligible for other Federal loan forgiveness programs specific to health care providers. Not more than 15 percent of amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year may be allocated to awards to non-physician specialty health care providers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E311B603ADB4F88876D753827A38D39"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this section, and not less than every other year thereafter through fiscal year 2033, the Secretary shall report to Congress on—</text>
<paragraph id="HA5A6AF12F7074D32B46C9F48D61335F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the practice location of special medicine physicians and non-physician specialty health care providers participating, or who have participated, in the loan repayment program under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD500782E45424830AD70B88856B5DDCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact of the loan repayment program under this section on the availability of specialty medicine or specialty health care services in the United States in rural communities experiencing a shortage of specialty medicine physicians or non-physician specialty health care providers.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F917D3E58424B30BED751E5C1FC41CD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Data updates</header><text>The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration shall update publicly available data on the supply of specialty medicine physicians and non-physician specialty health care providers, as appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD0E7EFEA93E24E318C0BAC9B0D0155C1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8B1BFEEECA764D64A7CA6A50B299A9C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-physician specialty health care provider</header><text>The term <term>non-physician specialty health care provider</term> means a health professional other than a physician who is licensed to provide patient care other than primary care services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9762F294C74149988554A40AAC349DEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specialty medicine physician</header><text>The term <term>specialty medicine physician</term> means a physician practicing in an area of medicine other than primary care.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H604D7EAE6FD5403DBD98E23BF7BA88BD"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2025 through 2034.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill>

