<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25E12-Y0R-T9-S5L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2362 IS: Ending Lending to China Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2362</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To oppose the provision of assistance to the People's Republic of China by the multilateral development banks. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="id8B0C826A6C374254A608BB68E7BA281A" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Lending to China Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" changed="not-changed" id="idb1a57b7f1518446ab5469b2259ba3f11"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opposition to provision of assistance to People's Republic of China by multilateral development banks</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88A3C5A1C4F340E9A995B47E6B338D90" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id1f5b0fa9e075405391ceaea1a2748a91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China is the world’s second largest economy and a major global lender.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ea0dc8a6d1f494e93a9c49f0c8728e4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In April 2025, the foreign exchange reserves of the People’s Republic of China totaled more than $3,281,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fa112c53a354d97a0d06c933bc13d3c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The World Bank classifies the People’s Republic of China as a country with an upper-middle-income economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e45fd50d2374f699188e299f36bcf39"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On February 25, 2021, President Xi Jinping announced <quote>complete victory</quote> over extreme poverty in the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3161f5cb1e70488d8335945779485d2b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Government of the People’s Republic of China utilizes state resources to create and promote the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank, the New Development Bank, and the Belt and Road Initiative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3286da385d88413ba36537fabb7fdbef"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China is the world’s largest official creditor. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida87f04435cbb4408b7db19b4b94a2a62" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through a multilateral development bank, countries are eligible to borrow until they can manage long-term development and access to capital markets without financial resources from the bank.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf308e55e2e9e4b61872d4c84acf08acd"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The World Bank reviews the graduation of a country from eligibility to borrow from the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development once the country reaches the graduation discussion income, which is equivalent to the gross national income. For fiscal year 2025, the graduation discussion income is a gross national income per capita exceeding $7,895. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e75e117e3a1439ea3999c636d31a7fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many of the other multilateral development banks, such as the Asian Development Bank, use the gross national income per capita benchmark used by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to trigger the graduation process. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideae85c3785c247c1969db3801240d98e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China exceeded the graduation discussion income threshold in 2016.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb31ec7e5873402bb829b6a8d76ebf2e"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Since fiscal year 2016, the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development has approved project loans totaling $12,938,000,000 to the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id688cd6e443de46de97c10b2d53c8c536"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 2024, the Asian Development Bank approved loans and technical assistance to the People’s Republic of China totaling more than $901,000,000. The Bank also approved non-sovereign commitments in the People’s Republic of China totaling more than $483,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id671f0e5ed94d482c87b1388d1bec7174"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The World Bank calculates the People’s Republic of China’s 2024 gross national income per capita as $13,660.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1F7C2F434AD445659B5209879DEA2839" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to oppose any additional lending from the multilateral development banks, including the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the Asian Development Bank, to the People’s Republic of China as a result of the People’s Republic of China’s successful graduation from the eligibility requirements for assistance from those banks.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2693505864294E0797C3654F5B8CEB6D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opposition to lending to People's Republic of China</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at each multilateral development bank to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id9A3DA685BFA4480A8419A554780389EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to oppose any loan or extension of financial or technical assistance by the bank to the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id1DF12F782ADA44F8B2E71FCF2C0F394E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to end lending and assistance to countries that exceed the graduation discussion income of the bank. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1311480117E84B3C8FBDAC15C6A5C627" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="idccf04d2d434e44778e9de251a935dddd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the status of borrowing by the People’s Republic of China from each multilateral development bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3149a007ad04810b979f0b4714fc7bc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of voting power, shares, and representation by the People’s Republic of China at each such bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1f11b38657f44fea59f9c9fc9337cf5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of countries that have exceeded the graduation discussion income at each such bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0090bcd8b0a7479da8ed6da819ec2d8d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a list of countries that have graduated from eligibility for assistance from each such bank; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddadc7a5e9d6047b88160255b76153f45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a full description of the efforts taken by the United States to graduate countries from such eligibility once they exceed the graduation discussion income at each such bank.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93DEC8CF99E2402587EAB3D0229AF49D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idaba314a80df544a0b1cb6d0c2c94e343"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9788F5D6E3E441A38F2A5128E63EB759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4DEA7E3CE0AC457494D08D7C486E29F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id76BC4E97100F442C8A1600E13C9DDFDC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Multilateral development banks</header><text>The term <term>multilateral development banks</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1701(c) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

