<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D53D2601D9C44FD83C7F8D76E4E55BA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 243 IH: Expressing support for designating Iranian American Heritage Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designating Iranian American Heritage Month.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Census Bureau estimates there to be over 540,000 individuals of Iranian descent residing in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States is home to the largest diaspora community of Iranian Americans in the world, with the largest hub located in Los Angeles, California;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Iranian Americans have established deep roots in communities across the United States, from Los Angeles, to Phoenix, to New York, and enriched our social, economic, political, and cultural tapestry;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian New Year <quote>Nowruz</quote>, which translates to <quote>new day</quote>, is celebrated on the Spring Equinox by thousands of Americans and symbolizes renewal, hope, and harmony with nature;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Iranian Americans have made significant contributions to the United States in fields such as science, medicine, technology, business, academia, public service, and the arts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas two members of the Iranian-American community currently serve in the United States Congress;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a 2010 study by the Small Business Administration found that Iranian Americans are among the top 20 immigrant groups with the highest rate of business ownership, owning over 33,000 businesses and generating billions in net income;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian people have contributed to modern civilization for millennia, bringing forth the Cyrus Cylinder as the world’s first human rights document and the Bani Adam poem by Sa’adi Shirazi describing all humans as part of one equal body which is inscribed on the entrance to the United Nations; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Iranian Americans have served in senior capacities in both Republican and Democratic administrations, and have held elected positions in State and local governments across the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iranian Americans have and continue to serve with distinction in the United States military and law enforcement, upholding the Constitution and safeguarding national security; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian American Contributions Project estimates that Iranian-American publications have been cited over 2,000,000 times, and Iranian-American inventors have filed for over 4,000 patents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian-American community is religiously diverse, including Jewish, Muslim, Christian, Zoroastrian, and other faiths, contributing to the rich cultural mosaic of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many Iranian Americans have overcome significant hardships as immigrants and refugees fleeing the brutal and dictatorial Islamic Republic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian-American community has turned adversity into action, with thousands taking part in the peaceful <quote>Woman, Life, Freedom</quote> protests across the United States to demand an end to the Islamic Republic’s violence, including against Iranian women and ethnic minorities and repression of the Iranian people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on January 26, 2023, the United States House of Representatives passed House Concurrent Resolution 7, commending the bravery, courage, and resolve of the Iranian people; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Iranian-American community is an integral part of American society, and their contributions, culture, and spirit have made our Nation a better place: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6DA4030864184D49BBCAD406B4AABD8D"> 
<section id="HF4056D44AC61494DA1035803B0718638" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HB41537CB13764F1B93F96D6D12C8194F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of Iranian American Heritage Month;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF587DFEDE0B4444BBB8FD90E4B35B86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the significant contributions Iranian Americans have made to our Nation’s culture, economy, and developments in the fields of science, medicine, and technology;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C670A65AFAF4DE0A65F77CB0940EEBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe Iranian American Heritage Month with appropriate programs, activities, and celebrations, such as the <quote>Nowruz</quote> new year celebration; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36CDC21070B349AFA9115682E6AE13EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>continues to stand with Iranian Americans and the Iranian people in their fight for a free and democratic Iran.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

