<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25098-WF8-ML-WGJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S426 IS: Ensuring Accountability and Dignity in Government Contracting Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for modifications to ending trafficking in government contracting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Accountability and Dignity in Government Contracting Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb12ce749a384485fa0e60ace37c46d83"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to ending trafficking in government contracting</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae816f35b7464ed4b8c74c3af9798332"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compliance plan and certification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1703 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104a">22 U.S.C. 7104a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3e31c6cc5f2740ff8676a67f477f8db4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>upon request</quote> and inserting <quote>at the time each certification required under subsection (a) is made and upon request</quote> ; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id111bf781bddb49dcbe13e74b8e8f7077"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cf2b51a189e4df6a0d80f4461eae585"><subsection id="id378a999b0b4f42739ae7b8e2fd96e8af"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incident reporting</header><text>If, after a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement is provided or entered into, the duly designated representative of the recipient determines that the recipient, subcontractor or subgrantee, or agent of the recipient or of a subcontractor or subgrantee has engaged in any of the activities described in section 106(g) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104">22 U.S.C. 7104(g)</external-xref>) during the term of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, the representative shall promptly submit to the relevant contracting or grant officer a report that describes the circumstances relating to such activities and the remedial actions taken to address such activities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0570e56363094799a3d1c60419eb219e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring and investigation of trafficking in persons</header><text>Section 1704 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104b">22 U.S.C. 7104b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id21bf85143bc747149312235baacf7bb2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>In the event that a duly designated representative of the recipient submits a report described in section 1703(e), the Inspector General shall conduct an investigation of the activities and remedial actions described in the report.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaeb5970a67cb4bb984dc58d4870a458a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following: <quote>If the rationale for not completing an investigation includes that a recipient acknowledged the activity occurred and has, according to the Inspector General, taken appropriate corrective action to remediate it, the Inspector General shall notify the head of the executive agency that awarded the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement and the relevant agency suspension and debarment official.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb56deb688294172afdce7ab6ee22d8b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0abb8878e3d481bb1aeb77f92ed8bce"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb6b6f681da340e1b6374e92dd7e1a4d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, as amended by section 1702,</quote> and inserting <quote>or failed to take appropriate corrective action to address such activities,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e7c9efe36b64cbda9333d9953c7b6e9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, suspend payments under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement until the recipient has taken appropriate remedial action,</quote> after <quote>debarment official</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4c21f58ee664e399d07f2fd4d384473"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20feda351b744058925a501af6b2ef3d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F) as subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E), respectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide0df968390d14496bef22f7ac7f5c527"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Management and Budget report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of—</text><paragraph id="id5a6ef0d04af74162a6236bd36bae8b41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amending section 1703 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104a">22 U.S.C. 7104a</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(a) of this Act, to require contracting officials, including those at the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, the Department of State, and the United States Agency for International Development, to assess compliance of contractor anti-trafficking plans for product and service categories and geographic locations that Federal agencies identify as higher risk for human trafficking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d1004538d204fcea8e3f58affc622ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>streamlining agency reporting required by Federal trafficking victims protection laws to promote efficiency while meeting congressional information needs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id376af27c813742608a0b922e03426f80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requiring Federal agencies, such as the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, the Department of State, and the United States Agency for International Development, to track and report whether contracting personnel have taken anti-trafficking acquisition training explaining their responsibilities to combat human trafficking. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

