<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA25369-WDT-2X-DJ0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2436 IS: Healthy Drinking Water Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2436</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on
                    Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to establish a
            grant program to assist with the purchase, installation, and maintenance of
            point-of-entry and point-of-use drinking water quality improvement products, and for
 other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Drinking Water Affordability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Healthy H2O Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc6fabbf63a784b69abe23fb22e5a6f2a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="idccc424d786a448338e3520f18c020c80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>clean and safe drinking water is necessary to ensure public health and a vibrant economy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92aeaf4522264b4d90929a6f7b480114"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communities that are dependent on private groundwater supplies to meet domestic drinking water needs, as well as those that continue to experience drinking water infrastructure challenges from public water supplies, including with infrastructure into and within households and living facilities, are disproportionately impacted by drinking water quality issues;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id62707b7b6d45471993427dc52eda4a79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in many instances, those communities and their households have been adversely impacted by the presence of 1 or more naturally occurring and human-caused contaminants found in drinking water, such as lead, arsenic, nitrate, nitrite, and volatile organic compounds, as well as federally unregulated contaminants, including perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances and hexavalent chromium (chrome-6), in local groundwater or other drinking water supplies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf50c3f65afbb40838d76f340a948c76f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>public health organizations and institutions, such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, have cited giardia, enterovirus, radon, rotovirus, norovirus, shigella, campylobacter, salmonella, hepatitis A, cryptosporidium, and e. coli as among the major diseases and contaminants that can be present in drinking water sources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1216286bbfdc441abb84f80c479e6424"><enum>(5)</enum><text>investments in projects to improve and support drinking water infrastructure are critically important to addressing water quality in the United States, but because those projects can typically take many years to complete, the current, and in some cases the ongoing, needs of communities impacted with immediate drinking water quality challenges cannot be or are not addressed in a timely manner;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65e763c461304108b372204eabfc05aa"><enum>(6)</enum><text>as an interim measure (and in some cases in rural areas, for longer term or permanently), point-of-entry and point-of-use water quality improvement products are viable solutions to address drinking water contamination challenges for the people of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7de8a2d3a55247b9bd3e46dca7dee10a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>grants provided under this Act are intended to provide financial assistance for eligible grant recipients (as defined in section 306F(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (as added by section 3)) that voluntarily seek to improve the quality of the drinking water of eligible end users (as defined in that section), and not to demonstrate that an eligible end user is in compliance with a Federal, State, or local primary drinking water standard or regulation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id83631ad1741d4cde8995f2c718cf77d6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Healthy drinking water affordability assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle A of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act is amended by inserting after section 306E (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926e">7 U.S.C. 1926e</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c8022d3e7ac493fac28e29bba06eda8"><section id="id971b6fce78ea4117921e6bbde0909244"><enum>306F.</enum><header>Healthy drinking water affordability assistance program</header><subsection id="id71306e72669044e38dbf523774cdd384"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id6ec8bd846bf441468a0c83a93c9ca269"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved installation</header><text>The term <term>approved installation</term> means the installation of an eligible drinking water quality improvement product or a certified filter component by a qualified third-party installer that—</text><subparagraph id="id60bdd84997da47fbb1c5a858ca967890"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complies with all local and State regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4edb6a7b82c94bbba2e14c59688c3020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>follows the installation instructions of the manufacturer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id24605cbedd204204930be2ef8ba12784"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved maintenance</header><text>The term <term>approved maintenance</term> means required maintenance—</text><subparagraph id="idee2262d758064f33a427ec6e397ed023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performed on an eligible drinking water quality improvement product that includes maintenance and replacement of the certified filter component;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2764b185138d4480918b507f1fef7e3b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>performed by a service technician who—</text><clause id="id0b9c3afabd664f2784d823704946275c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is—</text><subclause id="id6df6b7a256b04914aa379213bb7db926"><enum>(I)</enum><text>professionally qualified, certified, or licensed as a water treatment product maintenance professional, including a professional credentialed through a manufacturer or third party;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7a007fbb1b7649c28f64ab9ead4cded9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>operating under the supervision of a service technician described in subclause (I);</text></subclause><subclause id="id92d7143919bd4705a20c33a313efddeb"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a licensed plumber or a plumber operating under the supervision of a licensed plumbing contractor; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id85e70e22c39a4ee9a4c6e9e176ea41e9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an individual who holds a license or certification related to water treatment technologies issued by a State or local government; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id1666e71042f84ae98498f3cf00eb98ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regularly completes continuing education on water treatment technology and other subjects that enhance the services provided under this section;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2de3aac4d79c45209bed3f1854cd7d92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that complies with all local and State regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id762d928a5b284871b2f6d3cc23a45760"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that follows the maintenance instructions of the manufacturer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id704e3b5fdb374f6485f19a8405d51274"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certified filter component</header><text>The term <term>certified filter component</term> means a replaceable or replacement filter component—</text><subparagraph id="id009a56466ad249dc91b6cff71a293645"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for which approved maintenance can be performed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idded67a7fd26b49f8adea6c0a367dc91c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is certified by a third-party certifier as compliant with—</text><clause id="id984dabf36fb74f9d822daba66508448f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>NSF P231;</text></clause><clause id="id295f26f3ddd54b0182e1f534f6784b9e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>NSF/ANSI Standard 42, 44, 53, 55, 58, or 401; or</text></clause><clause id="idb4964b2c24c74b4797eb11f400edcab5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>another successor or relevant consensus-based standard for drinking water treatment units or systems that addresses health contaminant reduction, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0652065875fe4707bf78b709cd4e855b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible drinking water quality improvement product</header><text>The term <term>eligible drinking water quality improvement product</term> means a point-of-use or point-of-entry system—</text><subparagraph id="id4339e917872f4b5f8745bf4990c56db1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporating a certified filter component; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id328a3faff539404ca38972b5911e6579"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is certified by a third-party certifier to meet standards described in paragraph (3)(B)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b6475bfb4854355b9a14ef2ae477ec9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for material safety and performance; and</text></clause><clause id="id3b8ccf8eac114b86ad04234f246cb09c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve drinking water quality.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id418fe4ff5b274dd7bf5331fb8e29ba1f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible end user</header><text>The term <term>eligible end user</term> means a person or entity located in a rural area (as defined in section 343(a)(13)(B)) that is—</text><subparagraph id="id11977ca41fad4099ad224ee494dcdf79"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1b95e4f653f0405d81b20ad2ab5a3f4e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a homeowner;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id2c36bd65f06e49619241ded9b1686021"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual lessee or renter of a home, apartment, or other dwelling;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id4038d1f0f8d5468e8f59c15e40dda978"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a property owner of a multi-unit residential building with 25 or fewer owned, leased, or rented dwelling units;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id5f2adebae3354862873a0f1e605becf0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a licensed child-care facility; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id718e4d882f3e42c6afe0d69474331ab5"><enum>(v)</enum><text> an owned, leased, or rented facility; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e96babcb56e444189e915fff63b4161"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supported by a finding of need through—</text><clause id="id1666e8a236e547a19e9ba0787c426cde"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified water quality test demonstrating the presence of 1 or more health contaminants; or</text></clause><clause id="id322cef1218bb44fe827b16a5be722e87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other documentation determined to be satisfactory by the Secretary demonstrating the presence of 1 or more health contaminants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa7972c6dc0c4709af8fb4be0ed6c0fe"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible grant recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible grant recipient</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id75e2ab30ee694bf1baf60763a42d1f40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible end user; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71abf5991cd1496bbedf610c966e4dd6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that uses a grant provided under this section for the purposes described in subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2cc0e310c5748fca70be14b66350ac4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Health contaminant</header><text>The term <term>health contaminant</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id7b4840058b3048baa9392fd36fa1e27a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a health contaminant found in drinking water, including lead, arsenic, nitrate, nitrite, perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, hexavalent chromium (chrome-6), and volatile organic compounds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96a3503886ea448196a751f491fbac79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other contaminant—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22e875c014bc45dfa1b1c4f076490397"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that can be reduced by an eligible drinking water quality improvement product or a certified filter component in accordance with the standards described in paragraph (3)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="idd07536ec6b0d4ba88addc62ce1ed8778"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id42864499f8f6407fb3ceb7e5a9fc91af"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency has established—</text><item id="id8c5ba16b75fa44fd8d1f00111355eb56" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a primary drinking water regulation (as defined in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref>));</text></item><item id="id0ed3f7c542bd4d31bd689c2404c5356e" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a maximum contaminant level goal established in accordance with section 1412(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300g-1">42 U.S.C. 300g–1(b)</external-xref>); or</text></item><item id="ida52a8f151f1b4873b5b3761983d5f584" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a health advisory issued pursuant to section 1412(b)(1)(F) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300g-1">42 U.S.C. 300g–1(b)(1)(F)</external-xref>); or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id091223c6f48e41e381be7050e0ef75a3" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is regulated by a State agency.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida38dbf186d50493ca2d3616435490f76"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Improve drinking water quality</header><text>The term <term>improve drinking water quality</term> means to improve the quality of the water supplied between its source and human consumption by reducing or removing 1 or more health contaminants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92fbd82135dd4d518981519a954b69ae"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified third-party installer</header><text>The term <term>qualified third-party installer</term> means a person who—</text><subparagraph id="idcf4346faa5fe4d1c8d97302423edadc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="id588a3f9264f64438bdc11370a7eb46b2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a professionally qualified, certified, or licensed water treatment product installation professional, including such a professional credentialed through a manufacturer or third party;</text></clause><clause id="id87892e391ce94470a339d12e401911fc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a licensed plumber or individual who holds a license or certification related to water treatment technologies issued by a State or local government; or</text></clause><clause id="id36179b4d368d4b1bb2a56feab3a00604"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a company or plumbing contractor employing individuals described in clause (i) or (ii); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id143e3d9cd16b46b29497cc864d91811f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regularly completes, or requires applicable employees to complete, continuing education on water treatment technology and other subjects that enhance the services provided under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c76ea54afea42048011a39938c5f7cb"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Qualified water quality test</header><text>The term <term>qualified water quality test</term> means a baseline analysis of the bacterial and chemical characteristics of concern from a drinking water sample collected at the point of consumption and tested by a laboratory certified to conduct water quality testing—</text><subparagraph id="id2dc55e256d94486bb2ff6df243839996"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is provided to—</text><clause id="idd38c5f4ccb9549329cfaf5091bce3f02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="id8dcb8c8e73a04b4f859bea575de8762c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as applicable—</text><subclause id="id3af3d9ef24a64e999faa2f97dc20e719"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a person seeking a grant under this section;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8d22793736c6493283916a0f0e8959aa"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an eligible end user receiving a grant under this section; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idbc901056665c4905ad0f601a1badcfa1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an eligible grant recipient receiving a grant under this section and any eligible end users served by the eligible grant recipient; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c1f994fe0984e95a2e20966047bf9ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes information that provides—</text><clause id="id14a73260816d4160809116db8230c2cd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>guidance on test interpretation, including whether the bacteria or chemical characteristic of concern meets or exceeds a prescribed health-based contaminant level; and</text></clause><clause id="id8a25fac64c0e4fea9082896ff56f7684"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sources and citations that eligible grant recipients, independent third-party organizations and institutions, and government agencies may review and consult—</text><subclause id="id9fdb4fbf4a3349cea96b7bf0d731eed4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to determine available eligible drinking water quality improvement products for addressing detected contaminants; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id06b18715d6fc4fd682b5c9dc95ee381b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to evaluate efficacy across eligible drinking water quality improvement products.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbec3c71500e843e29d32a931f53683c5"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Third-party certifier</header><text>The term <term>third-party certifier</term> means an independent certification body accredited to ISO Standard 17065, <quote>Conformity assessment—Requirements for bodies certifying products, processes and services</quote>, by an entity domiciled in the United States that is a signatory to the International Accreditation Forum Multilateral Recognition Arrangement, such as the Water Quality Association, NSF International, the International Association of Plumbing and Mechanical Officials, and the International Code Council Evaluation Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida5138c21b4f34bf8807adf662d821269"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to establish, and shall carry out, a clean drinking water program, to be known as the <quote>Healthy Drinking Water Affordability Assistance Program</quote> or the <quote>Healthy H2O Program</quote>, to provide grants to eligible grant recipients to improve drinking water quality of eligible end users.</text></subsection><subsection id="idde07b6463103485e8d4aed045f636d06"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible uses of grants</header><paragraph id="id8a067df311b84c89a543cc6b00414753"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant under this section shall be used, as directed by the Secretary, for—</text><subparagraph id="id0cee4366297f486eb63a756eceded4d9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purchase of an eligible drinking water quality improvement product or a replacement certified filter component;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47aa831641574de18e165b443168aa7f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the approved installation by a qualified third-party installer of an eligible drinking water quality improvement product;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide9331a6734b74d0ba20d2c10fc121169"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the purchase and approved installation by a qualified third-party installer of a replacement certified filter component;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb65e69fc8144613b15c2b66c1ab9b5f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the approved maintenance of an eligible drinking water quality improvement product; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4bdc9b24acc4ee88526454b4bdd56fe"><enum>(E)</enum><text>qualified water quality tests to support products and services described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bd4293cf3cb4e3e848178dc164a819f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit organizations</header><text>A nonprofit organization that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant, in a manner consistent with the uses described in paragraph (1) and as directed by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="id8bf011e40a2742a1a98370b6c06ebf10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to offer qualified water quality tests for eligible end users on a voluntary basis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2461fbb86d64d1fbbe35c6ad3db4b41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to facilitate the analysis of qualified water quality test results for eligible end users;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id592b503af4454f2d921756f4a5efb3fb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to assist an eligible end user in determining the response options available and supporting the selection by the eligible end user of a response that best fits the needs of the eligible end user, informed by—</text><clause id="id19d8c6fb5add4809b9ee90229b85eada"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified water quality test; and</text></clause><clause id="idbe53f1e28cad44108a0b5b06824b86ae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an understanding of the relevant plumbing systems and environmental factors that will impact point-of-use or point-of-entry water safety; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0745f694e3f475882bc9c3eba799982"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to coordinate or facilitate the approved installation by a qualified third-party installer of the eligible drinking water quality improvement product selected by an eligible end user.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0009a0be5dc84bb8a3152fb3e9906d73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant limitations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5aee4b016c3d4ff7ab37b24f00b24111"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a grant under this section shall not exceed the reasonable costs, as determined by the Secretary, of the purposes described in subsection (c) for which the grant is provided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc593c5722734a0e9421344c6d6f07d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Income</header><text>No grant provided under this section shall be used to assist an eligible end user who is a member of a household the members of which have a combined income, or an eligible end user with business income, for the most recent 12-month period for which the information is available, that is more than 150 percent of the median nonmetropolitan household income for the State or territory in which the eligible end user resides, according to the most recent decennial census of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52160bda0f46441eb13d262984b6d752"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant administrator</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture to administer and manage grants provided under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7113d4da960d4893b3a2496f108f4964"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant allocation</header><text>In providing grants under this section to eligible grant recipients, the Secretary shall allocate funds and make grants available in a manner that—</text><paragraph id="id48cfebb489764bca97492dbd1f752d96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>responds to a range of water quality challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4129b2e274141999c5d483477517bb9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritizes funding to eligible end-users the sources of drinking water of which are private wells;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a9336169f2f42f2ab1a8022d41bcda9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improves local and regional capacity to respond to contamination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6009d0ec056443298bbfa8626d6be7c3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensures reasonable access to funds for—</text><subparagraph id="idbee067926f224ac9ae6b714dc8426d6b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible end users seeking a grant under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb82aeba6b7fa4ae5b9596a18ab7dbc9f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations seeking a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a5338d017204484804880ffcf09e5e2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report—</text><paragraph id="id2a9cb736d5744b59be2382555f61a83e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying ongoing barriers to universal safe drinking water prior to and after filtration or other treatment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f6129852a594dd58aed1fa42b401370"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzing conditions impacting eligible grant recipients, including—</text><subparagraph id="id279682c9e70e4bc48633b0b3f747406a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sources of contamination or degradation of water resources, especially groundwater resources or upstream resources that recharge stores of drinking water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefb1fa519ab741f9b2374b90bc1d3411"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trends in bioaccumulation and attenuation of contaminants and nutrients; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb163d3b0aca74a8a85d0ce8013a2ff2c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impacts of infrastructure materials, crop and land management practices, waste management, and other factors that impact drinking water quantity and quality;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55dd579ea377424d9edfea128dbc610d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing a comprehensive analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="id231f5ed1e31942b8ae42a496dec01dd7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>technologies available to and purchased by eligible grant recipients; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id877eacc06c9349fdb86c8235c069b0e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the emerging safe drinking water needs of rural and other homeowners, renters, residential multi-unit property owners, licensed child-care facilities, and other groups, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8b7ca1b5dc9408393e86c0540c97aa6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that includes information describing—</text><subparagraph id="ide12634c58cae4471a6074566868adb02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of treatment systems and filter components used under the program established under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide09b21e8dd324a38bbcb43720fbd27bd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of qualified water quality tests conducted under the program established under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id154f1d7a00384a14aead5b29e9988d87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emerging and changing trends relating to steps taken to ensure safe drinking water in communities and households; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecc0d13cb0fb4f29a793b48dd226a701"><enum>(D)</enum><text>trends relating to the availability and use of eligible drinking water quality improvement products, including—</text><clause id="id6e362a0419ae43119eddd8d46738d4b1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>affordability at purchase and through the lifecycle of the products;</text></clause><clause id="idd27d71217f9849fb887190cc5080756b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistency of operation as intended by the manufacturer and installer, including effectiveness across systems and technologies at achieving stated health protections; and</text></clause><clause id="id330ed192c41b488ebfcd2e963b15af5d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>lifecycle product performance, energy use, and environmental impact;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4056b476f23c40f5a0ab44139d15711b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing recommendations regarding the best methods to increase access to—</text><subparagraph id="idb3ded84894e449278a25982e33de0f9f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grants under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68dbdd2a35ce466fb01f790da9f942b1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the products and services described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f24bd4ee1bd4367bd0fd80be1223682"><enum>(6)</enum><text>that incorporates input from relevant—</text><subparagraph id="id63f25f80dfb2441a85c3777c4d4645df"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b2f30e897d84e968564e4fc0bf08627"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certification institutions that oversee the criteria for products and training of installation and maintenance professionals; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2191e5aba5614d738eb9392ae6cee235"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the purposes of which are—</text><subparagraph id="id98022f19999d4cba88a531b9eb5abed5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve data on health contaminants in drinking water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddca366bca25d4ca682563ad6472d67ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide educational resources on water testing and water quality improvement products and services to eligible grant recipients with drinking water contamination issues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39031bfecf8f41b59dcf64dc7c71065b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to collect information that improves understanding of water testing and water quality improvement products and services, including their associated health and economic benefits; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id777ad84c2be749bfbc73517dd72465db"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to increase public awareness of water quality issues and treatment options.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id49b65bfc05c4455cacdb5b277cfcc0f1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


