<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83F9D617BABB41808D48B4292F6F7BA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 324 IH: PPP Shell Company Discovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 324</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the collection and sharing of information, including tax return information, for purposes of criminal investigations with respect to loans under the Paycheck Protection Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB7460394D75A4EBFBFE0DCD025BF0404" style="OLC"><section id="HB8F2E173857E4110856A3150141D53F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PPP Shell Company Discovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9B3DE46FFB08484E9B52440BF77DAFF4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection and sharing of information for criminal investigations with respect to loans under the Paycheck Protection Program</header><subsection id="H66B1E20BC91F472A8772B0A43C73F650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of loan recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate (hereafter in this section referred to as <quote>the Secretary</quote>), after consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee, and such other persons as the Secretary determines appropriate, shall compile a list of the persons who received PPP loans. Such list shall include the name, mailing address, and taxpayer identifying number (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6109">section 6109</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of, and aggregate amount of PPP loans received by, each such person. The Secretary shall make all information included on such list available to officers and employees of the Internal Revenue Service and the Department of Justice.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DB0C3AD35394784BD8EB418C6DB7853"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Creation of lists of loan recipients based on certain payroll tax information</header><paragraph id="H01D961588244426DB6E0EA9E88C59FAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List of loan recipients with no FICA tax withholding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall create a list of PPP loan recipients (including the information described in subsection (a) with respect to each such recipient) which did not deduct and withhold any tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3102">section 3102</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 during calendar year 2019.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB87D6164BB174449A3B80A59BDED7934"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of loan recipients with large PPP loans relative to FICA wages</header><text>The Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall create a list of PPP loan recipients (including the information described in subsection (a) with respect to each such recipient) with respect to whom the aggregate amount of PPP loans received by such person (as reported on the list described in subsection (a)) equals or exceeds the product of—</text><subparagraph id="H2D7CFBF7A295486AB091941A583F3E92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the greatest amount of wages (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">section 3121(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) for any calendar month during 2019 with respect to which tax was paid by such person under section 3111 of such Code, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9DE7F5120FA48C8BAB58F7B691A91E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>4.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFA9F7A642E41A991159B61BD2DC7C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification of list completion</header><text>The Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall notify the Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury when each list described in paragraphs (1) and (2) has been completed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14368586C4C24883AF491EA7814FE66B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority to disclose lists for use in criminal investigations</header><text>For authority and procedure for disclosure of return information for use in criminal investigations, see <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(i)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H704DB61939504420841E4585BD4E5604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H395806E08AB148158D5B05D1A0CF6BE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>PPP loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>PPP loan</quote> means a covered loan made under paragraph (36) or (37) of section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>) that was forgiven under such paragraph (37) or section 7A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636m">15 U.S.C. 636m</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD28BF28A08BB41AC958E281DC5889873"><enum>(2)</enum><header>PPP loan recipient</header><text>The term <quote>PPP loan recipient</quote> means any person included on the list compiled by the Secretary under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

