<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="H11163c62-e350-4162-8969-f5fde25d3399" public-private="public" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 722 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5371) making continuing appropriations and extensions for fiscal year 2026, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 719) honoring the life and legacy of Charles “Charlie” James Kirk; and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 45</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 722</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–299]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</sponsor>, from the Committee on Rules<committee-name committee-id="RU00"></committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5371) making continuing appropriations and extensions for fiscal year 2026, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 719) honoring the life and legacy of Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> James Kirk; and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="Haf37bdb1-ba33-4c65-a982-5ad0982f03f8"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7c9e9cab-fd31-408e-9b16-7cef388934aa"><enum/><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 5371) making continuing appropriations and extensions for fiscal year 2026, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="H1FD09CD2D75C425ABFFA90E2EEDECE04"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order without intervention of any point of order to consider in the House the resolution (H. Res. 719) honoring the life and legacy of Charles “Charlie” James Kirk. The resolution shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution and preamble to adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question except one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform or their respective designees.</text></section><section id="HBE04A0CE664C481983869D6DA304C320"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 9, 10, and 11 of House Resolution 707, agreed to September 16, 2025, are each amended by striking “March 31, 2026” and inserting “January 31, 2026”.</text></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

