<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H47B59EEA7FFF4949A340D24498682273" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 826 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of October 20 to October 24, 2025, as “Careers in Energy Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 826</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251021">October 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of October 20 to October 24, 2025, as <quote>Careers in Energy Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States of America relies upon a robust energy industry to power its homes, businesses, industries, and infrastructure;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas access to safe, secure, reliable, and low-cost energy is fundamental to American prosperity, national security, and the health and well-being of all Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the energy industry encompasses a wide array of career paths, from traditional fossil fuel production and renewable energy generation to cutting-edge research, engineering, and technology development;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the dedicated and skilled workforce of millions of men and women across the Nation is the backbone of energy independence, ensuring the continuous and efficient delivery of energy to our communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these workforce professionals exhibit unwavering commitment, technical expertise, and a deep sense of responsibility in maintaining and advancing the energy industry;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the energy workforce will need tens of millions of replacement and new workers over the next decade;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is essential to raise awareness about the rewarding and vastly growing career opportunities available in the energy sector, particularly among students and young professionals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas highlighting the importance of energy education and training will help to cultivate a pipeline of skilled workers to meet the evolving needs of the Nation’s energy future; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas recognizing the contributions of the energy workforce will foster a greater appreciation for the vital role it plays in powering the Nation’s economy and fueling the energy needs of the future: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF82A785492EC4A79A6ACAB86CF7A0DCD"> <section id="HB923E2BE26CA4824B4904497DE7D345A" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A6CA4CB15BB4858A5C4570C69EE1B69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Careers in Energy Week</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FCF9281505844E3A29F691C21BA0943"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and honors the dedication and professionalism of the millions of individuals working in the energy sector who ensure the safe and reliable delivery of energy to the Nation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77158EF61DFD486EAA157D7000C0C930"><enum>(3)</enum><text>highlights the rewarding career opportunities available in the energy industry, from skilled trades and technical professions to engineering, science, and management roles;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9976CD07B644703A61BB24338514ADD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes energy education and awareness among students and the general public, emphasizing the importance of career and technical education, vocational training, and science, technology, engineering, and mathematics skills on the future of energy innovation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98FAD4D8BE7B43ECBF1708D4A37118C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages collaboration between industry, educational institutions, industry workforce, community-based organizations, and government agencies to support workforce development and address the evolving needs of the energy sector; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H971B31A3C4674B4BB3321172BE245227"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to observe Careers in Energy Week with relevant programs, activities, and ceremonies showcasing the full range of energy careers, promoting career and technical education opportunities, and strengthening workforce development.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

