<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H531E094D8D3B4CA4BA0B329F37AF2305" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 340 IH: The HCT/P Modernization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services carry out activities to streamline regulatory oversight of human cell and tissue products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E4CC601C20F4D7196EE32D35D4278AE" style="OLC"><section id="H08D6B6FC50A34D36A69A80D4A18EE989" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The HCT/P Modernization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBAC2BEF37E0640CD958951FD4B1AE534"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8F86C38FF1004EC0A0B8ED8CDBE5608D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Human cell and tissue product</header><text>The terms <term>human cell and tissue product</term> and <term>human cell and tissue products</term> have the meaning given the term <term>human cells, tissues, or cellular or tissue-based products</term> in section 1271.3(d) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEAC9A04531D485F88B82CDF87824F91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76C5CE5E5AA1467DAC34FF43316D3CDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tissue Reference Group</header><text>The term <term>Tissue Reference Group</term> means the Tissue Reference Group of the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H18E8AED24009431A9188C91B4D99BBFF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Streamlining regulatory oversight of human cell and tissue products</header><subsection id="HEF489F8EA4C1415EB39248E717045C3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information on human cell and tissue products</header><paragraph id="H402CA6BDC8C94971BFE374B532669504"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Website</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall publish on the public website of the Food and Drug Administration—</text><subparagraph id="HDC84A570C58C491A81A7CEADBF3EEDB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational materials about the Tissue Reference Group; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC36D6B4B01A5422ABBCB43563BF22C84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>best practices for obtaining a timely, accurate recommendation regarding human cell and tissue products from the Tissue Reference Group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2641AAF80A4D4A4FBAA38B6C9900F6E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public information</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually for the subsequent 3 years, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall publish on the public website of the Food and Drug Administration—</text><subparagraph id="HD6F8F51AA3E94495A09B1B8C0B3D814F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of human cell and tissue establishments that registered with the Food and Drug Administration on or after January 1, 2019;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B071E25FB32429CAB277776E52E4414"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of inspections conducted by the Food and Drug Administration of human cell and tissue establishments on or after January 1, 2019, including a comparison of the number of inspections for blood establishments with the number of inspections for such human cell and tissue establishments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98E360CA14EC463589D518C589EE8988"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number and type of inquiries to the Tissue Reference Group in the preceding year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFD56830CF1440CB82D62E43118236F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the average response time for submissions to the Tissue Reference Group in the preceding year, including average initial and final response time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FA58DB8E3B04966BE2ED8ECABF24ECB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Education</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall, with respect to the regulation of human cell and tissue products—</text><subparagraph id="H828915227A234C4A88750A45E394A97B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide information to relevant stakeholders, including industry, tissue establishments, academic health centers, biomedical consortia, research organizations, and patients; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2EA002665124E1D80298630B924CB88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct workshops and other interactive and educational sessions for such stakeholders to help support regulatory predictability and scientific advancement, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13309555FF8F4A70A4EF6E3F9C8DEDEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Human cell and tissue product scientific and regulatory updates</header><text>Section 3205 of the Food and Drug Omnibus Reform Act of 2022 (title III of division FF of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>best practices</quote> and all that follows through <quote>other cellular therapies</quote> and inserting <quote>best practices on generating scientific data necessary to further facilitate the development of certain human cell-, tissue-, and cellular-based medical products (and the latest scientific information about such products), namely, stem cell and other cellular therapies</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2029A30909884EA0990D9A952820C494"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public docket</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a public docket to receive written comments related to—</text><paragraph id="HEDB1F763EEEB4A1BAD2ADE4FACEFE325"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the approaches recommended for discussion during the public workshop described in section 3205 of the Food and Drug Omnibus Reform Act of 2022 (title III of division FF of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36641F4254CA4937B9DA761D29F724A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modernizing the regulation of human cell and tissue products, including considerations associated with assessing minimal manipulation and homologous use (as such terms are defined in section 1271.3 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)) of human cell and tissue products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BAF80CFE80D4F599A7CE4AE02F2ABE4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, the Secretary shall summarize the approaches discussed in the public workshop described in section 3205 of the Food and Drug Omnibus Reform Act of 2022 (title III of division FF of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>) and the public docket described in subsection (c), and develop recommendations regarding the regulation of human cell and tissue products, including provisions under sections 1271.10(a) and 1271.3 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, taking into account—</text><paragraph id="HFC68401A6BF14C56AB35D1FDC35D7634"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regulatory burden;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H111229FC94B14ACCB3C46DEC1FD0E8DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>scientific developments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2541D5E9C154CADB6DD09F98D7299E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to human cell and tissue products regulated under section 361 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/264">42 U.S.C. 264</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H067F9C048A34432FAFC62B44F3C64E45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>protecting public health.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

