<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HC2652EBB63644970BE0666FE91B06D80" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1276 RH: To remove restrictions from a parcel of land in Paducah, Kentucky.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 237</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1276</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–281]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 13, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove restrictions from a parcel of land in Paducah, Kentucky.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H4830923324D64B32A0E040A8F8669982"><section id="H2B0D1662DAD0453BB84D07747F82FB08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Removal of restriction</header><subsection id="H603AC256AC394E3F8793F3A383AE6A9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall execute such instruments as may be necessary to remove all deed restrictions from the parcel of land described in subsection (d), subject to the conditions in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBDCACE6057044DB7AEA7D5403D2F5D14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deed restrictions</header><text>The deed restrictions referred to in subsection (a) are those restrictions, including easements, exceptions, reservations, terms, conditions, and covenants described in the quitclaim deed from the United States to the City of Paducah, Kentucky, executed on April 27, 2012, and recorded by the Clerk of the County Court of McCracken County, Kentucky, on pages 247 through 260 of Deed Book 1229.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9CC2955D7B614C73971B311DD797599A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions of extinguishment</header><text>In removing the deed restrictions under subsection (a), the Secretary shall include a reservation requiring that—</text><paragraph id="H0248A61ABFE64BC89451954EBC933C10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the City of Paducah, Kentucky, not transfer or sell the parcel of land to any other entity, except the Oscar Cross Boys &amp; Girls Club of Paducah;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83203FF7E9EA413BACEC9BB75D7D216A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the City of Paducah, Kentucky, transfers or sells such parcel to the Oscar Cross Boys &amp; Girls Club of Paducah, that the Oscar Cross Boys &amp; Girls Club of Paducah offers to convey the parcel of land to the Secretary, without consideration, prior to conveying the property to any other entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA1FBB68541447A393F2E159202D27B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any new use or development of the parcel of land continue to be compatible with public use or recreation purposes. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78EDB82204404697B9F16D25449E08F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Land description</header><text>The parcel of land referred to in subsection (a) is the parcel—</text><paragraph id="H39AFCEDEE4FD45D9BF681C7FB4C5BA31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comprised of approximately 3.62 acres located at 2956 Park Avenue, on the Paducah Memorial Army Reserve Center, Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky, including the improvements thereon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CE11F3286114732803BE47E34ABD005"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conveyed by the Secretary to the City of Paducah, Kentucky.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

