<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC06918F1D6414B1C9DA54E51D34BAF0F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 220 IH: Veterans Infertility Treatment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250107">January 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide coverage for infertility treatment and standard fertility preservation services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55BFB5104F854DCE9585F8C703F632E7" style="OLC"><section id="HBD44541D27484C0A9BD3F03DF8210640" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Infertility Treatment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12707A13D1444EF5AC7E6F78A34CF313"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Infertility treatments for veterans</header><subsection id="H6A87641D240A4A2F9ED00358C9C330A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">Chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720J">section 1720J</external-xref> the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADFF508579C84682845FD6622A7422B1" style="USC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F836EFA6A8B4066AF834FAE2975C903" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1720K.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Infertility treatment and standard fertility preservation services</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEFCD0AAE1FE42FFA3B23FD3D450DC48"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment and services</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H97CD6AC86E12419FBC39CEA9310FA8EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furnishing medical services under this chapter, at the election of a covered individual and subject to paragraph (4), the Secretary shall furnish to the covered individual infertility treatments (including through the use of assisted reproductive technology), standard fertility preservation services, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5800DAD3B1E54F558B22F8EACF653489" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of in vitro fertilization treatment furnished under paragraph (1), the Secretary may furnish to a covered individual under such paragraph not more than three completed in vitro fertilization cycles that result in live birth or 10 attempted in vitro fertilization cycles, whichever occurs first.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA752FB86E1BE4BF982938D741388B6BD" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may furnish in vitro fertilization treatment under paragraph (1) using donated gametes or embryos.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19FABF29544C46AB9A5F21B4A162E4E9" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not furnish to a covered individual an in vitro fertilization cycle or other treatment or service under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary receives consent for such cycle, treatment, or service from each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA9FEEB649396489CA867627A24248BC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The covered individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA004EA0AB5254E63A0F45E123F6D9D3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the covered individual is a partner of a covered veteran, the covered veteran.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D5F4803CCBF4C1AB79B3EED1B03A015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If applicable, the third-party donor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEFE86D7C9A44010BB5396A618D2748C"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Secretary to furnish maternity care to a covered individual, in addition to what is otherwise required by section 1786 of this title or other provisions of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD3B84A040B604EAA99E81F23F54F4D60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The legal status, custody, future use, donation, disposition, or destruction, of gametes or embryos relating to treatment or services furnished under this section shall be determined in accordance with the law of the State in which the gametes or embryos are located.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDEB6D3BC18504C9DA27DB4E588196638" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payments for beneficiary travel for partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paying travel expenses under section 111 of this title for treatment or services furnished under this section to a partner of a covered veteran, the Secretary shall deem the partner to be a veteran receiving treatment or care under this chapter.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13966D7AB6A4489A8DCB9120B96D5F3B"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HBC209C972AF34CB0BBA910767A90580C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>assisted reproductive technology</term> includes in vitro fertilization and other infertility treatments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CD7FF08E8944106B19B7ABDB3E51303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means a covered veteran or a partner of a covered veteran.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H320331628C41436FA2098DECA16E6640"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered veteran</term> means a veteran who is enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment established under section 1705(a) of this title and—</text><subparagraph id="H45C47404AA564423887D5FB235B3A439"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has infertility; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08EBE018781B49C1945137CB755CC65F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is at risk of having infertility, as determined by a licensed physician based on—</text><clause id="H46B5E3A17A5945D3804DA33DD1DA5B1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the medical, sexual, and reproductive history, age, physical findings, or diagnostic testing, or a combination thereof, of the veteran; or</text></clause><clause id="H9E008E779322412EAC8CDA3F37057F87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any planned medication therapy, surgery, radiation, chemotherapy, or other medical treatment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5800FF150CCB4D7C9824BABECBE04D6B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>infertility</quote> means a disease, condition, or status characterized by—</text><subparagraph id="H2147394563914D979BDFAC6270252AA8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the inability of a person to reproduce either as an individual or with the partner of the individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF748CFC85B4A128C9814DAF6D67B41" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the failure to conceive a pregnancy or to carry a pregnancy to live birth after one year of regular, unprotected sexual intercourse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H473E500E08E943D5810CDD4FE820AF26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>partner</term>, with respect to a veteran, means an individual selected by the veteran who agrees to share with the veteran the parental responsibilities with respect to any child born as a result of the use of any infertility treatment under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBF48ABFA55F479B9C4AD8C57EA0DD20" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>standard fertility preservation service</quote> includes the procurement, cryopreservation, and storage of gametes and embryos.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA1E1C5C3ECE9473290230A3FEB433D3F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicability; regulations</header><paragraph id="H349609120F734FCDBA854140201124B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by paragraph (3)(A), section 1720K of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to infertility treatment and standard fertility preservation services furnished by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs beginning on the date on which the Secretary prescribes regulations under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35B27BE4E4964DF185142A1359C2F728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out section 1720K of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8CCF1BF5E44C8D9B50B8738D4C9B44" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interim policies</header><subparagraph id="H9C28311FB46C49928D3A838750E5E541" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Continuity of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subparagraph (B), an individual who on the day before the date on which the Secretary prescribes regulations under paragraph (2) is receiving counseling and treatment furnished by the Secretary pursuant to existing infertility authority may elect to—</text><clause id="HADBFE1CB70B6468BB05330E0C30F87D0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue receiving such counseling and services pursuant to the existing infertility authority, subject to the limitations of that authority; or</text></clause><clause id="H6A6028CD6AB24CB2B869E62E9DA8B905" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begin receiving such counseling and services pursuant to section 1720K of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), subject to the limitations of that section that shall be applied in a manner that recognizes such counseling and services previously furnished under the existing infertility authority.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB52D2671343F4820AE7F8FE9DFCF5727" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expansion of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the Secretary prescribes regulations under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall ensure that counseling and treatment furnished pursuant to existing infertility authority include the following elements:</text><clause id="H4D51C0E1D23042E795E00B6856934EDB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary may furnish such counseling and treatment to the partner of a veteran covered by such provision without regard to whether the partner and veteran are married.</text></clause><clause id="HC294F83BDEBC48719BE5855CFEA5E8F4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may furnish such counseling and treatment using donated gametes or embryos.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65748538C0464AC0A72A1495B2F15A71" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HF35D859A35824D099B08147C06F71C6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>existing infertility authority</quote> means section 234(a)(1) of the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2022 (division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 556), or other provisions of law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs enacted before the date of the enactment of this Act that provide authority to the Secretary to furnish fertility counseling and treatment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H048AB24B08F5406D9C0799CCB1215A60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>partner</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1720K of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

