<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EA1ECD7D2B249B18BEFE3AA27C70128" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3251 IH: Disaster Response Flexibility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3251</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for an alternative block grant program for funding public assistance for response to a major disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56EAA2C1E8DE4F3D9A72E2AA5D85E839" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H57BA0F07982C49FDAD908BF09B353590" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Response Flexibility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H425D57595C39457BBBD7EF0F825054D0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative block grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HACEBC33D39A7429EB1734ACDB7774A1A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H07B3FD4697C245D69EACECDCC281C897"><enum>431.</enum><header>Alternative block grant program</header> 
<subsection id="HB5EB8F72E5A04D3B941865C05EFAB820"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall establish an alternative block grant program for providing funds for public assistance in the event of a major disaster declared by the President under this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H710D6D3212BE4109B81265AFE41479CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment of cost of public assistance</header> <paragraph id="H1ED4ECDE6EE1414C9C368DE8073E5764"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment required</header><text>In the event of a major disaster described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19DA153D91DA46F48B8331C00DCDC885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the cost of public assistance of each impacted State that would otherwise eligible for such assistance under this Act, including reasonable administrative expenses incurred by the State necessary to manage and distribute a block grant under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE585AF425931463E9A2B069FC7DA6E07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced the total amount of such cost by the non-Federal shares that would otherwise have been applied for each activity carried out with such public assistance.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DC76B81560A4D15950F02CC5A64DE91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In making an assessment under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with each applicable State to validate eligible costs and ensure that the amount of the assessment reflects the scope of necessary recovery efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B76198744594645B2DAE4974AC80B2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the President shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFF5C30DC878D4A48A2A90A80920B1DB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process for a State to elect to apply for a block under this section grant in lieu of application for direct public assistance under this title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27C2F444629C4A2C9E4EA855F0CC61CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that a State may request a single adjustment to the amount provided in such block grant if the initial amount is insufficient to complete the activities that would otherwise be carried out under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H030D3E8E19E84956B10E10F2E753FC76"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a block grant under this section, a State shall submit to the President an application in such manner and containing such information as the President may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8482004E7E0A41878F5F39F5EF9B2225"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a block grant under this program shall not be eligible for direct public assistance under any other provision of this Act with respect to the major disaster for which the block grant is provided, including financial assistance and operational support (such as personnel, equipment, and contracted services).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17356803D6E741959F2B9D168B3E1D47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Remaining funds</header><text>Any funds provided under this section that remain after the completion of recovery activities for which such funds are provided may be used for preparedness or mitigation activities in the State that are eligible for assistance under this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HCCB954C455B849EA89296FC902A53D1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H9297A64E9BE84DA994CD556608320D23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State reports</header><text>A State that receives a block grant under this section shall submit to the Administrator—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB8C094EB37094933B64CB90304253558"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 120 days after the date on which such grant was received, an initial recovery plan outlining anticipated uses of funds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF83B7E6205F0485AB66858B26D9B7334"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the submission of the report under subparagraph (A), and annually thereafter until all funds provided under the grant are expended, a report containing—</text> 
<clause id="HFB161B04A87B439CAB547519C4E4F5A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of each activity for which funds were spent;</text></clause> <clause id="H1B3736EC05714D8CA384413FDA2F82DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in any case in which the State has remaining funds described under subsection (f), the proposed use of such funds; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H51927324C86D4EA3BD6AE3BC41EA1D94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the impact and effectiveness of any expenditures of such funds; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5712E7F2532845B89D42207D3074DC41"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after all funds provided under the grant have been expended, a final report containing—</text> 
<clause id="HB9D8A7635BCF4F5BA990945685BBAD31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of all projects carried out with such funds; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAEA227D989D3428DAF7868C6C3FAFE05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of the overall effectiveness of the activities carried out with such funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62B8708FF46F4E8DA6F35AD786B8338F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation and activities of the program established under this section that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FEA5CA3102F49C8B75B5FD74BF7B7ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of States that have elected to participate in such program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H164921854C794D2D9F457CC2D7997B64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the Administrator has implemented the program, including administrative procedures and timelines;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9E58A5D20BB4459A6D27E4F3FB81C95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of any challenges and barriers to State participation and program implementation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52F0B5ECBEB945018F02815263829BEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an evaluation of the accuracy and timeliness of cost estimates used to determine grant amounts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3E4753D3A4F4703BC63F2484322BF6F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the average length of time required to make cost estimates and disburse grant funds following a declaration of a major disaster;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD53706194284720AE5E9318AD0D1934"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a review of the administrative impact on the Administration and participating States, including staffing and oversight capacity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9922B6CDE3D94D7E9C79CCB58208C427"><enum>(G)</enum><text>recommendations for statutory, regulatory, or administrative changes needed to—</text> 
<clause id="HA87F130CE9794A879A5F4AA8D235E5B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve delivery under such program;</text></clause> <clause id="H066898A6D9C146549FED58525D1EBCD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support administration of the program; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2EBC77A707154D06A2FFE6DB9FA26DB1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enhance effectiveness of the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H400D66F528AD49EB83B9209905C62042"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Public assistance defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public assistance</quote>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7B44C538D64341D4BDE33E281EBCD09D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any activities eligible for assistance under sections 403, 406, and 407; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42D91B8BCADA42249119682B2A60C8B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include any assistance provided to individuals and households.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

