<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2E6165490DC4DACB105C970915694B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2698 IH: Bolstering Security Against Ghost Guns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security to bolster security against threats posed by ghost guns, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC3D67C8B6E8C4BCCB3C735770649BF8C" style="OLC"><section id="HE1D06BE42E754F458F000BE18B142BCA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bolstering Security Against Ghost Guns Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA6CDCEF53A9B4E7EB15AB1974898E51E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security policy to bolster security against threats posed by ghost guns</header><subsection id="H1A60AD683DEB46C3B29C02B264890325"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle H of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/451">6 U.S.C. 451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H47FD4D37999C4328AA3261A023A9E103"><section id="HDAFA08039C914284B561D2B0239FF843"><enum>890E.</enum><header>Policy to bolster security against threats posed by ghost guns</header><subsection id="H3A79B8E43D3641F0AB3E2A7ED1B62B4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans of the Department, shall issue a Department-wide strategy to bolster security against threats posed by ghost guns, in order to improve prevention, preparedness, and response to homeland security threats, such as an act of terrorism or targeted violence, associated with ghost guns. Such strategy shall identify the following activities:</text><paragraph id="HDC1B496B5BFD49A693828D3BBA86DF11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Across the Department related to ghost guns and approaches to enhance cross-component information sharing and collaboration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D2B9670EA4A4862873B3CDC34C840C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial partners related to ghost guns and approaches to enhance the Department’s collaboration with such partners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39202D2E569B44519D7A0C3266D9090B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cross-Border threats</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and the heads of other appropriate Federal partners, shall develop and disseminate a homeland security threat assessment regarding cross-border threats associated with United States-sourced ghost guns and partially complete frames and receivers, with special attention to ghost guns and partially complete frames and receivers used by transnational criminal organizations involved in illicit activity that pose a security threat to the border.</text></subsection><subsection id="H428E48DC9CE44BC0B4E60E872CA55425"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States Secret Service activities</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the United States Secret Service, acting through the Chief of the National Threat Assessment Center, in coordination with appropriate Federal partners, shall carry out research and issue public reports that provide guidance regarding how to prevent, prepare for, and respond to homeland security threats, such as an act of terrorism or targeted violence, associated with ghost guns.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAAEF0392635E48D1B175DAE6A8056755" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transportation Security Administration activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate regarding the number of violations of subsection (a) of section 1540.111 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and any other incidents involving the unauthorized carriage of a firearm at a passenger screening checkpoint, including information regarding which such violations and incidents during the period of time covered by each such report were committed by individuals while receiving expedited screening, which were repeat offenses, and which involved a ghost gun. Such reporting shall also include information regarding trends in the rates of violations and incidents on a per passenger basis, as well as a description of Transportation Security Administration efforts during the period of time covered by each such report to increase public awareness of the prohibition described in such subsection (a) of section 1540.111 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6C164CE90B34DDB8900D1D0C1DB71BB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement activities</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, acting through the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations, shall, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and appropriate Federal partners, carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="H318001D99594418C87C4DAFFF40E51D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Prepare an analysis that includes data from the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives and other Federal partners regarding homeland security threats, including border security threats, and cross-border illicit smuggling trends and patterns associated with United States-sourced firearms, including ghost guns, recovered in Mexico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7324A3D3545B48B3BE23D1E44CF6CEA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Research and develop a mechanism to share aggregated Federal information regarding United States-sourced firearms, including ghost guns, recovered in Mexico in support of carrying out the strategy under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B84CD737E184AE6A2DA9F167A1BCEFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop performance measures to assess the effectiveness of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement activities aimed at combatting homeland security threats, including border security threats, and illicit cross-border activities involving United States-sourced firearms, including ghost guns.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H258DCC3BB1D84FA89E11365168F54665"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Office of Intelligence and Analysis reports</header><paragraph id="H7576238FA4C540188168C25C70034039"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection and annually thereafter, the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall develop a report assessing homeland security threats of ghost guns and partially complete frames and receivers associated with a foreign terrorist organization or other individual in furtherance of an act of terrorism or targeted violence. Each such report shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2521D279A85E4B7CAD36B877DC6FD816" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the range of sources for acquiring, manufacturing, and trafficking ghost guns and partially complete frames and receivers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEA1C82AE55945CC806D170B07B132F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify each type of homeland security threat associated with ghost guns and partially complete frames and receivers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H844DAC247F4645F99762E589B0C60A37" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specify the level of threat associated with each threat identified pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DB4893E9555482A943002921209E82F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the protection of classified and confidential unclassified information, the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis shall—</text><subparagraph id="H18D0BE20135E44A8B1D7C01214705171"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit the initial report required under paragraph (1) to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement officials, including officials who operate within State, local, and regional fusion centers under the Department of Homeland Security State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative established by section 210A; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H460F731C5EB5497C9C4E3DCB88B11C48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit each report required under paragraph (1) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE788A0AF2D344C8F88B8521F042BA65F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8EFF39D5C411418FB6B8EEEB4595A77F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Act of terrorism</header><text>The term <quote>act of terrorism</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3077 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DCEB7875D724C67B3A63B37A8216269"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H698F02FD73854396AF0E42A7CB4CC63A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AA67C241B824EB2A867DD0F78D788A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6181E99CCC5F4ED2BCA21F740E3A6A53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Domestic terrorism</header><text>The term <quote>domestic terrorism</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2331 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F487E92F30D4C7CA7F92458CEDF7971"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <quote>firearm</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 921 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A3B59F360204543B1DF2B7A5C51FC66"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <quote>foreign terrorist organization</quote> means an organization designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H650E6E571CB14940853CBFBAFFEDB5A5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ghost gun</header><text>The term <quote>ghost gun</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>privately made firearm</quote> in section 478.11 of title 27, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E46B88AC02C46619171EAB71DE362AA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Targeted violence</header><text>The term <quote>targeted violence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 6418 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124h-1">6 U.S.C. 124h–1</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A6BC9B2A1EE44179AA2CED605893F6F" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Partially complete frame or receiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>partially complete frame or receiver</quote> means a partially complete, disassembled, or nonfunctional frame or receiver, as such term is described in section 478.12(c) of title 27, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6F547B4FCC824C39B5D5A6F434CF6939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 890D the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3899B9389BF341F4A2C3A32E5F366930" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 890E. Policy to bolster security against threats posed by ghost guns.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

