<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H56B00937C00545CC9508984910456848" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2766 IH: Special District Fairness and Accessibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2766</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to issue guidance to agencies requiring special districts to be recognized as local government for the purpose of Federal financial assistance determinations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H836B8D8331D1481EA80C3A2BBBD5D87D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6E78ED35B089400E8B85E4626BFBB002" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Special District Fairness and Accessibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB5ABFB9D2FB8472C9BD797C2492F02C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agency financial assistance guidance on special districts</header> <subsection id="H7C8F419288104D57A47235D3A60F3871"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for agency acknowledgment of special districts as grant recipients</header> <paragraph id="H5A2F638B7BB846C9A7689041AC6686EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>OMB guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall issue guidance that clarifies how an agency recognizes a special district as a unit of local government for the purpose of being eligible to receive Federal financial assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD59D387E61524E6681375A2E87B27AA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the guidance is issued pursuant to paragraph (1), the head of each agency shall implement the requirements of such guidance and conform any policy, principle, practice, procedure, or guideline relating to the administration of the Federal financial assistance programs of the agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B592FEAF0BD40AA98CA01067BE11214"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that evaluates agency implementation of and conformity to the guidance issued pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8EB3279F26747258C08B1A4863C7B70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAA605FA1A2E2488AB1BF491F8F604A23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC475BDD90E984F8C889793ADBEC12158"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF53B17620984CEE900935ACDA894E01" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal financial assistance</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H24E7F7617CEC4DC4B4B2BFA46C3559C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means assistance that a non-Federal entity receives or administers in the form of a grant, loan, loan guarantee, property, cooperative agreement, interest subsidy, insurance, food commodity, direct appropriation, or other assistance; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H259D39F5163F499E8D7790F0ED632D11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an amount received as reimbursement for services rendered to an individual in accordance with guidance issued by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43CF7DAC00004C49A563650852191C1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special district</header><text>The term <term>special district</term> means a political subdivision of a State, with specified boundaries and significant budgetary autonomy or control, created by or pursuant to the laws of the State, for the purpose of performing limited and specific governmental or proprietary functions that distinguish it as a significantly separate entity from the administrative governance structure of any other form of local government unit within a State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EAB94904E234830A90A0DF43422B6F1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

