<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB94BE4769F5540128BC89524978CD542" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HRES 66 IH: Affirming the role of the United States in improving access to quality, inclusive public education and improving learning outcomes for children and adolescents, particularly for girls, around the world.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 66</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250124">January 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming the role of the United States in improving access to quality, inclusive public education and improving learning outcomes for children and adolescents, particularly for girls, around the world.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas January 24 has been proclaimed as the International Day of Education, in celebration of the role of education in development, economic prosperity, and global security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas access to quality education reduces poverty, advances economic prosperity, bolsters peace and security, and strengthens public health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hourly earnings increase by 9 percent for every extra year of schooling;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every $1 invested in girls’ education generates as much as $2.80 in return, equating to billions of dollars in additional GDP growth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas doubling the percentage of youth with secondary education can cut the risk of conflict in half;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas secondary education can reduce the likelihood of young people supporting political violence by 48 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 251 million children are out of school globally;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 3 out of 4 children in low- and middle-income countries cannot read and understand a simple text;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, approximately 473 million children, more than 1 in 6 globally, live in areas affected by conflict;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, 49 percent of all school-aged refugee children were out of school;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education is lifesaving in emergencies and can provide a sense of stability, access to critical physical and mental health programs, and a chance to regain and grow essential cognitive skills, as well as essential learning like how to stay safe from unexploded bombs or how to prevent the spread of disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education in emergencies reduces the likelihood of child labor, trafficking, recruitment and use of children by Armed Forces or armed groups, child marriage, and adolescent pregnancy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas girls are 2.5 times more likely to be out of school in emergency settings, and are less likely to return to school following disruptions in their education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas disability is one of the most serious barriers to education, and there are 240 million children with disabilities worldwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in fiscal year 2023, the United States Agency for International Development’s (USAID) global education programs reached more than 44 million learners through preprimary, primary, secondary, vocational, and workforce development programs and provided nutritious meals to 3.5 million children across 34 countries, vocational and other workforce training to 1.5 million individuals, and educational interventions to more than 19.4 million young women and girls;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States support for partnerships, including the Global Partnership for Education (GPE) and Education Cannot Wait (ECW), complements United States Government programs and leverages additional resources for this important work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government has long been a leader in global education, and experience has shown that when the United States Government retreats from critical development and humanitarian programs, it leaves gaps that other influences will fill; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress passed the bipartisan Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development (READ) Act (Division A, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>), in 2017 and reauthorized that bill in 2024 for an additional five fiscal years to demonstrate the United States Government’s commitment to improve access to education around the world and ensure individuals around the world have the education and skills needed to be productive members of society and the workforce: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD5C8104F9C56464FA336CC4BD7809D94"><section id="H7F35B1925BD240E2A93F42E132A3F8D8" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB09C153B313B460D83D21D13993FAA23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the leadership and commitment of the United States Government to improve access to quality, inclusive education and improved learning outcomes for the poorest and most marginalized children and adolescents worldwide, which promotes global stability, economic prosperity, and poverty elimination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H902EF1F290D646EAB6F15B8D2C99BD6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that the United States Government’s basic education programs are strengthened and complemented by Global Partnership for Education’s education systems-level approach and partnership building and Education Cannot Wait’s focus on education in emergencies and protracted crises;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC525D3D1B26545CAAB74B53446E2F2DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that education is a lifesaving humanitarian intervention and encourages the United States Government to integrate education in all humanitarian response efforts and continue to promote coordination across all sectors and branches of the United States Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCACE2768C1D4B2F843F636468CE0A53"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implores the United States Government to meet its various commitments to international basic education through its annual budget requests to Congress, recognizing the significant global need;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FCBF840BFCD43609B036766EF11A0B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to use all diplomatic, humanitarian, and development means to promote access to quality education for children and adolescents throughout the world; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2610CCCF2D184D60A7366EB649CC9546"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls on the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to commit to prioritizing quality, inclusive public education for children and youth with disabilities, girls, children and youth in emergency and crisis settings, and traditionally marginalized groups as a critical component to learning equity, poverty elimination, and global stability and prosperity.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

