<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H768424CC0A064C19B4741A3F8A2CC64F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1660 IH: Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1660</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award grants to States to establish or improve, and carry out, Seal of Biliteracy programs to recognize high-level student proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in both English and a second language, and early language programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H969D7D0E27AA440D8BE1D0D80B1A36D4" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H3E1D0BD5F9D641A3AF52E6631686591A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BEST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H68C8974178B340EB9832B66EEDA562EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H0C33917AF8534530A35E222FDBBE61D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The people of the United States celebrate cultural and linguistic diversity and seek to prepare students with skills to succeed in the 21st century.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD66448E184BA494395A337AAFC83A146"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is fitting to commend the dedication of students who have achieved proficiency in multiple languages and to encourage their peers to follow in their footsteps.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4FA30DB92AAA4A45913020C5846D78C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The congressionally requested Commission on Language Learning, in its 2017 report <quote>America's Languages: Investing in Language Education for the 21st Century</quote>, notes the pressing national need for more people of the United States who are proficient in 2 or more languages for national security, economic growth, and the fulfillment of the potential of all people of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD1E49E0EEC94B018B2C8644F30B708F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Commission on Language Learning also notes the extensive cognitive, educational, and employment benefits deriving from biliteracy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCED206B84945480A8091A30AEC2D6287"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Biliteracy in general correlates with higher graduation rates, higher grade point averages, higher rates of matriculation into higher education, and higher earnings for all students, regardless of background.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10245E51F00D444183A43535B5C32948"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The study of America’s languages in elementary and secondary schools should be encouraged because it contributes to a student’s cognitive development and to the national economy and security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2FDA68183904711B4D81E1AB7D1A69C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Recognition of student achievement in language proficiency will enable institutions of higher education and employers to readily recognize and acknowledge the valuable expertise of bilingual students in academia and the workplace.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8B752F0D4434C769543613F73EFB633"><enum>(8)</enum><text>States such as Utah, Arizona, Washington, and New Mexico have developed innovative testing methods for languages, including Native American languages, where no formal proficiency test currently exists.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3EEE5FB3C7E3483E800FC58702586317"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The use of proficiency in a government-recognized official Native American language as the base language for a Seal of Biliteracy, with proficiency in any additional partner language demonstrated through tested proficiency, has been successfully demonstrated in Hawaii.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7348C04A83D141A593649702D4F07E3C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Students in every State and every school should be able to benefit from a Seal of Biliteracy program.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H23BD97A7BBF34E60963789C51E49A441"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBC2AA582442742899CA7FF300923D949"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>English learner</term>, <quote>local educational agency</quote>, <term>middle grades</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C89D4B763D34D339DDB42B2C103B8E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classical language</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>classical language</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB8A48CCD673E4B62BB3759EE5DB8C463"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text>
<clause id="HB68F20F674D54D84AA973E201A732ED3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a language that is no longer spoken; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEBA31E7C08214942B44BE515412A1839"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a language—</text>
<subclause id="H47085D22525542EAB96B56B982684DFE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the spoken varieties of which diverge further away from the classical language over time; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6CCD1E85C7184567BFDCCA8C9CE09FFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that possesses an independent literary tradition and a large body of ancient written literature; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C54293530A844E882AC08A1E8794472"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes Greek, Latin, Chinese, Arabic, and Sanskrit. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFE6D5AB89E84B95AAFC3500AAC69DB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Native American language</header><text>The term <term>Native American language</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2902">25 U.S.C. 2902</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H055E2402D19D44D1994D4B3DC9289FF8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Seal of Biliteracy program</header><text>The term <term>Seal of Biliteracy program</term> means any program described in section 4(a) that is established or improved, and carried out, with funds received under this Act. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0ABA4B89F7674D0EAF93245BE85A276C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Second language</header><text>The term <term>second language</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3E828A4D2B8484BA2C4147A046DAE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any language other than—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A7AC384B5314C6BAA39529A6ECE2378"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">English; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD19216E9797845F1AFD580FF0FA4D93F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case where the provisions of paragraph (2) of section 4(a) apply, the Native American language of proficiency described in such paragraph; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E8FC9368E2A46B5AB1BF8F02BD8BA50"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes Braille, American Sign Language, or a classical language.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B63CBD3B45F41C6B7003329A1B6BA1A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCCA45607951F460D96FBD8817820523E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for State Seal of Biliteracy programs</header> <subsection id="H746768630DAE4E1094A7ABB11F04225D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header> <paragraph id="HCD5BC91B152E48E19AC586C177810619"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available under subsection (f), the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to States to enable the States to establish or improve, and carry out, Seal of Biliteracy programs and early language programs that lead to a Seal of Biliteracy to recognize student proficiency in both English and a second language, which—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9CA2B85BA6F94251920D8F964B2969F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be demonstrated through proficiency in speaking and writing in both languages; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H440D4D997A194F1FBBE7FACC75D35583"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may also be demonstrated through reading and listening in both languages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABEA64822B55425084C2DFC4E96A0A75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of Native American languages</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), each Seal of Biliteracy program shall contain provisions allowing the use of Native American languages, including allowing speakers of any Native American language recognized as official by any American government, including any Tribal government, to use equivalent proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in the Native American language in lieu of proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in English.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F8391039CA049B1B2893682376CC702"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of 2 years, and may be renewed at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BE8D3436204455BB7FBDA2DAD81A464"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>At the end of a grant term, a State that receives a grant under this section may reapply for a grant under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F5D781A0D9D4E4A9614F7FC9040EB0E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A State shall not receive more than 1 grant under this section at any time.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H024613003355485C8749CCE2DAACC608"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Return of unspent grant funds</header><text>Each State that receives a grant under this section shall return any unspent grant funds not later than 6 months after the date on which the term for the grant ends.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA5614E14A1F542789AD24A473FACDBBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>A State that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H34EBA14ACB9B43D28B77A4AA46E5D875"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the criteria a student must meet to demonstrate proficiency for the State Seal of Biliteracy in both languages, which—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA64ED0809254055B7D261071E3F991C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include proficiency criteria for the 2 productive skills of speaking and writing; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D2B745051F740C5B66EF63145049D12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include proficiency criteria for the skills of reading and listening;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73CE188C22B44170B24B340D720CD22E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed description of the State’s plan—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCC8A0E51C2B04F4BAD8823B9A7B7DC08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure that English learners and former English learners are included in the State Seal of Biliteracy program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B8D9FC809E6403A8B3D78EA2E9F5774"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure equitable access to the State Seal of Biliteracy program for students with identified disabilities, including vision and hearing impairments and cognitive or learning disabilities, that preclude demonstration of language proficiency in one of the skills identified in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H88A054AABD38438CB828AB2272F6E464"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that—</text> <clause id="H3C48244EC947456197092EFAC2FA58A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all languages, including Native American languages and American Sign Language, can be tested for the State Seal of Biliteracy program; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HAE59378AFD6D407E82A2F4D1A6B5B5F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Native American language speakers and learners are included in the State Seal of Biliteracy program, including students at tribally controlled schools and at schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D0127AEB1184CE08E1A830B688E9A15"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reach elementary school and middle grades students (including eligible students described in subsection (c)(2), heritage language learners, and English learners), their parents, and schools with information regarding the State Seal of Biliteracy program;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8488786104834FA2A1939C1FA7A0F349"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assurance that a student who meets the requirements under paragraph (1) and subsection (c) receives—</text> <subparagraph id="HB84097A02B6C4F92964DECA83B0A593C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a permanent seal or other marker on the student's secondary school diploma or its equivalent; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4B52E7024E8B41C5B959FEA4A2CEC6E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>documentation of proficiency on the student's official academic transcript; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB89CF788669E42FABBC1D362E2F20BAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assurance that a student is not charged a fee for providing information under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD678A3B79644AD2A4D44A5281330823"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Student participation in a Seal of Biliteracy program</header>
<paragraph id="HC98047179CF64ACE91E75E42AC418F0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To participate in a Seal of Biliteracy program, a student shall provide information to the State that serves the student at such time, in such manner, and including such information and assurances as the State may require, including an assurance that the student has met the criteria established by the State under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6D004D2DD44C01888DB7810FCF7D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student eligibility for participation</header><text>A student who gained proficiency in a second language outside of school may apply to the State of the student's residence under paragraph (1) to participate in a Seal of Biliteracy program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8A9EBC2FB6B44E708735A362F9F6CAAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grant funds made available under this section shall be used for—</text> <paragraph id="H952808EEC957462EA291E4E633641155"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the administrative costs of establishing or improving, and carrying out, a Seal of Biliteracy program that meets the requirements of subsection (b); </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB719B59E8A0A4B5F9008F8BD6FD342E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>public outreach and education about the Seal of Biliteracy program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6F3E39E6E284E8CA3A0B5D5D998C85B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subgrants to local educational agencies for language educator professional development, public outreach, and subsidizing baseline and final Seal of Biliteracy testing for low-income students. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6F81578C21D84D33BCE1E4D6DD2B047E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after receiving a grant under this section, a State shall issue a report to the Secretary describing the implementation of the Seal of Biliteracy program for which the State received the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5AFF0F6564FD426BA63D94688C609760"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

