<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87164CDF3B1648DCB7A938BCFFAD4FB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3732 IH: Bring Animals Relief and Kibble Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3732</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide protections for good faith donations of pet food and supplies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H017CD244E46948CAB3B7F45B572B0177" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBE64B3CCC29B446BA7E8B68A66C0195C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bring Animals Relief and Kibble Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BARK Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H295357303C42402E9C492CACD466ACC5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Liability for damages from good faith donations of pet food and supplies</header> <subsection id="HF406288F65384F64969052A69AEFA8B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H1F9F923A974E4E85A2CA233DADD2EA71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liability of persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability arising from the nature, age, packaging, or condition of an apparently fit pet-related product that the person donates in good faith to a State or unit of local government or a nonprofit organization for ultimate distribution to qualified animals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9559E720C65146D1889C05735B422B68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Liability of nonprofit organizations</header><text>A nonprofit organization shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability arising from the nature, age, packaging, or condition of an apparently fit pet-related product that the nonprofit organization received as a donation from a person in good faith for ultimate distribution to qualified animals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8550E32F02BA4C48AA5B8393956E8121"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Liability of State and local governments</header><text>A State or unit of local government shall not be subject to liability arising from the nature, age, packaging, or condition of an apparently fit pet-related product that the State or unit of local government received as a donation from a person in good faith for ultimate distribution to qualified animals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDC5697CC8F644F8A3A690CE24FEB499"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver not applicable to gross negligence or intentional misconduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall not apply to an injury to, or death of, an ultimate user or recipient of the apparently fit pet-related product that results from an act or omission of the person, nonprofit organization, or State or unit of local government, as applicable, constituting gross negligence or intentional misconduct.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A48DA6D936044A09BA5A50A02299D46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partial compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person donates in good faith pet food or pet supplies that do not meet all quality and labeling standards imposed by Federal, State, and local laws and regulations, such person shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability in accordance with this section if the State or unit of local government or nonprofit organization to which the food or supplies are donated—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0AD537DC2D5540089EA3E708E5C64319"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is informed by such person of the distressed or defective condition of the food or supplies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H153454A2312243349E174A07322BD3B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agrees to recondition such food or supplies to comply with such quality and labeling standards prior to distribution of such food or supplies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72F8C826547745BDA77A19029D5B4E72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is knowledgeable of such quality and labeling standards to properly recondition such food or supplies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H05BF5B79B15143FF80A79FA5931A0D60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEF4A6516162F4847903CDA633071E74F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create any liability; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H837FFB0D5CFE4BD99FFE711A56BBBD9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supercede State or local health regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H499268F82C90435D807E67694F1B6416"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD487972C2F28439DBDB6272BA563EDD7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apparently fit pet-related product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>apparently fit pet-related product</term> means any pet food or pet supply that meets all quality and labeling standards imposed by Federal, State, and local laws and regulations even though the product may not be readily marketable due to appearance, age, freshness, grade, size, surplus, or other conditions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F7F44A0349048DAA2B50CE98DFEF952"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child Nutrition Act of 1966 terms</header><text>The terms <term>donate</term>, <term>gross negligence</term>, <term>intentional misconduct</term>, <term>nonprofit organization</term>, and <term>person</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 22(b) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1791">42 U.S.C. 1791(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC11285D215CA457B91A90EE16AE7BF65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emotional support animal</header><text>The term <term>emotional support animal</term> means an animal that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB122DD51A6B34CBFAFB77E1686DB2CD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is covered by the exclusion specified in section 5.303 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6AFED8C72D944D7945E6EA14B4C6552"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a service animal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BCD08EC24B44A1DBB40DE39F6228990"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pet</header><text>The term <term>pet</term> means a domesticated animal, such as a dog, cat, bird, rodent, fish, turtle, or other animal that is kept for pleasure rather than for commercial purposes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2954D0F0C29B479BA78BF3555990E415"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pet food</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pet food</term> means any raw, cooked, processed, or prepared edible substance, ice, beverage, or ingredient used or intended for use in whole or in part for consumption by a qualified animal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76EBB0C7C9054D978803717478A236D0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pet supply</header><text>The term <term>pet supply</term> means tangible personal property used for qualified animals, including pet carriers, crates, kennels, houses, cages, clothing, bedding, toys, collars, leashes, leads, tie-outs, feeders, bowls, dishes, pet gates, or pet doors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAB7F186A532420CBDC86736818DDDF1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified animal</header><text>The term <term>qualified animal</term> means a pet, an emotional support animal, or a service animal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74E4CD716F7946F3A2AE307782CFAF54"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Service animal</header><text>The term <term>service animal</term> has the meaning given the term in section 36.104 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

