<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD9A1B95D9054F9D935A7C343B2E5A2B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 613 IH: ATF Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to establish an administrative relief process for individuals whose applications for transfer and registration of a firearm were denied, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF304AFE77FA648C3926ED7967CC19875" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7A83A71949714DE993336765CC33FE1C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ATF Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75322DCAE9D844439D818EAF81A2FD70"><enum>2.</enum><header>Administrative relief for denial of firearm transfer application</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7538CA069084BF4A98117028D699BA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5812">Section 5812</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98D7A0B5F09A459A994C66F531536B3B">
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23AE68E67208432AA8CE609DEFA53312"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative relief</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A5BF4C2D5BE4A68A481F9FA793E25A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any application described in subsection (a) for the transfer and registration of a firearm which is denied by the Secretary based on a determination that transferring the firearm to the transferee would violate subsection (d) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or receipt of the firearm by the transferee would violate subsection (g) or (n) of that section or State, local, or tribal law, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91B6BE762BA14A8DAD7EDFE7EEEDBFA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the transferee with the relevant NICS transaction number with respect to such application,</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H246C068C89B9453D8EB1C62C8115B32F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit such transferee to appeal such denial to the Secretary in a manner similar to the process for appeals provided under section 25.10 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9353C0FE784545EABEA6FEEEB7714603"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit such transferee to provide information to the Secretary to prevent any subsequent erroneous denial or extended delay by NICS pursuant to a program (as established by the Secretary) similar to the Voluntary Appeal File program described in section 25.10(g) of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5618603C180040A5B23E8C7720A1A1C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney fees</header><text>In the case of any successful appeal by the transferee pursuant to the process described in paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall reimburse the transferee for any reasonable and necessary attorney fees incurred with respect to such appeal.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B5CAB283BBF486E93B27EFD5BC2A960"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">NICS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>NICS</term> means the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H52599C4B9007404F9ADD1911F53034B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to applications for the transfer and registration of a firearm which are filed or pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1D1E5E76834C4EFABAB634EBEBE8FA78"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely processing of applications</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H079927E14AA74339906C0BF20C564792"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of firearms</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5812">Section 5812</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0943F3AE5E54F5ABE1DE2D8C52A2C00">
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51E528CFFC0E4B8B8F03C79EA1C1CA4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Processing of applications</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), if an application described in such subsection with respect to the transfer and registration of a firearm has been filed with the Secretary and the Secretary fails to make a determination regarding whether to approve or deny such application prior to the date which is 90 calendar days after the date on which such application was originally filed by the transferor, the transfer and registration of such firearm to the transferee shall be deemed to have been approved by the Secretary for purposes of this section and such transfer may be made. The Secretary shall only deny an application described in subsection (a) on the grounds that the applicable requirements under such subsection have not been satisfied, and may not deny an application solely on the grounds that a determination regarding whether to approve or deny such application could not be completed by the Secretary during the period described in the preceding sentence.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H338B040F5A564FF1B36C423D0108AD36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Making of firearms</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5822">Section 5822</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding the preceding sentences, if a person files an application to make and register a firearm with the Secretary and the Secretary fails to make a determination regarding whether to approve or deny such application prior to the date which is 90 calendar days after the date on which such application was originally filed by such person, such application shall be deemed to have been approved by the Secretary for purposes of this section and such firearm may be made by such person. The Secretary shall only deny an application to make and register a firearm on the grounds that the applicable requirements under this section have not been satisfied, and may not deny an application solely on the grounds that a determination regarding whether to approve or deny such application could not be completed by the Secretary during the period described in the preceding sentence.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A338742D7414E50844D309950AFED53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to applications which are filed or pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H813EB331490548F8A3B8A211C3CA6D9A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports and agreements</header> <subsection id="H2AD63AB78B444D4494EAE58C3383AC46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unresolved NICS checks</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in conjunction with the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, shall submit a report to Congress—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0940DD7ACB1840A580474830F6A4887D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailing the number of NICS inquiries received during the period of calendar years 2010 through 2021 with respect to the transfer of a firearm which remained unresolved following the expiration of the 90-day period described in section 25.9(b)(1) of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEA007F20EDD4C7D9940118836B0B45E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing recommendations for administrative actions to be adopted by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to minimize the number of unresolved NICS inquiries described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H10D3DBB033AD4EE6B31CB4504ED7AA95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration of NICS checks</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall submit a report to Congress regarding the percentage of NICS inquiries during the period of calendar years 2014 through 2021 with respect to the transfer of a firearm which were administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation on behalf of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB660A7D929794AEABDCF36349127F1BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall enter into a memorandum of understanding regarding the administration and processing of NICS inquiries with respect to the transfer of firearms.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6562747A7A3E480CADF47FB36275E573"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBE3543709F04CD499D1E440A7D9E0AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> has the same meaning given such term under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5845">section 5845(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50832FFF1F624D7A91BBBCAAA9368FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">NICS</header><text>The term <term>NICS</term> means the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

