<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1B85AC327B354350967FEF9A02DBC568" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2223 IH: Building Capacity for Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make loans, loan guarantees, and grants for purchasing, planning, constructing, or renovating pediatric or adult mental health treatment facilities and pediatric or adult substance use disorder treatment facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H80E590CE77C7415AA9F52321BEA5E772" style="OLC"><section id="HD2A6919F73B04EB7A89AEBB33203B85E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Capacity for Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HECDCB918FA674CD6BB6C1D7A488F1075"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loans and loan guarantees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 399V–7 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-17">42 U.S.C. 280g–17</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F6BE96246814F9A96B02D2A4CF84E52" style="OLC"><section id="HD6BD54DEB5EB4223AC5C149B4AEFBC87"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Loans, loan guarantees, and grants for purchasing, planning, constructing, or renovating eligible facilities for pediatric or adult mental health and substance use disorder services</header><subsection id="H12F7E3F351F8487EA740483443ECDBB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may—</text><paragraph id="HF050EC0DCA1C480E87D8BE7BA2D5A9B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make loans, loan guarantees, or grants to eligible entities for the purpose of—</text><subparagraph id="H5C3F00D1EC5F4E6A92CD4E219ACB5882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchasing, constructing, or renovating, including planning the purchase, construction, or renovation of, a pediatric or adult mental health treatment facility or a pediatric or adult substance use disorder treatment facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3403EC792B354A0D88E0FED94D4C0B12"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving digital infrastructure, telehealth capabilities, or other patient care infrastructure at such a facility; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEA836602CC4160A8814745517E94D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>adding, or converting beds to, adult, adolescent, or pediatric psychiatric and substance use inpatient beds at such a facility; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H864D19323CA547879491FD36760A2DE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (f), make loans and loan guarantees for refinancing loans that were made for such purpose to an eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0364A38C50648AF9288841802257ABA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall be eligible to receive a loan, loan guarantee, or grant under this section if—</text><paragraph id="HD418681B588140DF89396B35BF86E475"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such entity is a public, private for-profit, and private not-for-profit—</text><subparagraph id="H91E41591C0054EE6A9884C6088139615"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hospital, including a general acute hospital, psychiatric hospital, critical access hospital, rural emergency hospital, sole community hospital, children’s hospital, or other hospital as specified by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFEAF4BA11B442A7A051E503A60626A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>substance use disorder treatment facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD4CCFE641CB4C5A97C3868828436883"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mental health treatment facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AFE633DC72744E48417FDF4AEB9935B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facility that employs licensed mental health and substance use disorder professionals, such as child and adult psychiatrists, child and adult psychologists, advanced practice nurses, social workers, licensed professional counselors, or other licensed professionals that provide mental health or substance use disorder services to pediatric or adult patients;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6915F95D142D4203822DC50F7272EFCB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>alliance of hospitals or facilities listed in any of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), or (D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1294D5DA7D649BB9410C2EFD2083B74"><enum>(F)</enum><text>health care facility, as determined by the Secretary; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H002AF497463C4626804D12432686C629" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such entity proposes to purchase, construct, or renovate a pediatric or adult mental health treatment facility, or a pediatric or adult substance use disorder treatment facility, that will—</text><subparagraph id="H6FA1FC1819354CA09ED724E1F381AF97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase the number of pediatric, adolescent, or adult psychiatric beds or pediatric, adolescent, or adult substance use disorder beds in a county that has insufficient psychiatric or substance use disorder treatment bed capacity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7054C9B05534D16A6DFE486ABCD0702"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide mental health or substance use disorder services in a high-need rural or underresourced community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H208C507F4D1541AEB83C5D1798365ED7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide multiple services across the continuum of mental health or substance use disorder care; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2498DD31E0A24EC2A0FC692D9BA84B0A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have the capacity to provide integrated or specialized mental health and substance use disorder care for complex cases or patients with medical co-morbidities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB0F0D15258041BB8B6BE6772ABED55C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking a loan, loan guarantee, or grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may specify. Such application shall contain the proposal of the entity to purchase, construct, or renovate a pediatric or adult mental health treatment facility, or a pediatric or adult substance use disorder treatment facility (as described in subsection (b)(2)) and such other information as the Secretary may specify. </text></subsection><subsection id="H3CAE8EC07F7D42BA9082BCA6043ABB63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographic preference for grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities located in—</text><paragraph id="H5B7500EBD7984073BA3D4F4224680A51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a mental health professional shortage area, as designated under section 332; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H871068FB6B3C4AB1BE433AF6A087D0D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a county (or a municipality, if not contained within any county) where the mean drug overdose death rate per 100,000 people over the past 3 years for which official data is available from the State, is higher than the most recent available national average overdose death rate per 100,000 people, as reported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC0718A1A95A40C7905BC0AEE20846CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a county (or a municipality, if not contained within any county) where the mean suicide rate per 100,000 people over the past 3 years for which official data is available from the State, is higher than the most recent available national average suicide rate per 100,000 people, as reported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACFD1DD242344C5D8647F27F6C4533FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Loans and loan guarantees under this section shall be made on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, subject to the provisions of this section including the following:</text><paragraph id="HBA0A0CD84FB34E83AB77120860019677"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may allow credit to a prospective borrower only where—</text><subparagraph id="H4A8107EE8D5542049633AF77F96103F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is necessary to increase the number of psychiatric or substance use disorder treatment facilities to enhance the public’s access to a comprehensive continuum of mental health and substance use disorder services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0350E3AAD1B4C7CB69957DE6E0B004C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a credit subsidy is the most efficient way to achieve such increase (on a borrower-by-borrower basis).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6353EF2A834445CBA2EFAEC69D21C86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The final maturity of loans made or guaranteed under this section shall not exceed a period of 20 years, or the period of 50 percent of the useful life of any physical asset to be financed by the loan, whichever is less, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3C352BE24741029EC45B469AB3E9A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may not make a loan guarantee under this section, with respect to any borrower, in excess of 80 percent of any potential loss on the loan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F6B8DE0113403FB96B2306CE6C21A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary may not make any loan or loan guarantee under this section if the loan will be subordinated—</text><subparagraph id="H031A08F4A8EC4F8F9348D6F706B4AAFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to another debt contracted by the borrower; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DB93C021EF04726A959B7516742FA1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to any other claims against the borrower in the case of default.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A10283F8844F6BB6E123D90399D144"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any loan guarantee under this section unless the Secretary determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H90758252BCD04851A74C4BF505FDD8CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the lender is responsible; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E79BFC9DC04E78A5B5CA5C811B73DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adequate provision is made for servicing the loan on reasonable terms and protecting the financial interest of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF5D50F4BF148A88820028021F20D98"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any loan guarantee under this section if the income from the loan will be excluded from gross income for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF5494878A4B409E8594AF2B74B1D8B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any loan or loan guarantee under this section unless—</text><subparagraph id="HCEBD1663F2C543A3975EB53634764EB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the loan and interest supplements on any loan guarantee will be at an interest rate that is set by reference to a benchmark interest rate on marketable Treasury securities with a similar maturity to the loan being made or guaranteed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9DA5DB921A548149B0FB96ED0547A08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the minimum interest rate on the loan—</text><clause id="H7EBB84A17E6B446EA1164E3B7C1DF221"><enum>(i)</enum><text>will be no less than the estimated cost to the Government of making the loan plus 1 percent, with the goal of keeping the interest rate below the interest rate of a comparable and competitive private sector benchmark financial instrument; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E849D9F05904480893E842318681851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will be adjusted, as determined by the Secretary, every quarter to take account of changes in the interest rate of the benchmark financial instrument.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C2AC791F5F4F2EA430F96EAC42091C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any loan or loan guarantee under this section unless—</text><subparagraph id="H5B5E06C0264340839156D82A37730FB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees or premiums on the loan or loan guarantee and corresponding insurance coverage will be set at levels that minimize the cost to the Government (as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990) of insuring such loan or loan guarantee, while supporting achievement of enhancing the public’s access to a comprehensive continuum of mental health and substance use disorder services, including increasing the number of inpatient psychiatric and substance use disorder bed counts in areas with insufficient bed capacity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E0250FD0FBA48478221BA1AA8CA74BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the minimum guarantee fee or insurance premium imposed by the Government will be no less than the level sufficient to cover all of the estimated costs to the Government of the expected default claims, plus one percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H619327DC98FD41E8976E3FB187707F95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>loan guarantee fees imposed by the Government will be reviewed every six months to ensure that the fees imposed on new loan guarantees are at a level sufficient to satisfy subparagraph (B) based on the most recent estimates of such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18947310CD0D4285A05670CBC71195D7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The provisions of any loan guarantee under this section shall state that the guarantee is conclusive evidence that—</text><subparagraph id="HB015C50203644D54A113146D6A82D51A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the guarantee has been properly obtained;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DDFDCC2B5124304AEDFADE7865308D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the underlying loan qualified for the guarantee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BAE7DBD55A34A49B20634E8219B3AA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>except in the case of fraud or material misrepresentation by the holder of the loan, the guarantee will be presumed to be valid, legal, and enforceable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC193FC8659BB4279B29F0686B49850B0"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any loan or loan guarantee under this section unless—</text><subparagraph id="HC4EE443F1ADB438BB7C9A4953B20B329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the borrower finances at least 25 percent of the funded project from other sources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40ABA2C2D1ED4D62BDFE2FEBF6A6B81F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the borrower uses funds that were not derived from Federal loans or loan guarantees to pay the fees or premiums on the loan or loan guarantee under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H957EEA52286C4331B94C4750CFDC6EA0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H82A728FBB00043BD88E1D9CA7711F67D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall prescribe explicit standards for use in periodically assessing the credit risk of new and existing direct loans and guaranteed loans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D9331D23DA34A57990DF1796321691C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not make a loan or loan guarantee under this section unless the Secretary finds that there is a reasonable assurance of repayment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D632C4DBADA4CF3849535CCC2C9A491"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on refinancing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority vested by subsection (a)(2)—</text><paragraph id="H48E323DE76DF46389B4510C306C0CA2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorizes making loans and loan guarantees only for refinancing loans that are entered into on or before the date that is 24 months before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Mental, Behavioral, and Substance Use Disorder Treatment Infrastructure and Capacity Act</short-title>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05837CA9B51F4D4190161056BFBBBD7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>terminates on the date that is 24 months after such date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD43FED94DE4C4EF8A9CA326B2DA81171"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Payment of losses</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H358E2A8E311C4380909C7A4298B5D924"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Default on guaranteed loans</header><text>If, as a result of a default by a borrower under a loan guaranteed under this section, after the holder thereof has made such further collection efforts and instituted such enforcement proceedings as the Secretary may require, the Secretary determines that the holder has suffered a loss—</text><subparagraph id="H40DCF992902243448CA84A6BD804BFD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary shall pay to such holder 75 percent of such loss, as specified in the guarantee contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD798E91AF9E146498733FA5D34FD2548"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon making any such payment, the Secretary shall be subrogated to all the rights of the recipient of the payment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H748784B1F1F347838895C77C51401E48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary shall be entitled to recover from the borrower the amount of any payments made pursuant to the guarantee contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD3BDB6B50099473F95C1FA4A74972EC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required enforce of Federal rights</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States shall take such action as may be appropriate to enforce any right accruing to the United States as a result of the issuance of any guarantee under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H346B727BDA9D4062AB5F9757A87D1B32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Forbearance</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes any forbearance for the benefit of the borrower of a loan that is made or guaranteed under this section which is agreed upon by the parties to the loan and approved by the Secretary, provided that budget authority for any resulting cost to the Government (as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990) is available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38A6FB6D25C244F6A4C8FE7B58A547EE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H251A57BACA714A43B0185146B8DC1F6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>children’s hospital</term> means a hospital that predominantly serves patients under the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H101B30534EFA413AA334F19865CCF062"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>critical access hospital</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 1861(mm) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D0963862F64D37847CFFE47B0D4DCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>mental health treatment facility</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HBBA3CD46D0AC42B099B724F039DCA1E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause id="H903F7D29309148DE903C1B20B28AF10B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a child or adult outpatient facility that provides—</text><subclause id="H3CB0E9A176D8400C852218B20086B4E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>intensive outpatient services;</text></subclause><subclause id="H654F0F1E6D5D4974BD45A39C7985C987"><enum>(II)</enum><text>partial hospitalization services;</text></subclause><subclause id="H56E567BD18194A3C97C9AA054822F664"><enum>(III)</enum><text>crisis intervention and stabilization; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE27C28D10F864B66BE7D84A53E24DE8E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other mental, behavioral, or emotional health services deemed appropriate by the Secretary;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H103C382468964C4EA09012223B141464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hospital (including a general acute hospital, a psychiatric hospital, a critical access hospital, a rural emergency hospital, a sole community hospital, a children’s hospital, or other type of hospital as specified by the Secretary) that—</text><subclause id="HEC8ACD6E5E214443930703810899E13F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides acute, short-term inpatient psychiatric treatment services or outpatient services; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4884407774AA4C2B9D91D40BE64A4AD1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include a military services program to meet the needs of active and retired military servicemembers; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H651185E2E83449F2B07D3D2AFD43375C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a facility within or near an emergency department for providing discharge planning and instructions to emergency department patients in need of mental health or substance use disorder treatment and transfer to an appropriate mental health or substance use disorder treatment care setting; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62407D5B264E4D889D81DB7D1BCA12AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes a facility that provide long-term inpatient care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F398ADF12594810A7269B1C7B538993"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>substance use disorder treatment facility</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H20D35B9455C64DDB886B618343FB9F55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause id="H85530A49974E473098516B83046A703E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a child or adult outpatient facility that provides outpatient substance use disorder services; and</text></clause><clause id="HC5570FD9BB2441A4A21923D236F02361"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hospital (including a general acute hospital, a psychiatric hospital, a critical access hospital, a rural emergency hospital, a sole community hospital, a children’s hospital, or other type of hospital as specified by the Secretary) that—</text><subclause id="H02EDC6CAA9BD4D529A553F258EAD2E2E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides acute, short-term inpatient substance use disorder treatment services or outpatient services; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4B1AE9192B2D4954803B993A5EF267CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include a military services program to meet the needs of active and retired military servicemembers; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B6E68B605584047BC3A8B2A40895291"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any facility described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC65F9B44176E4B6C81C2E9D3BC9A6675"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>psychiatric hospital</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 1861(f) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66014A6465764DDC8FE4A54B98EC2BBD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>rural emergency hospital</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 1861(kkk) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29BEDAC37BA346B0AA93C76821B8AA87"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>sole community hospital</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 1886(d)(5)(D)(iii) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA29F1D4F009C4CDBBF192D512EDC3C00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H505474B8F8E84D74A23D5C867AB12626"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations for loans and loan guarantees</header><text>The Secretary may provide loans and loan guarantees under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H3979828668934E908947ACF6B0736FBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>only to the extent or in the amounts provided in advance in appropriation Acts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAF580E6D97047C2A04185B9666FA493"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">totaling not more than $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E2D28B0DD34F9A90496D391993AE54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to make grants under this section $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HEA0163D1FD5E4DDCA8734675B366E834"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mental Health and Substance Use Treatment Trust Fund</header><subsection id="H5FA03CD19930445BBD99832A161C29CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Mental Health and Substance Use Treatment Trust Fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>Trust Fund</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H220051CDBF6343B2BAC9FFC82C94469A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Trust Fund, to remain available until expended, amounts equivalent to any revenues from the program of loans and loan guarantees under section 399V–8 of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 2, that exceed the costs of carrying out such program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5296A17004F14811A049D1C01274252F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for block grants for community mental health services under subpart I of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x">42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

