<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H158D1FD0F99543CF90257A053B5562D9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3343 RH: Greenlighting Growth Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 89</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3343</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–119]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 13, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal securities laws to specify the periods for which financial statements are required to be provided by an emerging growth company, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HB9364F18F996424595BCC6AAF589E51C"><section id="HA03FEAB512F047308297797958C4ACA9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Greenlighting Growth Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3E96674F9C4240B7A1680ACCA94285EE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Financial statement reporting requirements for emerging growth companies</header><subsection id="HEB8A897FBDBA41AFA8B5485B0484BCE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Securities Act of 1933</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(a)(2) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77g">15 U.S.C. 77g(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H589A84628CFB428782EBC2A59E2149A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04695F05C1E74432A595E3D6A83B9393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8085FD5E9C674147AC79478389FF4F1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9B7AC5B4A547425CA0E767565867BFA7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><subparagraph id="HDC58445E4A954F7EB58C08092CC4EB36"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">need not present acquired company financial statements or information otherwise required under section 210.3–05 or section 210.8–04 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, for any period prior to the earliest audited period of the emerging growth company presented in connection with its initial public offering and, thereafter, in no event shall an issuer that was an emerging growth company but is no longer an emerging growth company be required to present financial statements of the issuer (or acquired company financial statements or information otherwise required under section 210.3–05 or section 210.8–04 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto) for any period prior to the earliest audited period of the emerging growth company presented in connection with its initial public offering; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED70287326D9472D8A27F5A17A569CC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12(b)(1)(K) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78l">15 U.S.C. 78l(b)(1)(K)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>firm</quote> and inserting <quote>firm, provided that the application of an emerging growth company need not present acquired company financial statements or information otherwise required under section 210.3–05 or section 210.8–04 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, for any period prior to the earliest audited period of the emerging growth company presented in connection with its application and, thereafter, in no event shall an issuer that was an emerging growth company but is no longer an emerging growth company be required to present financial statements of the issuer (or acquired company financial statements or information otherwise required under section 210.3–05 or section 210.8–04 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto) for any period prior to the earliest audited period of the emerging growth company presented in connection with any application under this subsection</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

