<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H715C764FD07444698899D425D476FD07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5324 IH: No More Missing Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5324</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Unaccompanied Alien Child Anti-Trafficking Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD5E7876018DF438C8D469EE80BC727F8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC287F3E66D8469B9F0B5DF6B2AFBFE3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No More Missing Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6DBF894AF67941E3BAA7E13C0D99B20A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien child anti-trafficking program</header> <subsection id="H9B534C5E299846AF984164E3AED3A82C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Unaccompanied Alien Child Anti-Trafficking Program</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Program</quote>) to prevent the trafficking, disappearance, or loss of unaccompanied alien children.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H272627936DA14D5E879555162E8D23A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enrollment</header> 
<paragraph id="H0DC746BEE52D4E81B2832157AC9B7E3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enroll in the Program—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDF9D9BBD0CB4460B2863C4510215E0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each unaccompanied alien child released from the custody of the Secretary on or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H253877E0FCA44AE4B497EDFF89265019"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each unaccompanied alien child released from the custody of the Secretary before the date of enactment of this Act who is physically present in the United States as of such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84E253F22B87444EB141551AFCBA2EED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each unaccompanied alien child enrolled in the Program shall remain so enrolled until the earliest of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE20A72AC7C5141EF905C28E4ADAE2678"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the removal of the child, if ordered removed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H049E0D72561042D4978B93716991A6E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the child attains the age of 18; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38F422766FF4420A8BA7C22CC739D821"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the child obtains lawful status under the immigration laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD7FA541445E473385E407ADA6DBF659"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall do the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0D15376D1DCD493F8F4AAB48B5FDC19E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that any sponsor to whom an unaccompanied alien child is released under section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) is vetted in accordance with subsection (d), and is not ineligible to serve as a sponsor under subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1B0C2D74C884117B59704AA37B4FABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Require each unaccompanied alien child and each sponsor of such child to be continuously monitored by GPS for the duration of the period that the child resides with the sponsor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H494C7B074B684F6EAF7BC937537F7E19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of an unaccompanied alien child who has attained the age of 4, require telephonic reporting for both the sponsor and the child, not less than once per month.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9580F989FCE440AFA0032D40A7044DB2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collect the DNA of each unaccompanied alien child, each sponsor of such child, and each adult member of the household of such sponsor, and in the case of a sponsor who asserts that they are a biological parent or biological relative of an unaccompanied alien child, confirm such relationship using DNA testing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE833C1EF5B542ADAB1448B8AB4115A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediately take custody of any unaccompanied alien child the Secretary has reason to believe may be subject to exploitation, abuse, or subject to unsafe conditions, and notify the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2774BF245DCF4840B83B0A7AB52FB7D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Conduct home visits as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD395DF506A4B488F9EC56BB556E94EFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Visit and inspect the household in which each unaccompanied alien child is proposed to be placed before such child may be released from the custody of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C4C6128E8234C45AF4840AEA66583E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conduct not fewer than 6 unannounced, in-person visits during the first year of a placement of an unaccompanied alien child, and not fewer than 4 unannounced, in-person visits per year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A64FD83D7C341919809C2BAF1C7646B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vetting of sponsors</header> 
<paragraph id="HC58A7A288AC442A69765A9923EFB0BF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial vetting</header><text>Before releasing an unaccompanied alien child from the custody of the Secretary into the custody of a sponsor, the Secretary shall require such sponsor, and any adult member of the household of such sponsor, to provide the Secretary with their biometric information, and in consultation with the Attorney General, conduct a background check and vetting process that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H98E580BAFC7E4516A60184CD625A615B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an in-person interview and inspection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88B5D2B600B54F1BA6DCEC191D02EF2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public records check;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CF870E91CE4429CA1F2D7226E2831BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a check of the Combined DNA Index System;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H591E548384304EE3AAAFF2796B63AC29"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Federal Bureau of Investigation National Criminal History check;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8F43D461A834ABE89AF45F6EF0132BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an interagency check through the National Vetting Center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D682643AD5143969FC48193DC9416CC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a check of the National Counterterrorism Center and Terrorism Screening Center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC258667F0C4441BC83ED1AEA5CF52520"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a child abuse and neglect check in relevant States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C4C555388294857AFA33EFDCBE34F72"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a check of the criminal history repository of the relevant States, localities, and any foreign country in which the sponsor has resided (to the greatest extent possible);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CC9CC92B4BE4704909C82988E34AF82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a check of all Department of Homeland Security databases, to include a determination of immigration status;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H382DC4E294C54820A5F518DFBD05BAB0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a check of the National Sex Offender Registry; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E7276B89B1A47249CAF8EECF075DE74"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a synthetic identity check against fraudulent identities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7E500B9F1AB48948445CDC144224FA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplementary background checks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After placing an unaccompanied alien child into the custody of a sponsor, the Secretary shall, on an ongoing basis, and not less frequently than quarterly, conduct supplementary background checks and vetting to ensure that the sponsor and any adult member of the household of such sponsor continue to be eligible to have custody of the unaccompanied alien child.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72730D17B7F147C1BFACC4D111CE52A5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sponsor eligibility</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not release an unaccompanied alien child to the custody of a sponsor, if such sponsor, or an adult member of the household of such sponsor—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6D62FF76B5414BED8BBE9EA792C9E73E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is an alien unlawfully present in the United States, unless such alien is the parent, legal guardian, or a biological relative of such unaccompanied alien child;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6DA981ACAAA4385ABFD03BE185C624A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is an associate or member of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8F7C4FE34DD148B7BD6A43C96394E01F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a transnational criminal organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4E9A82892CE4AA8953916CD95FC6ECB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a criminal street gang;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF732985953A4928BBAE1654FDA3EB93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an enterprise involved in a pattern of racketeering activity or through the collection of an unlawful debt;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H838DFF1718E74BE285DC49E736CE98B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a foreign terrorist organization, designated pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FD42C6746F848AC997593CC3F74DBB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an entity designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorist, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA5B2F4D26EF4512973ADE277D8B08EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a sex offender who is required to register on the National Sex Offender Registry under section 113 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20913">34 U.S.C. 20913</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBC912435E70466FAFFE26DD647AF19F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has been convicted of crime under the laws of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, which—</text> <subparagraph id="H00D45C683E434DB3AE29AB66E412E1A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carries a maximum sentence of 1 year or greater; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5C3EC1BD51F4A2699ABC4E330291EE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carries a maximum sentence of less than 1 year, during the 10-year period preceding the custody determination made by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9764679883F04B449E7C2FD59603706A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been convicted of a crime of violence under the laws a foreign country; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED4FB871421246A9B5B3F1A615D4B088"><enum>(6)</enum><text>has been charged with a crime under the laws of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, with respect to which the disposition is pending.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCD31C1C20F4B446CA8368237797B08AD"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Failure To comply with conditions of release</header> <paragraph id="HBD5A8BE4B6BB456DAA7826EDCC9A425F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>If, at any time, a sponsor fails to ensure that an unaccompanied alien child in the custody of the sponsor complies with the conditions of their release from the custody of the Secretary or the conditions of the Program, the Secretary shall—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HD9DABE57C1EF49E0BDDFAE904AFA0DB4">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>terminate the placement of the unaccompanied alien child with such sponsor;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H043F8045C6B54B229B2F32B0AF900264"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>take custody of the unaccompanied alien child; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HED4140EC5C544838B96A403AF7F48A62">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>prohibit such sponsor from sponsoring that unaccompanied alien child or any other unaccompanied alien child.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB6A3CCEFC4E24A4AAE82E2CAD01A9278">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Failure to comply</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, failure to comply with the conditions of release includes failing to attend a court proceeding and violating an order of an immigration judge.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4555680708D47F7B39D72509B85D209"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H54DB268BA3D346F78D7EB59C02475E0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>adult</term> means an individual who is 18 years of age or older.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15F83FF8C4E54204ABEEF080C8063A8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>alien</term> and <term>immigration laws</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13EC5EDD55044A44B4DE3E43E7B282DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>continuously monitored by GPS</term> means uninterrupted tracking of a person’s location and movement history using satellite technology through a body worn device.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF43AF16807FC46319825DC053901D881"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>crime of violence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 16(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE29145732ED04CB88F5CE5B6C0D664AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>criminal street gang</term> has the meaning given such term in section 521(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF32CCBA6C43543A1A411ADD752AD25DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The terms <term>enterprise</term>, <term>racketeering activity</term>, <term>pattern of racketeering activity</term>, and <term>unlawful debt</term> have the meanings given to such terms in 1961 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B766B2A2672436FAF47C370F0AA332C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>member of the household</term> means, with respect to any person, any individual sharing a common abode as part of a single family unit with the person, including a domestic employee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27113DDAA0A647908B8652AC51F90A19"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>telephonic reporting</term> means a telephone call that compares the voice of the person calling to a biometric voiceprint of the person required to place such call.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B952EB391D54730AEC973D630BA85D4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <term>transnational criminal organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3003 of the FEND Off Fentanyl Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/2341">21 U.S.C. 2341</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EA4A712885E473C8A4F1075BA86EBD8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>unaccompanied alien child</term> has the meaning given such term in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

