<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ARP25030-RKN-7L-6FN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S453 IS: Wildfire Intelligence Collaboration and Coordination Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a Wildfire Intelligence Center, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id192882c85b39430c94ed2b6a9198c8a6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Intelligence Collaboration and Coordination Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id16d872996bd3402f98458465f0439659"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idf71f80c966c2491889fb7c3b2168330b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>wildfire management is a complex, multijurisdictional issue that requires an integration of efforts at all levels of society, including the Federal Government, State, Tribal, and local governments, and the private sector; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfaa2dbc7d8dd426889276d65ea136947"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission entitled <quote>On FIRE: The Report of the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission</quote> and dated September 2023 represents a consensus set of recommendations from 50 diverse experts to improve the outcomes from wildfire in the United States, finding that—</text><subparagraph id="id815027e01ca64a5ebb3a7dc9ad731b5c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rapidly changing ecosystems represent fundamental shifts in conditions that existing fire behavior models and existing fire management system are not designed to meet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb401d424d6ef4503bb069f6babfd7962"><enum>(B)</enum><text>research, applied science programs, data management, and technology procurement and application relating to wildfire are housed within a wide array of Federal entities and academia, leading to a limited ability to set priorities and general inefficiencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9e401a17cc6445085a256271912a980"><enum>(C)</enum><text>various predictive services and decision-support functions exist to aid Federal managers and decisionmakers in the wildland fire community that, due to the different missions and jurisdictions of the Federal agencies involved and the fact that the services reside in several different Federal agencies, would benefit from improved interoperability and more coordinated priority setting and purchasing power; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0b05aa3d4f94b38b6a1885e27241046"><enum>(D)</enum><text> an interagency joint office should be established—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida22f9be0d26f414c9ad24b3e897d3bd5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with membership from entities conducting research and addressing wildland fire management;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf74402a09d904fdc8ba66f24f6e3283e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with dedicated and separate funding to fulfill the mission of comprehensive assessment and prediction of fire in the wildland and built environment interface through data aggregation and science-based decision-support services; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf75ca72bd0444ee49647dbd4d0c1c80b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in close collaboration with the existing wildland fire management system in the United States. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49a02ed532004406aada9cb7147b91fd"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10ac2c916ffe4818a2d6d032deec1524"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the Board for the Center appointed under section 4(e)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d95e81d64234f0aadbf4280d331de15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Center</header><text>The term <term>Center</term> means the Wildfire Intelligence Center established by section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="iddb5f6793127849e09258da8ddd393ac0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Wildfire Intelligence Center</header><subsection id="id6bbb06a4eb364593b13a8238c47b5bd2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of the Interior a joint office, to be known as the <quote>Wildfire Intelligence Center</quote>, the duties of which are to study, plan, coordinate, and implement issues of joint concern among the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of the Interior, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21262d4361f54cb59bd672253e7df50d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving as the development and operational center for the comprehensive assessment and prediction of fires that occur in the wildland and fires that move into the built environment to provide decision support services to inform land and fuels management, community outreach and risk reduction, post-wildfire recovery and rehabilitation, and fire management and response activities carried out by entities, including—</text><subparagraph id="id8c65a9e6d25f4807804b428f3647f63a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2af79b1c60b24d8f899dbd81a1425d1c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, Tribal, and local governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb79597b9159841c8b065edf5371d9bd3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>land managers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb87d01adc594473ac7ae1bff51a2b4b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>incident management teams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3da535522ed6460a8e780449b96942df"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Interagency Coordination Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6529c9f6af5b47f1b54db9a77e795a5d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>geographic coordination centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id618e147f46a64673a490b34952171659"><enum>(G)</enum><text>land, air, and water managers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadc0de745f1a441dacf4083399689901"><enum>(H)</enum><text>burned area rehabilitation teams; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f134fd386124d75bb7bd777989d442f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>public health entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideeb56c576df34958b956bf032710bfdc"><enum>(J)</enum><text>other entities identified by the Board;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id758884b31138456ea3957ed94c6d6be4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating collaboration and information sharing across Federal and State departments and agencies, Tribal entities, academia, and the private sector on matters relating to wildland fires; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id216af3b142d346c9922472b3c9f85cee"><enum>(3)</enum><text> addressing any other issues the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior identify as issues of joint interest in support of the functions of the Center described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id928ee7e9360d412f8cc65a5f668965cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Headquarters</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board shall select a permanent location for a physical headquarters of the Center within the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idba080b46f1fd425abe8a9ec3369b9055"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Center shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id7cfd9d1f006f43d68f009df9c29f57bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing real-time, science-based, and data-rich scientific and technical analytical services, decision support, and predictive services across all phases of fire to inform pre-fire land and fuels management, pre-fire community and built environment risk reduction, active fire management and emergency response, and post-fire recovery in the built and natural environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd45d38460d174100a506fa99819d7eae"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessing and monitoring wildland fires and wildland fire conditions across all phases of fire, including ignition, behavior, and spread, climate, weather, drought, soil moisture, fuel conditions, smoke, aerosols, fire severity, debris flows, and erosion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idafd7281cd6d44b7c9dfa2bb12e85edaf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Comprehensive modeling of wildland fire behavior and risks, including ignitions, wildland fire intensity and spread, air quality, and dependence on burn history, vegetation conditions, climate, and weather. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3878599f9fbc49ff873d152d588543da"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing and combining existing data, mapping, technological, and consultation services to support pre-, active, and post-fire activities, including—</text><subparagraph id="idc8842a0133a34200b6666b9a0dd0d9dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creating and maintaining a real-time nationwide wildland fire risk catalog by leveraging existing risk mapping at land management agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9b23839ab614339b9b97d1f27d2c2d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assisting with the creation of evacuation plans for at-risk communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3757c469a197464aaff01ba2f52924ed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assisting with the creation of public safety power shutoff plans; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43bd7189b9aa49d89473f5cf9cd92544"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assisting with the creation of wildland fire response strategies, plans, and treatment and mitigation measures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e95aad7faa04c8b843e8e5c76d15d8a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing gridded and point data forecast and assessment products in support of operational and planning activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ccb47d9de254cbf921b65a841dccd9d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing a testbed framework for testing and evaluation of new tools and products intended for decision support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c77e1acac8c4ae49aebaa0f9d52176f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Consolidating air quality monitoring and forecasting data to support health risk information to help inform risks to public health and protect the public from smoke impacts associated with wildland fires, including providing planning guidance for safe and effective beneficial fire opportunities to prevent the risk of wildland fires.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fa0f05d53d34d06998b952500395354"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Providing accessible tools and products that support emergency and land management decisions relating to wildland fire prevention, preparedness, and response, including risk assessment and contingency planning, which shall include the development of a data interface to assist and inform, in real-time, firefighters, first responders, and approved contractors in responding to wildland fires, including the use of any observations by the civil, military, and intelligence communities of the Federal Government and commercial Earth observations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd602dbbbd264981bd638630f8bb773d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Establishing an interoperable information technology infrastructure accessible by Federal agencies, State government offices, units of local government, and Tribal governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca20c9ff6729465d9c6fec4c589a20b2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To the extent feasible, establishing data interoperability through—</text><subparagraph id="idc64fcb72d7da4fe7b4295f69b94502c6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of common data standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebc3136e29de4abfb5b1748fa42b7629"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of comprehensive searchable data inventories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id285c6c37843e49609496dd3df3d5bdbf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with Tribal governments in nation-to-nation partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81396c4fdcc6465ebf4852525de5c7ab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the integration and sharing of information and resources of the Federal Government and State and local governments to support the essential functions of the Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13b203625cdd4cdfac3e06cd44ec992c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the development of data standards to protect confidential information that may be essential to the core functions of the Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide61e682e7fd74d898421275308e20772"><enum>(F)</enum><text>regular updates and maintenance of research and technology essential to achieving the core functions of the Center; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79b26550558a4cfdbdcc56246b3eb6d4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the development and maintenance of a big-data architecture to compile, maintain, standardize, and evaluate data associated with the core functions of the Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6591f97933a48f585eac3296d47880d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In coordination with relevant Federal agencies and coordinating bodies as determined by the Board, and in consultation with State government offices, units of local government, territories of the United States, and federally recognized Indian Tribes, developing and disseminating tools to support wildland fire planning, risk reduction and response guidance, guidelines, maps, and training materials to help inform State, territorial, local, and Tribal governments and decisionmakers with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="ida729550e86e44afc830665ebd9e0371a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use and implementations of wildland fire risk assessments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c2c0ae055a6474084c6c2b37ea96d42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applied use of the database and information developed under paragraphs (7) and (8);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f6cdb1b4b0a4fa3854ef9b675fbd80a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reducing losses from wildland fires; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id014181e006d44fb5aa53707000e47334"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing benefits from wildland fires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03e28092e81b41e8ad4571297a46a05e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>resources available for communities and responders working to improve wildland fire preparedness; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20c1a805e33f4d72b73481a5f74eea83"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enhancing communication management in emergency wildfire situations, land and resource management, and scientific studies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94af380077b74585b6322f67e1fb7fbb"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Working with Federal, State, and Tribal agencies to develop and improve National Wildland Coordinating Group wildland fire preparedness curricula and training modules for—</text><subparagraph id="id90d8a1c42a7244d7a2ffdee5329e2a3d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State, territorial, local, and Tribal officials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9fd3cca6a2f44e02b5d9985a7ebb156a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal, State, territorial, local, and Tribal emergency managers and responders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8edb247207db4fe8ab2c806cfd4cb35a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf08fe7ff67244cdc84acdc25d8fc1cfc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior shall cooperatively administer the Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd51c86f063504ab8a43ede6674f254f1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11f16b4df9ea419ca8ecb0d35df58444"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior may transfer funds between the Forest Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the United States Geological Survey from funds provided to establish the Center and to carry out the duties of the Center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a856057c50841cfbaedbaa89fb430f8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 15 days prior to transferring funds under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary of the Interior, as applicable, shall notify the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives of the proposed transfer. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida40e8e08e23c407da2a81bd42d2ef36d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Board</header><paragraph id="id3b5c8f4857a2493b836640c0e051081a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text>The Center shall be governed by a Board, composed of 14 members, as follows:</text><subparagraph id="id87235d87202843d38574c2d06024fc9f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Department of the Interior, to be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c42629ba8cc43ad8d7c467037322fd2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Bureau of Land Management, to be appointed by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd425d12218af46068d66ccb2401fb159"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, to be appointed by the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c289476c5a54635830dd5cfda96f150"><enum>(D)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the National Park Service, to be appointed by the Director of the National Park Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee7d585459c24507a6a7709a72a6cbb0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to be appointed by the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id901d2bcd871d4979a37d57fc34e15759"><enum>(F)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the United States Geological Survey, to be appointed by the Director of the United States Geological Survey. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6F4A6E5BA3E847098D6B23A076139CA5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Department of Agriculture, to be appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbe234dac9a24ceb94187089fa03d8bd"><enum>(H)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the research and development areas of the Forest Service, to be appointed by the Chief of the Forest Service. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id437c78f8348c4af88929246336ebc2a8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee in fire and aviation management of the Forest Service, to be appointed by the Chief of the Forest Service. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaced58d01a774450be52156834d4ecc4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to be appointed by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4620d2d0d5145b097a8e83049a64360"><enum>(K)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the National Weather Service, to be appointed by the Director of the National Weather Service. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79dfe62982fd4dab997975a21d906942"><enum>(L)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, to be appointed by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46fdfe410ae34d6b933b4f426a49b0e7"><enum>(M)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the United States Fire Administration, to be appointed by the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id200eaef1587046e78224c82281652130"><enum>(N)</enum><text>1 member who is a career employee of the Department of Defense, to be appointed by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8765755a8a2240a4b3c0fc16d08b3c9b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>A member of the Board—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99e950d4023b4f79b3dd55319407f1f4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be appointed for a term of 3 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24c397e4bc74461f873511227d3dd0d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be reappointed for not more than 3 additional terms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0f737714db9412d8a567595e8668b85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson; Vice Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson of the Board shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf416e0e6042a484c979aaf129122dbd0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be selected by the members of the Board from among the members appointed under subparagraphs (F), (H), and (J) of paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb5c1d220fbf5499f9c39ceca5dbd74cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve for a term of 1 year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id624beaa16115423aa9fe97cc97ace69e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Majority vote</header><text>Voting consensus by the Board shall be not less than <fraction>2/3</fraction> majority vote of the members present. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce55c3929104409ab8e9e2ea3e7ad3a4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonvoting status</header><text>At the discretion of the Board, the Board may include nonvoting observers to the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47af8b1305b14826beab5957911f9115"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Executive Director</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8964ae85036446faeaefd89d98b090d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall have an Executive Director, who shall be appointed by, and serve at the direction of, the Board. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id907b8866b5d247aa9bed17690cca650a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private sector drought monitoring</header><text>The Executive Director of the Center shall engage with entities in the private sector to improve drought monitoring, forecasting, communication, and response that may be essential to the core functions of the Center if the Executive Director of the Center determines that the engagement is appropriate, beneficial, and cost effective.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbf6bcc7d95f40ed990afd7d78ad35b1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea7fa68a7244432e93c26c9c8188f294"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director of the Center may enter into and perform contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other similar transactions that the Executive Director of the Center determines to be appropriate to carry out the functions of the Center. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaa04d24a98b430aa098ed61c1e906a8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board and the Executive Director of the Center shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that provides—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ca21a69d97e4f3ea8837ae6751038bf"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of existing contracting authorities of the Executive Director of the Center; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idced70d43b6a74fff81bb3f758d39a020"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on whether new contracting authorities or modifications of existing contracting authorities are needed. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb3546082f2c54735a18511c9c82d0946"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior may detail or assign to the Center such employees of the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of the Interior, respectively, as are determined by the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior, respectively, to be necessary to carry out the duties of the Center.</text></subsection><subsection id="idafda7169f42d4f3785dfdb677c4f166d"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Interagency financing</header><text>Notwithstanding section 708 of the Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 4706), or any other similar provision of law, interagency financing may be used to fund the Center.</text></subsection><subsection id="id46f4ccff0d1b41f1a74402a19240f893"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination with other agencies and entities</header><text>The Board shall coordinate with agencies represented on the Board and other relevant entities to achieve the core functions of the Center, including with—</text><paragraph id="id661c2c18bcf4482b8f1ef8ece50bfb5a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Wildfire Coordinating Group;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9089ef8f8c94ec8935895b8d6484a66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State and Tribal governments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe386055a4af476e8bece4d39ef17f88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other agency—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26b23beaacc140ca8573b769c0fbbbab"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is responsible for the management of Federal or State land; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74ad7e04ad67498c8d48939c0d311cdc"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has data, science, and technology expertise relevant to the Center; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id99ec14fa248548558c43a8a79138cf03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other relevant Federal, State, Tribal, or nongovernmental entity that is representative of an element of the wildland fire community.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

