<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25081-8V2-P4-H3F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>102 S258 IS: Tornado Observations Research and Notification Assessment for Development of Operations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 258</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250127">January 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve forecasting and understanding of tornadoes and other hazardous weather, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="not-changed"><section section-type="section-one" id="id10f5d5fd-1d89-4d9d-8196-cb2022d3a42b" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tornado Observations Research and Notification Assessment for Development of Operations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TORNADO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0ca21d1f-3acf-4be3-87b5-d759b03c6234" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph commented="no" id="idb68c3c82-c466-4894-b241-0c8302604237" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hazardous weather and water events</header><text>The term <term>hazardous weather and water events</term> means weather and water events that have a high risk of loss of life or property, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6e8301de-df86-41d8-ae34-554b27232130" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>severe storms, such as hurricanes and short-fused, small-scale hazardous weather or hydrologic events produced by thunderstorms, including large hail, damaging winds, tornadoes, and flash floods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id2f98431a-0b1a-487f-8c6a-093d0365a148" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>winter storms, such as freezing or frozen precipitation (including freezing rain, sleet, and snow), or combined effects of freezing or frozen precipitation and strong winds; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id257a308f-a382-41a9-adf3-88d94684aa74" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other weather hazards, such as extreme heat or cold, wildfire, drought, dense fog, high winds, river flooding, and lakeshore flooding. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e0582f6-238a-4412-b1c7-59bc2dc8cbb8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college or university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83548a960d9b44fdac54db81626e5e8f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc99c2771-d435-4028-b334-9c08969e9ccd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04e5489f-f943-4df4-a703-715a1e5f8cb8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6e39f9c-af84-41e8-aa4a-583dda5a8221" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id5432d8ca-12ad-4cc5-8e8b-dd706f2a3213" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hazardous weather and water event risk communication</header><subsection id="id7c970183-26b0-46f3-82fd-c7a907f878d2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall maintain and improve the system of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration by which the risks of hazardous weather and water events are communicated to the general public, with the goal of informing action and encouraging response to prevent loss of life and property.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida3fa2efd-35c3-4168-aa07-4cfe97f69609" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hazard risk communication improvement and simplification</header><paragraph id="ide7ba73cb-8270-4e46-b417-028c543055d3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall maintain a hazard risk communication office (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>), for the purposes of simplifying and improving the communication of hazardous weather and water event risks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd68b15f8-8df3-4d59-9ec3-bbc222cfc9e4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terminology</header><text>The Office shall identify, eliminate, or modify unnecessary, redundant, or confusing terms for hazardous weather and water event communications and add new terminology, as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82cdba14-b20b-4594-940a-984c555a79c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications improvement</header><text>The Office shall improve the form, content, and methods of hazardous weather and water event communications to more clearly inform action and increase the likelihood that the public takes such action to prevent the loss of life or property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1a9e21f-bc20-4d75-96c1-4e36ab29acc3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>The Office shall, in coordination with the performance branch of the National Weather Service, develop metrics for that branch to track and evaluate the degree to which hazardous weather and water event communications inform action and encourage response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64a40ef6-4a12-4079-82ca-42c411951bf8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Support plan</header><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id984c5f22bc0744acb93b09bc4654b273"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall develop a plan for the purpose of supporting the activities described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21d7f05f34734ad7880726c546a2d9b9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic update and elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan developed under subparagraph (A) shall be periodically updated and informed by internal and extramural research and the results of the evaluation of hazardous weather and water event communications conducted under paragraph (4). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd04a6bac-d96a-4f4e-83cd-80516f73b76e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Office shall develop and implement recommendations that—</text><subparagraph id="id9cf1543c-d120-4f4a-bd5c-b5cceb58848f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are based on the best and most recent understanding from social, behavioral, risk, and communication science research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaab4a113-c454-4cc8-b0d6-1d8437e1bb46" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are validated by social, behavioral, risk, and communication science, taking into account the importance of methods that support reproduction and replication of scientific studies, use of rigorous statistical analyses, and, as applicable, data analysis supported by artificial intelligence and machine learning technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34f84b29-7901-4ca9-96a2-cd81ae3b9cd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for the needs of various demographics, vulnerable populations, and geographic regions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9be3a35-8a09-4f94-9419-3fa9eb7000e3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>account for the differences between various types of weather and water hazards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8ce907b-b247-4ce1-854a-d0c69f643a40" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>respond to the needs of Federal, State, and local government partners and media partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15109335-3c5a-47de-85e0-564cf9528d8c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>account for necessary changes in the infrastructure, technology, and protocols for creating and disseminating federally operated watches and warnings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id329205b9-216f-4906-9554-97ae66e6cf54" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In implementing this subsection, the Office shall coordinate with—</text><subparagraph id="id51a32cf7-fb1a-46b6-b4d3-22d3ce8277dd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal partners, including National Laboratories, Cooperative Institutes, and regional integrated sciences and assessments programs; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8ee7e26-c058-4fc4-a307-b3375a2dbb66" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State and local government partners; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbcdb6a0b-e681-443a-a908-7eade0f75af8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Indian Tribes; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0775941c-f02a-4f22-ba14-638baeda23c4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>institutions of higher education; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id736b6a35-e217-4891-9518-dad286dc28d4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>media partners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2beac1ee-18f6-4bc1-8886-5517773dc9dd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Timeliness and consistency</header><text>The Office shall develop best practices and guidance for ensuring timely and consistent communication across public facing platforms that disseminate hazardous weather and water event information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf56b8984-c0d8-40ff-8108-37b3ddc72ac4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hazard communication research and engagement</header><paragraph id="id69c110ca-7a09-4f29-b9b7-67d753ea7b3b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish or maintain a research program—</text><subparagraph id="id83857f9e10434148b6f9bf44f72c8718" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to modernize the creation and communication of risk-based, statistically reliable, probabilistic hazard information, with the goal of informing effective actions and encouraging responses to hazardous weather and water events; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ab7597d-6b53-4efc-a366-aa2bfcff6aed" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the fundamental social, behavioral, risk, and communication science regarding hazardous weather and water event communication.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e0587c2-6964-45c7-b631-78a25b993b8a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out the research program required by paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall coordinate and communicate with States, Indian Tribes, localities, and emergency managers on research priorities and results.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide90e8a87-3385-478d-b42e-1af5a11d31a8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pilot program for tornado hazard communication required</header><subparagraph id="ide1aa40fc-7851-455e-84f7-18ef56d47473" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To further research into hazard communication, the Under Secretary, in collaboration with one or more eligible institutions, shall establish a pilot program for tornado hazard communication to test the effectiveness of implementing the research conducted under this subsection with respect to tornadoes. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14cb16e3-b881-408c-9112-20c4e7043bb9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible institution defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>eligible institution</term> means any of the following: </text><clause commented="no" id="id3a88fac6-d0a3-4e38-9f67-a4400b78a4da" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A historically Black college or university located in an area of persistent poverty that is subjected to frequent severe weather, such as tornadoes, hurricanes, and floods. </text></clause><clause id="id17c1bbbc-99ed-4f93-8cc6-4a09de07b980" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An institution of higher education in close proximity to a Weather Forecast Office of the National Weather Service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c8a2aaa-c155-4b1c-9734-dc91a60dd4fb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data management</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish, maintain, and improve a central repository system for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for social, behavioral, risk, and economic data related to the communication of hazardous weather and water events, including data developed or received pursuant to paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="iddceb8130-a1c4-4269-bf5f-a8bdca8bb1bd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Digital watermarking</header><text>The Under Secretary shall develop methods to reduce the likelihood of unauthorized tampering with online hazardous weather and water event risk communication, such as developing digital watermarks. </text></subsection></section><section id="id9ac58ce0-c4d0-4b24-bf50-1a2e41781845" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Warn-on-forecast strategic plan</header><subsection id="ide8dc79a1-6394-478d-aa12-33bde59eb25a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a strategic plan for developing and prioritizing the implementation of high-resolution probabilistic forecast guidance for hazardous weather and water events using a next-generation weather forecast and warning framework.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2619e738-ad74-4153-8b56-f5bb8d005e43" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan elements</header><text>The strategic plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="id7b56493b-64fe-4768-9539-6fa291686fc2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A discussion of—</text><subparagraph id="id59152999-32a8-471a-9732-068ec0ee8759" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the priorities and needs of vulnerable populations and National Weather Service partners; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3c5dc3f-729c-47af-aba4-ec63aff3c836" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>high-performance computing, visualization, and dissemination needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb30db9a9-ea2c-430d-aa6f-aa0255ee8e32" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A timeline and guidance for implementation of—</text><subparagraph id="ide0895655-36ff-4353-9f4c-ac575a2fb66d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-resolution numerical weather prediction models; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3e41fe6-59f9-4e94-a90a-337e12bae9f2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methods for meeting the high-performance computing, visualization, and dissemination needs discussed under paragraph (1)(B); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4177c429-c449-4e85-b7c3-2a83fc29b095" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>real-time high-resolution probabilistic forecasts; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb68e664-eafb-49a5-8a46-58106e65d6e5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improved observations, including through radars, satellites, and uncrewed aerial systems; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida264401f-b858-4504-8488-561e8d332193" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a flexible framework to communicate clear and simple hazardous weather and water event information to the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b02f759-bbe2-4ed3-8329-f63ac73cb5a0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>social, behavioral, risk, and communication research to improve the forecaster operational environment and societal information reception and response. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id51431688-ec73-4502-a0c7-dfadcdd2a5f4" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header>Tornado rating system</header><subsection id="id2cb0c649-97ae-4270-a5af-3b7c088e533e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall, in collaboration with such stakeholders as the Under Secretary considers appropriate—</text><paragraph id="idbfc50068-e089-4e4f-ad6c-8d5f73edd03b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the system used as of the date of the enactment of this Act to rate the severity of tornadoes; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a95abfa-d7b2-4e05-a40c-7ba49b24feef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine whether updates to that system are required to ensure that the ratings accurately reflect the severity of tornadoes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83ced2a6-588e-46fb-b09c-eea0d45c2bd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update required</header><text>If the Under Secretary determines under subsection (a) that updates to the tornado rating system are necessary, the Under Secretary shall update the system.</text></subsection></section><section id="id8c724b9f-ea4c-46cc-ada6-910fa8086a14" changed="not-changed"><enum>6.</enum><header>Post-storm surveys and assessments</header><subsection id="id8e533b2e-f257-400d-8412-86c10039c7e2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall perform one or more post-storm surveys and assessments following each hazardous weather or water event determined by the Under Secretary to be of sufficient societal importance to warrant a post-event survey and assessment.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida9fdb850-f922-448f-9f11-4ad0d94c8040" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Under Secretary shall coordinate with Federal, State, and local governments, Indian Tribes, private entities, and relevant institutions of higher education when conducting post-storm surveys and assessments under subsection (a) in order to optimize data collection, sharing, and integration.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8de22322-de80-4776-889a-0a93770e43c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data availability</header><text>The Under Secretary shall make the data obtained from each post-storm survey and assessment conducted under subsection (a) available to the public as soon as practicable after conducting the survey and assessment.</text></subsection><subsection id="id69de39eb-4d0a-4836-8268-34c46410ca2f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Improvement</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="iddf7024b4-20bc-450a-b477-b798f67e9d50" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate the role of uncrewed aerial systems in data collection during post-storm surveys and assessments conducted under subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf7f52fc-8e22-480a-ad1a-ae4e2d0b27d7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify gaps in and update tactics and procedures to enhance the efficiency and reliability of data obtained from post-storm surveys and assessments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida55d4227-12f6-4350-bbdb-413b4b820fd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase the number of post-storm community impact studies, including by—</text><subparagraph id="ide7dde6ad-5f1c-4207-b984-70b32bc76494" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>surveying individual responses; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0972e094-e0ab-4e26-859d-9c42cad0c529" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting review of the accuracy of prior risk evaluations; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e424596-b35d-4dec-b54f-5bee35629b70" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluating the efficacy of prior mitigation activity; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f4acbf6-40f5-40ab-aa9f-198fae4b5b8c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>gathering survivability statistics. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbfacecda-de00-46b5-a4cb-8d7ba6499cec" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Support for employees</header><text>The Under Secretary shall provide training, resources, and access to professional counseling to support the emotional and mental health and well-being of employees conducting post-storm surveys and assessments under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="id17b22ee4-4b39-45f0-8f6b-f8a2361cf5b8" changed="not-changed"><enum>7.</enum><header>VORTEX-USA program</header><subsection id="id417e7855-2ac9-492a-9590-1c3a064cd9ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8513">15 U.S.C. 8513</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id86089b75-8046-4aea-a6bf-9d3feda9ff56" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Tornado warning improvement and extension</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">VORTEX-USA</header-in-text></quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4e36623-377b-41c2-aa1b-afe0ea83961c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>establish a tornado warning improvement and extension program</quote> and inserting <quote>maintain a program for rapidly improving tornado forecast and warnings</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd7c94ac-5d79-42d3-b961-945671bdcaad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2db5ef55-7e6e-428e-a3db-780f5f8ead7a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idaab59511-eb6c-46f3-99a9-aa2d89978674" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id250d5f27-1460-4c1f-92da-5de065dbe49a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Warnings</header><text>The program required by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id24392bf1-9821-471e-8b82-ebf22e436602" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continue the research necessary to develop and deploy probabilistic weather forecast guidance technology for tornadoes; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97086924-56b2-4c5a-bf5a-6399bab12ed4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate, as appropriate, hazard communication research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19b213b7-b16d-4aa6-851e-3b709031204e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Research</header><paragraph id="id50f1a17e-c860-40d2-995e-f96f2928ff80" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall, through the program required by subsection (a), award grants for research that focuses on improving—</text><subparagraph id="idd747bd85-afba-4329-b54a-b8e9dff84067" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the social, behavioral, risk, communication, and economic sciences related to vulnerabilities, risk communication, and delivery of information critical for saving lives and property related to tornadoes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37865b7e-f5d0-47e4-91b4-c118e81432bb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the physical sciences, engineering, and technology related to tornado formation, the interactions of tornadoes with the built and natural environment, and the interaction of tornadoes and hurricanes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7614448-665b-4aaf-8ed3-6ef79d3d107a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority institutions</header><subparagraph id="idbe971ce5-39ab-4d59-b54a-a4aafbd42f48" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary may prioritize awarding grants to minority-serving institutions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec5f1699-67df-4d8c-8852-0fe77752e7cd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition of minority-serving institution</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means—</text><clause id="ida163390c-67d8-4605-ba63-ee15698201c5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a part B institution (as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="idb36f1948-34c4-44de-abc4-241e43fc0300" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Hispanic-serving institution (as defined in section 502(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="idc8ff6f99-a7b7-47a7-946a-7bb646512196" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="id0480c445-4169-40bd-a108-d23c0ad9fbfd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an Alaska Native-serving institution (as defined in section 317(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="ida18ae857-580e-4211-b49b-540ca21eacb7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian-serving institution (as defined in section 317(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idcc80ce5b-6e5f-4962-9fd2-8dba40ee125e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a Predominantly Black Institution (as defined in section 318(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="idf357f012-0244-48a6-acde-a833d8887055" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution (as defined in section 320(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g(b)</external-xref>)); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idcfe0a321-13df-4c72-a6f9-681c23dc7078" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a Native American-serving, nontribal institution (as defined in section 319(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059f">20 U.S.C. 1059f(b)</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c9a25c0-7eeb-4c8d-a931-75f507d0b207" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idfcfd9287-e29b-4aff-8383-354ddb57d571" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id4de65024-bebf-4455-b6e5-bddab2731bd4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary to carry out this section $11,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2032, of which not less than $2,000,000 each fiscal year shall be used for grants awarded under subsection (e).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d8eb3ee-364c-47ce-aab9-15bc706ef2ee" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/25">Public Law 115–25</external-xref>; 131 Stat. 91) is amended by striking the item relating to section 103 and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dcfc0a1-e39a-4043-ba92-2f9aa7a42382" changed="not-changed"><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry bold="off" level="section" changed="not-changed">Sec. 103. VORTEX-USA program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id8259a2da-c1ff-4ce4-8a67-a2e039b25994" changed="not-changed"><enum>8.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report on hazardous weather and water alert dissemination</header><subsection id="id22f57124-4471-421d-8def-e0e6a20e59c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that examines the information technology infrastructure of the National Weather Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, specifically regarding the system for timely public notification of hazardous weather and water event alerts and updates. </text></subsection><subsection id="id23233bce-bc30-46d8-b9c4-14be5ffe2f94" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="idfa357d31-343e-40aa-804d-fedb469ea3b6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of the information technology infrastructure of the National Weather Service, including software and hardware capabilities and limitations, including an examination of server and data storage methods, broadband, data management, and data sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ea26afd-9c7f-432c-a71c-458b2b8581c3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of secondary and tertiary fail-safes for the timely distribution of hazardous weather and water event alerts to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3c7bab8-4651-4e4f-abac-81d0f39f02ec" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A determination of the extent to which public notifications are delayed and an identification of corrective measures that do not add additional notification time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66cf66e0-6e52-42dc-83bc-a923e186cdbb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of whether collaboration with other Federal Government offices, States, or private entities could reduce delays in notifications to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd91f92c1-9e29-46f6-8ec0-c6e9f6a0178a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of actions being undertaken to better identify critical steps in the hazards notification process that may be vulnerable to disruption or failure in the event of communication, technologic, or computational failure. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id20fd9b5b-e110-4b89-afbe-70dbaa543bb6" changed="not-changed"><enum>9.</enum><header>Elimination of certain report requirements</header><subsection id="idd63ad746-b998-4689-be4d-28e36f5e1bea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017</header><paragraph id="id966f9382-5c3e-480a-8330-98a868358f9a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 403 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8543">15 U.S.C. 8543</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id318f26ae-74c5-4e49-afaa-182c4b105b1b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 403(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8543">15 U.S.C. 8543(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the</quote> after <quote>Director of</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6d142317-17f9-41c7-ab19-5a936cb60256" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992</header><text>Section 106 of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/567">Public Law 102–567</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 4274) is amended by striking subsection (c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1537">15 U.S.C. 1537</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

