<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8362B9E9AC824820AA3598A01C95B334" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3575 IH: Axing Nonmarket Tariff Evasion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize the United States Trade Representative to impose remedial measures with respect to certain entities that evade or may attempt to evade duties imposed with respect to nonmarket economy countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD4E420B166141B8A3CC719B4D38BD10" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H2B7090E7CBB24A53B0EF21847BB9000D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Axing Nonmarket Tariff Evasion Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ANTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H45897E0FC1AB47A1BDAC33316C257ADE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition by Trade Representative of remedial measures in case of evasion of duties by certain entities of nonmarket economy countries</header> <subsection id="H8FC46D2C8C2E41C0BADA9B2D039020B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CE0D5406ABC452EAEBA04902729A87A">
<section id="HB506AE97DADF483E817E98B0D8A6378A"><enum>311.</enum><header>Remedial measures regarding evasion of duties by certain entities of nonmarket economy countries</header>
<subsection id="H57BA1E839E8A49EBA754B1AFEB9AFB66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inquiry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Trade Representative may initiate an inquiry into whether a covered entity is establishing, planning to establish, or has established an investment in a third country that would avoid duties imposed under section 301 with respect to a nonmarket economy country.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H968C8B7DCB1746C2AA6AA7A02D138775"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedial measures</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA96A5FBE75A49E5B6AAAFE03535E3B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Trade Representative makes an affirmative determination under subsection (a) with respect to a covered entity and the investment of that covered entity in a third country, the Trade Representative, subject to the specific direction, if any, of the President, may impose a remedial measure with respect to goods produced in the third country by a covered entity, which may include the imposition of a duty equal to not less than the value of the duty placed on the relevant product of the nonmarket economy country under section 301.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCD4DC6C31D0412E84BB04AF49D4F098"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action under paragraph (1) may be taken with respect to a covered entity—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F50ECF895D54ED8A09EA5890B030E61"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at any point during an investigation under section 301 if the third-country investment of the covered entity has begun production; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A61D24C51204967AB381A32A51D8967"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prospectively, if the covered entity has plans to establish production in the third country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8142ED4E82D04CF0B9FAB84EF507FAEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matters relating to inquiries</header> <paragraph id="H8E3B175346F34BFFBFF062A56303D24D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An inquiry under subsection (a) may be self-initiated by the Trade Representative or may be requested by interested persons (as defined in section 301(d)(9)) or Congress.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA0A0DA65D7B948FABBA984654E0EB38E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiation</header>
<subparagraph id="HB0B1AE3E72C14957BC45697A27F78808"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an inquiry is requested under paragraph (1) and the Trade Representative determines there is a reasonable indication that a covered entity is establishing, planning to establish, or has already established an investment in a third country that would avoid duties imposed under section 301 with respect to a nonmarket economy country, the Trade Representative may initiate an inquiry under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H686D2FA238AA4DCBAB2E4D5240DA44DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information from other agencies</header><text>Upon request of the Trade Representative, the head of a Federal agency shall submit to the Trade Representative any relevant information of the agency that is necessary for the Trade Representative to carry out an inquiry under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6F3261DE7FD74C8096D4762FE059573C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination To initiate inquiry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after receipt of a request under paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall determine whether an inquiry under subsection (a) is warranted.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H43E8C96B88EC4FB3885E1DA96221A2D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination of evasion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after a determination under paragraph (3) that an inquiry under subsection (a) is warranted with respect to a covered entity, the Trade Representative shall make an affirmative determination of duty evasion if it is found that the third-country investment—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HDE537C2563454E948437D2D429A0810A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is being established or acquired, or has been established or acquired, by the covered entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2245AEA461C4D6BB9513D44E29294FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is producing or planning to produce a good subject to a duty under section 301.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H61C0B8B1E30248AA83637D35148944F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional measures</header>
<paragraph id="HD8E8D832A0124999871CB6F48BEF4B05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the findings of an inquiry under subsection (a) with respect to a covered entity, the Trade Representative may, at the specific direction, if any, of the President, unilaterally impose a measure—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA30DC7E0C4F43A89B7CC8938D914187"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the covered entity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDF46B350B4874A95ACFC805F91C9CF0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to goods produced in a third country pursuant to the investment of that covered entity in the third country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6149C83E963C4710A92CB2D07DABF754"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A measure may be imposed under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered entity—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC754311D24554521910C334545A444C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the covered entity has begun production; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7FA76CD20244CDE876896A72A4A3E51"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prospectively, if the covered entity has immediate plans to establish production in the third country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4580D219CC8F4361B620D3B4E190393F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decision not to impose a measure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Trade Representative does not impose a measure under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered entity, the Trade Representative shall submit to Congress a justification as to why such a measure was not imposed, which shall include a description of the social and economic impacts of not imposing the measure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99E3882881594733B6154CB48A9833D4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration of measure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a measure is imposed by the Trade Representative under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered entity, the measure shall last as long as the remedial action with respect to the relevant nonmarket economy country imposed under section 301 remains in effect, or as long as the relevant nonmarket economy country has a controlling interest in the third-country investment of the covered entity, whichever terminates sooner.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HA580957FDEC4472598A54A69F3855315"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H63F78A0C977C48A4B918BE64E3029CA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>control</term> has the meaning given that term in section 800.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF708122EA55947389FDDAB0D428CF35B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5A4A79EFCAE41AFBC54260AE8559B80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an entity owned, controlled, subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, or operated by a nonmarket economy country; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H671F5232E4504237A9C07BFD085BDB7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any entity for which, on any date during the most recent 12-month period, not less than 25 percent of the equity interests in that entity are held directly or indirectly by one or more entities organized under the laws of a nonmarket economy country, including through—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HB0DF75A12CA44B6695FB1F396E8BC013"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interests in co-investment vehicles, joint ventures, or similar arrangements; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HD5E2886564B54DF3990C44E1317F9F03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a derivative financial instrument or contractual arrangement between the entity and a nonmarket economy country, including any such instrument or contract that seeks to replicate any financial return with respect to such entity or interest in such entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1FE9D71D268D40918C65DFDFF7CD8521"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonmarket economy country</header><text>The term <term>nonmarket economy country</term> means any country that is both—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8846EC3F3B8042A792500C0DB1CD2F3F">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>determined to be a nonmarket economy country under section 771(18) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1677">19 U.S.C. 1677(18)</external-xref>); and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8AEFF94D08234387B8E3522B731CEC36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included on the priority watch list, as defined in section 182(g)(3) (commonly known as the <quote>Special 301 Priority Watch List</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H613E1C62E3FB4430B76764E1B4CDC45B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Trade Representative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Trade Representative</term> means the United States Trade Representative.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H3B53D85AC2EE4606953F833590F46FFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Trade Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 310 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDAE0729C658448E8A3AC1EDCF9CB26D"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 311. Remedial measures regarding evasion of duties by certain entities in nonmarket economy countries.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

