<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25509-VT9-K6-16C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S1484 IS: Forecasting Optimization for Robust Earth Climate Analysis and S2S Tracking Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1484</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve weather research and forecasting by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forecasting Optimization for Robust Earth Climate Analysis and S2S Tracking Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FORECAST Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id3fc73d901018404a81a574df8282dc2c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to weather research and forecasting</header><subsection id="id2a9f5a7459c043e6b5be457c15c5ce38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements to subseasonal-to-Seasonal forecasting</header><text>Section 1762 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8521">15 U.S.C. 8521</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="ida96038784ca24fd7804120407e0c9fca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a1e9b0ae64042fbbcdd86605a50529c"><subsection id="id4726b0e640d640d6a5927549192494fb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idced2f7946dcd4e369f011b9ac15db4ee"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary and the heads of such other programs of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as the Under Secretary considers appropriate, shall—</text><subparagraph id="id07dbc058868a4c6aad088c311e6b3395"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct and support fundamental research to improve understanding of the sources and limitations of season-to-season predictability for temperature, precipitation, and other Earth system variables and applications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0652032e833041a686df03ad8cb601dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect and utilize observational data across the Earth system and other information in order to make usable, reliable, and timely foundational forecasts of subseasonal-to-seasonal temperature and precipitation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1900cbc90c0043718422110ee9d7c258"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prioritize the advancement of multi-model ensemble forecast systems and forecast verification and evaluation capacity, including—</text><clause id="ida1c3fae02a0b4760a155bfc75d4c61f0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the development of advanced coupled data assimilation methods using robust Earth system observational data;</text></clause><clause id="id88229f17eeb94d69b53f2789a1820f75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the development of improved coupled subseasonal-to-seasonal ensemble prediction systems;</text></clause><clause id="ida2d34ebf7fb74d7d9701314644f8b309"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the improvement of exchanges and interactions between datasets across different models and Earth system observations to better understand local relationships between and drivers of ocean, land, snow, and ice observations; </text></clause><clause id="id5a4ebcd8d3dc472786d7cacc687306d6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the provision of additional resources for the research and development of multi-model ensemble forecasts for purposes of advanced forecast modeling; and</text></clause><clause id="id9daade1b93924d0e80e570f5e0791804"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the development of data management strategies to support operations and research activities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9da33a45ce4747758d6542169b527dac"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leverage existing research and models from the weather and Earth system enterprises to improve the forecasts under subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7877ce6a24714b0fa2a632fee89faaf6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>accelerate the operationalization of emerging modeling technologies developed within the research community, including pursuant to collaborations with other agencies and entities, as determined appropriate through increased funding for activities under section 102(b)(5) of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8512">15 U.S.C. 8512(b)(5)</external-xref>), to support and assist the cross development of fully coupled subseasonal-to-seasonal forecast systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bde333abdca4a2a8b7d11fd1fe23903"><enum>(F)</enum><text>determine and provide information on how the subseasonal-to-seasonal temperature and precipitation, as forecasted under subparagraph (B) may relate to—</text><clause id="ideb23f841d5174ca0a6b931fd16bc93e2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number and severity of tornadoes, droughts, hurricanes, fires, floods, heat waves, marine heat waves, coastal inundation, winter storms, high-impact weather, or other relevant natural disasters;</text></clause><clause id="idf10923593361405e8ec236ea756f7944"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>snowpack;</text></clause><clause id="id40d55eea9d5c4ed188feb650d48a14ff"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sea ice conditions; and</text></clause><clause id="id3401a34070864fcd96586d62f29a10c4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>permafrost thaw and increased microbial decomposition;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id837f6cb295bd4c0b871db0da7d51ff36"><enum>(G)</enum><text>develop an Internet clearinghouse to provide the forecasts under subparagraph (B) and the information under subparagraphs (B) and (F) on both national and regional levels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac2ba4eac65348e59d4acdbc3e48f653"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leverage emerging technologies, such as artificial intelligence, machine learning, and use of unmanned systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb991f6675f8a48e7803322b0ebf2b2f8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alignment with report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary and the heads of such other programs of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as the Under Secretary considers appropriate shall carry out the requirements under paragraph (1) in alignment with the findings of the report submitted to Congress by the Under Secretary pursuant to subsection (h) on July 12, 2018, entitled, <quote>Subseasonal and Seasonal Forecasting Innovation: Plans for the Twenty-First Century</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d4498803172485da475c7642758c0c2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Earth system defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Earth system</term> includes atmosphere, ocean, terrestrial, ice, and related processes, and data that influence or drive subseasonal-to-seasonal weather and climate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfae0aacfe83409193ae79158819c4b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (j) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id920eab2c474a4a8ca2d092a343e22fa5"><subsection id="idc3262bc7bfac4181b4e8939d23caccf4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="idc20f9caeffe3468690b100748e4bdb1d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary, for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027—</text><subparagraph id="id5b393c6ff19341c599c2a743a00e1b68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$28,500,000 to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c49bf96eb384f9ab7bc8966451a8f5d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for activities under section 102(b)(5) of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8512">15 U.S.C. 8512(b)(5)</external-xref>) pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(E), such sums as may be necessary to carry out such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2865a88c48d41469439fb2262fb18c1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to an authorization under paragraph (1)(B) shall be used for the designated responsibilities of the modeling team of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration within the Earth Prediction Innovation Center or an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), including activities that fall under the following focus areas:</text><subparagraph id="id9a1c60f90b654668a83107f3155f68e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>High-performance computing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b06aca8eb2b47c489cc1476a74c1550"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Scientific innovation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fab7f51829d4bc5aa4530dd9ddd1eb7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Management and planning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5221ed4544da4449a3186731448280ec"><enum>(D)</enum><text>External engagement and community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5b44ecf4a1124e0093f639bd8e2b871f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Weather and Earth System Modeling And Data Assimilation Workforce Innovation Program</header><paragraph id="id428f52d4e8124821b53d4f29b983f3d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title IV of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8541">15 U.S.C. 8541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47c70422a1d6418287f1d27fa2f39579"><section id="idff0b595ea10b4349af514f0f9d768577"><enum>415.</enum><header>Weather and Earth System Modeling and Data Assimilation Workforce Innovation Program</header><subsection id="idd086746ce93a4617921cf5697e7432c5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Weather and Earth System Modeling and Data Assimilation Workforce Innovation Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id8076444416994e80b596467626cfd082"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education and recruitment</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Under Secretary shall support the education and recruitment of personnel and establish a set of new workforce development programs to develop pathways for next-generation researchers, engineers, and practitioners who are skilled in and can operate or develop weather and Earth system technologies that exploit and advance emerging computing architectures, artificial intelligence and machine learning, unmanned systems, and next-generation data assimilation and observing systems, including through financial assistance for scholarships, fellowships, and research at institutions of higher education in areas relevant to improvement of data assimilation systems and weather and Earth system data modeling capabilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="idff47ec4155e74714890c9cf5e61dd332"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Human capital planning</header><paragraph id="idfe20169654154c25b8a988a88f68754e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Under Secretary shall develop and, on an annual basis, revise a data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling workforce human capital plan that identifies workforce needs to facilitate innovation in emerging weather technologies and data assimilation systems, including by identifying gaps in funding and expertise, hiring challenges, and policies to mitigate turnover that will help avoid mid-project staffing changes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a00d0ec7492465eadc90609444a2acd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of plan</header><text>The Under Secretary shall submit the data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling workforce human capital plan required under paragraph (1), and any revision to that plan, to the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb817280c716c47acb50f2ddb8d0376d2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of plans</header><subparagraph id="id130204064df5412f829436839532cdb5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall use the data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling workforce human capital plans required under paragraph (1) to carry out the education and recruitment required under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fd37840ddff4535a7148356ba0849d0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pathways to hiring</header><text>In carrying out the data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling workforce human capital plan required under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary may use the pathways programs established under part 362 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor program), to facilitate the recruitment and hiring of personnel for data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9553d7ba92c243ad8c03af200655e75e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority to provide funds</header><text>If the Under Secretary, in preparing the data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling workforce human capital plan pursuant to paragraph (1), identifies workforce gaps for the data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling processes of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Under Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="id8f9795b7d0aa498dbbfc1c60904b4427"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use funds made available to the Administration to carry out such plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb951036d93e043a69de5ff4bc40facf4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish agreements and awards with institutions of higher education or nonprofit entities to facilitate the integration of innovative data assimilation and weather and Earth system modeling technologies and systems into the larger weather enterprise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3594000570984fd28a35d33d9e672816"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates to direct hiring authority</header><text>The Under Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office of Human Capital Services, shall make necessary updates to the eligibility requirements for the direct hiring authority program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to include the program, the Weather Program Office Innovation for Next Generation Scientists Dissertation Fellowship, the Consortium for Advanced Data Assimilation Research and Education, and any other fellowship or internship programs determined by the Under Secretary to be relevant to the weather enterprise.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd59783582c6a4ced928bfc18c03e9bd7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the initial date on which the Under Secretary provides funds under subsection (c)(4) to an institution of higher education or a nonprofit entity, the Under Secretary shall, using information about the program collected from any such institution or entity in receipt of those funds, submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness and impact of those funds in improving the quality and preparedness of the weather and Earth system modeling and data assimilation workforce.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7e08d9d2ead84e8d9ce608f222f4ee6f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3b946b4be59460c8a547aadaf4f8c97"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Earth system</header><text>The term <term>Earth system</term> includes atmosphere, ocean, terrestrial, ice, and related processes, and data that influence or drive subseasonal-to-seasonal weather and climate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dab1393fcba459cb027b40273d74939"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id857a0807fecd4de28ec939ec5ffbea65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonprofit entity</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit entity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0883e2d382c341bda5989310a0881424"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the program, as determined by the Under Secretary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id7091729b4bed4d899a2296cb256f52bc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/25">Public Law 115–25</external-xref>; 131 Stat. 91) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 414 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id8ae2c6ce-d8ca-40ee-bb41-8162ac56fceb"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idff0b595ea10b4349af514f0f9d768577">Sec. 415. Weather and Earth System Modeling and Data Assimilation Workforce Innovation Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

