<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41F3FB4C7A0F4B02921B8E88BADDED96" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3697 IH: Rural American Vitalization in Extraterrestrial Space Reporting Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study, and publish guidance, on the conversion of rural abandoned factories, space centers, and military bases into space-related manufacturing facilities and space complexes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F7D64BB922245FD90FE4A9FFA2DB39D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H22309A4DB2EA4B5BB8CF7C947E34DF31" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural American Vitalization in Extraterrestrial Space Reporting Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAVES Reporting Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9208B163C97B462BB693BCA94C18D5F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and guidance on conversion of rural, abandoned factories into space-related manufacturing facilities</header> <subsection id="HAB2BB7C2C1064D39B4D907C2D38B13FA" commented="no"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Study</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation, and in consultation with the Office of Space Affairs of the Department of State and the Small Business Development Center of the Small Business Administration, shall conduct a study, and publish guidance, on the conversion of abandoned factories, space centers, and military bases in rural areas into space-related manufacturing facilities and space complexes.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5EBDB6B731794A7FB8B890683A4AB04E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study and guidance required under subsection (a) shall include information relating to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1D14591DCC1E48DDA310A43832D62921" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On average and by State, the cost of conversions of abandoned factories, and space centers, and abandoned military bases in rural areas into space-related manufacturing facilities and space complexes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF06E25F83D564B32AAB2C9FA238EDBA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Greatest needs for terrestrial space manufacturing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA3C917A90AB45ADA60116D546DBE1F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Environmental and sustainability concerns relating to such conversions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9DF78866806400B8A14FBBF7214C2D0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Impact on local economies of region in which such conversions are carried out.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5311139D516141FDABDCA8C8417084D6" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Technical skills and relevant education needed for construction workers, engineers, scientists, and other elements of the workforce relating to such conversions, as well as for the operation of such facilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA22FA04C2EE64BB7835913B5BA533F97"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Potential for collaboration with local community colleges relating to such conversions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5174DB080AE46E3B218E643DAA7AC00"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Effects of artificial intelligence on workforce development relating to such conversions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BF011C637CF44398C6978508FBA353E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The number of factories and military bases in rural areas abandoned as of 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA65224148A9C454995E4A107D9DAD7A9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Potential for development within rural communities relating to such conversions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H944D1276896A4E03B5BB2B10116D7575"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Viable sources of potential funding or incentives for private sector entities for such conversions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC63E5A6DA0E644B6982EC06D5C5AD03D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Potential national security implications relating to such conversions, in particular with regard to United States adversaries and the Space Command.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB61759B0B73F4AE1BD0286D0826A35A5"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An estimate of the time required to complete such conversions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A18F71B80EB450C92A8BB1B2E8C21B9" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Input from private and public entities that have collaborated or currently collaborate with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) regarding space manufacturing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DF17F29D4EB46948A7A047CB7B82369" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><text>An analysis undertaken in consultation with outside experts in the aerospace field on the current state of the aerospace industry in rural areas of the United States, including a description of best practices relating to such conversions.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HFF33B225D0D24099AE28A5406FE992CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress the study and guidance required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE604E2A77FC4F67BDD3BF6D93D87AAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4BBAF3CF132A49A5B65DA49B5E51706C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abandoned</header><text>The term <quote>abandoned</quote> means out of use or underutilized for at least five years, with no apparent plans to restart production or repurpose for other uses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBE5BA9A827A4BB086E6AFC1786D0434"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factory</header><text>The term <quote>factory</quote> means an industrial facility for manufacturing goods or parts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE3A7ABF099A4FEC9342C0FA40306DC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>rural area</quote>, with respect to an abandoned factory, space center, or military base, means such a factory, center, or base, as the case may be, that is located in any area other than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE97A5E7F876C49C089CFBE5AF0F10710" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a city or town that has a population of greater than 50,000 inhabitants; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7C829BA26EE4BC2A32ED96BA629FD47"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any urbanized area contiguous and adjacent to a city or town described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81BB8C9946A14DB2AF9A897198B9792D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Space complex</header><text>The term <quote>space complex</quote> means a group of buildings designed for the purpose of building spacecraft, instruments, or technologies to study space, or testing or launching such devices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

