<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2506E51CFFF44A66919336B1FFC3DDC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1715 IH: Public Health Funding Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To fully fund the Prevention and Public Health Fund and reaffirm the importance of prevention in the United States healthcare system.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H30F55E64820D4C23AB2520CF1844CB7D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4F57040988BB47D5BFA79316A4A54B98"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Health Funding Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB231C8B8130F46FD8A554954ED0BCDAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H697F66E16760483B80A0E02DF89CA3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Prevention and Public Health Fund (section 4002 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-11">42 U.S.C. 300u–11</external-xref>)) was designed <quote>to provide for expanded and sustained national investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and help restrain the rate of growth in private and public health care costs</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC63B5DBC814C25AC31456AA1B1EB83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Funding under such section is essential to core efforts at the Department of Health and Human Services and in State, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments to prevent and control the spread of infectious disease and prevent injuries and the development of chronic conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6BFD2A3C214F209A9EB506C6DC9C19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prevention and Public Health Fund dollars support evidenced-based investments in tobacco use prevention and cessation, nutrition, mental health, childhood lead poisoning prevention, elder care initiatives, and immunizations, among other prevention initiatives. Funding gives States and communities the flexibility to respond to public health threats that may be unique to their communities and bolsters the State, local, Tribal, and territorial response to global public health threats. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C77EDDF436A424891EBFD9EBC720565"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such prevention efforts have shown to be effective. Funding increases for community-based public health programs reduce infant deaths and preventable deaths caused by cancer, diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Every dollar spent on prevention saves nearly $6 in health spending and every dollar spent on childhood vaccines saves $16.50 in future health care costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D0B368BE2D74866834DCAA2A3B430ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Investments in prevention reduce the cost of health care in the United States. $2,900,000,000 in investments in community-based disease prevention is estimated to save $16,500,000,000 annually within 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H804369BCA6DB44C5843894BCA7A67722"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Cuts to the Prevention and Public Health Fund and other public health prevention efforts undermine efforts to create an affordable and accessible health care system, and a better quality of life for Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5245C7F1D5D44B09D3A3C80E7C4420A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Cuts to the Prevention and Public Health Fund endanger the ability of States and localities to distribute vaccinations and public health information successfully. The Prevention and Public Health Fund is critical to the growth of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s section 317 Immunization Program and to the Epidemiology and Laboratory Capacity program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44F182848A1942359E48CA5C4C8DF8AB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Restoring Prevention and Public Health Fund funding to $2,000,000,000 annually will allow the Fund to invest in more innovative, evidence-based public health programs and maintain and expand investments in programs with demonstrated success.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10CAFE9DBD444CCB97DACB3BB248DE81"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Restoring Prevention and Public Health Fund funding to $2,000,000,000 will give the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and State, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments funding that they need to invest in prevention efforts that will help the country avoid future pandemics and epidemics. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H39AFA215792C4474B38C66B4E3836425"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prevention and public health fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4002(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-11">42 U.S.C. 300u–11(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1D2CA399AA574B9CB818D43699762AFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end <quote>and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87FE1DF4DD2B492B8649BF0619FB3EFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (5) through (10) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC00E54A41AA548BCAD8E13D13E4B62FE"><paragraph id="H3A0BADEF1A2C45B8B8DC51AC8A51605A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter, $2,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

