<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB25723850D4549219DAEB5156E6CF38E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1903 IH: Congressional Trade Authority Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1903</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 to impose limitations on the authority of the President to adjust imports that are determined to threaten to impair national security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E04127EAFFB4C75BE2D2731A020C0FB" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE51ABAECBBC648A4AF7C161FAB57831B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Trade Authority Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H885A6E3060CB47DC862F4EC85A59A0FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on authority of president to adjust imports determined to threaten to impair national security</header><subsection id="HF5A42F8E37FD4EE6986F655B0EC9A995"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on articles for which action may be taken</header><text>Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0135FAB2C2CC4A70857ACD327243AE64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an article</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>a covered article</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33D68DA2810D43FB83E19A16A0513DDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any article</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>any covered article</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F85B57988894868BDA63577FB8D5293"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the article</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the covered article</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD85DD6D89BF40B5A6B41A04CEB8E5CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the first subsection (d), by striking <quote>In the administration</quote> and all that follow through <quote>national security.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF1AF3B7CFCC4B0D89C70E39DB7BEC0F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3B1C53687E6642B89234D57591DE2521" style="OLC"><subsection id="H8F2113D317D44BF998C2BFEE961CC38A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCD425DEAB2034690A05DC0EF8EB38C00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered article</header><text>The term <quote>covered article</quote> means an article related to the development, maintenance, or protection of military equipment, energy resources, or critical infrastructure essential to national security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A971E6B5F404366B1CECFBD6E522E86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National security</header><text>The term <quote>national security</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H1689D0C88EAF4DA98146177429EE73F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the protection of the United States from foreign aggression; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B5D09F182794AF3A7EC4849DB0CA915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not otherwise include the protection of the general welfare of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F1F52CD9A0B46DD95F1C90A7EE8B910"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibility of secretary of defense for investigations</header><text>Section 232(b) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE9E72D61D0CE4CCF913761BB72E7F989"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H4A2C91CBDAE044619412C5DCE55A698F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the Secretary of Commerce (hereafter in the section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Defense</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EA8414F637F42C0B0D7D49FFC3A0F08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HADEA86F5E3D64B208F27E691C53AE558"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary of Defense</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H5A149D2C5F2D4BC388F1FE0EB18D7012"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Secretary of Defense</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Commerce</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46DDAAB555FB48DCB0C56DB6DA9FB90E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H13C5EDC0C9D3462BBB5EC80D24028B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HFD5AAD496D584C258CDD2C9EDDABC5F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Defense</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H7D31F37EF9234A6BAD93FB2730FCCE7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>the Secretary of Defense</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Commerce</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7370307002CC489F9ADAA304FEA1407D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HB8CACA0D3C184AD19DCCD060C8479FEA" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HFEB0159B83A043239FDF4734681828C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon the request of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce shall provide to the Secretary of Defense an assessment of the quantity of imports of any covered article that is the subject of an investigation conducted under this subsection and the circumstances under which the covered article is imported.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H964ADCA7501F40F8B0B0DEAB68E6E405"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="HDCA99BD86252465AA0B1932701EA9A4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H3D10B2A2EA2D48FB92EB739B5CB655A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>the Secretary shall submit</quote> and all that follows through <quote>recommendations of the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly submit to the President a report on the findings of the investigation and, based on such findings, the recommendations of the Secretary of Commerce</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H7F5D4B38FECD478C89667B9C2D91EE42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Secretary finds</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Secretary shall</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretaries find that the covered article is being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as to be a substantial cause of a threat to impair the national security, the Secretaries shall</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EDC2CD7C0934E8680AB595753A07C42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>by the Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED8AF0DCDF5842B691DA7EE03C131C64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Defense</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A7C2465BBCE466DB662A1B29E5F3731"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations of president</header><text>Section 232(c) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF013CD3D08BD4421A907340987F909DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HFAD23AE9FA754E5B8D148E903CFEF626"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D9906A294FA4542AF3F10A99E0D3478"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text><clause id="HEFD94F9A15EE4B5DA4C710A6A134926C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) Within</quote> and inserting <quote>Within</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H4FB2A2C7331B47C5978F5CDE0240F697"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in which the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>that</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4220B1DA2FC48C48C1F58AD28D4AA21"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02753C26F1524A96AF884D35DF184DB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as redesignated by subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>of the Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8090918F3B344508516BB9F3780C8E4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B), as redesignated by subparagraph (C), to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H77F7F7399A924BDB94FFA07FE5A75261" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H089374F5619B42DEAA47648DFAF1E88E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the President concurs, submit to Congress, not later than 15 days after making that determination, a proposal regarding the nature and duration of the action that, in the judgment of the President, should be taken to adjust the imports of the covered article and its derivatives so that such imports will not be a substantial cause of a threat to impair the national security.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AEAEF3A072E4E21A4E07F235CD170EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H41541654031F459A976A422621B41635" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H6138C2C54AF9498290CAF7C7410836B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President shall submit to Congress for review under subsection (f) a report describing the action proposed to be taken under paragraph (1) and specifying the reasons for such proposal. Such report shall be included in the report published under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DE0D3D58E684B4CBDFABF680B7061AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional approval of presidential adjustment of imports</header><text>Section 232(f) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H0811CF465D8241A6B4BDC62CE8F725FC" style="OLC"><subsection id="H6CF2E83ABCE441DE8A3CF4427AF76F1E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Congressional approval of presidential adjustment of imports; joint resolution of approval</header><paragraph id="H104EC164AE58433C9A2FECBFDFF4D1A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An action to adjust imports proposed by the President in a report submitted to Congress under subsection (c)(2) shall have force and effect only if, during the period of 60 calendar days beginning on the date on which the report is submitted, a joint resolution of approval is enacted pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35356B118C22468191335CB7F13262A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint resolutions of approval</header><subparagraph id="H7B3A798B10FC40A2A957D51CDDA122FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>joint resolution of approval</quote> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><clause id="H37BA1916F1BC49B2A6A9CB237CC513A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution approving the proposal of the President to take an action relating to the adjustment of imports entering into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as to threaten or impair the national security.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H78955BB67B38461FA31529DC13A00A44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress approves of the proposal of the President relating to the adjustment of imports to protect the national security as described in the report submitted to Congress under section 232(c)(2) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862(c)(2)</external-xref>) on _____ relating to _____.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date and the second blank space being filled with a short description of the proposed action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B21069FB5364DD5B88F4664378F4212"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>During the period of 60 calendar days provided for under paragraph (1), a joint resolution of approval may be introduced in either House by any Member.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7745102F1384A7BA703BD05DEEDEF58"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration in house of representatives</header><clause id="H29D8071BC0A44AD78ACB537C0F88C17D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of approval introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text></clause><clause id="HF73AFA8F6D0C41968C7D59F7447E87E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Ways and Means has not reported the joint resolution of approval within 10 calendar days after the date of referral, the Committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></clause><clause id="H668130244CAF47D184C1B1440A5488A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after the Committee on Ways and Means reports the joint resolution of approval to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="H1CCAD0270CD9490AA558A576FA3EDEE6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header><text>The joint resolution of approval shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22FB40163C74492EA0803331C66EF1F0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Consideration in the senate</header><clause id="HCE15B8E9CC634777B4986594320A559D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of approval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></clause><clause id="HDB32613BF3DD44B9A39EE30D0779D62C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Finance has not reported the joint resolution of approval within 10 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, the Committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></clause><clause id="HBC2E9A4F442648059CA1EF623073AEED"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Finance reports a joint resolution of approval or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="HBE8C5375CCD1441D807BB3248CE0765D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of approval shall be decided by the Senate without debate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD5AA3FD3F345828FA4DC647CD8E79F"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Treatment of house joint resolution in senate</header><clause id="H499B3C54DBC447DCB2E597631F1DCD42"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), a joint resolution of approval that has passed the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be referred to the Committee on Finance for consideration in accordance with subparagraph (D).</text></clause><clause id="HD5F71C3CB52A4D5D9B46A4C05C09F24E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consideration of house resolution</header><text>If a joint resolution of approval was introduced in the Senate before receipt of a joint resolution of approval that has passed the House of Representatives—</text><subclause id="H9EAEF2AFB5234AE08CFAE63D14C25B96"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the joint resolution from the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be placed on the calendar; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCDD5FF7E91B246C7A3A12699BFF69234"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the procedures in the Senate with respect to a joint resolution of approval introduced in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution of approval had been received from the House of Representatives, except that the vote on passage in the Senate shall be on the joint resolution that passed the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2713EFE14EDE41749F9C46EC2F241A47"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>House resolution received after passage by senate</header><text>If the Senate passes a joint resolution of approval before receiving a joint resolution of approval from the House of Representatives, the joint resolution of the Senate shall be held at the desk pending receipt of the joint resolution from the House of Representatives. Upon receipt of the joint resolution of approval from the House of Representatives, such joint resolution shall be deemed to be read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed.</text></clause><clause id="H6E1A8B9A59E5459F82C1E9DFDE0675FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Consideration of house resolution if no resolution introduced in senate</header><text>If the Senate receives a joint resolution of approval from the House of Representatives, and no joint resolution of approval has been introduced in the Senate, the procedures described in subparagraph (D) shall apply to consideration of the joint resolution of the House.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2FEDD58ECFA4D60AF9D9513E3455B4C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rules of house of representatives and senate</header><text>This paragraph is enacted by Congress—</text><clause id="H44C48926E4534ADCB6D413437DE66F17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></clause><clause id="H6F810D61D8DD4DE6A6AD62A33C63C9BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDCDD6EAF2D514D2D9539A8441BEE8550"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusion process; report</header><text>Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0798C299CE4742C399B4A23962A6FB13" style="OLC"><subsection id="H17A977B0EBC2451B9AA654DB6D2D287F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administration of exclusion process</header><paragraph id="H547FEE7B08854C09AE735C1093424017"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States International Trade Commission shall administer a process for granting requests for the exclusion of covered articles from any actions, including actions to impose duties or quotas, taken by the President under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H197951E474794FB2B117192A762B1E10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In administering the process required by paragraph (1), the International Trade Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6918EEBF3ABA4C3482F4535A885098DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider, when determining whether to grant an exclusion with respect to a covered article, if—</text><clause id="HB0B85BA0477842F7A9294FDF5A0AE739"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered article is produced in the United States and is of sufficient quality, available in sufficient quantities, and available on a reasonable timeframe;</text></clause><clause id="H7EEC936E33084E4090177C7BFD73D941"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the failure to grant the exclusion would result in severe economic harm; and</text></clause><clause id="H5A0BC280A0694BF884D09A366FA6B23C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the failure to grant the exclusion would impair the ability of the United States to maintain effective pressure to remove an unreasonable or discriminatory practice burdening United States commerce, and further if the International Trade Commission determines that—</text><subclause id="H823F98DD6755470D908E5C951BCE45F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the article or a reasonable substitute is not commercially available to person requesting an exclusion under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered article; </text></subclause><subclause id="HC1159C7EA53F460E81F8AA03BC7B3D24"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the imposition of the duty with respect to the article would unreasonably increase consumer prices for day-to-day items consumed by low- or middle-income families in the United States; </text></subclause><subclause id="H0E701DC9A7CE423E816B64C92630148F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the imposition of the duty would have an unreasonable impact on manufacturing output of the United States; </text></subclause><subclause id="HB66318A8E2464584BDC541A4C51EBBA5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the imposition of the duty would have an unreasonable impact on the ability of an entity to fulfill contracts or to build critical infrastructure; or </text></subclause><subclause id="HD2305B57909A4F5D9E1F74EA46FA9722"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the failure to grant the exclusion is likely to result in a particular entity or entities having the ability to abuse a dominant market position; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA6DC471479B4CA3A67EA79AEB420D7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that an exclusion granted with respect to a covered article is available to any person that imports the covered article;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4E00CCF99FB4B53B67DABE032407ACA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not disclose business proprietary information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E6E62D16AD342BA84DFFFC0A6B9279C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish guidelines to provide for—</text><clause id="HB31F59EC6CE849548E25514381CA7A07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maximum period of time that an exclusion will be in effect;</text></clause><clause id="H67FD2240A98C4D0F86BED89E14AE229D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applications for renewal of an exclusion; and</text></clause><clause id="H458BE57D37FF422DAFB0558227D15812"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>written reasoning to a person that has requested an exclusion that the International Trade Commision has denied.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB6D1014ECE1437BBF918D19A1E79A7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of procedures</header><text>The International Trade Commission shall publish in the Federal Register and make available on a publicly available internet website of the Commission a description of the procedures to be followed by a person requesting an exclusion under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered article.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74033A3C7428488FB15CA21C1E3DD9B0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report by international trade commission</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the President takes action under subsection (c) to adjust imports of a covered article, the International Trade Commission shall submit to Congress a report assessing the effects of the action on—</text><paragraph id="H0B9B318C41444375B254ACA6430490C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the industry to which the covered article relates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FA8D154993841E0BB0E3B1D251B14A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the overall economy of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6610D82597E5442DAE641C8115693681"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit on an annual basis of the exclusion process established under subsection (g)(1). </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCC6CB7BE35EE43199A64FDE6E14B20CA" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>), as amended by this section, is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC6EA448904CD43DC9B548F5F93AB4D82" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H5C48322A8E6549D68151837BEB979FFE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, an action to adjust imports by the President in a report submitted to Congress under subsection (c)(2) with respect to a covered article shall terminate not later than the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of a joint resolution required by subsection (f) with respect to such action. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7BAEF52DCD6D4A818916D363F5116CC4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>), as amended by this section, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HF8E82765772B4AA7AB490AAC848E68BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first subsection (d), by striking <quote>the Secretary and the President</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, and the President</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E20D81CAF9C4F62AFDFE1D158D86A87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBEFC27FBBC0404D9CF14CD72318A13A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of subsection (e), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Defense</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF5819C4B851432DA4303A9102FC1E24"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Except as provided by subsection (h), the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any proposed action under section 232(c) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862(c)</external-xref>) on or after the date that is 6 years before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB83FC53555D4D1F9A5186CFA59611E1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transition rules</header><paragraph id="H172A4495123F44C69D8B0247563FE79B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approval process for actions take before date of enactment</header><subparagraph id="H0FF07E6F2EC54BA1BAFDA2DBFAAC3926"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, during the period specified in paragraph (2), the President makes a determination described in subsection (c) of section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, to take action with respect to an article—</text><clause id="HE6FCCDDF9CE745E8AF357E070EFF5B36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 15 days after such date of enactment, the President shall resubmit to Congress the report required under that section with respect to the action; and</text></clause><clause id="H644B5D5888E14B7EBF548AA075BBE63F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the action shall have force and effect after the day that is 75 days after such date of enactment only if, during the period of 60 calendar days beginning on the date on which the report is resubmitted under clause (i), a joint resolution of approval is enacted pursuant to subsection (f)(2) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended by this section, with respect to the action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ED8EFBDE81149C1AC2481C9D240E4DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of definitions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to an action without regard to whether the article to which the action relates is a covered article (as defined in subsection (i) of section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as added by this section).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7793C413AAD4C01A1725F1C16DADB88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period specified</header><text>The period specified in this paragraph is the period beginning on the date that is 9 years before the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the day before such date of enactment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BEE5893F8FB43678A16997803AEA3AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration of exclusion process</header><text>In the case of an action with respect to which a resolution of approval is enacted as required by paragraph (1)(A)(ii), the Secretary of Commerce shall continue to administer the process established before the date of the enactment of this Act for granting requests for the exclusion of articles from the action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H946FBBDCD0D248D29BCDA331CB1CA095"><enum>(4)</enum><header>International trade commission report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States International Trade Commission shall submit to Congress a report described in subsection (h) of section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as added by this section, relating to each action taken under subsection (c) of section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as in effect on the day before such date of enactment, during the period specified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B5FB589D5A249BABBC4378A53403085"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination of actions not approved</header><subparagraph id="HB397D552C08B452BA1441033A5866ED0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An action described in subparagraph (B) shall terminate on the day that is 75 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA50A08AFCD8A48BBBCD791D25A75943D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Action described</header><text>An action described in this subparagraph is an action with respect to which—</text><clause id="H8E572E1514C048F4909A88FA3095CBAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the President made a determination described in subsection (c) of section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, during the period specified in paragraph (2); and</text></clause><clause id="H949A37AB005241E5A0AFD4550EEDB7E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a joint resolution of approval is not enacted as required by paragraph (1)(A)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD3E491C530E4078B3DA3BCBD8BE1012"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modification of duty rate amounts</header><clause id="H497529F3EC99497BB6D3774287189985"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any rate of duty modified under section 232(c) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, pursuant to an action described in subparagraph (B) shall, on the day that is 75 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, revert to the rate of duty in effect before such modification.</text></clause><clause id="HBA64D1ED326B4A78B4BE18852686E09B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Retroactive application for certain liquidations and reliquidations</header><subclause id="H0D22A0F69A7E4642BA233CD028FB6CC0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), an entry of an article shall be liquidated or reliquidated as though such entry occurred on the date that is 75 days after the date of the enactment of this Act if—</text><item id="H4D331E7D9A3944FF92494127F7831EE4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the rate of duty applicable to the article was modified pursuant to an action described in subparagraph (B); and</text></item><item id="H929AA76B996848A9967ED63928C14120"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a lower rate of duty would be applicable due to the application of clause (i).</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H0C8CE0A4B38F48FCBBCA1CE629490200"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requests</header><text>A liquidation or reliquidation may be made under subclause (I) with respect to an entry only if a request therefor is filed with U.S. Customs and Border Protection not later than 255 days after the date of the enactment of this Act that contains sufficient information to enable U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</text><item id="H9C596EE5F0CB4E7CAEE783A5451184BE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to locate the entry; or</text></item><item id="H91EB22ED33E64765A9C42EBC0F32904B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to reconstruct the entry if it cannot be located.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1C547E29160E4634B8E405910316371C"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Payment of amounts owed</header><text>Any amounts owed by the United States pursuant to the liquidation or reliquidation of an entry of an article under subclause (I) shall be paid, without interest, not later than 90 days after the date of the liquidation or reliquidation (as the case may be).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA42568B74A314173BFD1928BCA867A9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Entry defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the terms <quote>entry</quote> includes a withdrawal from warehouse for consumption.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

