<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8713C6C8E1C2439694EBD4E58FE98C9F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5341 IH: Livestock Owned by Communities to Advance Local Foods Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5341</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to exempt certain owners of livestock from inspection requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H39062E262C2546019C5DC85DE3C852D2" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H40FF49DC6CEB425EA00EA4609056743E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Livestock Owned by Communities to Advance Local Foods Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LOCAL Foods Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA48869778BD448699C5BC55FB7FA6695"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemptions from inspection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 23(a) of the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/623">21 U.S.C. 623(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the slaughtering by any person of animals of his own raising, and the preparation by him and transportation in commerce of the carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products of such animals exclusively for use by him and members of his household and his nonpaying guests and employees</quote> and inserting <quote>the slaughtering of animals by any person that is an owner of the animals in whole or in part, or the preparation or transportation in commerce of the carcasses or parts thereof or meat and meat food products from those animals by an owner, if such slaughter, preparation, or transportation is exclusively for the use of an owner or the household, nonpaying guests, or employees of an owner, subject to the condition that if an owner designates an agent to assist in such slaughter, preparation, or transportation, the owner shall maintain custody and specific identification of the carcasses or parts thereof or meat and meat food products, as determined by the Secretary</quote>.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

