<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D3DE9F3932140479A52AD34179437E4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 536 IH: Supporting the designation of the week including June 23, 2025, as “National Women’s Sports Week” to celebrate the anniversary of the passage of title IX and the growth of women’s sports.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the week including June 23, 2025, as <quote>National Women’s Sports Week</quote> to celebrate the anniversary of the passage of title IX and the growth of women’s sports.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this preamble as <quote>title IX</quote>) was enacted on June 23, 1972, to end unjust sex discrimination in education, including in athletics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas title IX transformed sports by guaranteeing women and girls the right to equal athletic opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the purposes and benefits of title IX are negated for women whenever men claiming to be women are granted access to female sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas title IX has resulted in a 545 percent increase in the percentage of women playing college sports and a 990 percent increase in the percentage of women playing high school sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas athletic participation helps women and girls develop confidence, initiative, and leadership skills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas policies allowing for the inclusion of men in women’s sports have no basis in biological fact or valid medical research;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas providing equal athletic opportunities in sports to women is impossible without single-sex teams and competitions reserved exclusively for female athletes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, without separate single-sex teams and competitions based on biological sex for men and women, men will dominate competitive sports where size, strength, and speed are factors, depriving female athletes of athletic and academic opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the biological differences between men and women have led to women being injured by men competing in women’s sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2017, men have won at least 24 professional women’s sports titles and an innumerable number of unreported titles at the middle school, high school, and collegiate levels;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2018, at least 300 high school-aged boys in the United States ran the 400-meter dash faster than the most decorated female Olympic champion in the world has run it in her lifetime;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Executive Order 14201 (90 Fed. Reg. 9279; relating to keeping men out of women’s sports) emphasizes opposition to male competitive participation in women’s sports as <quote>a matter of safety, fairness, dignity, and truth</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of June 22 through June 28 is <quote>National Women’s Sports Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA295CA4147CD47DEA2F60DB244D6331B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H965BA8AE63B348F9B0AFFB95239725D7"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives supports—</text><paragraph id="HA1163F63E6DD43B2AF2F6EA09A8F8C62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>observing <quote>National Women’s Sports Week</quote> to recognize—</text><subparagraph id="H76757A8C9DB7412B8BD9882F50DFA321"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the incredible expansion of opportunities for female athletes since the enactment of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF373653C0EB4A8382F1E54737D07BCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the role of the provisions of law described in subparagraph (A) in guaranteeing equal athletic opportunities for members of both sexes; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF175EDDD36C94D4C87109494B08D8F16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>marking the observance of National Women’s Sports Week with—</text><subparagraph id="HF96F047FBFF34B228724F71D3600F3EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appropriate programs and activities that—</text><clause id="H255C729F7BA8464291FE376F3BB3B250"><enum>(i)</enum><text>celebrate the contributions of individual female athletes in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H12B785079FBB4B0DB2E9249889994305"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>honor the coaches and parents who support female athletes in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H6401E63EA8E54CC093244EB8418EA162"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promote equal access to athletic opportunities for members of both sexes; and</text></clause><clause id="HEA5204BC2F394D5F96F52FC48FA549BF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>support the commitment of the United States to supporting female athletes; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF534271A6FF54D5AA0CEA965B0F46A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>legislative efforts to protect single-sex sports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

