<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H850BD6723B86468897F756946BA919E8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 809 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the second Monday in October 2025 as “Indigenous Peoples’ Day” to celebrate and honor Indigenous Peoples and their shared history and culture.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 809</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the second Monday in October 2025 as <quote>Indigenous Peoples’ Day</quote> to celebrate and honor Indigenous Peoples and their shared history and culture.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas currently over 200 municipalities and 17 States celebrate <quote>Indigenous Peoples’ Day</quote> on the second Monday of October;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Columbus Day is a Federal holiday, established by order of President Roosevelt in 1937, and is officially recognized by some cities and States around the country on the second Monday of October;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Columbus Day does not currently provide an opportunity to reflect on the stories and perseverance of the Indigenous People of lands that are now part of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, prior to Western contact, Indigenous Peoples lived and flourished in the lands that are now part of the United States for thousands of years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Western contact of the lands that are now part of the United States led to the suppression, forced assimilation, and genocide of Indigenous Peoples and their cultures;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives recognizes and values the vast contributions made to the United States by Indigenous Peoples’ knowledge, science, philosophy, arts, and culture;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives recognizes its responsibility to honor the history, traditions, and cultural contributions of the Indigenous Peoples of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the second Monday in October would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>Indigenous Peoples’ Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCBF96B68A5D1458F81D5E52FAAA3B0E8"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDD3972257807459BACED1320BCF7277E"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H178D5E68175345FBA33C8B29CF1B48F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors and recognizes the unique contributions Indigenous Peoples have made to the United States of America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E9A2357B4C34EBDB145BDCFA6F15FF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe <quote>Indigenous Peoples’ Day</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities that celebrate and promote awareness of Indigenous Peoples and their shared history and culture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26856DF0FF564ADF9ACA0AD35BA4DFF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Indigenous Peoples’ Day</quote> as a Federal holiday.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

