<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25435-F2N-K2-KC1">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2320 IS: Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2320</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on
                    Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate regulations
            relating to the approval of foreign manufacturers of cylinders, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id05e79ba64ac744588d4356828c91dc65">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Regulation of foreign manufacturers of cylinders used in transporting hazardous
                materials</header>
            <subsection id="idea3f77ba71e747619c856d6011f26180">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idbd4168e2ac874750a885ba08e7dfb0c3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Cylinder</header> <text>The term <term>cylinder</term> means any cylinder specified under any of sections 178.36 through 178.68 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idcb4f7ef1270b46e98a86d848e509619c">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Foreign manufacturer of cylinders; FMOC</header>
 <text>The term <term>foreign manufacturer of cylinders</term> or <quote>FMOC</quote> means an entity that manufactures cylinders outside of the United States that are intended to be represented, marked, certified, or sold as qualified for use in transporting a hazardous material in commerce in the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id10d0a51685674743a833484edf1adc29">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>In good standing</header>
 <text>The term <term>in good standing</term>, with respect to an FMOC, means that the FMOC—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idb592f88ac13c4d928a01d7093d9b411d">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is approved by the Secretary pursuant to section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id26f2f9496e7549e08b0fd9747eb226c6">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>has demonstrated 3 years of compliance with—</text> <clause id="idb0538bf7f7f94d859a0ed70d9eba92c8"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>part 107 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id5423089a7b724de2941def546d684b49">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idbcd10008e24540a6895fe126e856463f"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Secretary</header> <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0cd054ef10af44808b55534c9945556f">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Approval of foreign manufacturers of cylinders</header>
                <paragraph id="idd1989c4c195b460db2991c3cdf0b95ad">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to provide that an approval provided to an FMOC pursuant to section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), shall be for a period of not longer than 1 year, except as provided under paragraph (2).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6688903c76fb41c9b43b9e79265dd8cb">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>5-year approval</header>
 <text>The Secretary may provide a 5-year approval of an FMOC pursuant to section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), if the following requirements are met:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idc763e71d0c7443f3b32d02ad82eabfaa">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The FMOC attests that none of the cylinders made by the FMOC are prohibited from entry to the United States under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id82ce333a4088489f8bf678907717444f">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The FMOC certifies that—</text> <clause id="id40a653a61c66470bacbe8c8e579108b7"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the information provided pursuant to subsection (e) is accurate; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id62be8873651c496a8d11a2547eb4e422">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the FMOC has a proactive responsibility to inform the Secretary if any such information materially changes.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id76cd65b7ebbc4909be3e8064da663f27">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The Secretary determines that the FMOC is in good standing.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id2a19e4a7e45d44f48d389d0c80add1f3"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Facility inspections</header> <subparagraph id="id95cca6933c774e71831e314846151e98"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Definition of obstructs</header> <text>In this paragraph, the term <term>obstructs</term> means taking actions that are known, or reasonably should be known, to prevent, hinder, or impede an inspection.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id8ee9b07101d84176a3193c794259a742">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Penalties</header>
 <text>The Secretary may suspend or terminate an approval of an FMOC if the FMOC obstructs or prevents the Secretary from carrying out an inspection under section 107.807(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf5141f38ece249ffa3ab203e78b35775">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Interaction with other statutes, agreements, regulations</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent the harmonization of cylinder standards otherwise authorized by law.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id840c4212fe014288b5d5018df93b6aec">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Other cause for suspension or termination</header>
 <text>The Secretary may suspend or terminate an approval of an FMOC on determination that the FMOC knowingly or intentionally misrepresented responses to the Secretary required by law, including under subsection (e).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idba98e6477d0948ceb97bf9dffdf5e1ef">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Reevaluation by request for related violations</header>
                <paragraph id="id35441122760c4eb9bc05bce29020b349">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to establish a process, as determined by the Secretary, for any interested party to request a reevaluation of the approval of FMOC cylinders under section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), to review the accuracy and safety of the actions of the FMOC.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id446838569dc845caa545faeb27894615">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Petition for reevaluation</header>
 <text>The regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall allow an interested party to file a petition if that party has evidence of inaccurate, changed, or fraudulent attestations or responses made by an FMOC to the Secretary under subsection (e).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1214400942f54c179442c62a7bd1df2c">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Notice and comment for applications by foreign manufacturers of
                    cylinders</header>
 <text>On receipt of an application for approval under section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), the Secretary shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="id356BDC328D684AC7A9D40525E7B4D435">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>timely publish notification of the application on the website of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5FDE62A78BF94B84AC815206BD3F9DAF">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>provide 30 days for public comment on the application prior to approval.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="id530754ac59f94b848c4a0d18f220f380"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Additional questions To ensure safety and compliance with DOT processes</header> <paragraph id="id3e4a90edc12f4a59b311ee73db3564ec"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Additional questions</header> <text>The Secretary shall require, as part of an application for approval pursuant to section 107.807 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), that the applicant answer the following questions:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="ida3a36688fdab4f2792060f277d8dad06">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, has ever been subject to a civil monetary penalty under title 49, United States Code, relating to any actions carried out as an approved FMOC or during the application for approval under that section.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id8aebcd601aa348a091d544027447ed7f">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, has been delinquent in the payment of any civil monetary penalties or other fines or fees under title 49, United States Code.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id5d2b6d971b484855ac9274e340356adc">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, is subject to the Do Not Pay Initiative established under section 3354 of title 31, United States Code, as of the date of the application.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idaa36017b633749ae8e4f0916acf0c9be">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, is listed in the Military End User List of the Department of Commerce as of the date of the application.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id93f7ca13ed5c4f9582ac95a3790ca934">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, is identified by the Department of Defense as an entity listed under section 1237 of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</external-xref>) as of the date of application.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9d66b2d04bff4cdaa2858b1cebccebfb">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, has been found guilty of a criminal penalty or assessed a civil penalty under section 1760 of division A of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4819">50 U.S.C. 4819</external-xref>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id0df72a1de37947609e3d8a0388b1d07f">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Whether the FMOC applying, or any entity controlling more than 10 percent of that FMOC, is subject to a final antidumping or countervailing duty order from the Department of Commerce as of the date of application.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5cfd35699f6f4e3db95a2d97f2358637">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Denial of application</header>
 <text>The Secretary may deny under section 107.709 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), an application for approval under section 107.807 of that title (or a successor regulation) based on the responses to the questions required under paragraph (1).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ide0d83e99f0244361a3ab2125bf68b30f">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Foreign manufacturers listing approvals</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall publish and maintain on the website of the Department of Transportation a list of approved foreign manufacturers of cylinders and the duration of those approvals.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id28c4cd59ca444f1caee462daa4cae402">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Authorizing foreign inspections</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise section 107.807(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations—</text>
                <paragraph id="id95488cfebd464f129d31e363d43d5021">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to require that in any case in which the Secretary determines there is good cause, an inspection under that section shall be carried out annually for such duration as the Secretary determines appropriate;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id34e99927d514421b87eb142c547bdf57">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to specify that a refusal of inspection under that section shall result in a loss of the status of in good standing;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc7c13cadbead4e16ab8f4ede20ba9f58">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to allow the Secretary to request, at the discretion of the Secretary—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id332A83155CCD40DBAA71319B3F4C26E5">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>production of test and production records; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idAE31F243CD934289BF388165311159F4"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>random sample testing; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc93d9d1e89a74ae68e11cfd9d0e0be99">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to allow for the recovery of all associated costs of foreign inspections to include travel, time, and other costs, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

