<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB74D4F07FBBB42D6A229849C00ACC837" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4160 IH: Veterans Border Patrol Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4160</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a pilot program to hire transitioning servicemembers to be Border Patrol agents.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6EB304E29D6F4B3FA7FEF79B637F9F10" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB0735313230240289A0921FCB9323711" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Border Patrol Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H096C5B86B8A0437EA8FE023E83036F54" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Border Patrol Skillbridge Pilot Program</header> <subsection id="H647FBD0239074B299009C87ECBE089A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish an interdepartmental pilot program through which the Department of Homeland Security shall use the Department of Defense SkillBridge Program to train and hire transitioning servicemembers as Border Patrol agents for U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3799E1A7885F44F7A2212E6D8E8D9431"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Employment skills training</header> <text>In carrying out the pilot program established pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the Secretary of Defense, shall use the authorities available under section 1143 of title 10, United States Code, to train and facilitate the transition of members of the Armed Forces to service as Border Patrol agents.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HE87AA6BCEDFE4AD0A0CAB97C740F54A5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the pilot program is established pursuant to section 2(a), and annually thereafter until the date referred to in section 4, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes for the reporting period—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4C5B31E06EF34B11AC9520E3CCEAED0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of participants in the pilot program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H029CC97A0A9B451EB501CD01EB77C032"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of eligible participants who applied to be part of the pilot program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DDFCEF9C7284EF19540FB0CA3FD113C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of pilot program participants who are—</text> <subparagraph id="H0462F0C3052B43239F4AD9CBBB4BED61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDBA128AEA1342F1AF2F0D6B97A77FF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reserve members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD08B03D617A54AE9BB08279CDEADF883"><enum>(C)</enum><text>commissioned officers or non-commissioned officers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H064A9C723C1A4FB299704FC5278F76A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enlisted members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07755251165746FE94C99AECC3217F16"><enum>(E)</enum><text>veterans;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5195500E8E5E47349A05885571AE5975"><enum>(F)</enum><text>spouses of such members of the Armed Forces or veterans; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A8B8DEF29AA409A95970E3AECADEC19"><enum>(G)</enum><text>dependents of such members of the Armed Forces or veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H92CBE212930E46A0A184470AE797FCC2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The pilot program established pursuant to section 2 shall be terminated on the date that is 5 years after the date on which such program is established.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

