<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3380B34D9AE4FFBA1B8ABC51C077C89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2345 IH: Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve Establishment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve in the State of Georgia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B5D30F4B04348BAB0BEC9E76F64188D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HAFC5A0F1AB1E48D09A442263C8E84257"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve Establishment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H392617B2698D4CD4B9B5EC2A1852FEE1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8379F1DC8964730B492D8271D85CE23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve Advisory Council established under section 5(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DFA7FA0229D44F69338BFD1723755B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 363/193026, and dated September 2024. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A733917FD094BB8949AB1273650DB05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85C0E4A2726045C8BF3A78DBE1EDCAE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Georgia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC0ED593EEB34F4EA923B18565678D04"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Muscogee (Creek) Nation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H12487AE6A8434DCE9E8E7FB45E1B197A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation of Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and establishment of Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CE97C155CAB428A9A7CC59DFCF2527B"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Redesignation of Ocmulgee Mounds National Park; land acquisition</header> <paragraph id="HD4A2A41C7769463891DF4B848132A8EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park designated by section 2102(b)(1)(A) of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410yyy-3">16 U.S.C. 410yyy–3(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) shall be known and designated as the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8578D1F8CB244CA5AB8DECBE20A9E2A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94C2E02371E74AB1B433D58EF17AB0F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Land acquisition for Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</header> <subparagraph id="H17E5A8C3821B4E3B89A647406F414B37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire land or any interest in land within the area depicted as <quote>National Park Area</quote> on the Map for inclusion in the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park by purchase from a willing seller, donation, or exchange. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52DCABB314954E9197910429EC640D04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Any land or interest in land acquired under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2FFC23D8D8A4C6C8B32652CDD5BB78C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporated into the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB37AF9D9808E469BB053004E384F4B3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administered by the Secretary in accordance with section 4.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0ECC1B22E0E4CFFBF034FFB1E3D6002"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of eminent domain</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph authorizes the use of eminent domain to acquire land or an interest in land. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H89B81A8952A74BE1A7DAD77137445D2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve</header>
<paragraph id="HC999ACCAFA6E480BA40B360667D89D4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a notice that the Secretary has determined that sufficient land within the area depicted as <quote>National Preserve Area</quote> on the Map has been acquired under paragraph (2) to constitute a manageable unit, there is established the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve in the State as a unit of the National Park System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9CCCF559CFF4643AC109D48C9D6543C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land acquisition for Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve</header> <subparagraph id="H0949A274C9004091A36598B9AFE0478B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire land or any interest in land within the area depicted as <quote>National Preserve Area</quote> on the Map for inclusion in the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve by purchase from a willing seller, donation, or exchange. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1DF78586D69E4E799411F7153C15D967"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Any land or interest in land acquired under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6BF6C4A90AD43E895B078E7200FBB7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporated into the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F3C715C4956436EB6971DF77F36AA15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administered by the Secretary in accordance with section 4.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D89B080E4AA4156897200C5D5EED73D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of eminent domain</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph authorizes the use of eminent domain to acquire land or an interest in land. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A0EF58DBBF64294867EF3E8C409D764"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The boundaries of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve shall reflect the land and interests in land acquired for the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve under paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B9388FE18A94761A38F4B46E65BAF72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header> <paragraph id="HA00A197595CE484CAD728C19065B447E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The Secretary may make technical corrections to the Map.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H365CD9AAFDB54C29AF610AF83831DFE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H0E22702C02E04503B94732287C86E4F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration of Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve</header> <subsection id="H7F31D662A6B04E418B4358FEE6C6A966"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve shall— </text>
<paragraph id="HF36916D2AC404A1E83D47BBB2456CF55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be administered as a single unit of the National Park System in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBD11EB0ED6C46679F37276F600768D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C112A61FE2742A5A1B565E26F32CE6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text> <clause id="HBB10C7D180B448C08B5E21D44C6A2A80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3B88409A76F24D40A65B73B9329DB31C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76F7A18DE975412AAF10EC2BE15F53E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any management plan developed under subsection (b); and </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E9DAE0AD38F4A70A946405A78211E37"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collectively be known and designated as the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H996B6001EE1141BE9890F07B1FAA9A57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <paragraph id="HB554211A8A0844859A32768FBA936849"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Council, shall develop a general management plan for the preservation and use of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3C9E7E5FC9F43F4A80EF06848E8E4E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cultural resources and landscapes</header><text>The general management plan developed under paragraph (1) shall provide for—</text> <subparagraph id="H54D976DF484B4A809D9DD0B833859B9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text> the interpretation and preservation of cultural resources of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve, including burial grounds and other sites that are sacred to the Tribe; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB13D0C6312E94FAE9E11DCB177BF17CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an inventory of important cultural landscapes, including flora, that should be preserved, managed, developed, and maintained because of the cultural, natural, and public use significance of the cultural landscapes, including to the Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H092E1C47D8014061B2FBAC9E92476F89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hunting and fishing</header> <paragraph id="HA652B42062C54DBBB861E0F32EA100EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hunting</header><text>The Secretary shall allow hunting on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the boundaries of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Preserve in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2DF0270F6B7A46ECB790C3BCEC12F9C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fishing</header><text>The Secretary shall allow fishing on waters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the boundaries of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87DDA9B1059F4998852517EBABAC6D2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may designate zones in which, and establish periods during which, no hunting, fishing, or both, shall be allowed for reasons of public safety, administration, fish or wildlife management, or emergencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE2D2C337D774D939796E3C82C90B177"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure any regulations prescribing such restrictions under this subsection shall be put into effect only after consultation with the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF2A61B4B7A5423CA3E88E15FC632816"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Private land</header><text>Nothing in this subsection prohibits hunting, fishing, or trapping on private land in accordance with applicable State and Federal laws.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H780F0E6CB237460F962C409D85A76C40"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Congressional intent</header><text>Nothing in this Act is intended to affect the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FFB9272B69141BD954A3BAF95C8DA28"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hiring preference</header><text>The Secretary shall establish policies to provide a preference for hiring members of the Tribe for positions at the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve, consistent with the Indian preference policy established by the Secretary of the Interior under section 12 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>) (48 Stat. 986, chapter 576; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5116">25 U.S.C. 5116</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H48E7DD98BAA243C68D1282151B035651" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect on administration of Bond swamp national wildlife refuge</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H018A33CBF66E4F83B16CC226F6E36B08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in this Act affects the continued administration of the Bond Swamp National Wildlife Refuge by the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service as a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H875C35B96F2649E18726B1213E0CFCFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cultural interpretation activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Park Service shall consult with the Tribe to provide cultural programs and related activities with respect to the Bond Swamp National Wildlife Refuge with the consent of the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8A53BD599A14E1781C5925541EA5234"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tribal consultation</header><text>Nothing in this Act prevents continued consultation with federally recognized Indian Tribes pursuant to Executive Order 13175 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Indian Tribal governments). </text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA80E82EA191C4578A17F4126E1892672"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Military overflights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act precludes—</text>
<paragraph id="HA10F10B2B18B4DADB51DD4D850F6726A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68246AD95E514F74A5938388B7E40246"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special use airspace over the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9E35C3CD4EEA4F71BA51DF452AB1F9D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H327AA77B7DBD47C1A50809C389AB9B25"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sacred and cultural sites</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the protection of sacred sites and cultural sites within the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve and provide access to the sites by members of Indian Tribes who have ancestral connections to the Ocmulgee River Corridor, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996 et seq.</external-xref>) and Executive Order 13007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref> note; relating to Indian sacred sites). </text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7D688FA831064EBE959FAEED67D7AC0E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Advisory council</header>
<subsection id="H4B3C4309C09C4668903E1F2E0865C7B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory council, to be known as the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve Advisory Council</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H39BA704039EC4FA9B74CC1E69E38362C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD05C78FF8887471FB5E93B6EB23C45D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Secretary with respect to the development and implementation of the management plan for the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H133329400666493CB44D0E855847E579"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the Secretary recommendations regarding how the Secretary would consider and accommodate Tribal interests in the management of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve, including recommendations regarding how the Secretary and the Tribe may collaborate with respect to land management, species management, and the interpretation of cultural resources and resources of the Tribe at the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and Preserve. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H89F14F67EB3848AFB608951959BE977D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Advisory Council shall consist of 7 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA47F419C581245058F51084726FFE670"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 member, who shall be a representative of the applicable National Park Service office.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A4054910B404BE1929F2432FE102CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>1 member, who shall be a representative of the applicable United States Fish and Wildlife Service office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE7F95A40CFE4239AD4670A5D0F416B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>3 members, who shall be representatives of the Tribe.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H445D89727A09432F85027D0133D936E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>1 member, who shall be a representative of the State Department of Natural Resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBA834BB769E46018B898F43A698DFD9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>1 member, who shall be appointed after considering recommendations from the Middle Georgia Regional Commission. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H11ECC25C68854450936DB2F75DC05F98"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote><act-name parsable-cite="FACA">Federal Advisory Committee Act</act-name></quote>) (other than section 1013 of that title), and other applicable laws.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8957EC333C614E8592BE41054BF347CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on the Advisory Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99A6D5148E1A45ABA12382E11C582DEF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Advisory Council (including not fewer than 1 member who is a designated representative of the Tribe) shall constitute a quorum.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA9EF12526A04AB9BF6B4BBF907375EF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Frequency of meetings</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet 2 times per year, or more often as the Chairperson of the Advisory Council determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8CB63F0496E64631975FE22036FD66AE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32D375B1038C48C78AC93B27EC8BFE08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">elect a chairperson of the Advisory Council from among the members of the Advisory Council; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C1ED6A3441044D6AF380AD6AF02BA3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish any rules and procedures for the Advisory Council that the Advisory Council determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC0EDF942E3C640FB8E27DE43F25B7D14"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No compensation</header><text>Members of the Advisory Council shall serve without compensation.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD086EE41436B46868BD7896E10D3116C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Land to be held in trust</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the approximately 126 acres of land owned in fee by the Tribe are hereby taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe. Such land—</text> <paragraph id="H2145C6CB2034425B876B447DA84CD3A9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is part of Indian country (as defined in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code) of the Tribe; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3ED962883CAD4C1CB5AE621B3780FE28" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to property held in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H27AD2D2320B24BB8A6B8276ED4CE659D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

