<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25018-6YJ-DP-96H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S74 IS: Fair Play for Girls Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 74</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Attorney General to submit to Congress a report relating to violence against women in athletics.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Play for Girls Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5993aa1e6204584b86c3cd089b4c128"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a report on violence against females in athletics in the United States that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id917ac9fc2f3b47c69f62c945caf400f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfccca0ba8673458b9a9c92589ce56fed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impediments to fair and safe competition for biological female athletes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02856cfd465e4651b6b55a79c9468645"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prevalence of biological female athletes losing opportunities, including medals and championships, when competing against biological males;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida85e3df19aca451f997279f0d069b181"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of State laws aimed at mitigating the risk of bodily harm and loss of opportunity associated with the permitting of biological men to compete in women’s sports; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id111b9bd360584b6f8c6a15eb98b3b00a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the prevalence and root causes of online violence, harassment, and abuse against women and girls in athletics; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id900a5cb4263244738291144ff19f4e1a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the prevalence of sexual harassment and abuse of women and girls in athletics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cf376c2322e415ea74d53e629379be2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the effectiveness of Federal and State laws aimed at preventing the sexual harassment and abuse of women and girls in athletics; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c5f33c56707425e957dd42f83c9e411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>policy recommendations to solve the issues described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

