<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H046BABB0DCB14F88976573E8D2A0299D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 23 EH: Illegitimate Court Counteraction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 23</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the International Criminal Court engaged in any effort to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute any protected person of the United States and its allies.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H868A733ED5DB4632BBB55D7EDFF448AC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6219215B0C43418B9B5C24DD2C07B8F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegitimate Court Counteraction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H88CF3C2A69C0496E86B8A6C900F4C288"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF693BFE9D989472FB33F737400A8A381"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States and Israel are not parties to the Rome Statute or members of the International Criminal Court (ICC), and therefore the ICC has no legitimacy or jurisdiction over the United States or Israel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99B291A34C8D437D89B73F2D4B99E510"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On May 20, 2024, the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, Karim Khan, announced arrest warrant applications for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Minister of Defense Yoav Gallant and should be condemned in the strongest possible terms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2739615DB1C41DE87D5D6CD64F8FAF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On November 21, 2024, the ICC’s Pre-Trial Chamber issued warrants for the arrest of Netanyahu and Gallant, which should be condemned in the strongest possible terms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2941CE1F64164C24B2D37D3CFA7230AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The bipartisan American Servicemembers’ Protection Act was enacted in 2002 to protect United States military personnel, United States officials, and officials and military personnel of certain allied countries against criminal prosecution by an international criminal court to which the United States is not party, stating, <quote>In addition to exposing members of the Armed Forces of the United States to the risk of international criminal prosecution, the Rome Statute creates a risk that the President and other senior elected and appointed officials of the United States Government may be prosecuted by the International Criminal Court.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE6822A27DF84168B4C80F98A207646C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ICC’s actions against Israel, including the preliminary examination and investigation of Israel and issuance of arrest warrants against Israeli officials, are illegitimate and baseless and create a damaging precedent that threatens the United States, Israel, and all United States partners who have not consented to the ICC’s jurisdiction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C98B19919A94B63AB09C91E27674F1B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States must oppose any action by the ICC against the United States, Israel, or any other ally of the United States that has not consented to ICC jurisdiction or is not a state party to the Rome Statute of the ICC.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H2987431DBF1346BD88842B846546340C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to the international criminal court</header> 
<subsection id="HABB91A6890A947E7BD6E7F8DE77E46D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and on an ongoing basis thereafter, if the International Criminal Court is engaging in any attempt to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute any protected person, the President shall impose—</text> <paragraph id="H41BD3064158643EAAA34EA15ED0A08DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H34AE1CC4D84F4E7A861B481A2CD82988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has directly engaged in or otherwise aided any effort by the International Criminal Court to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute a protected person;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H569741E48964447DB2B4CBF36A3FA596"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of any effort by the International Criminal Court to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute a protected person; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H695287D4F73A465CA319C34CB517A1CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by, or is currently acting or purports to have acted, directly or indirectly, for or on behalf of any person that directly engages in any effort by the International Criminal Court to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute a protected person; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC82B6E7A5644E1FA4248F850C72A552"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sanctions described in subsection (b)(2) with respect to the immediate family members of each foreign person who is subject to sanctions pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0B0174007C84871AFB4ED2D4C3EC526"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDA6F807950A149B085D8FD761D2941D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property blocking</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any foreign person described in subsection (a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6542D0593504FA0B48DB48D48358D9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7E6B131673444857AE2F1763B756212B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>In the case of an alien described in subsection (a), the alien is—</text> <clause id="HE8A6491236724E62BFF563777A112E5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4DD7764F7C2F425E802D844DF9FE94C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H531503B18C414134B5FA6A00B54CB630"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECDF8142A36B4818B30A9DD9D2B8FD6F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> 
<clause id="H3BB8CE85F53B4E7A924B9CBA306CC7B8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></clause> <clause id="H4A80E7491DAC473A8BEF5F524F94AF93"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H407D2A214DCF446A9A5BAF20BA7F3DCC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H92FB46DAD03A48349DBB1FF4750705EE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H51DA2772082946C982DE581A04AFF61E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="HC966D6E37191419BA9FB76D2C2B0960C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H532BA3636A694FD58E42D1F40822A305"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE47ACBFABC9B44CD9657F04BDBA3F401"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification to congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days after any imposition of sanctions pursuant to subsection (a), the President shall brief and provide written notification to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the imposition of sanctions that shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HA78096E397D549BDA855D8CEA1BC328F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the foreign person or persons subject to the imposition of such sanctions, including the foreign person’s role at or relation to the International Criminal Court;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC46A901B53C244BAA7977F711FEA5D46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any activity undertaken by such foreign person or persons in support of efforts to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute any protected person; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3634516FFDAB49FDA55D3476A42535EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the specific sanctions imposed on such foreign person or persons.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6E3D2068A684AF4829A329266D90930"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="HF9ECB538673542198874BDEB86BE6D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis and for periods not to exceed 90 days each, waive the application of sanctions imposed or maintained with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees before the waiver is to take effect a report that contains a determination of the President that the waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H599AE4ECE04B45CAB00575777894EA11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) with respect to a waiver of the application of sanctions imposed or maintained with respect to a foreign person under this section, or the renewal of such a waiver, shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF795D74E58534BA58FDEC6E75C84BC4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a specific and detailed rationale for the determination that the waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76641157E89B4FB99FF610E7258A6EB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the activity that resulted in the foreign person being subject to sanctions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B62D664AF9846228FEDACE64DE79BFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description and list of actions the United States has taken to stop the International Criminal Court from engaging in any effort to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute all protected persons; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A693B5B972345D597FD3BE3E8D78A14"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description and list of actions the International Criminal Court has taken to permanently close, withdraw, end, or otherwise terminate any preliminary examination, investigation, or any other effort to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute all protected persons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABAAECF379D04D8BBA7E5EB043C511BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required by paragraph by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H76AA8C7B943546739E9C3AD15765EDBB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The President may terminate the sanctions with respect to the foreign persons described in subsection (a) if the President certifies in writing to the appropriate congressional committees that the International Criminal Court—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB502AD6270E4C5D806BC3B1F66F45C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has ceased engaging in any effort to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute all protected persons; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DBD1EBBA64D4946B4F92B0E2E51BCE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has permanently closed, withdrawn, ended, and otherwise terminated any preliminary examination, investigation, or any other effort by the International Criminal Court to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute all protected persons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD847D566BD724321BB83DAD45FFDE964"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rescission of funds for international criminal court</header> 
<subsection id="H58D87E4293AF4A7689654EE698FA77A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act, any amounts appropriated for the International Criminal Court and available for obligation as of such date of enactment are hereby rescinded.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A0BE0B574EF4542B69E5FCBB4F2A3BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on future appropriations</header><text>On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, no appropriated funds may be used for the International Criminal Court.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8942787EB6104406B0D09954F29A3016"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0CE66E5D965B48ACAF4F4AF63BB6F0FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted alien</header><text>The terms <quote>admitted</quote> and <quote>alien</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D237F9EEDC3426F8A5592AC360147CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ally of the united states</header><text>The term <quote>ally of the United States</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5AD598E8D8094FB7B91B8300E256DE0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a government of a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDDF86A82CB04FC7A1950A5B0D76ECE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a government of a major non-NATO ally, as that term is defined by section 2013(7) of the American Service-Members’ Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7432">22 U.S.C. 7432(7)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1F9479C70EE4CB2B566747D88C471BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H77981311A14A405097352E3BA8B8EBAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC73423A1A50049CA879039F9D879BC27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37A74CEC48E34B668B65D19DCFDD06AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C1B7D8F33544B6EA6A006B8880B16D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <quote>immediate family member</quote>, with respect to a foreign person, means the spouse, parent, sibling, or adult child of the person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H531DC3DFC64A4D60905E09ADEF7B5E88"><enum>(6)</enum><header>International criminal court; rome statute</header><text>The terms <quote>International Criminal Court</quote> and <quote>Rome Statute</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 2013 of the American Service-Members’ Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7432">22 U.S.C. 7432</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FBFD4352F5242CBBF30B01E920D4942"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protected person</header><text>The term <quote>protected person</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1C145B22E701439981873AA1CAE0AA2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any United States person, unless the United States provides formal consent to International Criminal Court jurisdiction and is a state party to the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court, including—</text> <clause id="H82513C5BDB554BABA008AE4A9322F0D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>current or former members of the Armed Forces of the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBEA6D02DBC4C47CDB6C2F12C64C35F7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>current or former elected or appointed officials of the United States Government; and</text></clause> <clause id="H46E6949F8FD24950A41C07E53A6CFA6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person currently or formerly employed by or working on behalf of the United States Government;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9658764DFC42464593DF180DC01F8A10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any foreign person that is a citizen or lawful resident of an ally of the United States that has not consented to International Criminal Court jurisdiction or is not a state party to the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court, including—</text> <clause id="H23BEB459A87C4505B99C2C26820C6636"><enum>(i)</enum><text>current or former members of the Armed Forces of such ally of the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3D9733D66CDB4F8C9F85DC80411E8028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>current or former elected or appointed government officials of such ally of the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBC63D74D4E0F44B4954273F7C5F08254"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person currently or formerly employed by or working on behalf of such a government.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CC44E8C2ED44EF9B19395E2F082F16E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0EFFA6409CB042669DD88EDAF4A1FFB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC8FB1D25CB74862ACB0F495C03309EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4430548C3ED410DB660C5820E9B5EFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250109" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 9, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


