<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H08EFCDAEAED34E10A506F39F293CDCC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1385 IH: Strengthening Cooperation and Security in the Middle East Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1385</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250214">February 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, to develop a strategy to increase membership in the Comprehensive Security Integration and Prosperity Agreement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF83C6A89DB124A129DBE17B19086EB6B" style="OLC"><section id="HDD251AB60B7C4228A3F097FD629AE540" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the ‘‘<short-title>Strengthening Cooperation and Security in the Middle East Act</short-title>”.</text></section><section id="H519AE617B89B49749565021AC40B51AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report and strategy on increasing membership in the Comprehensive Security Integration and Prosperity Agreement</header><subsection id="H610EC3F22E36436C84E4870E7767F072"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H3810DDA96BD545B08DE83EB6F4BA0A55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes a strategy to increase membership in the Comprehensive Security Integration and Prosperity Agreement (CSIPA), done at Washington, DC on September 9–13, 2023. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA5951C22A3446DB4A5E08F6EAF0A06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall also include—</text><subparagraph id="HD1250ADB5D244DB78D5D849AEBE44E2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text><clause id="HF8031AFED0EB4153833A037555CC89B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the comprehensive strategic benefits of CSIPA, including improving joint military readiness in the Middle East, enhancing shared economic interests, collaborating on advanced technological and scientific pursuits, and building stronger regional alliances to improve stability and counter mutual threats;</text></clause><clause id="H8AC7A441E6584C92B32E96A370B9813F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the role of CSIPA in supporting rapid and effective responses following the Houthi attacks on merchant vessels the Red Sea that occurred since October 7, 2023; </text></clause><clause id="HA4DED99CC16F482EB05074238F2F80B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the CSIPA framework can leverage the United States Navy’s Fifth Fleet headquartered in Bahrain for projecting strength in the region and supporting immediate responses to imminent threats posed by the Islamic Republic of Iran or other adversaries of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HA7ED9115F5824818B89E4A6364679FF6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the long-term benefits of widened membership in CSIPA; </text></clause><clause id="H1448165B5FD44A9AA3E7551E89C4B84D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how the framework of CSIPA can be altered to foster broader regional security integration, bolster mutual deterrence against external threats, and expand cooperation in the fields of commerce, science, and technology; </text></clause><clause id="H43DB25FDFA7A4E19801A31D8BDC1E8BC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>requirements for resources and capabilities that can be provided to expand CSIPA membership; and </text></clause><clause id="HB2A991839DEE4D7F96DD2CAF1DA65367"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>domestic and regional factors or barriers among allied countries of the United States and Bahrain that may be limiting the expansion of CSIPA; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73B1CD29CD584B8C87F75F6E2F1521CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for areas of further collaboration between the United States and other CSIPA members. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F3128115B484598BF64B6F49A684CEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph id="H16E75D6009734E75937BCD06697907C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the submission of the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy on how to best engage allied countries in the Middle East and outside of the Middle East to join CSIPA and affirmative steps the Administration can take to increase membership in that agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB450FCF3CCF248708D3FBC328DE2C1FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary develops the strategy required by this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on a plan for implementing the strategy. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA54031F2DAC4F65B3F0A675DEAD8625"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) and the strategy required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA24EB8D5F7EB45E2A17A8B48F59D7261"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term ‘‘appropriate congressional committees’’ means—</text><paragraph id="H405001FDD3CE476B87646C04660B9934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A57F045E8341518D2521D27C4800A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

