<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B13BE08772340FA83C2B16CD2FA1343" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 HR 4027 IH: Frontline Fighter Force First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4027</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To recognize the historical achievements, the ongoing service, and to make a priority recapitalization of the frontline and surge fighter forces at active-duty Air Force bases.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF970321D5D234E859BFE919034E6DD7F" style="OLC"><section id="H0FA2D0F1600243C4B26C2E0A308F127F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frontline Fighter Force First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H95B04673B9374C4991C671A3D0FF5F73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H3FC1C15C54AA4512AA8E84FC34ECA4B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ensuring that the United States military remains the strongest fighting force in the world requires a highly mission capable frontline fighter fleet across fourth, fifth, and next-generation platforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16241077A2F04AE6A0B5A2239C4E881B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In particular, fighter wings that deploy at least 50 percent of the time, including the 335th operational squadron at Seymour Johnson Air Force Base, are on the frontlines of the fight for freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD99A304FC51844008CD46A314202E9EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At the same time, with declining mission capable rates, including 55 percent for the F–15E fleet, prioritizing recapitalization of legacy aircraft with aging equipment and engines like the Block 220 F–15Es must be a priority for the U.S. Air Force. By recapitalizing active-duty bases with upgraded fourth generation aircraft like the F–15EX to replace the legacy fleet, the U.S. can fulfill its mission to sustain optimal mission readiness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC01BECE80E4185A60696B112737A0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Further, that recognizing the historical contributions of Strike Eagle aircraft at a time when they continue to deliver unmatched payload capability and range in active theaters, including CENTCOM, is a high congressional priority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B0F5C2DCA6341ECBE0CA5206855F0BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>F–15E aircraft can carry up to 12 unique missiles, an unrivaled combination of heavy payload and long range with stealth capability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H269378245B5D4CEC971578254A4F6D4A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Since their first combat flight, F–15Es boast an undefeated 104–0 winning record in Air-to-Air missions across the Persian Gulf, Iraqi, and counterterrorism operations in the CENTCOM AOR.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F6D1C19A3E4EFFB1BE10469BC75EB4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>During the Iraq War, F–15E Strike Eagles from Seymour Johnson Air Force Base in Goldsboro, North Carolina, played a significant role, deploying for Operation Iraqi Freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC3A858E82C46308DC4683EE0467B55"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Then, on April 13, 2024, with only 24 hours to prepare ahead of an unprecedented ballistic missile attack from Iran, airmen from the 335th operational squadron, under command of the 4th Fighter Wing based at Seymour Johnson deployed in four F–15Es that alone intercepted more than two dozen of the one-way attack drones fired at Israel and U.S. military personnel based in the region. They defended our coalition partners, including Israel, embodying the true essence of service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E18FD8766C4454A543D707AC2C0EEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To commemorate their courage, General Ken Wilsbach, commander of Air Combat Command, awarded airmen from the 4th Fighter Wing high-level decorations during a ceremony at Seymour Johnson Air Force Base. The airmen were recognized for their rapid response and valiant performance in the largest air-to-air engagement in over 50 years. Those heroes, receiving well-deserved decorations and surrounded by their families, have rightfully earned our nation’s deep gratitude. To fighter pilots, maintainers, and all airmen that keep the F–15E fleet alive and well, Congress must continue to uplift the power of the E platform, including upgraded F–15EX fighters.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HADAA7C201D0F41AA9AD732C6E99597ED"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recapitalization of air force active duty frontline fighter force</header><subsection id="HCA9AA0C17C2544EE89073CF18F3C2417"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procurement of fighter aircraft</header><paragraph id="HEDD4A610F04D4D739D8E0EA6DBE90AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Air Force shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure the continued production and procurement of at least one model of advanced capability fighter aircraft until the date on which the Secretary certifies to the congressional defense committees that the Secretary has replaced all legacy capability fighter aircraft within each Air Combat Command Fighter Wing with an advanced capability fighter aircraft, with replacements made sequentially, starting with fighter squadrons that deploy at least 30 percent of the time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20269EEF11714C71A48B3780B45AEA44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>For purposes of fulfilling the requirements of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H36D80D6FB1124FA5A1428EB54A7BA519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek to enter into a contract for the procurement of advanced capability fighter aircraft; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8B3273869C343FE9AC971ADAAE72006"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modify a contract to provide for the procurement of additional advanced capability fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA751E1F0122D47D4AC663723579CB7EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gao review and report</header><subparagraph id="HFF47509D1D93489A8C79E37CB04085CB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of advanced capability fighter aircraft. Such review shall include—</text><clause id="H3D905F31D447499E8933ADA1C7FF89D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of any challenges to the procurement of such aircraft by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H5D6F7B9690FF40B9829CD5BC85B060A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations on how to solve such challenges.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95BAEABF86934D7FABF3DF1703A57CA1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the preliminary findings of the review conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70317835CE8B4DB68D11A0F49B168585"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the Comptroller General provides a briefing under subparagraph (B), the Comptroller General shall submit to the congressional defense committees a final report on the review conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB578C0D7873E48688D8179C79ACB3A91"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on progress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Comptroller General provides a report under paragraph (3)(C) and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the progress of the Secretary in—</text><subparagraph id="HA322CE46FBB44DAE8435EA473B8E40C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing the recommendations of the Comptroller General issued pursuant to paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3043389E610E4AC2BF6E7B6860409F95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>replacing the legacy capability fighter aircraft within each Air Combat Command Fighter Wing with an advanced capability fighter aircraft, fifth generation fighter aircraft, or next-generation air dominance fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD572362FCB94692A02F9F6F2022FEAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5357B34505E546C09F24D6112CADF5F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>advanced capability fighter aircraft</term> means a Block 70/72 variant or later variant of the F–16 fighter aircraft, an F–15EX fighter aircraft, an F–35 fighter aircraft, an F–47 fighter aircraft, any future variant of such fighter aircraft, or any other more advanced capability fighter aircraft identified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1420A1564744C26994F06EC57DE1D10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E510B37B9A4FD190FC888DF7CFD1DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered Air Combat Command Fighter Wing</term> means any fighter unit of the Air Force with respect to which the Secretary has not commenced or completed the process of replacing the legacy capability fighter aircraft of such unit with advanced capability fighter aircraft or fifth generation aircraft as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD215D35C4E334C2F9D999EF7CAC81D26"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>fifth generation</term> has the meaning given such term in section 154(d)(2) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB62CF0A098B3499BB8BBE07101D0F17A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>fighter aircraft</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9062(i)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13BAF31B9DAD4C2DAD4EE7856CF4F138"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>legacy capability fighter aircraft</term> has the meaning given such term in section 154(d)(4) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

