<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAB8EE0EFC0AD4D1FADD774B0E5BA7B44" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4874 IH: Affordable Housing Resident Services Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4874</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize funding of enriched resident services in federally assisted affordable housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59A9BAD89CA242C695F1252ED3E616A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDC6433A27AE549C4AC14FFCC465DE5B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Housing Resident Services Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6DE46DB2207543F4BDF00B52AF306527"><enum>2.</enum><header>Affordable housing resident services grant program</header> <subsection id="H34BCF89C364E490AB1AC152F040BA826"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Administration of Children and Families (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), shall annually, as part of the Services Research Demonstration program, award grants on a competitive basis to eligible recipients as described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6F2A8FC9C7A344E4A448F1703EB076F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header>
<paragraph id="H319CF3542B6B4EBC826428FF35B72345"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant under this section may only be made only to—</text> <subparagraph id="H503244B1A88A493D8AA72AF3921010A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that has demonstrated experience and capacity in owning, managing, and operating qualified properties or delivering resident supportive services within qualified properties; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A22C6EAF2D9478CB59ADC585BC40129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a tribe or tribal organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74F99AE1F4E340F096DE820247D138C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Director shall give priority to mission-driven, non-profit entities when awarding grants under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA145C70506884F1B806D6D01CFFA77C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms of grant</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be funded for a term of 5 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H01B049C4C4774B7CA2C62325890952BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Voluntary services</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section may not require any resident to accept any services provided by such entity using such grant amounts. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2ADB4E4BF0D9443E9EAC200B00821072"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header>
<paragraph id="H76551E20150E44DB9A87B44B4F0263EE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible recipient may use not more than 75 percent of any amount awarded under this section to cover the costs of activities undertaken by a service coordinator—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2242681B51A4931B31E4B60E40706D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing the access of residents to health services, including mental health services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H78C664D9B59242D7B4C4039D01238E0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing educational opportunities for residents, including after-school programming, mentoring, tutoring, college and career readiness, and life skills training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40D49A3A0F2D4D50A949EABF95310632"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing the economic self-sufficiency of residents by providing financial literacy, housing stability, and homeownership opportunities or connecting residents with housing counselors approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to promote these services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8B1C5922F2F3424CA52412EED2700209"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting older adults to enable them to age in place, including by connecting them with services and supports to facilitate the ability to age in community, home modifications, accessibility upgrades, as well as home- and community-based services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23E5683AA81D41F0BF7642DFB7F43324"><enum>(E)</enum><text>enabling residents with disabilities to live independently and in integrated settings, including by providing home-and community-based services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H38BDE07F09E241FE99E64712A15175C1" commented="no">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting residents to receive public benefits for which they are eligible; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC8EBB390BEC74C2F913CAE477E3B09EA"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an additional activity as determined appropriate by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33DDDED55AD8413A91DCD31F52DDD64E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of amounts for salary, benefits, and training</header><text>Not less than 25 percent of any amounts awarded to an eligible recipient under this section shall be by such eligible recipient for salary, benefits, and training for service coordinators. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCA81D0C24A2B49E5BB6E8A726CEE1CD1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified properties</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified property</quote> means a property—</text> <paragraph id="H012986A9ADB2454190217A0D2C94DFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assisted under—</text>
<subparagraph id="H102BFDCC2A574A329C5C1F1CAAB819C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the low-income housing tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H440814B39DB94D61A3D813AB9B549BB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the project-based rental assistance programs under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, including units assisted by project-based vouchers under section 8(o)(13) of such Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD11A182C0C42457AA0DD9D0912D50683"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the program under section 236 of the National Housing Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD854E85D84E94A1BB163C59486FE2225"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the below-market interest rate mortgage program under section 22(d)(3) of the National Housing Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H20AD1F1D7A3C467A87F04F8A37F2AEA7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the rural rental housing program under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H842EB68706404F279495150988332327"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a program under title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11361">42 U.S.C. 11361 et seq.</external-xref>), but only permanent supportive housing projects subsidized under such programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFE684167AFE74B02B499B24B52DCD919"><enum>(G)</enum><text>section 1131 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/289">Public Law 110–289</external-xref>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD9C514D04D44BBCA75C863D3726EA3B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the supportive housing for the elderly program under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H47B6C2D5D77B4C189411262583A277E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the supportive housing program for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70C69AD2133A4E0AA9EA5815C480E752"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Housing Opportunities for Persons With AIDS under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC6A41EA737BE449CA76CAAA4E762AC9D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>affordable housing units owned by public housing agencies that are not assisted under the Housing Act of 1937; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0C9100703D7422983E3970D23251DF6" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">properties funded through, or who work in partnership with programs funded through, a community services block grant; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6809752735BB428C962305EECCBE5492"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise determined qualified by the Director. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H11EC30EFF52D452EABB8F5954E97EFCA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>Grants shall be awarded on a competitive basis, based on the following selection criteria:</text>
<paragraph id="HC5A16C92CBE84B008A41EA09DC8E102C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The extent to which a grant may enable an applicant to provide new types of enriched services, to provide services to more residents, or provide more effective services to residents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCC9653DB2D3458191EAB3EE31980237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which an applicant can demonstrate the likelihood of achieving objective outcomes for its residents that are described in the application.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB19F6E1394154B57A1996D09CE836FD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent of experience with respect to eligible activities and a demonstrable track record in providing resident services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05A93EF4C40B4BDBB78A6BF822664F50"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent of relationships and partnerships an applicant has with localities, non-profits, continuums of care, federally qualified health centers (as defined in section 861 of the Social Security Act), and other health care providers that provide services or facilitate the provision of services that improve outcomes for residents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D79E748716B45FFBE672564C2829674"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any experience the applicant has with respect to development, ownership, and management of qualified properties for low-income families, seniors, and disabled persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94A2D77918EF401D9E80438A7E0EBCB7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The selection of a diverse range of grantees, including minority business enterprises and owners of properties located in rural areas, persistent poverty areas, colonias, the United States territories, and other underserved areas.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE1DC86D862A248D08A571F6ABE735B74"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Director shall coordinate with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development as the Director determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC2D681F35AAF4FD8AF77801CEB9042BF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H41C3F50A748343AAADC6159631F3D48C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director may reserve not more than 5 percent of any amounts appropriated to carry out this section for technical assistance activities which support grantees under this program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H047C0D21CD9C4E3FA4CD7FAE74D9CFCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of grant funds under this section may reserve not more than 1 percent of amounts from each grant awarded for use to develop the capacity of the grantee associated with such grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B0103DB4C4D4663B636D2C0CC2B6C92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Caseworker Capacity</header><text>Amounts awarded to a grantee may be used by such grantee to finance the hiring of caseworkers to assist in carrying out eligible activities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H895514129D704F4392BD540DCE3D53EA"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Program evaluation and outcomes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, each grantee that receives amounts under this Act shall submit to the Director, and the Director shall post on a on a publicly accessible website, a description of each activity carried out by such grantee using amounts provided and the impact of such activity.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

