<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H246045DB69274CBBA146A97471F25DB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2977 IH: Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2977</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250421">April 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative to carry out projects for the protection and restoration of the Mississippi River Corridor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1E30B781D1874A589AF48807F203E5E6" style="OLC"><section id="HD4A75BE0E35E4DE887B054FCE233626A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MRRRI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEF636A0EB9264B9C883BA8ECA55C639B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to establish the Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative to protect and restore the ecological health and resilience of the Mississippi River for current and succeeding generations of Americans and for the fish and wildlife that rely on the Mississippi River and its floodplain. The MRRRI is a nonregulatory initiative that will build upon existing efforts and provide funding for projects and activities to protect and restore the nationally significant resources of the Mississippi River by—</text><paragraph id="H623B16D0E87049CDAB85B7B99A3F8072"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing the Mississippi River National Program Office;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E7D3AD7C104231B53213820BE20BC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing the focus areas and identifying qualifying activities for MRRRI programs and projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC3BEAD56DB4E3BB4E2483BA0060E88"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directing the development of actionable goals, an action plan, and a science plan, and regular updates to such plans, to guide the MRRRI and ensuring the integration of the MRRRI with other Federal, State, Tribal, and local programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H260445A4306B4E02BD96A5DD7F2FFC88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing criteria for measuring the success of the MRRRI in restoring the ecological health and resilience of the Mississippi River;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6FD5B8742C94EE1ABCFF261C7F1440A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>requiring the Environmental Protection Agency to coordinate and consult with Federal and non-Federal stakeholders to implement the MRRRI; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDC7F9276C84C2BBC2EAB5F6B8087FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establishing the Mississippi River Corridor Research Centers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1A126AF7BF4B4DC5B84299635B24511B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H45CDC1090E3D41709923E7A2C900A571" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H720E210E3B6D464BAAB211D99BE7E686"><enum>127.</enum><header>Mississippi River</header><subsection id="HACF4BD15637C4C1CA6182041E0B012E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3FFEC322C60E46CA991F18763E4E2E2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>Agency</quote> means the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD5A0D74E74E4535AF0820575C6717BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hypoxia Task Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Hypoxia Task Force</quote> means the Mississippi River/Gulf of Mexico Hypoxia Task Force established pursuant to section 603 of the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/4001">33 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF4474A6DD449CCB06AEA9999AE8556"><enum>(3)</enum><header>MRRRI</header><text>The term <quote>MRRRI</quote> means the Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative established by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B7B88C040824E2F909C36B7AD11E810"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program office</header><text>The term <quote>Program Office</quote> means the Mississippi River National Program Office established by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF915AEF923CC45EE8D6A27780A2567B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>MRRRI Director</header><text>The term <quote>MRRRI Director</quote> means the Director of the Mississippi River National Program Office established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14A7F0CED2524D729718F5B02D672329"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mississippi River Corridor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Mississippi River Corridor</quote> means the portions of the Mississippi River watershed (including tributary watersheds) located in a Mississippi River State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA61DD9DF555D4862A24C7578FD239E75"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Mississippi River State</header><text>The term <quote>Mississippi River State</quote> means Arkansas, Illinois, Iowa, Kentucky, Louisiana, Minnesota, Mississippi, Missouri, Tennessee, or Wisconsin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1A3A8B8D8C4548A5F1326CC02A3790"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Tribal government</quote> means the recognized governing body of an any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H520392101D9343ED985DBE346504EE44"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Tribal organization</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF02EF5A2412344A3AD8541FA0CCAA871"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Relevant Federal agency</header><text>The term <quote>relevant Federal agency</quote> means any of the following agencies: </text><subparagraph id="H0F6F58FE020B40779B1EAEF1F5D63064" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture—</text><clause id="H4E0113B5D0DA40EC82A621C48F302B10" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Natural Resources Conservation Service; and</text></clause><clause id="HFB051BC1CB634C30B95875AA6A653E7E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forest Service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE3B414CF3E441F6B45784598B58A5AA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior, including—</text><clause id="H4429A4785B0D4E718D4DF68C0DFC2B36" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text></clause><clause id="HF57BA1EFB2924789A76F168118239E92" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; </text></clause><clause id="H484E2AEC41DA4BAD860D3EC6D5C6BDC2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Geological Survey; and</text></clause><clause id="HD47F8A0CBCDD4237BAB086193765784F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Park Service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CA57B12F79343DF9F521581BF12515D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9A89C171BC43C6940AEC7F1BD55E2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE7E80D6D60E4A0E9E76C3ABAD4E409C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC2C08773FD74161B7E183538514A540"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Coast Guard.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFD96A652DE646BFB881AD363152F07E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other Federal agency the MRRRI Director determines is relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83E2B7DCE82D4AAD94BDCF3196CEF15E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mississippi River National Program Office</header><paragraph id="HE8DBEF3B29FD4AF6BCA539D49935B83B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a Mississippi River National Program Office within the Agency to carry out the Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9528FE840F864AC79BB0710D5E30753B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The Program Office shall be located in a Mississippi River State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE5DE08B3A2E4343858F8182C7F16E36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Program Office shall be headed by a Director, appointed by the Administrator, who has management experience and technical expertise relating to the Mississippi River and who is highly qualified to direct the development of programs and plans on a variety of issues related to restoration of the Mississippi River. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB2908A1C20458BBED9123A534D69B6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The MRRRI Director shall—</text><subparagraph id="H86B4D8D160004346B576F814BFEC3D06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate actions of the Agency that seek to protect and restore the Mississippi River Corridor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5553A3CAD2724B4489CADB7C2463AE91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, implement, and update the MRRRI, actionable goals, and action plan required by this section, in coordination with relevant Federal agencies and non-Federal entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06D3D67A5C1146B1A2C0E1C327DE313E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>document information and updates related to the development and implementation of the MRRRI, actionable goals, and action plan and make such information and updates available to the public, including on a public website;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4EA77C737204E77BE896A9BF0FC0CA3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate engagement and consultation with Tribal governments and Tribal organizations to ensure Tribal needs and priorities are solicited early and throughout the development of the actionable goals and action plan required by this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43A5687FE91345E5957E2582DD3960AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>work cooperatively with the Bureau of Indian Affairs and other Federal agencies to carry out subparagraph (D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BAF0E2EF66F4B508587A6BF82B0217C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>submit to Congress, and make available on a public website, an annual report describing—</text><clause id="HF8F7A37382024526A9077EB433A78888"><enum>(i)</enum><text>progress made in implementing the MRRRI;</text></clause><clause id="H71A1668986424706B43EB6F36F0DD3D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the coordination of the MRRRI with other Federal, State, Tribal, and local programs;</text></clause><clause id="H5BF36C148ECD4403876DC3B57EF6EAEC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any funds transferred to relevant Federal agencies under this section;</text></clause><clause id="H1E0AF5C6B87F4AB781B236D77FFB32A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any grants awarded under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H1DB7335D749A4732BB366AE5CF980831"><enum>(v)</enum><text>specific projects and activities carried out pursuant to this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32C4BB9E37554203B5E8F3D842E1D7E5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (4), the MRRRI Director may enter into agreements, as applicable, with relevant Federal agencies and non-Federal entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F533E4377434576AE74AFBB2BD2F9F9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tribal liaison</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The MRRRI Director shall appoint a Tribal Liaison within the Program Office to ensure enhanced interagency technical support, communication, and coordination with Tribal governments, Tribal organizations, and Tribal stakeholders, and to carry out other duties as determined necessary to meet the needs of Tribes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76D9BBC9B5594A2C8ABBD63C1FBA340F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative</header><paragraph id="H6C3C27C566C3438387EF1D12C5EF08A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Agency the Mississippi River Restoration and Resilience Initiative to implement projects for systemic, large-scale restoration of the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85A10EC5164642F19297833D803C42D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Focus areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any project or activity carried out under this section shall address at least 1 of the following focus areas:</text><subparagraph id="H387AB97E4EA54149B014962A6D433C58" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The improvement of water quality in the Mississippi River Corridor and drinking water quality in the Mississippi River States by—</text><clause id="HACEBA8B288E04BF7B1C55605CC5B7B8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing the amount of polluted runoff, excess agricultural nutrients, and sediment in the Mississippi River Corridor; and</text></clause><clause id="HE891175DE5874D15AB86294D6B90CA8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving source water protections. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91E6B95FA9914C7F901A6437B2B74B13"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The improvement of community resilience throughout the Mississippi River Corridor by restoring the ability of the Mississippi River floodplain, riverine wetlands, delta and coastal wetlands, and backwaters to minimize and ameliorate flood and storm risks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H694DBD20E0B341EE91C449E312357DCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The protection and restoration of fish and wildlife habitat in and along the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7F2156BB221495880D9B6EADECCA44D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The prevention of the spread of aquatic invasive species in the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6837CC5DB34B414591ED002B6D410F61" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The improvement of communication and partnership activities related to the focus areas described in subparagraphs (A) through (D). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H585D1F87021F458283491E5B85E005FC"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitoring, collecting, and evaluating scientific data to assess the focus areas described in subparagraphs (A) through (D). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51033452304047B0A60A45FE87E12B00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Project implementation</header><subparagraph id="HAC48A60D3D664BB59A3AFED7AE0B80A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funds made available to carry out the MRRRI may be used to implement eligible projects and activities described in paragraph (5) that are carried out by a relevant Federal agency or by a non-Federal entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0A49902CB6044BEA914DE8B95FCEB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The MRRRI Director, or the head of any other Federal agency receiving funds under this section, may make a grant to, or otherwise enter into an agreement with, any non-Federal entity (including any State, local, or Tribal governmental entity, nonprofit organization, institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)), or individual) that the MRRRI Director or agency head determines is qualified to carry out an eligible project described in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H752DB3C037074257B098BBCAF46A94EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project selection</header><subparagraph id="H4B834E1FAAEC4A2EBF4282B4F395E5E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the MRRRI, the MRRRI Director shall collaborate with relevant Federal agencies to select projects and activities to be implemented pursuant to this section using appropriate principles and criteria, including—</text><clause id="HE58C7C6895D54EC486B8CC6A2448B77F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the selection of an equitable distribution of projects and activities along the entire Mississippi River Corridor;</text></clause><clause id="H05C8DD2CE994496F80A01522C9B27EF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of a project to achieve strategic and measurable environmental outcomes;</text></clause><clause id="HD05901B0A535499FA3C192E77F2E67B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the recognition that projects may provide benefits to local or regional communities or to the entire Mississippi River Corridor;</text></clause><clause id="H5D9F57A406EB4F92A0A0CABF0E76D616"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the feasibility of prompt implementation, timely achievement of measurable results, and resource leveraging; and</text></clause><clause id="H547D343C1F6F4C288C96BD17363BADB2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the opportunity to improve interagency, intergovernmental, and interorganizational coordination and collaboration to reduce duplication and improve measurable environmental outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0939664DE37F4279A7923EB16EF17799" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compatibility</header><text>The MRRRI Director shall ensure that projects and activities carried out under this section are compatible with—</text><clause id="H40CB3C01EB18441DBC9273ACC69931F0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of the Corps of Engineers to maintain navigation in the Mississippi River; and</text></clause><clause id="H9E8828CD100841DF880DAD8F62302DF7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the structural integrity or effectiveness of Federal, State, local, or Tribal disaster risk reduction infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC824E0C45A74007BFF3C455970A56D6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><subparagraph id="H745FB1178BA74EEF97EA5D4EB321758D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funds made available to carry out this section may only be used to implement a project or activity that addresses at least 1 of the focus areas described in paragraph (2) and that carries out at least one of the actions described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B90AB73C17540B09CDD02888A337646"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>The actions referred to in subparagraph (A) are actions that—</text><clause id="HD88C09DD2ED24D298E4B27EE399C3B92"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect or restore naturally occurring hydrologic, geomorphic, and ecological functions and processes, including the restoration or rehabilitation of wetlands, in-stream habitats (including through reconnection of side channels and backwaters), living shorelines, or upland habitats;</text></clause><clause id="H410827A4FBCD422FA1E52DD7103BACCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remove or modify structures, including culverts, levees, and dams, to restore—</text><subclause id="H98C58193A3994408AEEBFF9D3F606613"><enum>(I)</enum><text>natural hydrology of rivers, streams, floodplains, wetlands, or coasts; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H64AA8F1838354005943E88919B5201A4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the form, function, or processes of rivers, streams, floodplains, wetlands, or coasts;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H651908EA24644D4DB046874F2373B1FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>permanently protect privately owned lands through fee title acquisition or enrollment into voluntary permanent wetland, flooding, or other conservation easements;</text></clause><clause id="H8F16DB1CC8AD4719A3E4EB3067F5D38F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate habitat restoration using responsibly sourced and clean dredged sediment material by covering the cost differential between the Federal standard for dredge disposal and the cost of transportation;</text></clause><clause id="H02AC7A11989F4B35BFABB8A0CA53DC62"><enum>(v)</enum><text>relocate, elevate, or demolish, and clean up flood-prone structures, and carry out any related floodplain restoration;</text></clause><clause id="HD6B2C486E07A4556BA61C29F3B50FC0F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase water retention and infiltration through actions that promote a healthy soil ecosystem, including maximizing soil cover, maximizing soil biodiversity, and maximizing the presence of living roots;</text></clause><clause id="H6364E7483FA24E1BB2372375689A4B95"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce nonpoint sources of pollution and promote landscape-scale vegetative cover (including perennial grains, perennial woody crops, winter annual cover crops, perennial pasture, and other approaches to maintain year-round vegetative cover) through the implementation of voluntary initiatives developed with the support of market research;</text></clause><clause id="HD0EEDC8EDA004B339F789C3805B72A39"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce stormwater flows and inflows that contribute to combined sewer overflow events, and accelerate the adoption of urban stormwater pollution prevention minimum control measures through municipal separate storm sewer system permits issued under section 402(p);</text></clause><clause id="HC5FD5B65EB4044ECB3670D0D62E68EEC" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the cleanup of legacy contaminants that are not hazardous substances (as defined in section 101 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>)) or designated as hazardous substances pursuant to section 102 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9602">42 U.S.C. 9602</external-xref>); </text></clause><clause id="H1567EEDEDC444C30A4BCFDDD18D4BAFA"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">control, manage, or eradicate nonnative aquatic invasive species or reintroduce native aquatic species, including through—</text><subclause id="HA79B603526A741A2A92F13E88AD80C56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>investments in technology and research to combat the spread of aquatic invasive species; </text></subclause><subclause id="H60D02235A8A0474983C6AF2B60F22AE6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the use of in-river physical deterrent or controls; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB9C0F42D5B3342CD9393E3C5B2882EE9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the promotion of commercial harvesting of nonnative aquatic species;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6AC942EE98644F3295B7301AE6C5EDAD"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build capacity within communities to undertake MRRRI projects to address the effects of the ecological degradation of the Mississippi River Corridor, including through—</text><subclause id="H4E21185BD10A4C83A74BB5151DF6CFBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community based participatory research;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB9D60F42157543D281B39B1B3D56646A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>project or community-wide planning;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3B67604E8AF487CAF109355A0BCAEC4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>outreach and community engagement; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H4D2C28664A2942B4997E8CD19D13366A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>restoration-related job training and workforce development; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2038668F134A4D56A0E56FF4F4FC9057"><enum>(xii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional actions determined to be eligible pursuant to subsection (d)(2)(B)(v).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2DB250BA5454190B3C9FA00B2CED91F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Protection against invasive plant species</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to carry out this section may not be used for a project or activity that proposes to use a plant that has an elevated risk of becoming invasive, as determined by the MRRRI Director through the use of a credible weed risk assessment tool.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1354340AFCFD44D0BFB85E73266A7C4B" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Monitoring plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal agency or non-Federal entity receiving funds to carry out a project or activity under this section shall develop a detailed plan for monitoring the implementation and ecological success of such project or activity, as applicable, that—</text><subparagraph id="H69DA334807054280AEC1420B83FEE7E0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes criteria for ecological success by which the project will be evaluated based on replacement of lost functions and values of the Mississippi River Corridor habitat, including hydrologic and vegetative characteristics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01DB5414E9824DA58685E92665546015" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies an entity responsible for such monitoring; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8049F6249B174C429FC5DB87A4162BAE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes continuation of such monitoring until the project is determined to be successful based on documented achievement of the ecological success criteria described under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H788D873D8D064308A4A1809A36A67384"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Actionable goals; action plans</header><paragraph id="HEC11F4A3B9014F73B9AED46FE07ACE9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actionable goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the MRRRI Director shall develop measurable goals for the MRRRI, including establishing criteria for measuring the success of the MRRRI in addressing the focus areas established in subsection (c)(2) and in restoring the overall ecological health and resilience of the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F14DE0EDE694C3886583A5BB47979F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action plan</header><subparagraph id="H5B6B54CFF4044AB7918DABD518598B23"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the MRRRI Director shall develop an action plan to make progress on the MRRRI through the implementation of MRRRI projects and activities under subsection (c). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H662D7B92D96248AA9F0E1C3E1FC202CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The MRRRI Director shall include in the action plan developed under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H559603897508451DA6F6805397BC725C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of existing Federal, State, Tribal, and regional plans, programs, and activities affecting the Mississippi River Corridor that may be used to advance the MRRRI;</text></clause><clause id="H1C508E9BD29742CCAF6AFC817D072F68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for a comprehensive approach to advancing systemic, large-scale restoration of the Mississippi River Corridor that, where appropriate, leverages existing Federal and State programs;</text></clause><clause id="H1A92233B80C749F2A1C58F9F899919AE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a multi-year plan that identifies objectives within each of the focus areas described in subsection (c)(2), with corresponding commitments for activities, research, and measures for progress;</text></clause><clause id="H3028D66EE1C6420790ED602113B4A426"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a plan to monitor the implementation of any recommendations developed under this subparagraph; and</text></clause><clause id="HB6269618FB8D4E7189E50BE87BE5CA4A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any additional actions the Director determines are eligible under this section. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6FC5224506E40E4BA2C06BEA60CB4E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Project recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The action plan described in subparagraph (A) may include recommendations for specific projects or activities that advance the objectives developed under subparagraph (B)(iii), including timelines, budgets, and the identification of entities responsible for the implementation of such projects. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED16AFD86E594DF0B811AC9EAFB032C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header><subparagraph id="H0A1B316C48FF4B8D8CD34967F0865A01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once every 5 years, the MRRRI Director shall review and update the actionable goals and action plan developed under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF637C97CCC9045A1B297D1374CA6CE9A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Integration with science plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In updating the action plan pursuant to this paragraph, the MRRRI Director shall incorporate any relevant information contained in the science plan developed pursuant to section 4(b) of the <short-title>MRRRI Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E40C2A3F733467DA50114757C58D4B5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination and consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and updating the actionable goals and action plan required under this subsection, the MRRRI Director shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF6ED26C1FAD7456297FC35D349CE4AED" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with Mississippi River States, Tribal governments within such States, the Secretary of the Interior, the Chief of Engineers, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Hypoxia Task Force; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD64584232A724A61B73F0FE4EC961163" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage with relevant Federal agencies, local governments, nongovernmental organizations, institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)), and members of the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFEC5871360B44DBAC394C07F7053DEE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit input from the entities described in subparagraph (B) through a formal public notice and comment period. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF32063F4E374E6BA5D7E674E7654E75"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H40EE0F12F000453EADCDF1A185BCB482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfer of funds to Federal entities</header><text>With funds made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year, the MRRRI Director may—</text><subparagraph id="H51152640EFF7456BB7EFA529FC00D07E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfer funds to the head of any relevant Federal agency, with the concurrence of the head of such agency, to carry out activities in accordance with this section; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C64F10A44634721B56349FFF0C60659"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer funds to other Federal programs to be used for achieving specifically targeted and measurable environmental outcomes that advance the actionable goals developed and updated under subsection (d); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE0A3118DCDD4C55BBABCE51CF4A06B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enter into an interagency agreement with the head of any relevant Federal agency to carry out activities in accordance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94EDFAFC94654FC786E8B82247BA88B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of funds to Bureau of Indian Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The MRRRI Director shall transfer not less than 5 percent of the funds made available to carry out this section to the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, with the concurrence of such Director, to make grants or otherwise enter into agreements with Tribal governments or Tribal organizations to carry out projects or activities under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5E4758D6CA40018CDECD2ECC0C8311" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of funds to implement projects prior to completion of the first action plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the date on which the first action plan is developed under subsection (d)(2), the MRRRI Director may transfer funds to another Federal entity, or award a grant or otherwise enter into an agreement with a non-Federal entity, to—</text><subparagraph id="HD84EB4005F40409E9759CA2E9A50F000" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out projects or activities that meet the requirements of subsection (c)(5); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD0FDA1732D4A5B858293B1390F4227" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish the research centers required under section 4(a) of the <short-title>MRRRI Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A3A889F656C4076B5B8357BECD66CA2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cost share</header><subparagraph id="H1703DC2F350A4C8EA945CFABB7831A18" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Federal share of the cost of a project or activity carried out by a non-Federal entity under this section shall not exceed 80 percent of the total cost of the project or activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4D01906171D4D48B390A46044019B4A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project or activity carried out by a Tribal government or Tribal organization under this section, and the Federal share of the cost of a project or activity described in subsection (c)(5)(B)(xi) carried by a non-Federal entity, shall be 100 percent of the total cost of the project or activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H042ECEB2904E4969B286CBC4DFCD3F13"><enum>(C)</enum><header>In-kind contribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal share of the cost of a project or activity carried out under this section may include the value of an in-kind contribution provided by a non-Federal entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CC03F317C8F40049C1DC118426FAB81"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds made available to carry out this section may be used for any water infrastructure activity for which financial assistance is received under—</text><subparagraph id="H6E12D21F992147B4B0FF5837135CA29A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State water pollution control revolving fund established under section 603;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5236EA672F643C8A377A85D8F5C6965"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State drinking water treatment revolving loan fund established under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8CEEBF12D42426AA6C30558A62A2E62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3901">33 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD1E264DFAB24AAFAA54451349F8A2C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Set aside for action plan</header><paragraph id="H10C8FB6BD2914B43AF7A2E05547C3061"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the total amount of funds made available to carry out the MRRRI under this section for each fiscal year beginning with the first fiscal year after which the action plan required under subsection (d)(2) is developed, not more than 5 percent may be used for projects and activities that are eligible under subsection (c)(5), but that do not address an objective identified in the action plan under subsection (d)(2)(B)(iii). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA60D2C7905B84741BF6B2E921CB0CD56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In using funds under subparagraph (A), the MRRRI Director shall prioritize projects that reduce the effects of natural disasters or respond to emerging threats from natural disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CF5DA220A074A27AA65A61AEDA26236"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Activities by Other Federal Agencies</header><paragraph id="HA80EDC660F6B4D1FA0487129782F187C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a relevant Federal agency that is engaged in, or has authority over, programs relating to research, monitoring, and planning to maintain, enhance, preserve, or rehabilitate the environmental quality and natural resources of the Mississippi River shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE6BE2E3F42D4423D9C45B2931EB6DC73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit an annual report to the Administrator describing the activities of the agency relating to the MRRRI;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B26EF8F436D4879975485089685E6AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strive to identify new projects and activities to support the goals of the MRRRI;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D743864A2E944FA8898A90CBE4CE9D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that any funding provided through the MRRRI supplements, and does not supplant, funding obtained through other agency budgets or other sources of funds for activities related to the Mississippi River; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F16411FF49B4E739C2351CF7DD8AA83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strive to maintain, and where possible increase, the base level of funding for activities of such agency related to the Mississippi River, without regard to funding under the MRRRI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA78BF3FE0BE844B493F6BDECF374E51E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Budget item</header><paragraph id="HEB52B07CFD074BEEBDEC5CC9118F91BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, in the Agency’s annual budget submission to Congress, include a funding request for the MRRRI as a separate budget line item. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E35D4F5253E420885FBD544C54E7EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The budget justification for the budget line item described in paragraph (1) shall include the amount to support the operation and activities of the Program Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE0C078379EC434F8761FAE73646C089" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H808DBB1470E849A6ADB70DB92E314545"><enum>(1)</enum><text>waive any requirement under any applicable Federal environmental law, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1C11E1AD7E134F67993C18F773A5E393"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44FE6A8346D8437FB8D3EC2166854503"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37CB1D6A77974C9F956936A587D8B625"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H865CE0C08DDE4913BCF384CE13766932"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/662">16 U.S.C. 662 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1A7275830B46F1A1942BB10409A9E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supplant the functions of the Hypoxia Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H880CC97FB0AF4E50B0C796D7AE6B95D0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mississippi River Corridor research centers and science plan</header><subsection id="H10AF1BD2A06E4466A6EBF8FD73CBBD75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mississippi River Corridor Research Centers</header><paragraph id="HAA7C28440D004C93BE5A5E2DBF60AB8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall coordinate with the MRRRI Director to establish a network of 3 Mississippi River Corridor Research Centers within the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78950DE81CCC4700B71A543F8322C095"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The network of research centers established under paragraph (1) shall consist of—</text><subparagraph id="H746231467E0F4C0384FE90F9B842CAAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a National Mississippi River Corridor Research Center located at an office of the United States Geological Survey; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF62A8D2A86F54F36871A4F8B031A0093"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 regional research centers, each of which shall be based out of a host university, as follows:</text><clause id="H1B3AF3E8D4934CB4B957EFDA351D1140"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Upper Mississippi River Research Center located in the region from the headwaters of the Mississippi River to the confluence of the Ohio River.</text></clause><clause id="H54243C3FAAB14CAD918BA13F0017D529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A Lower Mississippi River Research Center located in the region downriver from the confluence of the Ohio River to the Gulf of Mexico.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0455F487A244CA5BD9C2D8444E4F044"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the research centers established under this subsection shall be to—</text><subparagraph id="HEA555D2431C54CEBB746F623BA9EDC48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct scientific research on the MRRRI focus areas described in section 127(c)(2) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (as added by this Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A74E398C8AB43D188617EF06E7AAAA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with and advise relevant Federal agencies on—</text><clause id="HE65FD05A21704674A15B8AF8E1E6257F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the improvement of programs that monitor water quality in the Mississippi River Corridor and the health of the Mississippi River Corridor habitat or the establishment of such programs, where necessary;</text></clause><clause id="HCD135CF2CD7547D6B63221CBB87884FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of projects and activities carried out under the MRRRI; and </text></clause><clause id="H53696909CBD14C93863F97ADC918B4D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any additional goals, priorities, metrics, and research objectives proposed as part of the science plan described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D729B7BFD0349488C6241082C691D65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consult, and to the extent practicable, collaborate with relevant Federal agencies and non-Federal entities regarding research, monitoring, and other efforts to promote the restoration and resiliency of the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE35102B6A444F39BB3F2223226E8F3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Integration with other Federal activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that research and other activities carried out under this subsection are carried out in coordination with other Federal research and monitoring activities related to efforts to promote the restoration and resiliency of the Mississippi River Corridor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC23B415AA0A4DA6AC75EF3DB712C18E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Science plan</header><paragraph id="H4C8D1370274A47E89CBD4A15540BA1DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mississippi River science forum</header><subparagraph id="HD35A3763F6984A93834A6A72CE930D03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Geological Survey shall host a Mississippi River science forum with relevant Federal agencies, Mississippi River States, Tribal governments, Tribal organizations, academia, and other non-Federal entities to—</text><clause id="H5870CFD637DE4316804BA4850ED8B52E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>share current science and identify data gaps and areas of concern related to the ecological health of the Mississippi River Corridor; and </text></clause><clause id="H7530168D90C84B169DB3E3FFB5A3D596"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the resources that are necessary to—</text><subclause id="HAF70F7912A3849C794CB703CEE7E817D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>address any data gaps and areas of concern identified under clause (i); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA6BE87123C9246EFBD71A9B0371777E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>develop an integrated science plan under paragraph (2).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DE4141196A4D0CA43609D9274FC090"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the Director of the United States Geological Survey hosts the Mississippi River science forum under subparagraph (A), the Director shall submit a report on the findings from such forum to—</text><clause id="H73B90621B2224931811DC5796660480E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></clause><clause id="H4E0B6527044A4E72B06620990091FC9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the MRRRI Director;</text></clause><clause id="HFEF8A44F398C46CD8304A23EE6D4BB18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H5CCB3085EB634FAE8E0E093CBAAE7286"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF91674D976484591B393577A510A9C6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Science plan development</header><subparagraph id="H0540AD3C49BF47D9816FCCB891D81E85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the conclusion of the Mississippi River science forum required by paragraph (1), the Director of the United States Geological Survey shall develop a science plan that establishes priorities, metrics, and research proposals for the MRRRI.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F4346DBD6E4F728FE2F789A7B79C4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the science plan developed under this paragraph, the Director of the United States Geological Survey shall make such plan available on a public website and submit such plan to the MRRRI Director to inform the implementation of the actionable goals and action plans developed for the MRRRI under section 127(d) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (as added by this Act).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE867AB6F3E8D4D88840533890941F949"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once every 5 years, the Director of the United States Geological Survey shall coordinate with the MRRRI Director and the research centers established under subsection (a) to review and update the science plan developed under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE08BE17F7A48A0B6E1AB218A6016B0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and updating the science plan, the Director shall solicit input and comment from the public through a formal public notice and comment period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H19EDE2321D1144EC8E0CE90BA4FCB161"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the terms <quote>MRRRI</quote>, <quote>MRRRI Director</quote>, <quote>Mississippi River Corridor</quote>, <quote>Mississippi River State</quote>, <quote>relevant Federal agency</quote>, <quote>Tribal government</quote>, and <quote>Tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 127(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as added by this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

