<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25A95-S65-T0-0CW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2116 IS: To require the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to annually review, update, and report on the facilities and property of the United States Government determined to be national security sensitive for purposes of review of real estate transactions under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2116</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to annually review, update, and report on the facilities and property of the United States Government determined to be national security sensitive for purposes of review of real estate transactions under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id95faebc8dbc041dd942f21f0a15c3cff" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Review of and reporting on national security sensitive sites for purposes of reviews of real estate transactions by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bedac1e537d4a2c8f256e800bee3a9c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">List of national security sensitive sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 721(a)(4)(C) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)(4)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idB8AC28BE8EA34D4D908865CE34C365EE" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><clause id="idaed659b64ad74363ad116d1318831327"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>List of sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (B)(ii), the Committee may prescribe through regulations a list of facilities and property of the United States Government that are sensitive for reasons relating to national security. Such list may include certain facilities and property of the intelligence community and National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idd1fca314808c463496fd3e8875051e89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and reports</header><text>Section 721(m) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(m)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83b3d495705f48d8a19138f6c4bc1e04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A9207BB245944AE9520A96DEBD0BB90"><subparagraph id="id5c880ffb0cd94b4b9adf2dfe3919876b"><enum>(L)</enum><text>A list of all notices and declarations filed and all reviews or investigations of covered transactions completed during the period relating to facilities and property of the United States Government determined to be sensitive for reasons relating to national security for purposes of subsection (a)(4)(B)(ii).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f548f1e9ea54b8ea4eaddf1c266ed8c"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification that the list of sites identified under subsection (a)(4)(C)(iii) reflects consideration of the recommended updates and revisions submitted under paragraph (4)(B). Upon request from any Member of Congress specified in subsection (b)(3)(C)(iii), the chairperson shall provide a classified briefing to that Member, and staff of the member with appropriate security clearances, regarding the list of sites identified under subsection (a)(4)(C)(iii).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0763925397ba4ff6b3d62a727b3d17dc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff2403070e03423c9a06f587ea292e71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA65AEA865DF741A09AD3F968530A9988"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8dff2ee84514d278f619735ffe1268f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual review of list of facilities and property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each year, each member of the Committee shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0c30a77bc604fd5af8c4c75d043ffaf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the facilities and property of the agency represented by that member that are on the list prescribed under subparagraph (C)(iii) of subsection (a)(4) of facilities and property that are sensitive for reasons relating to national security for purposes of subparagraph (B)(ii) of that subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0341f0cca64946dc8ff58b6e1fb3b18f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the chairperson a report on that review, after approval of the report by an Assistant Secretary or equivalent official of the agency, which shall include any recommended updates or revisions to the list regarding facilities and property administered by the member of the Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

