<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC905FE905F1D4706AA67ACC0D6A2C349" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4489 IH: Sunshine on Solar Lending Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4489</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to require certain creditors to disclose dealer fees in solar financing transactions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H388AA09CCE234F8192BA1E23BE90A382" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2276BC46ABFB47A6B21373186BBEBF6D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sunshine on Solar Lending Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD91BEC5C67E44F05A5DDA254113812E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H56265D4AA4344611B2955606DBA5611D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Homeowners are increasingly installing solar energy systems, including battery storage systems and other related systems, to reduce electricity costs and maintain power during grid outages.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2D0B20EC0C34383A74FBA7C39334A2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The high upfront cost of purchasing and installing solar energy systems often requires consumers to obtain financing, typically through loans or leases facilitated by solar installers and originated by third-party creditors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03689C8510134C08BB4EC3939726AFA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Solar financing arrangements are frequently marketed by third-party sales representatives or installers who partner with creditors to offer loans at the point of sale. In some cases, these arrangements include dealer fees that are not clearly disclosed to consumers, leading to inflated financing costs and a lack of transparency regarding the true cost of credit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA38CF2AF725E4841BF8DC0C8B24156E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The <quote>Seller’s Point</quote> exemption under Regulation Z is sometimes improperly used to exclude dealer fees from the calculation of the finance charge in solar financing transactions. The use of this exemption has led to confusion and inconsistent treatment of such fees, particularly in transactions involving third-party financing and indirect compensation structures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C7476A40BB543A68F34F2935C2E436C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Truth in Lending Act applies to creditors, as defined in the Act, that offer or extend credit for solar energy systems. All such creditors are required to comply with the disclosure and consumer protection provisions of the Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2464988D47B4996BFACFA56F3599656"><enum>(6)</enum><text>This Act is necessary to clarify and reinforce the application of the Truth in Lending Act to solar financing transactions, ensure consistent treatment of dealer fees as finance charges where applicable, and promote transparency and accountability in credit transactions related to solar energy systems.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB20564DADC1147DF9F47226C032D4AA7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosure of dealer fees in solar financing transactions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1605">15 U.S.C. 1605</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB0FD6D4A4B6D4191A3B4D476EED06D9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H14D4DC2D6CD24D57BCFE165798C0F824" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H6AFF08C253434D329D50F146D28128AC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in any consumer credit transaction for solar financing, as defined in subsection (h), any seller’s points or other charges imposed by the creditor upon a noncreditor seller for providing credit to the consumer or for providing credit on certain terms.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD27426885A9446EC87EDC0EEB00EE335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1470D87A53B649869683D10919E00D27" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HBBC299947A99480BAC7272A1668F0DCD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Disclosure of dealer fees for solar financing transactions</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC13DB0381544657B96A66FD75369A19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A creditor for a solar financing transaction shall clearly and conspicuously disclose in writing to the consumer—</text> <subparagraph id="H16833BBD378A4EB59F565AF6ED854287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any fee charged to a third party by the creditor relating to the solar financing transaction;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H111239F7A8444DBEBEEDCFD1F51BDAFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any fee imposed directly or indirectly by the creditor or a third party, that is payable directly or indirectly by the consumer, relating to the solar financing transaction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14DFD0DA7C114384BB59BCE0F81E8ED4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the identification of any third party that is a party to the solar financing transaction; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4104A894C13E4128B27A3BF13A57D3B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a comparison of the amount financed by the solar financing transaction, including the amount of any finance charges with—</text> <clause id="H42D4FA0A4E1F4258B69D82DCEAF891B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total cash price for each product obtained by the consumer through the solar financing transaction, including infrastructure and labor costs; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCB91B8B176A140CC94A3600162AB1B4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total cash price for each service obtained by the consumer through the solar financing transaction, including maintenance and repair costs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EEC0F5E32B24C79B98115B88A54041E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In-person transactions</header><text>With respect to a solar financing transaction negotiated (in part or in whole) with the consumer in person, a creditor or third party (as applicable) shall provide the consumer with a paper copy of the disclosures described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90C3EF37A98042F4A02991F76A363D4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Arbitration</header><text>A solar financing transaction may not include terms which require arbitration or any other nonjudicial procedure as the method for resolving any controversy or settling any claims arising out of the transaction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4C9B1EBD7ED642CB9C37E300C4BEADE8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Solar financing transaction defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>solar financing transaction</quote> means a consumer credit transaction to finance the purchase, installation, or associated costs of a solar energy system, including solar panels, inverters, battery storage systems, electric vehicle charging stations, and any related infrastructure required for the operation of such solar energy system.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4EA7246DFBE24E3A945BFEF69461B3C6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to a solar financing transaction (as defined in subsection (h) of section 106 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1605">15 U.S.C. 1605</external-xref>), as added by this Act) entered into on or after such effective date.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

