<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25704-86D-MD-2N3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2186 IS: Preventing Pretrial Gun Purchases Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2186</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure that the background check system used for firearms purchases denies a firearm to a person prohibited from possessing a firearm by a lawful court order governing the pretrial release of the person.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC690E4DAC10F4064B142532F62C6227D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEB973D2809BB4261AAF25F917C36E5B3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Pretrial Gun Purchases Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8ECFACC3A6D14FEC879F956F20FB306B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Gun Control Act of 1968</header><subsection id="H306807FC9BC24C51B00661C0BA3B3181"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 921</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC1425CDDFF7445C99BADF843DB9F6433"><paragraph id="HC1FDFD784FAF4F6C814109A456ED9B83" indent="up1"><enum>(39)</enum><text>The term <term>pretrial release order</term> means an order of a Federal, State, Tribal, or local court that governs the release of an arrested person pending the trial of the person for a crime.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1C087D82F0AD4158A76894617375543C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Section 922</header><text>Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H80F049D7DC3A4C48A54E4CE327713C44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="H3C435524F08746C6AC5E5ADFD6077F45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAAE56C304324B258BCE6744D3254E4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6714AC4C092947A298483827D3025F7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (11) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF339BD4F341D4563948065349DD6DCB3"><paragraph id="H39CF30EDC99642B1B8DA64780410A569"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to a pretrial release order that prohibits the person from purchasing, possessing, or receiving firearms.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6809C4EFD3504A54BC62072CB68823F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (t)—</text><subparagraph id="H762C6A3338BB4C1A9EDCFB82CAC45FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>receipt of a firearm</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section</quote> and inserting <quote>knowing sale or disposition of a firearm by the licensee to such other person or the receipt of a firearm by such other person would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n) of this section</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B42F7D5346F4893BB8C1716C39FE358"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>receipt</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(n)</quote> and inserting <quote>the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm to the person or the receipt of a firearm by the person would not violate subsection (d), (g), or (n)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8F2D5A723D147838C141924A368875D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)(A)(ii), by striking <quote>that possession</quote> and inserting <quote>that knowing sale or disposition of a firearm by a licensee to such other person or possession</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6931A93EB4C4369847EB76B90358284"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0DB77FD269E417BAE5688CFC2122EC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>receipt</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(n)</quote> and inserting <quote>knowing sale or disposition of a firearm by a licensee to such other person or the receipt of a firearm by such other person would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6A128619625470BB6638CD85EB34A70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting a comma after <quote>State</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC62B417BD08F4A318AF0711DF49FF80D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4F1984A635543E49E932FBEEEF8C7F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>receipt</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(n)</quote> and inserting <quote>knowing sale or disposition of a firearm by a licensee to such other person or receipt of a firearm by such other person would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2219C03D0AA04D69BAF687FED67015DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting a comma after <quote>State</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2100B68BA4AC48F59369E4DABED9B58A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subsection id="HDEB0703DF7C24B4CBFCEC6912B338218"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 923</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923(d)(1)(B) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>under section 922(g) and (n) of this chapter</quote> and inserting <quote>by subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 and is not a person to whom the knowing sale or disposition of any firearm or ammunition is prohibited by section 922(d)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H23E7D179575E4DFCAF61713F127A97A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Section 925A</header><text>Section 925A(2) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>and to whom the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm was not prohibited by subsection (d) of that section or State law</quote> before the comma.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC889565A49224098AFCAE8A9EB7D9AD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6B550BE19F4D483EB0B7BBE6F878A2B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HBD52452BC30C41A3907EB2E4BD295111"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>for whom receipt</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(g)</quote> and inserting <quote>to whom the knowing sale or disposition of or for whom receipt of a firearm would violate subsection (d), (g),</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H453F0CB6FC894FC99D9A1D03ADFD25C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>(g)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d), (g),</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3373F0046ED4FEB80A1A9ADF3C756CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)(iii)(I), by striking <quote>(g) or (n)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d), (g), or (n)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA1C493B45454111B6A31E6772222FCB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G)(i), by striking <quote>(g) or (n)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d), (g), or (n)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7428FA1DC04AEC88E19D75D81309E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate subsection (g) or (n)</quote> and inserting <quote>the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm to or receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H614EA01D8EE7463B91020B1CB97FF74A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(2), by striking all that follows after <quote>respect to persons</quote> and inserting <quote>to whom the knowing sale or disposition of, or for whom receipt of, a firearm is prohibited by subsection (d), (g), or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or State law.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDE58EE1D8BA45A891E5FC9CA0671E81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007</header><text>Title I of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40911">34 U.S.C. 40911 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAE509B8042374AC58C1CA692C96B7636"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40911">34 U.S.C. 40911(b)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H1DFF1E9CE0334E0083C9814AD5FFC2CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>a person is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g)</quote> and inserting <quote>the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm to a person or receipt of a firearm by a person is prohibited by subsection (d), (g),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0249006E1F64DE5A9B575A13A218BAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text><clause id="H2E0B0EB2D4E94CBBAB8F3CF8A164A699"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>after the</quote> and inserting <quote>after a court martial imposes a pretrial release order or the</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H187B576F0F484FD7ABFBDF02A1DDA919"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a member of the Armed Forces involved in such proceeding is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n)</quote> and inserting <quote>the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm to or receipt of a firearm by a member of the Armed Forces is prohibited by subsection (d), (g), or (n)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E7188E8ADA42B58C812D031DE14D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 102 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40912">34 U.S.C. 40912</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HE06D64B1ACB04CE49E9368D35119B0D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g)</quote> and inserting <quote>are described in one of the categories under subsection (d), (g),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E19DFA111AC4F6F958E872A2C64D510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(A), by inserting <quote>the knowing sale or disposition of a firearm to a person would be prohibited under subsection (d) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or applicable State law or whether</quote> after <quote>determination of whether</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7D15F87C555E490486564A787D21EBA1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Funds for States that report pretrial orders restricting firearm possession to NICS</header><subsection id="H82424CD82AB64DE99CE39CBF60C385A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered pretrial release order</term> means an order of a State, Tribal, or local court that governs the release of an arrested individual pending the trial of the individual for a crime, and which prohibits the individual from possessing a firearm or ammunition (as such terms are defined in section 921 of title 18, United States Code). </text></subsection><subsection id="H535D1B8AF5E44AC882831C5C24366CA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make grants to States and Indian Tribes for the purpose of reporting information about covered pretrial release orders to the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>). </text></subsection><subsection id="H9423859A795B49278B6230EC2D020088"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The chief executive of a State or Indian Tribe seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEFB9829BB2BE45C68B59467BC49E621A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants made under this section shall be in addition to any amount that a State or Indian Tribe receives under section 302(c)(19) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10132">34 U.S.C. 10132(c)(19)</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Criminal History Improvement Program</quote>) or section 103 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40913">34 U.S.C. 40913</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>NICS Act Record Improvement Program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H721584799B214C8EB29027F8EDC14A41"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

