<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25009-XH6-5J-H4V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S233 IS: Restoring Confidence in the World Anti-Doping Agency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2006 to modify the authority of the Office of National Drug Control Policy with respect to the World Anti-Doping Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Confidence in the World Anti-Doping Agency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idEA5683D6B7E745128B75A20D855174AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority of National Drug Control Policy with respect to the World Anti-Doping Agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 701 of the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/2001">21 U.S.C. 2001</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id5b6fa180b6574cfea329f7371c1f661e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id34831961b3024a509da377f3d7d654ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae7903956c234870903a12aa4adcfe6c"><paragraph id="id1998f4ca411a4137ac99f5b9690c02e9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee</header><text>The term <term>United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee</term> means the organization established by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/2205">chapter 2205</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id195f0086468f48238d12cb9f70bebf4b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/22501">36 U.S.C. 22501(b)(1)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/220501">36 U.S.C. 220501(b)(1)</external-xref>)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe3acd7a75ba48a8a1d26b994f127e6f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (3) as paragraphs (4) and (1), respectively, and moving the paragraphs so as to appear in numeric order; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a13ce7e5a00492facd7762de10e601e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3ecc0012af74cdb87522b1010157ee9"><paragraph id="idf9083e4e4b0746c782da8908497872ce"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent athlete</header><text>The term <term>independent athlete</term> means an Olympic or Paralympic athlete who does not serve, in any capacity—</text><subparagraph id="id7ea679f05ee44e8c9a411c61c0871d40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the International Olympic Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a35fe4349f54239aef630c916cd6d31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the International Paralympic Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaa175552aca4930b13a2f6a85390a32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at an international sports federation recognized by the International Olympic Committee or the International Paralympic Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77a35387ccf14d9696df5cbed1822bc2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>on the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2b2b66034ac423d9eb0912395bf96b7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>at the World Anti-Doping Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide025bdf289c9407f98edd7d8d80127f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="idcd9c40b7a8eb4840954c3b849ed7ae23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>United States Olympic Committee</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf522be075568430d80e3aa34dcd7ab11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id786f9bd27dcd4441b8caea577f38b7a2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab22baaefcbf453c814b2a3752c1c0ff"><paragraph id="id19c4b9ff3c7b4fd9a2493124d1dc0475"><enum>(6)</enum><text>carry out responsibilities with respect to the World Anti-Doping Agency, as described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89ad43a05a0c4f2aa2e0874a5ae2b1cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7812478252c4e19b57216a283d8cc8d"><subsection id="idbec57c2e6b4a496a863b07009eec16e8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority with respect to the World Anti-Doping Agency</header><paragraph id="idba098dcbffdd4d8e8daa0b39ce200465"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office of National Drug Control Policy, in consultation with the United States Anti-Doping Agency, the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee, and the Team USA Athletes’ Commission, shall—</text><subparagraph id="id2785e589f60549fcbc2f714af9c95cf3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use all available tools to ensure that—</text><clause id="id6f971cc4ceba4abb9fa23bc84f6fbb4f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the World Anti-Doping Agency has a credible and independent governance model that provides for fair representation of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id804216caa17e429aa9945f1969c91177"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the World Anti-Doping Agency fully implements all governance reforms, including a proper conflict-of-interest policy for all members of the Executive Committee, the Foundation Board, and all relevant expert advisory groups, standing committees, permanent special committees, and working groups of the World Anti-Doping Agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id8a2d6349bbaa4b9ba937d2e201858cea"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>independent athletes from the United States and other democratic countries, or representatives of such athletes, have decision-making roles on the Executive Committee and the Foundation Board, and in all relevant expert advisory groups, standing committees, permanent special committees, and working groups, of the World Anti-Doping Agency;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc56917a2a4834f898a2cb34e24c6f18b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate leadership within the global community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9749e47dcb9045f5b2286d807b95e920"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have strict standards that work toward countering doping in every form, including by countering systemic fraud through doping involving—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6d4aacd3657418396ba3e3d2dbf05b8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">governmental law enforcement, intelligence, or anti-doping institutions; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6cf0b463faa455084e59fa2d69443aa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sporting organizations; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d651e7cad254d1eb16a6dabc377674e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">athlete support personnel; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb53d408f3e584d5290534283f0675118"><enum>(D)</enum><text>work collaboratively with democratic countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3637c087884f4291a2f0f108b26f0bcd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><subparagraph id="id41fddf6885da4409a96e7c74e32c63bd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, in consultation with the United States Anti-Doping Agency, the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee, and the Team USA Athletes’ Commission, shall make a determination as to whether the World Anti-Doping Agency—</text><clause id="idb2727b7ea32043ba977da3541a83ba88"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a credible and independent governance model that provides for fair representation of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id00ad81c1ae564f6bae64ad8e4fc7ea0a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fully implements all governance reforms, including a proper conflict-of-interest policy described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii); and</text></clause><clause id="idc85bfd81d58c40c7a1d5291adc57dd00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allows independent athletes from the United States and other democratic countries, or representatives of such athletes, to have decision-making roles on the Executive Committee and the Foundation Board, and in all relevant expert advisory groups, standing committees, permanent special committees, and working groups, of the World Anti-Doping Agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc599eaafab7541e1b79f230dfe0fed86"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accountability</header><text>In the case of a determination under subparagraph (A) that the World Anti-Doping Agency does not have such a governance model, has not fully implemented such governance reforms, or has not allowed decision-making roles described in clause (iii) of that subparagraph, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, in consultation with the United States Anti-Doping Agency, the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee, and the Team USA Athletes’ Commission, shall—</text><clause id="id1579063d8b4d464ca1ed46926642f9eb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use all available tools to ensure that the United States has fair representation in the World Anti-Doping Agency, including—</text><subclause id="id1eddd011552b4c8896d718e914bb2b89"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on the Executive Committee;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd74ad2a6258d4da9a92a86ca13e6efa1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on the Foundation Board; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idee8093a166114c23b66267bdfdc475e2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in all relevant expert advisory groups, standing committees, permanent special committees, and working groups of the World Anti-Doping Agency; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="iddca246437bf14f0b801ac37c9ff818b1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date on which the determination under subparagraph (A) is made, issue a report that describes the barriers to participation and fair representation of the United States on the Executive Committee, the Foundation Board, and all relevant expert advisory groups, standing committees, permanent special committees, and working groups of the World Anti-Doping Agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f1c564334054ffa9acc405d400c7e89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Voluntary nonpayment of dues</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided1285eeab3c415ebc3e507bde3cf62a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a determination under paragraph (2)(A) that the World Anti-Doping Agency does not have a governance model that provides for fair representation of the United States, has not fully implemented governance reforms, or has not allowed decision-making roles described in clause (iii) of that subparagraph, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, in consultation with the appropriate committees of Congress, may voluntarily withhold up to the full amount of membership dues to the World Anti-Doping Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf34bb8b00c324400ba76e024d6fb0f10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ae9e499af3049b78517b499347ca8c1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection, Product Safety, and Data Security of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate (or a successor subcommittee); </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a7d6c2253af4a5cab4f4863beae3331"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate (or a successor subcommittee); </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dd988eb05134c8bbcda594743571416"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives (or a successor subcommittee); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f708aaf2ae6475fb024f09851a8b5ed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives (or a successor subcommittee).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3618b3a178f48b582540c551594f11c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Spending plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days before the Office of National Drug Control Policy obligates funds to the World Anti-Doping Agency, the Office of National Drug Control Policy shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a spending plan and explanation of proposed uses of such funds.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

