<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4383F941579447ECBEE12FE11B43233F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1417 IH: Rural Health Care Facility Technical Assistance Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1417</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand and codify the Rural Hospital Technical Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture and rename it as the Rural Health Care Facility Technical Assistance Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA7B3C851412C45E7A18A88B6C59C1C28" style="OLC"><section id="HA6AAB2A4B230400BBDA3659ACC5BD51B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Health Care Facility Technical Assistance Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEE09B6A2D1464CBB92D0A4651E710BE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion and codification of the rural health care facility technical assistance program of the Department of Agriculture</header><subsection id="H29FDEC39455C46FD9419F544FC0C9B19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In lieu of any other authority under which the Secretary of Agriculture (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may provide technical assistance to any eligible health care facility, the Secretary shall establish, and maintain, directly or by grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, a Rural Health Care Facility Technical Assistance Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to provide technical assistance and training, tailored to the capacity and needs of each eligible health care facility, to help eligible health care facilities in rural areas—</text><paragraph id="H3B835A005B5742AA989662577785944C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify development needs for maintaining essential health care services, and support action plans for operational and quality improvement projects to meet the development needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9ED799C25D47A283793DD023B8E725"><enum>(2)</enum><text>better manage their financial and business strategies, including providing financial planning assistance and preparing long-term financial plans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H425377B9E49E4E85A8EA4DEDBCD3C79B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify, and apply for assistance from, loan and grant programs of the Department of Agriculture for which the facilities are eligible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F86C6AD949D44269AC91E6B073217D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the Program shall be to—</text><paragraph id="HCBA10C00AB504D4C828EEC2253E202EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the long-term financial position and operational efficiency of the eligible health care facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25217512DFC24DB3AE2A5531D04B5D06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the closure of eligible health care facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7664D6F20D466F8DEE20D82F67AE73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthen the delivery of health care in rural areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H167001B4164A4BC69D3AD0386F843B91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>help eligible rural health care facilities better access and compete for loans and grants from programs administered by the Department of Agriculture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50002A4497964E26B17D8F58C6315477"><enum>(5)</enum><text>continue the activities of the Rural Hospital Technical Assistance Program in effect as of the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB2ADEC5B93F4FDF9554576CEA6E8244"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program participation</header><paragraph id="H999406D0ACA74E1A8140574532A899F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall engage in outreach and engagement strategies to encourage eligible health care facilities to participate in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90595D17B3D842EFB5768E72B2CD56BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible health care facility selection</header><text>In selecting eligible health care facilities to participate in the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to borrowers and grantees of the Rural Housing Service, Rural Business-Cooperative Service, and Rural Utilities Service. The Secretary may also consider—</text><subparagraph id="HEAAE871F4C2A459CAEE3B383C91BCE70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the age and physical state of the health care facility involved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8565CAD52B34B619C3A736A7D4C7251"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the financial vulnerability of the eligible health care facility, and the ability of the eligible health care facility to meet debt obligations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB8BEB356C2B45E3B7129B9922F5CABB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the electronic health record implementation needs of the health care facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BA74D8239CB4AA79B84702936F6E5BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the eligible health care facility is located in a health professional shortage area or a medically underserved area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63DB17A5CC824F0194A49C2FFFCDE80A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the eligible health care facility serves a medically underserved population; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E14294392544269A9E270DBF28E0231"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other criteria and priorities as are determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65C47C2A7DA34EB9945039687361C76D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a written report describing the progress and results of the program conducted under this section, which should include—</text><paragraph id="H213F382AD73142FB955BC79DFF1C49AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a brief description of each project to provide technical assistance to an eligible health care facility under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="HD96B1027CF304792BBCA0FB2C4E8B7D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and location of the facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1366CB99802441A6BA765D5208122024"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the assistance provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10B84FD049134C8DA36CC2E8BD4EB9C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the outcomes for completed projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE5E7CFDB6149DEA01348E905DD42E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the cost of the technical assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AD1AE3E57C3406D940A2C942EC8A704"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary deems appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0515C3CB63374831A794B26B62782CF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the technical assistance projects completed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0497C88BE05641CD97501A0C8FD49B4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of the outcomes of the technical assistance projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H408ECDCFA3F04A8EBB9FE8A8962A9CD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6339A8EC78448EAB094F7E13851DC52"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H640CF30825244B5EA3E04CF3BE7C9C91"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary not more than $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB96FE26837CD43EEA3C2DD69893EAFA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0D86358824DB4C9DB466FCCB59516D2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 343(a)(13)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1991">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)(13)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F2E9941D9F417DA3F1573C1C5897C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development needs</header><text>The term <term>development needs</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HB50A987F25EB4B22B239896FD979C654"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constructing, expanding, renovating, or otherwise modernizing health care facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF7B86B27F042A49E50428C0A9BEB86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing telehealth capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EB6920B964452B94B74359A5327159"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acquiring or upgrading health care information systems such as electronic health records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4259815431546BC9C049254BA1003D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing financial planning assistance and preparing long-term financial plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51637AB083E6449F93E0C215904FCA52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other needs as the Secretary deems critical to maintaining health care services in the community in which an eligible health care facility is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE37796637EAD4019A4C24195F31E1624"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible health care facility</header><text>The term <term>eligible health care facility</term> means a facility that is located in a rural area and is—</text><subparagraph id="HF0A0C79F81A94E62BA46D06777A973E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a hospital (as defined in section 1861(e) of the Social Security Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A142D65F0B340C698159390CE2463A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a psychiatric hospital (as defined in section 1861(f) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB45C84DD70F34B29A564E54C56D68448"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a long-term care hospital (as defined in section 1861(ccc) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C3F61988A7D405EB984568B29606C3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACD16AB0A59748FAABE8349FADDEA21D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a rural health clinic (as defined in section 1861(aa)(2) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45F50A325CE3453A8092FD82AECEA6CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a religious nonmedical health care institution (as defined in section 1861(ss)(1) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4599D33AC559481EB91052C7A754A469"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a sole community hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(C)(iii) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H868424C50329436FBDE692967F335498"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2) of such Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10EC4DAA6599423087C008602B84DFC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a home health agency (as defined in section 1861(o) of such Act); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BA542DF10EC4F848778D30FA86EFCE8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a community health center (as defined in section 330 of the Public Health Service Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF0F1B6CF94401F98D19A288207BCE9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Health professional shortage area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health professional shortage area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 332(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CF30CEE02246759B03B426D5C5C871"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Medically underserved area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medically underserved area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 330I(a)(5) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD9A2A6D37F3488F9EAE128C69903FEF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medically underserved population</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medically underserved population</term> has the meaning given the term in section 330(b)(3) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

