<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB49E4157BBE448C4965DFD4BF39BE0E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5657 IH: Fair Pay for Federal Contractors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5657</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide back pay to Federal contractors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD94178291D9444E1909BB67E21175B95" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE0F15CD357344929BC4BC60B219B19E7" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Pay for Federal Contractors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H995795A3557F4574B19049E3141B8848"><enum>2.</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, such sums as may be necessary for each Federal agency subject to the lapse in appropriations that began on or about October 1, 2025, and any subsequent lapse in appropriations occurring during fiscal year 2026 for adjustments in the price of contracts of such agency under section 3: <italic>Provided that,</italic> such sums shall be available for such purposes until December 31, 2026.</text></section><section id="HACC05E50AD3842698E033B8B01FB9410"><enum>3.</enum><header>Back compensation for employees of Government contractors in connection with the lapse in appropriations</header><subsection id="H29BDDCF510C543118A9B28B98DE621C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Back compensation</header><paragraph id="HA3AB9808DCE643109A9D312C4C22A854"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency subject to the lapse in appropriations shall adjust the price of any contract of such agency for which the contractor suspended, delayed, or interrupted all or part of the work of such contract, or stopped all or any part of the work called for in such contract, as a result of the lapse in appropriations to compensate the contractor for reasonable costs incurred—</text><subparagraph id="HD347CCFCF1014997B32430FFBBF20020"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide compensation, at an employee’s standard rate of compensation, to any employee who was furloughed or laid off, or who was not working, who experienced a reduction of hours, or who experienced a reduction in compensation, as a result of the lapse in appropriations (for the period of the lapse); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CDBD7DEB972496095F13FC076EA79A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to restore paid leave taken by any employee during the lapse in appropriations, if the contractor required or permitted employees to use paid leave as a result of the lapse in appropriations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B6F31963E794335B34913FA24EFD388"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment notwithstanding contract terms</header><text>An adjustment may be made under this subsection for costs incurred as described in paragraph (1) regardless of whether the contract concerned provides for, or otherwise prohibits, the contractor to incur such costs or receive such an adjustment for incurring such costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51BCCAFF1DAE4BC893F005130E84BDD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on amount of weekly compensation covered by adjustment</header><text>The maximum amount of weekly compensation of an employee for which an adjustment may be made under subsection (a) may not exceed the lesser of—</text><paragraph id="H13AD83742223498FACCE29331FD80978"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the employee's actual weekly compensation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BD9421BEA9C468999D5F9738A14273E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,442 (or an appropriate lesser amount pro-rated for an employee who works less than 40 hours per week).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C36CAF8CA5D4D86A0B05A2B372CD1BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of adjustment authority</header><paragraph id="H12DB92985ACD462190AA6B1ED2F4FA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adjustment only for costs actually incurred</header><text>An adjustment may be made under subsection (a) only for costs actually incurred by a contractor as described in paragraph (1) of that subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H527671D9F32E4FF99609C706C08409CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proof of provision of compensation</header><text>A contractor seeking an adjustment under subsection (a) shall provide the head of the Federal agency concerned such evidence of the costs incurred by the contractor as described in paragraph (1) of that subsection as the head of the agency, in consultation with the Administrator of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFD13B21035246B08221D1610533ED1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timing of adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The adjustments required by subsection (a) shall be made as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2068E5F5D2D945D4813EC1CE1A3A7D58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AD3B0B8081A4BB0BAF9CCC3D3E49F14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and make publicly available a report on the adjustments made under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31403A79DE984C57BB0255054ED2CF31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall set forth the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D59EA667D78479BB04A003F76785C0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each Federal agency described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) that made adjustments required by that subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6083E86FB57E43879AD278881EA83A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For each agency, the following:</text><clause id="HD5A160877E96490C85D3A73118DC01B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of contractor and subcontractor employees working for such agency as of the commencement of the lapse in appropriations described in subsection (a)(1).</text></clause><clause id="HC358C044139F47C0B1E544472B5586C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total number of contractor employees covered by clause (i) who were furloughed, laid off, or did not work as a result of the lapse in appropriations.</text></clause><clause id="HC6C2156EF4A043EC8F9FDAB046CC0026"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The total number, if any, of employees covered by clause (ii) who received back compensation in connection with the furlough, lay off, or cessation of work.</text></clause><clause id="HA67877D51C1A475582A24B9BC0FBE156"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The total number, if any, of employees covered by clause (ii) who were required or permitted to use paid leave in place of the furlough, lay off, or cessation of work.</text></clause><clause id="H44EF723116AB42D5A022BAE3E98DF16F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The total number, if any, of employees covered by clause (ii) who received back compensation equal to such employees' actual weekly compensation in connection with the furlough, lay off, or cessation of work.</text></clause><clause id="HE57B02B86E8640D3A12ACF248A845D7A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The total number, if any, of employees covered by clause (ii) who received back compensation that was subject to the limitation in subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H920A1C8CEA0C47E681D2D8D331DE0BDC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2AE5062272344276B711590C9957A5D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H7DA56AD299F54ABC9892FBE6F72EB77C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43DD2389C8A6483A843F11C9B5D37A90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45D096C209C4414D872E840235692AAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term> has the meaning given that term in section 6701(1) of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E01AFD1D2ED438C83F73FFC592E29CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employee</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H09CDEEA05B2642F3AA02FE087DDB9FE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A <quote>service employee</quote> as that term is defined in section 6701(3) of title 41, United States Code, except that the term also includes service employees described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of that section notwithstanding such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H766AA91D33A94E81B8AA56ADD4CB8F3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A <quote>laborer or mechanic</quote> covered by section 3142 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H75EE3740F4E14A2C81A4C2EC5532D60D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each Federal agency subject to a lapse in appropriations for adjustments in the price of contracts of such agency under section 3.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

