<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF7AB54F89E9F454DBF113ADBA6697868" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3561 IH: Federal Overhaul of Reserve Command Executive Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3561</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a National Defense Executive Reserve, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B2D30D3C33A4B84B34FDCE95C5DCAC8" style="OLC"><section id="H3E53C93704524902B8EFA7ECB3082C75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Overhaul of Reserve Command Executive Modernization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FORCE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H18B2193FD3704CA0B0CCB156E847C71A"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Defense Executive Reserve</header><subsection id="HDEBF40E0A05F469A9F380ADA80D43F17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4551">50 U.S.C. 4551 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 711 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC4AFB34F77AD4B60AB8CBADAAC4ED5FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HD2BA131547214A31AA15945B01842857"><enum>712.</enum><header>National Defense Executive Reserve</header><subsection id="H1BB60C1AC5DA4D8787223AC5076D7E00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish a National Defense Executive Reserve (in this section referred to as the <quote>Reserve</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0203154FFC24032ABAF55DECBB232DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Reserve shall be to—</text><paragraph id="HA5BD0A95462B427A8F2B4927213EF5B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the preparedness of the Federal Government for national defense emergencies by allowing private persons with unique expertise to volunteer, be trained for and temporarily employed in Federal positions within any of the Federal agencies that has established a Reserve unit under subsection (c) that may be necessary during an national defense emergency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7B38733A77D4BABA0FAC86EE424DF6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efficiently augment the capabilities of the Federal Government with these private persons as required during periods of national defense emergency when activated by the President;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DD33EB02919471790D2C5E720F5FA5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide a cost-efficient way of expanding Federal Government capacity for the management of future national defense emergencies without needing to dramatically expand the number of full-time Federal employees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65B53522239C410CB65643A481B48C35"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enable the appropriate controls and oversight to be established by the Federal Government in advance of the activation of the Reserve to avoid real or perceived conflicts of interest or other harms created by the temporary employment of private persons who volunteer to be temporarily employed by the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BB6102E93824D02949E142A0842FFB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reserve units</header><paragraph id="HE9D179613A4F411CAFE25CF09BF97FFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall require the heads of each of the following agencies to establish a unit of the Reserve within the applicable agency:</text><subparagraph id="H8EF403CD6D89419587D1A495D7DDCB1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5FD36C0D133422EAEBFDB5C6B767146"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6619931D7E543D29CECA5394E475CC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2640BA9DFEA1432298EF0638C18A4E48"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other agencies as the President determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A3EDCAE49664D5CB27BA66044EE7B45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The units of the Reserve within the agencies described under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) shall be established not later than 180 days after the issuance of the final rules required under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3271DC2E0554D8B8934ACF0F94E357A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may only activate a unit of the Reserve—</text><paragraph id="H3A36D208E2B445678EB425745C0601FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on non-delegable basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8A68DD3D9314961ABE6842480271ED5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during a national emergency declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1601">50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to which the President has specified, as described under section 301 of such Act, that the President may activate the Reserve pursuant to the authorities under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F8A9DCEABED468FA4F4290F04573304"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon a public determination by the President that the activation is necessary to support the national defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DB5F089BED64EC6A803C498059E2D70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The President may, without activating the Reserve, allow for periodic training and exercises to prepare the Reserve for duty during an activation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB18FF5996C19430F86EC59CCFAB32651"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall issue rules, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to provide—</text><paragraph id="H1A4DAEDB67174A47A88B4B5FA4A5DF76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>instruction on—</text><subparagraph id="H77D642356DF249A1979363FE07BD5A65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>criteria for determining the number of positions in and organization of Reserve units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C4B58D3F13E4B7A8E297C6760D8244B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>criteria for determining the appropriate level of seniority and job classifications of Reserve positions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65191AE8C0A64780ABF42C913496E429"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the advertisement of the Reserve to the public to generate interest in volunteers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C4943A9382441C89C4103DE0A325389"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the selection of individuals for the Reserve and the job assignment process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E27D97B185B46369EF18C0975251054"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the appointment authorities to be used by the head of an agency during an activation of the applicable Reserve unit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B4F4AA1373F45F291AAD37438DCD4F0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the appropriate levels of compensation for private individuals for service in the Reserve, dependent on the qualifications and expected roles of the individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F4B11338A554C74B3D7B2D89A0500AD"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate levels of compensation for private individuals for service in the Reserve for additional expenses, such as travel and accommodation, to fulfill the responsibilities in the Reserve, including during training and exercise;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H776C2C0512C84C37828ED2AFDD28E564"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional incentives to be provided to private individuals to encourage participation in the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1AF88AB8F40418B9B04E20C138D36AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether and how to issue security clearances to individuals selected to serve in the Reserve, both prior to and during activation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6BAC2156D6F4687A43F8F4A30EE5F27" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the frequency and content of training and exercises for the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98320E1497FA4EFA884E1F3696C924C9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the appropriate interaction between permanent Government employees and individuals in the Reserve during training, exercises, and activations of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF20EA7B312442C980CF01C37E55DF26"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the appointment of permanent Government employees to manage the Reserve for each agency with a Reserve unit, both prior to and during activation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE40ACFD5A6F043E595C84F2BE7F98B11"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all other matters necessary to effectively manage the Reserve, as determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H574A9443D182456C905B325DB80F7838"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations and considerations for the President on selective activation of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26127E6B87114C209D5173C5592262FB" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management may issue any additional internal guidance as the Director of the Office of Personnel determines is necessary to supplement the rules issued under subsection (f).</text></subsection><subsection id="H55D8F1D33CB6452AB4440689CC0A90E7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Employment protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, an individual absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into service in the Reserve shall be subject to the same employment and reemployment protections as are provided under such chapter for an individual absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into service in the Federal Emergency Management Agency as intermittent personnel under section 306(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H01F085C6B8E9432F94E8F91BD9C6510F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 304(c) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4534">50 U.S.C. 4534(c)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and section 712</quote> after <quote>this title</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H82D4DAF49DD34A2685DAF55861C8B09C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 710 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4560">50 U.S.C. 4560</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2AAAE7EB34C842A1BD16E4A7FA5A590A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98185437C87143D1BF312A894CD64323"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26B6F368574B41EA81F2288403A24540"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving the use of voluntary agreements</header><subsection id="H97B8DA3C3D1F4A79A4230F79DBCA457F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 708 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4558">50 U.S.C. 4558</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA44FA2F90CD94CC9B955227B0A0FC29C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c)(2) and inserting the following: <quote>The authority granted to the President in paragraph (1) and subsection (d) may be delegated by him to the head of any Federal agency to which the President has delegated authority under this Act.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30BDFD41EE2849E3ADDC841F88AB43C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c)(3);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17A19556030D4007A7B99899D6519191"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2), by striking <quote>and the Federal Trade Commission.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H114E8E52AB8249A595A8CBF076F3B19A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4F68B464D6424AC2A85B7454DDB18C7A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HC3B65CED2E7946B3A36D05E032DA2108"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking relating to voluntary agreements</header><paragraph id="HF944242F2FA64983A0A5AA7ECA594D83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce issue rules, after approval of the Attorney General, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, that incorporate standards and procedures by which voluntary agreements and plans of action may be developed and carried out.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49448E8BA3314F749D203505F65D26EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary of Commerce shall publish any rule issued under paragraph (1) in the Federal Register not less than 30 days before the effective date of such rule.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F982D648E014B3C9E35CD064EC6453F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="H85A69E80F199438E89F35E7E62365D54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)—</text><clause id="HB105800EB3B4405A9BDDEA9518BC4F18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>striking by <quote>(after consultation with the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HDD398E90A761454DA6AD8C549B50D4C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>striking by <quote>and publishes such a finding in the Federal Register</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18BB3707E6604C8EB20A1EDD9CE2E2E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>(after consultation with the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26CAC36196564A97A76D1BD1A8111EC7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission</quote> and inserting <quote>and the Secretary of Commerce</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E4204985EBB4FE19BB6A9573CE5AD8E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text><subparagraph id="HEEEC4EE6B96140C6B8D1DC7914F39D7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (2), by striking <quote>and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD985CF48A7DC4802B0F590711B9917C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (3), by striking <quote>, or the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission</quote> in both places it appears;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9163B67BB9EA48319233FC3AE76801A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (4), by striking <quote>and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H933E608A902546E1B45F99A6A13FCD53"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (6), (7), (8), (10), and (11) and redesignating paragraph (9) as paragraph (6);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD3E0AFBF1B04BEA833039D15FCCCF32"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (6)(A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEED57A7F161461781A5D67B05218CAE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (6)(B), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2177FDC8AF44D45B9BA4550D8DFA9CC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by striking subsection (i) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H806291240F054996B28E642D7EDCECCF" style="OLC"><subsection id="HFF824642EEED432A9B11AD3741F931FD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>The Attorney General shall, not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, issue a rule, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, that establishes how the Attorney General shall carry out the responsibilities of the Attorney General under this section in a manner that maintains a proper balance between providing for the national defense and protecting competition and preventing anticompetitive practices and effects from the creation and implementation of voluntary agreements and their plans of action.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A966F95EA44B3C8F725EE75A3339B7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (k)—</text><subparagraph id="H36391DEB4F9E4E55BA0C41911C07253D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the Federal Trade Commission</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6083A6C46C04101904029DCCFD15441"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(after consultation with the Federal Trade Commission)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7052730267543B0BD01E3A57B57D0DC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in subsection (m)—</text><subparagraph id="HA16C00F5FFCC4A06AB071C33BA986207"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d)(2),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFE082EFCCBA4FC8A43AFF21FF226083"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(7), and (8),</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41291F9521754E18B8B70546ABF85A70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required development of voluntary agreement</header><paragraph id="H9DB2B0C53E4F4632855D2D59FFC003CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the later of the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and the date on which the Attorney General issues a rule under Section 708(i) of the Defense Production Act of 1950, the President shall develop a voluntary agreement under section 708 of the Defense Production Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD18E8BDB00AA4E739AE02379E0AB66C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The voluntary agreement entered by the President under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2A45E2CCD677483DA83DD90AD7E62365" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address a current critical national defense issue, such as—</text><clause id="H807DBCD8435646ED8B99833C50A439B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the need for a plan of action to respond to a catastrophic cyber attack on a sector of critical infrastructure, as defined in section 5195c(e) of title 42, United States Code, including how to restore that sector as quickly as possible from the attack through public and private cooperation; or</text></clause><clause id="H1754061897DD48A39BE25F7AD0C8DC4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another issue pertinent to national defense as determined by the President and notified to Congress within 270 days of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD7B9625758E4CD58CD296CC2F2E032E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use 1 or more of the units of the National Defense Executive Reserve established under section 712 of the of the Defense Production Act of 1950.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

