<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25145-XWC-L2-RY5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 457 IS: Designating the week beginning on October 19, 2025, as “Coal Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251020">October 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week beginning on October 19, 2025, as <quote>Coal Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the men and women in the coal industry who play a part in building, maintaining, and delivering access to energy should be commended for their hard work and vital role in modern life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas coal continues to serve as a reliable and affordable source of baseload power for consumers across the United States and provided 19.5 percent of the utility-scale electricity in the United States in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas coal is the most abundant source of electricity worldwide, providing more than 36 percent of global electricity as of the date of introduction of this resolution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas coal was a critical source of power for the industrial revolution, driving steam engines, factories, and transportation such as railways and steam ships;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas coal is an essential energy source that significantly enhanced the military readiness of the United States by enabling modernization of the Navy fleet from sail to steam-powered ships;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas coal remains an important source of energy for the United States, supporting the reliable power needs essential to military readiness and national security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has made significant progress in reducing emissions from coal power plants through the adoption of advanced emission reduction technologies; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these reductions contribute to improved air quality and public health while sustaining the energy necessary to maintain a steady and strong national gross domestic product: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="iddc7edb9a77334d9aa362f11ff38b3296"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designates the week beginning on October 19, 2025, as <quote>Coal Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50d4680d95624442b61f167aa507ed52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congratulates the ongoing progress in reducing coal emissions every year, while recognizing the role of coal in ensuring essential energy for the military readiness and economic stability of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

