<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25176-42C-NX-2FN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S905 IS: Arsenal Workload Sustainment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the establishment within the Department of Defense of a pilot program on arsenal workload sustainment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id3356d1af8b684be2b96991339dacbccb" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arsenal Workload Sustainment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idadb53613be514a4880ee4337f90d3de3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on arsenal workload sustainment</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b73dd8c2cc944a386bcbca64c384ee9"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id945414c47eef4e1fa7c161c955ebc8f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has a long and proud history of manufacturing defense products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id765ee7668bfa4e90bd856e4a0be836dc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Factories and arsenals of the Department of the Army that are owned and operated by the United States Government are a critical component of the organic industrial base.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd7141509c7341aa912bf34f89e6560f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The first ever National Defense Industrial Strategy released in 2024 recognized the need of the Department of Defense to more strategically utilize the organic industrial base in order to maintain a competitive military advantage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf71e24ef28b94682b751b5561e8c51ac"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Sufficient workload at arsenals of the Department of the Army that are owned and operated by the United States Government ensure cost efficiency and technical competence in peacetime, while preserving the ability to provide an effective and timely response to mobilizations, national defense contingency situations, and other emergency requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc1abc2049c0743e7b74955db946fbbfe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to be known as the <quote>Arsenal Workload Sustainment Pilot Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id41d6c0e2005842d79846129427783976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The pilot program shall be conducted for a period of five years.</text></subsection><subsection id="id65d43e1b01f84e67a0a2f560a7f3b327"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preferences for procurement actions or solicitations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae786cb18a2d45428d71a989ed41e622"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense shall give a preference described in paragraph (2) for any procurement action or solicitation by a non-public partner who has entered into a public-private partnership with the Secretary in the source selection process if such non-public partner uses an arsenal of the Department of the Army that is owned and operated by the United States Government as a partner in any type of contractual agreement with the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a840d1b230d4b2db87c49e17e90ec46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preference described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A preference described in this paragraph is the addition of 20 percent to the price of any offer by a non-public partner that does not use an arsenal of the Department of the Army that is owned and operated by the United States Government as a partner in its bid for the same procurement action or solicitation described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97126310662b4bbd82fe53c902fb5c7c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Further preference</header><text>In selecting non-public partners under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall give preference to non-public partners that—</text><subparagraph id="idd2db2e417d6a4e87a7a3f9382da935ba"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilize the Advanced Manufacturing Center of Excellence of the Army; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id850027a8c91c425bb69c2da967c48dbf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure not less than 25 percent of the activities under the partnership are performed by employees of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id179d5b4733a04c98b59915e1183046a5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca22fc555eb240f7a3e3c0f9d1336d50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities carried out under the pilot program, including a description of any operational challenges identified.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19d4000ae4d14b2b981dd11beee069aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa36b31955c9475589de9f51624f5407"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A breakout, by relevant budget accounts, of workload at an arsenal of the Department of the Army that is owned and operated by the United States Government that was achieved in the prior fiscal year, whether directly or through public-private partnerships under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4206f7df93364896a32cb29a67bf186d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of relevant budget accounts where such an arsenal can be utilized to meet future procurement needs of the Department of Defense, irrespective of cost.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0d4abdd73934a10a5d36a089032c4f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An outlook of expected workload at each such arsenal during the period covered by the future-years defense program submitted to Congress under section 221 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0db94929b6e842c7b53426baca347700"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The capital investments required to be made at each such arsenal to ensure compliance and operational capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id67e2f9f0e9c8467d8d12af355580f32e"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id054b2f17f29b4873967b3e331b53f95a"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id4274e1437e1e4d188b60846de7dd4183"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide93c0ff9b86e473f82589c93cfffc555"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2af07ea1f12d480ab648767ce49db6f8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-public partner</header><text>The term <term>non-public partner</term> means a corporation, individual, university, or nonprofit organization that is not part of the United States Government. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

