<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98E2A86833BA4947A32E886EE46E346E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2065 IH: Unmasking Hamas Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2065</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide penalty enhancements for committing certain offenses while in disguise, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7EDE5809BBCA472A8DF22A1C4364CC51" style="OLC"><section id="H7ACDEDD4700A4695A1C0ADDE7BB0FC06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unmasking Hamas Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H480DEF9FD59A47BA80F07F00E81B09DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HA1068B121CDC4A629D6567113DDF1B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Universities and colleges across America, including Columbia University, California State Polytechnic University, the University of New Mexico, and Barnard College, have been increasingly targeted by violent student protests in the name of Hamas. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EA4FDD479F8429CBB24FBCDA014CD7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Violent student protests at universities and colleges across the country have caused significant damage to campus property and have barred university and college students from accessing educational services. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC57E2E38D54C6E866D5B18E31C8150"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Violent protestors continue to utilize masks as a disguise to cover their identity in order to evade the law. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE71C4F7EA833434DBFC9E34B6F361208"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support for designated terrorist organizations, antisemitism, and calling for the genocide of Jewish people have no place on our university and college campuses. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9925AEEEC4904CB29A2EDDA4A439BF53"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iran and Hamas-backed organizations partner with United States-based anti-Israel organizations to fund anti-Israel demonstrations and protests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H386F0E42BD594F8A978CA9A044B9C4CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>During Prime Minister of Israel Benjamin Netanyahu’s address to a joint session of Congress in 2024, Hamas-sympathetic masked protestors vandalized Federal property in Washington, DC, across from Union Station.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68BD643F82DC405C85750190CE7CBDD6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Pro-Hamas advocates have anonymously vandalized multiple memorials and commemorative statues across Washington, DC, including the Lincoln Memorial and the General Lafayette Statue outside of the White House.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC61BDF752ADB448AB102D2D2383CF761"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Anonymous bomb threats to synagogues dramatically increased in the months following Hamas’s October 7, 2023, attack on Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB31A02D6AEB4A9EA378C7CAD5331425"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Police officers disbanding unlawful assemblies have been subjected to violent confrontations by masked protestors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E898E193B2F462D99B114E4EEECB8A1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Masked protests have repeatedly led to the desecration of public property.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5DAACA2EDB8347B2BF8F7861FCCE240E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interference with protected rights while in disguise</header><subsection id="H9163A5997B17469B801491D1D16D04AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/250">section 250</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9DC1F1873D44383938CBAEEB11F4A45" style="USC"><section id="H75EECA001AE242019B94968F57DCC4C4"><enum>251.</enum><header>Interference with protected rights while in disguise</header><subsection id="H398D43D54D9540699ABE79E4E15EEE11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, whether or not acting under color of law, while in disguise, including while wearing a mask, injures, oppresses, threatens, or intimidates any person in any State, Territory, Commonwealth, Possession, or District in the free exercise or enjoyment of any right or privilege secured to him by the Constitution or laws of the United States, or because of his having so exercised the same, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5132F7C7461E4CF481578DF2B5F5BC17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed so as to deter any law enforcement officer from lawfully carrying out the duties of his office; and no law enforcement officer shall be considered to be in violation of this section for lawfully carrying out the duties of his office or lawfully enforcing ordinances and laws of the United States, the District of Columbia, any of the several States, or any political subdivision of a State. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means any officer of the United States, the District of Columbia, a State, or political subdivision of a State, who is empowered by law to conduct investigations of, or make arrests because of, offenses against the United States, the District of Columbia, a State, or a political subdivision of a State.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC353C830EC2B46909AFF6C090ECFB096"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item related to section 250 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA54990F36B9413DB58D14A88ED27BA2" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">251. Interference with protected rights while in disguise. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HD999A481A5AA49AF9BF443C2A63865FE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Destroying buildings or property within special maritime and territorial jurisdiction while in disguise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1363 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Whoever, during the commission of an offense under this section, wears a disguise, including a mask, shall, in addition to any term of imprisonment otherwise imposed under this section, be imprisoned for 2 years.</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

