<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H47CB2C2B9EE845A88DDC0E0044CCEC12" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 684 IH: Expressing support for the designation of September 9, 2025, as “National Firearm Suicide Prevention Day” to educate about the growing firearm suicide crisis in the United States and promote the importance of storing firearms safely and securely as an essential component of suicide prevention.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 684</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of September 9, 2025, as <quote>National Firearm Suicide Prevention Day</quote> to educate about the growing firearm suicide crisis in the United States and promote the importance of storing firearms safely and securely as an essential component of suicide prevention.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas each and every day in the United States, 74 individuals lose their life to firearm suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s National Center for Health Statistics, in 2023, a firearm was used in 55 percent of all suicides in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas firearm suicide rates across the United States increased by 14 percent over the past decade;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas firearms are by far the deadliest method of suicide, and 90 percent of suicide attempts with a gun are fatal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas easy access to firearms triples the risk of suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4,600,000 children live in homes with access to an unlocked or unsupervised gun;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in 75 percent of youth firearm suicides, the gun storage method was identified, and the gun was stored loaded and unlocked;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas firearm suicides among children have increased by 57 percent in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native American/Alaska Native youth have seen the greatest increase in suicide rate, while Black children face the highest suicide rate amongst all preteens in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elder white males (ages 70+) face the highest rates of gun suicide compared to any other demographic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 71 percent of veteran suicide deaths are the result of a firearm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas simply storing a firearm safely is a factor known to reduce the likelihood of a gun owner dying by firearm suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recent studies have noted that even a 20 percent increase in the number of households in the United States practicing safe storage could prevent almost one-third of all annual youth gun deaths from suicide and unintentional shootings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a November 2017 Government Accountability Office report, <quote>Personal Firearms: Programs that Promote Safe Storage and Research on Their Effectiveness</quote>, identified 16 public or nonprofit programs that promote safe gun storage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Firearm Suicide Prevention Day</quote>, founded by Brady and End Family Fire, is held annually on the second Tuesday in September as an opportunity to promote awareness about growing firearm suicide crisis in the United States and the evidence-based role of safe firearm storage in preventing it; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September 9, 2025, is the second Tuesday in September and is designated by national and local organizations as <quote>Firearm Suicide Prevention Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H60E12428E7624421891AE3A6B1EF30EE"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H037DD4298AA64C4FA9A15D8C45CC32F8"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H9537D144292C4193A2FB20C72565B067"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Firearm Suicide Prevention Day</quote> to encourage storing firearms safely and securely as an essential component of suicide prevention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6601D1B5A1B543C08B7E4E61B9A5E1D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages public health, medical, and other professionals to discuss gun ownership, gun safety, safe storage in the home, and suicide prevention with their patients; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C04D1E899DB4329B640AB5CEDCFBFBA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Firearm Suicide Prevention Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

