<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H69677A60AD2742FB987C9CE17A7BE621" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1780 IH: Hawaii Native Species Conservation and Recovery Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1780</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a competitive grant program to support the conservation and recovery of native plant, fungi, and animal species in the State of Hawaii, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H66ECAC2D6912429F9C154C1EDCBF36E4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H98A2F43BB6174BD18E4D0B1E2E2A3314" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hawaii Native Species Conservation and Recovery Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H21523B8D822F47FE84E9390E9E2808CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H0D0E8220E75646B6805F14DE8CB1E0A8"><enum></enum><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFDBA4DD30D774DF5B327FE990C6F6694" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H65D406BC62D1463990F21F6C0FAFC54E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H878710FAD6B84DAB808641887A570A9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a unit of local government in the State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F7F2A747E134252BE2A2E5AB895B2F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian organization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBB24087AA62A4A6998A5F53B9ED91C83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA8F802C286824E39A62815067735AC7C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a business; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1D2B310375BD41C0B3F358FE91B899DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EA2C49A53A644D4B7B06309810EE01B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>The term <term>grant program</term> means the Hawaii Native Species Conservation and Recovery Grant Program established under section 3(a). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H06EA05682D9947B685D2DF7281C601E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Native Hawaiian organization</header><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the NATIVE Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4352">25 U.S.C. 4352</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4969B66D6590422BB39B140833BF6904"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Native species</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>native species</term> means a plant, fungi, or animal species that is native to the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BB572A2028942B9A3FA9A1B3BEC7FC7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63D9D1F19FD640BF99F31A4EC9008C79"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Hawaii.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEE0ABA35291E4B3B9FEEDEBB50931F66"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hawaii Native Species Conservation and Recovery Grant Program</header> 
<subsection id="H7F35088A6D9E422B97D5D4CB6E619BB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which amounts are appropriated to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall establish a grant program, to be known as the <quote>Hawaii Native Species Conservation and Recovery Grant Program</quote>, to annually provide, through cooperative agreements, grants, micro grants, or other means, funding to eligible entities to carry out projects that—</text> <paragraph id="H818785CBAB564D8F85C0072C9674DAF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>achieve the funding priorities developed under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03509E6D12664D3184E055C4F97D0660" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>meet the criteria developed under subsection (e). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFA137320A66E479C8FAE0F90BA48AC04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The grant program shall identify priorities and provide funding and technical assistance to carry out coordinated, evidence-based conservation and recovery projects in the State—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCFAB9339FC0444CE838832A1CFA1AC76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prevent and mitigate the introduction and spread of invasive species, pests, and diseases that threaten native species;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6EBC1D37F1C4FD2B54BC7A3EC77E188"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address the ecological consequences of climate change on native species;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBBAC94676A445D4AE2DAF6EE1646BF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to address loss and degradation of native species' habitats;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4AAE3A8DB8E4628B3235FC9362C98A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to manage, maintain, and restore populations of native species;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98774044D48149EA80162491337A4AF0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to increase scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary for the conservation and recovery of native species;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEEB1FB7675B44EBB024FCEA1C030745"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to improve information collection, ecological monitoring, and management relating to the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (5); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75C4C7787D0D491A9ED71EC78A65787D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to engage the public through outreach, education, and community involvement to increase capacity and support for the conservation and recovery of native species in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D77444C2C8545C0A00C5A7C51F6EE97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of priorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the grant program, the Secretary shall coordinate with the following individuals to develop annual, evidence-based funding priorities for the grant program that support the purposes described in subsection (b):</text> 
<paragraph id="HE60ECF05E7D7489A9DE679B0C4A722A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heads of Federal agencies, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H969EBEE48D31498B913334C1913C364E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (or a designee);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDC13CA064034F18A1E9E99C818B50A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (or a designee);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB265943869AB4147805B5BB5CDDD555B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture (or a designee); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0D9EA3161A8442DA937674F2D81C88D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the head of any other applicable Federal agency (or a designee), as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D105A1376EE4A81BB7D7728B7E62F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Chairperson of the Hawaii Board of Land and Natural Resources (or a designee).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24963087721448BBB4FB9F8ADE8A78B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Chairperson of the Hawaii Board of Agriculture (or a designee).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F1A66E482C047EC8BF8165A8723307B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other relevant stakeholder involved in the conservation and recovery of native species in the State that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB31FF71AF5F14B53A159687C49E24F80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Request for proposals</header><text>The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register an annual request for proposals, in accordance with the funding priorities developed under subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H484AAB4B83F6436192ABB1246AA1CE1A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the individuals described in subsection (c), shall annually develop criteria for ranking project proposals to receive funding under the grant program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB32A98ABFED428E92AE68FB8F4434DE" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recusal</header><text>If the State or a unit of local government in the State applies for a grant under the grant program, then the individuals described in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c) who are representatives of the State or that unit of local government, as applicable, shall recuse themselves from all funding decisions relating to those applications.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60B68A8FDCAC4B748D7E7948570DB3DD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header> <paragraph id="HB96625920232465CAF7F146BA35C97CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header> <subparagraph id="HACE902CBBDE846F0911AB84204DA7839"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the grant program shall not exceed 75 percent.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A99F20E757147FD8B8BC32EB8D0F95C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the grant program may be 100 percent, as determined by the Secretary—</text> <clause id="HBB993E7CC44A467A944835F53B2BD722"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for any project, in the discretion of the Secretary; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2E1C03637F374194B443E8B8151B6C1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the project—</text> <subclause id="H0610758A5F85421DAA99C94DF7D15883"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is carried out by a Native Hawaiian organization;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF1C71CF35FD14285B9DBB4DAA87C73BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>significantly contributes to youth workforce readiness in the implementation of the project; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H294AEDF05D1E4572A86E2F7D7B7332E0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is carried out using a grant awarded under the grant program in an amount of not more than $50,000.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2069D6063F664DE5B14C6E29E6ADCDE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the grant program may be provided in the form of an in-kind contribution of services, materials, or access to land.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2596A7C62C1407A933A0B3D147D1CAB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out the grant program for each fiscal year, not less than 5 percent shall be used to award grants for projects described in subclauses (I) through (III) of subsection (g)(1)(B)(ii).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09094636DC344B009C546A6DD6D37BA8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance to eligible entities to assist in the implementation of projects that receive funding under the grant program.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6946F6EA67F742A3A1682FC4E58E8994"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consultation with Native Hawaiian organizations</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out the grant program, shall consult with Native Hawaiian organizations with respect to any project that receives funding under the grant program with implications for the Native Hawaiian Community.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38537CAA49884147A474A3C3FC992251"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds made available to carry out the grant program for each fiscal year shall supplement and not supplant other funds made available to carry out the purposes described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (b) in the State.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCC7FFB33019346049299FA9CC0647182"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual report</header> <subsection id="HA2E953006BC641C48872E27549EF63DF"><enum></enum><text>Annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this Act, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8E338A5B9A645A0A6897DA115D62B04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of each project that has received funding under the grant program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7621C823FBC43D98A995E51ADF6DCD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the status of each project described in paragraph (1) that is in progress on the date of submission of the applicable report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFCF45EDB66D8415593BC3E7E83124CD9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HAB176A07ED7F4DEF9A28C86CEA28141B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $30,000,000 for the first fiscal year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act and for each of the 9 fiscal years thereafter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8B195268C7BB4B0B9F0A545C0E44790D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the amounts made available for each fiscal year under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use not more than 5 percent for administrative expenses relating to carrying out the grant program.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

