<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25064-N0X-YN-5PH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 33 IS: Expressing support for the recognition of January as “Muslim-American Heritage Month” and celebrating the heritage and culture of Muslim Americans in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 33</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of January as <quote>Muslim-American Heritage Month</quote> and celebrating the heritage and culture of Muslim Americans in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate is proud to recognize and commemorate <quote>Muslim-American Heritage Month</quote>, an observance that celebrates the contributions of Muslim Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in keeping with the time-honored traditions of the Senate, the Senate recognizes and pays tribute to those who foster cultural pride and enhance the profile of diverse communities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigration of Muslims to the American colonies began with the arrival of indentured workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 17th, 18th, and 19th centuries, a significant number of slaves of Muslim heritage were brought to the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas in the 19th, 20th, and 21st centuries, successive waves of immigration brought additional Muslims to the United States, who sought to pursue economic and social opportunity, as well as freedom of religion, and enriched the fabric of the society of the United States as business owners, entrepreneurs, health care professionals, humanitarians, scientists, and students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Muslim Americans contribute greatly to charitable organizations that help people from all faiths in the United States and around the world by providing medical assistance, family services, and scholastic supplies, running before- and after-school programs, feeding the hungry, and providing recuperation efforts following natural disasters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Muslim Americans have contributed to every part of the society of the United States by making advancements in architecture, arts, business, culture, government, law, medicine, the military, religion, and sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Bangladeshi-American Fazlur Rahman Khan left his mark on the cityscapes of the United States by pioneering a new structural system of frame tubes used to construct iconic buildings like the World Trade Center in New York City, New York, the Hubert H. Humphrey Metrodome in Minneapolis, Minnesota, and the Willis <quote>Sears</quote> Tower in Chicago, Illinois;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many Muslim Americans pursue the American dream and contribute to the economy of the United States as business owners and entrepreneurs, including Pakistani-born billionaire Shahid Khan, owner of the auto-parts company Flex-N-Gate and the National Football League's Jacksonville Jaguars;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the invention of the ice cream cone by Syrian immigrant Ernest Hamwi is a practical confection with a near ubiquitous presence in the life of the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2006, Keith Ellison of Minnesota was elected to the House of Representatives, becoming the first Muslim American to serve in Congress;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2008, Ambassador Sada Cumber was appointed by President George W. Bush to serve as the first Special Envoy to the Organization of the Islamic Conference from the United States, representing the United States to 57 Muslim-majority nations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2015, André Carson of Indiana, the second Muslim American elected to the House of Representatives, became the first Muslim American to serve on the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas actor Mahershala Ali became the first Muslim American to win an Oscar for his supporting role in <quote>Moonlight</quote> in 2017;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2018, Rashida Tlaib of Michigan and Ilhan Omar of Minnesota were elected to the House of Representatives, becoming the first Muslim-American women to serve in Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, Zahid Quraishi was confirmed as the first Muslim American to serve as an article III Federal judge as a district judge of the United States District Court for the District of New Jersey;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2021, Rashad Hussain was confirmed as the first Muslim American to serve as the United States Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the invention of the intraventricular catheter system by Pakistani-American neurosurgeon Ayub Ommaya provides chemotherapy to treat brain tumors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Muslim Americans have fought in support of the United States in every major war, from Bampett Muhamed and Yusuf Ben Ali under the command of General George Washington in the American Revolutionary War, to Captain Humayun Khan, who made the ultimate sacrifice in Iraq in 2004;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Imam Warith Deen Mohammed, the first Muslim American to deliver the invocation for the Senate, and El-Hajj Malik El-Shabazz, the civil rights activist and reformer also known as Malcolm X, were prominent religious leaders and scholars;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Muslim-American professional athletes like Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame members Kareem Abdul Jabbar, Hakeem Olajuwon, and Shaquille O’Neal, and 2-time world heavyweight boxing champion Hasim Shariff Rahman, thrilled sports fans across the United States and around the world during their respective careers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Muslim-American Olympians, such as boxer Muhammad Ali, track and field athlete Dalilah Muhammad, and fencer Ibtihaj Muhammad, won medals in international competitions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with roots in at least 77 different countries and identifying racially as White, Black, Arab, and Asian, Muslim Americans are an extremely diverse population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the current population of Muslims living in the United States is estimated at over 3,450,000 individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 4,500 Muslims serve on active duty, and over 2,300 Muslims serve as selected reserve personnel in the Armed Forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Muslim population has been growing in the United States, and the present-day Muslim-American population is a tapestry of ethnic, racial, linguistic, social, and economic groups;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 50 percent of Muslim Americans have reported experiencing religious discrimination, with that number rising to 64 percent for Muslim Americans whose appearance identifies them as Muslim, such as women who wear the hijab or headscarf;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a need for public education, awareness, and policies that help people be culturally competent when describing, discussing, or addressing the impacts that Muslim Americans have on all aspects of the society of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Muslim-American Heritage Month</quote> will be observed in the month of January; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the incredible contributions and heritage of Muslim Americans have helped to build a better United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H7E9235E6497747FFB6E7A4820C051A9F"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2906DFE4A6384219BC2CCB895A4A6341"><enum/><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H598226F8DF224592BEBD6149F4DB27C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of January as <quote>Muslim-American Heritage Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A6EAF9264B44C14AE0B39088C0BE098"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the contributions and integral role of Muslim Americans in the economy, culture, and identity of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC64EDFFBF6FC44298FCE9BF439EF5A37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the people of the United States to observe <quote>Muslim-American Heritage Month</quote> with appropriate ceremonies, programs, and activities that celebrate the contributions of Muslim Americans to the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

