<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H533879135710476692694522946BE8BD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 624 IH: Honoring the life and heroic sacrifice of Mr. Anderson “Chase” Childers, a former Georgia police officer who selflessly sacrificed his life rescuing swimmers from a deadly rip current off the coast of South Carolina.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 624</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and heroic sacrifice of Mr. Anderson <quote>Chase</quote> Childers, a former Georgia police officer who selflessly sacrificed his life rescuing swimmers from a deadly rip current off the coast of South Carolina.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 13, 2025, Mr. Anderson <quote>Chase</quote> Childers, a former police officer and minor league baseball player, courageously entered the ocean near Pawleys Island, South Carolina, to save a family caught in a dangerous rip current;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers displayed extraordinary courage and selflessness when he saved the family of five;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after expending all his energy saving the family, Mr. Childers was unable to stay above water as the rip current swept him away, ultimately causing him to pay the highest sacrifice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers, at 38 years old, was a decorated former police officer with the Cobb County Police Department, where he received a lifetime achievement award for saving lives throughout his career;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers was a loving son, a dedicated brother, a treasured friend, and an exceptional father;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers is survived by his beloved wife, Nataley, and their three children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers’ selfless and heroic actions have inspired thousands of people and led to a nationwide outpouring of support;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the town of Pawleys Island and communities across South Carolina and Georgia mourn the loss of a true public servant and everyday hero; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Childers’ final act was consistent with the values of honor, duty, and sacrifice that he upheld throughout his life: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H129F49EA5F0E4E72AA38E9403BF07477"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H57CF454F5BE645CA8643493A615C6F22"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H8022523D5CCD483F8B43B4C60A699FBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the life and heroic sacrifice of Mr. Anderson <quote>Chase</quote> Childers, a former Georgia police officer who gave selflessly sacrificed his life rescuing swimmers from a deadly rip current off the coast of South Carolina;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC33391F6A64BD0A6B136EC6E866727"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers its deepest condolences to the family, friends, and loved ones of Mr. Childers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C03E36F171471DBCFA7E958D5508C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the first responders who assisted in the recovery efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE14F2C0FADBD4B7CB65A931E1FC3A311"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the danger posed by rip currents and supports public education efforts regarding rip currents to reduce future loss of life;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57A6BA6738FB48FBAB085758C0C3D66B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>celebrates the legacy of service and heroism that Mr. Childers leaves behind; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB92F7728F25403A8692BBA49F62E4CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expresses gratitude for all those who act selflessly in service to others, even at great personal risk.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

