<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBE14AE921ACC4020BBD77C886126EAAA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2669 IH: Community First Pretrial Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2669</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a new Justice Department grant program to reduce the number of individuals incarcerated in local jails, reduce the number of days individuals are incarcerated in local jails, and support community-led local justice reinvestment.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD5FA1A5E086E43758864BC7AFBE8E47B" style="OLC"><section id="H7D22E5EAFA504260BEE501EF86CD706A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community First Pretrial Reform Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Community First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0EF5569EEFF34D64B3FA53FEC8EA4967"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><subsection id="H5F28CCCB13C84678A54097FC1AD0BDF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Bureau of Justice Assistance, shall make grants to eligible partnerships for purposes of reducing the number of individuals in jails operated by units of local government and the number of days such individuals spend in jail as follows:</text><paragraph id="H910963649417441F8F8826A2621151E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants for analysis and planning, which shall be used to—</text><subparagraph id="HA4A5D7A51B9649E0A7776E9B82920B3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect and analyze local criminal justice and incarceration data, including data on equity disparities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F3D0A2143AE4CB184354B3EAE357459"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a strategic, collaborative plan to decrease local jail incarceration that shall be public facing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931ACED4973C43A2B703299925AD4543"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants for implementation of the plan described in paragraph (1)(B) and which may be used for activities to reduce the number of individuals incarcerated in local jails and to reduce the number of days that individuals are so incarcerated including—</text><subparagraph id="H4B9B1722AFFE4DA7825DA253B4B01203"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing the use of cash bail;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0D5C4B2ED3F4EC7981A095D7DB3DA94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing revocations of conditional release;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB7EA67BEF984A819CCDAD199395621C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creating or increasing the availability of pretrial services, including efforts undertaken in collaboration with community-based organizations and nonprofits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24391D2A6B5C4B1CA7821CB5D112DBB4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>investing in case processing and processes to reduce overall time to disposition and time between court events;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02315299ECA44C6BBE6B939315757F0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensuring early assignment of counsel and presence of counsel at individuals’ first court appearance or bail hearing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F57EECBF404330A5764C2B90C8D7E9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing training to various actors within the criminal justice system on indigent defense that is aligned with best practices in the field;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D5800C3C83A4E0BBA93962595268E7A"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating or expanding diversion programs that do not require an individual to enter into a guilty plea and do not use incarceration as a sanction for noncompliance—</text><clause id="H56FA031ADCC142BBA68CB57C76CC4848"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the pre-arrest phase;</text></clause><clause id="HE3CB1C547AFB4F7A8BF8545CEC0BF93F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the pre-booking phase; and</text></clause><clause id="H547C7AB563554F01AA7A95836E9C065B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at the post-booking phase; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4B126A7724A4A51B46135DAFDFB2B24"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other emerging, promising, or evidence-based practices that an eligible partnership proposes and the Attorney General deems likely to reduce local jail incarceration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60A85FFA33DA4AEAB6CDA8D22953EEB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible partnership is a partnership between not less than two of the following:</text><paragraph id="HAAA746BFC8BF43F88AA7D6650ADA339B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A unit of local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2140599FB39D4C2789E78A9D2E45A6A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A territory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4EF4362356407298E645AB5066210D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An Indian tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB250A446B68E4826B1BB68DECB0A4467"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67989665F6B0436089D77F66485165F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application for a grant shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H26C0AA4E401A43639E3D1BE228EF2004"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Details of the range of pretrial services available within the jurisdiction where the jail being targeted for incarceration rate reduction under this Act is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC367171546F0409EADDD2600ABE026DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to ensure that individuals in pretrial contact with the justice system will be subject to the least restrictive conditions or combination of conditions necessary to reasonably address the imminent risk of willful flight or the risk of imminent threat of serious physical harm to a reasonably identifiable person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F461CFCEE44B5392FC639FAD81E2BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A plan for ongoing process evaluation and outcome evaluation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68334A99E2404799BA68D59C3FD4C12C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Either—</text><subparagraph id="H480E9A36E3194777862450A2BB6C0324"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data—</text><clause id="HFBDED61D7D0E488486CFBF709D916A7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregated by key demographic indicators, including factors such as community background and identity, on incarceration for correctional facilities within the local jurisdiction for each of the last five calendar years that includes——</text><subclause id="H720CAFB122BD4F31BC0A2852EBD2DC51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average daily population;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE275E573A7804DE0A0A399F68BAF729E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of individuals held pretrial and post-conviction; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEC732A96602A4D9287DABEA32195C6DC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the average length of stay for individuals held pretrial and post-conviction; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4D586D882AF24F27A9FFCCA28BC18F72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregated by key demographic indicators on arrests made by all law enforcement entities operating within the local jurisdiction over each of the last five calendar years; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5BEA3E0648C4B4BBC2E5663094643EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the event that elements of such incarceration or arrest data are not able to be compiled and reported, a comprehensive plan to obtain as much of the unavailable data as possible within the first year of the award.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC223C93747594897A06C2D51A096DAB7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements</header><subsection id="HE20F0E4A1BC74F4E93419AFEEEF83F5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grantees shall—</text><paragraph id="H4AC449D0B233454FA26AF86F2E43EF3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult in all phases of planning, implementation, and evaluation with municipal, county, and State law enforcement agencies, courts in the local jurisdiction, public defense organizations and criminal defense practitioners in the local jurisdiction, local substance use and mental health authorities, local community members, local community members who have been justice-involved, and community-based organizations and service providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B77366470C4197A8319AB654419B84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze local jail incarceration and arrest data to identify the drivers of jail incarceration and equity disparities and ground jail population reduction strategies in that data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09DCA54186AA4101AC86B165DA453F9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce incarceration rates by no less than 5 percent the first year of an implementation grant, 10 percent in each subsequent year, and 50 percent by the end of the grant period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65CDD6BE643F43B8869AAE6792CA23A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in consultation with the Bureau of Justice Assistance—</text><subparagraph id="HB10DE9BF363B47048A7353953B6F17A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adopt and implement a methodology for measuring equity disparities in jail incarceration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F02AEDA90E5481A80C1DDCF44D2039D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>set goals for the reduction of equity jail incarceration disparities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEE363DD72C148D0BA23E88FB8B87AC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>decrease levels of incarceration across all races and ethnicities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF3372EB5A345FBA3F0181B3AF52C61"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage an external evaluator to coordinate data collection and reporting in an ongoing fashion and perform both a process and outcome evaluation, with support from the Bureau of Justice Assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B2FEEE962E49DAB74FBED19C6B5464"><enum>(6)</enum><text>use financial savings created through decreased incarceration to sustain programmatic and community-based efforts to reduce jail incarceration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E730B9371DE4C9092D3AF322F8626F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant oversight requirement</header><paragraph id="H450C1262A1CE4B55ABB8A7362A39B4E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a grantee fails to meet the incarceration rate and equity disparities reduction requirements under subsection (a)(3) in any year of the award, the Bureau of Justice Assistance shall perform an audit of the use of their award and the grantee shall implement new strategies based on that audit. If a grantee fails to meet the incarceration rate and equity disparities reduction requirements under subsection (a)(3) in any two consecutive years of the award, the Attorney General shall terminate the award.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED9D85BB755E4DD2B6181454D4285D29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification authority</header><text>The Bureau of Justice Assistance may grant a modification to the incarceration rate reduction requirement under subsection (a)(3) if the Bureau determines after an audit that the failure to meet the incarceration rate reduction requirement was caused by an increase in population in the covered jurisdiction. If a grantee fails to meet the modified reduction requirements in any two subsequent years of the award, the Attorney General shall terminate the award. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0AF9665E98484CF887351B8272660C3A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><subsection id="HB2D615781D814FF0847604CBB960DFE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Planning grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under section 2(a)(1) may be for not more than $100,000 for a single grantee, and shall be for a term of 1 year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1F5E757A3A04A0DA6CB4D2CF727A012"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header><text>A grant under section 2(a)(2) shall be for a term of 6 years, and shall be structured as follows:</text><paragraph id="H253666EB6E224D0AAF52C1E47128E0CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For the first year of the grant term, an amount shall be disbursed that is to be not less than $500,000 and not more than $3,000,000, contingent upon acceptance of a grantee’s proposed budget for activities under the grant, which may be subject to revision during the award process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA8467430264E8BA292940A0F370AAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Award amounts shall decrease annually by—</text><subparagraph id="H80CBFE2195474513B5D6161C82EF5BBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>10 percent in the second year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41E1F0D72A4745FAAC8AC6C65E789879"><enum>(B)</enum><text>15 percent in the third year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H698DA8701D384BA39A53CDBE0F6F1B7B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>20 percent in the fourth year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B2F0C973D5D4897A1666832F8DF32C4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>25 percent in the fifth year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25DA735715264F078706F6391FC36662"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Award amounts during the sixth year of the award may not be used for programmatic activities and shall support only program evaluation and the drafting of a final report, and such funds shall be available to the grantees until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2ED6B21D07B74F3A8C26ED603268EEE2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Selection priority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In selecting grantees, the Attorney General shall—</text><paragraph id="HD7A5F9855AA04889AC3F40AE4FB4BF52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority to applicants from jurisdictions with the highest incarceration rates that are not already in decline and whose applications contain the most ambitious and attainable plans for reducing that rate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F873384066A49CCB3D150EBF906D902"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give additional priority to applicants from jurisdictions seeking to use funds under this Act to prevent the local government from expanding the number of beds in local correctional facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BAE55723C64AD4BF5974B86ECF4AD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for any year in which there will only be one new or ongoing award, ensure that a small metropolitan, micropolitan, or noncore area is the recipient of the award;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2FDD498BD2E43A49B3BE9D5F7080CD0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for any year in which there will be more than one new or ongoing award, ensure that small metropolitan, micropolitan, or noncore areas are the recipients of at least two awards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A0A2BCF42D485F93A0F639F3C5B56A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for any year in which there will be three or more new or ongoing awards, ensure that no more than one large central metropolitan area is a recipient of an award.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBEBE1719F0284AD982908A26BBA78046"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6458D354A12944149027D4AC6DF89696"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conditional release</term> means probation, parole, supervised release, home confinement, community supervision, and other practices under which an individual is supervised in the community by the criminal justice system and may be incarcerated if found in violation of the conditions of their release.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F2829E6803B4E06B4E54AFF58BD8396"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>diversion</term> means a program or practice that—</text><subparagraph id="HE140C4820FB040959CEAE6A28FA78769"><enum>(A)</enum><text>places individuals who come into contact with the criminal justice system into alternative processes outside the standard scope of criminal justice processing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D366D5CA564454A7F34FC87F5D3D1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduces an individual’s involvement in the criminal justice system in both the short and long term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11085B1431294EC485400F101B97D9F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>emerging practice</term> means a program or practice—</text><subparagraph id="H50BEC3E27C3A4540B42BFEF2D3AC9F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with initial implementation resulting in decreased local jail incarceration in one or more communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC41411F63C2E4E1E9BD07919C56B27CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that will be evaluated through a well-designed and rigorous study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D67723A6E36437A82E4C088E67F6442"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>evidence-based practice</term> means a program or practice that—</text><subparagraph id="H621E2D04FC7A4E02A78FCF02B3A0B0E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is demonstrated to be effective when implemented with fidelity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1959E700F4664E8084B3FC357ECFDC56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is based on a clearly articulated and empirically supported theory;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E4F07158E324B64926313DE9E2585AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has measurable outcomes relevant to reducing jail incarceration, including a detailed description of the outcomes produced in a particular population, whether urban or rural; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EABBF677DBC4978BB22F3934D2700A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has been scientifically tested and proven effective through randomized control studies or comparison group studies and with the ability to replicate and scale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D0664E7C8914B4EAC8905F0BB461ED5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>micropolitan area</term> has the meaning established under the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (hereinafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>CDC</quote>) National Center for Health Statistics Urban-Rural Classification Scheme for Counties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F63F16E3816418AA37F3F1A91C37AD5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>small metropolitan area</term> has the meaning established under the CDC’s National Center for Health Statistics Urban-Rural Classification Scheme for Counties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46BED68E576D40C182C8C4BFE6FD44DA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>noncore areas</term> has the meaning established under the CDC’s National Center for Health Statistics Urban-Rural Classification Scheme for Counties. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC230B5BC29304698B653C354212C3ECD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>post-booking diversion</term> means a program or practice that diverts individuals from formal criminal justice system processing after formal intake processing into jail. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1F8DAC9184D44EF82CCF210419A6CAE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <term>pre-booking diversion</term> means a program or practice that diverts individuals from formal criminal justice system processing prior to arrest or prior to formal intake processing into jail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H420E7F68C35F4DBFB85095054EDCF66F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>promising practice</term> means a program or practice that—</text><subparagraph id="H32BBEBDA02C84FA6AFC01ECAE39C13C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is demonstrated to be effective based on positive outcomes relevant to reducing jail incarceration from one or more objective, independent, and scientifically valid evaluations, as documented in writing to the Attorney General; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A2C5439D1DC4ED3BE5723CCB4F77078"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will be evaluated through a well-designed and rigorous study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBEB9A1DE64F494296B993DBDAE713D9"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>equity disparities</quote> means an measurable differences in outcomes, treatment, or access to services within the criminal justice system that are correlated with demographic factors such community background and identity. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H544D3DB125EA485990A14623DE4E61FA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated—</text><paragraph id="H7978FE06494447ABB31556190BCC6D82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 for planning grants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60E2FBF78FCA4A21A40A258459A21113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 for implementation grants, of which 10 percent of any appropriated amount is reserved specifically for evaluation activities.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

