<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E37AD3ADE20466BBA039248D66E1D9D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 555 IH: Expressing support for the designation of June 28, 2025, as “Community is Stronger than Cancer Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 555</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 28, 2025, as <quote>Community is Stronger than Cancer Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 18,000,000 people with a history of cancer living in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas more than 2,041,910 individuals in the United States may be diagnosed with cancer in 2025;</text>
        </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas a 2016 report estimated that at least 2,800,000 people provided care to a person with cancer in the United States in a given year, and those individuals spent an average of 32.9 hours a week providing that care;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Community Is Stronger Than Cancer Day</quote> celebrates the community that comes together to support cancer patients, survivors, caregivers, and their loved ones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Community Is Stronger Than Cancer Day</quote> was first celebrated in 2021 by providing community-based support to patients, survivors, and caregivers who have experienced a cancer diagnosis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Community Is Stronger Than Cancer Day</quote> will be celebrated by 196 locations in 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Community Is Stronger Than Cancer Day</quote> is a celebration of inspiration, companionship, connection, and hope; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas our community is truly stronger than cancer: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC0D1873C53EF4108B851D4964BCB6BDB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE0018C2D8E6C4E67B2E0B4D8B7F98DE0"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H631C4E15CADC411C9EACF3B572E14790"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Community Is Stronger Than Cancer Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE156453900D4B2699EBA2A22F5EE637"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all people of the United States to support those impacted by cancer by providing support, fostering compassionate communities, and breaking down barriers to care to all affected; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H109D945A62434B00BBD4347F6990864C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>aims to celebrate inspiration, companionship, connection, and hope for all communities impacted by cancer.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

