<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E1C2A1F29044991BF7C32257CA48289" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3551 IH: Teaching Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander History Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3551</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to eligible
      entities to carry out educational programs that include the history of peoples of Asian,
      Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander descent in the settling and founding of America, the
      social, economic, and political environments that led to the development of discriminatory
      laws targeting Asians, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders and their relation to current
      events, and the impact and contributions of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific
      Islanders to the development and enhancement of American life, United States history,
      literature, the economy, politics, body of laws, and culture, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD630FFEC1FC94D1EBDC6DBF97B2B8B13" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H7BDEE69413744C90A447573A8479E15E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teaching Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander History Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1F2B04C3E6054D21B78FB9529CA43AF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBFCE9E244BDD4627880F771570068CC4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has benefitted from the integral role Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders have played in our Nation’s history and contributions to the world.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EC81D4CC2BB4855950196369D6DE3D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Pacific Island Territories of Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and all of the Pacific Islands including Melanesia, Micronesia, and Polynesia have unique histories that are often overlooked in American history despite their immense contributions to our Nation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE46194EA93504671A5605243AFEB17E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The traditional American history curriculum for kindergarten through grade 12 continues to be taught from a Eurocentric point of view and excludes histories of racist immigration laws relevant to policies today.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF18F2339FAF545779353FB23C9AD86A9">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Social studies textbooks for kindergarten through grade 12 poorly represent Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders, overlook the diversity within those communities, and print images of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders in stereotypical roles.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60E25598E8474398AB1F9C0D4D50EFF2">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government, through support for educational activities of national museums established under Federal law, can assist teachers in efforts to incorporate historically accurate instruction on the comprehensive history of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders and assist students in their exploration of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history as an integral part of American history.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA8952F3CB5943248C3E9BFD3E9BF9EC" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The history of America’s system of immigration is rife with racism, embedded with goals of hiring workers to work for cheaper wages and labor in heinous working conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83943FE1C22A42E38EC40D5C286F4B2E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress has continuously passed anti-Asian laws as the result of the scapegoating of Asian immigrant laborers for economic downturns in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1484EDE868CE4591A72CC1ABC3297BCC">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>The history of South Asian Americans in the United States dates back to the late 1700s.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68C5993716F243D8A28770C0BADBDA0D">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>The history of Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders in what is now considered to be the United States predates the founding of our Nation.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H498F16EEB37943F2BA243E8F5D918570">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>In 1993, Congress passed a joint resolution that was signed into law formally apologizing for the role of the United States in the illegal overthrow of the Kingdom of Hawaii, which resulted in the suppression of the inherent sovereignty of the Native Hawaiian people.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45ACBED109EA4AF5A26B6DE29E139943"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Twelve thousand Chinese laborers worked in atrocious conditions to build the Transcontinental Railroad, many dying from harsh weather conditions and the dangers of handling explosives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9498D62714AB460183AB1AEAD8443587"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Page Act of 1875, the first restrictive immigration law in the United States, sought to prevent the entry of Asian women perceived as immoral or suspected of prostitution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86AC1E94E0BA478993AD361C798A37CF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>After the Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882 banned Chinese immigrants from immigrating to the United States, Japanese immigrants were hired. After the Japanese were banned from immigrating due to the Gentleman’s Agreement of 1907, which halted immigration from Japan, Filipino immigrants were hired under 3-year contracts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H930E1AB55E13476A9BB47EFD8FAB8A52"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Filipino farm workers helped found the farm worker labor movement in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C297B4B98BD4E84BF9075ACBE659C30"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Immigration Act of 1917 restricted immigration to the United States by barring immigration from the Asia-Pacific zone.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27364925C6C343108AB63D404E82EE30"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Immigration Act of 1924 set a national origin quota to deter immigration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H365D84E98B2B426F89F3B246B52DC030"><enum>(17)</enum><text>President Franklin D. Roosevelt’s Executive Order 9066 authorized the incarceration of more than 120,000 persons of Japanese ancestry, two-thirds of whom were American citizens, based solely on race.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B74C572F3394891983DE13E4A6FF406"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in 1954, the United States displaced more than 3,000,000 refugees from Cambodia, Laos, and Vietnam due to covert and overt United States military operations in Southeast Asia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA29263645AF4D30827A38A8D7ADCE7F"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration Act of 1965 made family unification and skills-based migration the bedrock principle of immigration to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCEA621357C5418688A776F527863528"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nuclear testing conducted by the United States on the Bikini and Enewetak Atoll of the Marshall Islands has made parts of the island nation uninhabitable and caused forced migration and health complications that still impact the community today.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96D2BC9D8A4F490093C4861898BCBC29"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States ratified a Compact of Free Association with the Federated States of Micronesia, Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau enabling citizens of these Pacific Island nations to legally migrate to the United States visa-free while the United States retains certain strategic military rights over their territorial waters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE66D503BC6D94223A7A51037186B3092"><enum>(22)</enum><text>In the aftermath of the Vietnam War, the Refugee Act of 1980 helped more than 500,000 Southeast Asians gain permanent resident status in the United States within the first decade of its passage.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8C895DB3C944C2D94036AACB2DF454D"><enum>(23)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Pacific Islander community represents the largest concentration of any ethnic group enlisted in the United States military, as well as representing the highest numbers of casualties in recent wars.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F844A2CB5064AD1BE49E33F97664542"> <enum>(24)</enum> <text>The <quote>model minority</quote> myth perpetuates the stigma of Asian Americans as perpetual foreigners, and such stereotypes are used to pit minority groups against one another.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H121B068ABEDB4A688C3563C3C2FA676A">
        <enum>(25)</enum>
 <text>The pattern of hate crimes and hate incidents directed at Asians and Asian Americans has repeated itself throughout history.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76C534B16A2C4B698551DF0676286EA4">
        <enum>(26)</enum>
 <text>Asian American and African American histories of fighting against oppression and racism are intertwined, from the Black Power Movement of the 1960s that birthed the Asian American Movement to civil rights protests in present day.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08E702B87C1945A3BEF68F4A78239783">
        <enum>(27)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders and their allies continue to fight discrimination, racial prejudice, hate crimes, scapegoating, structural racism, economic inequities, and benign and overt omission of the integral role they played in the development of this Nation.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB0EAC46D4FA34977941B7686746566BD"><enum>3.</enum><header>American history and civics education</header> 
<subsection id="HBB7A6B77F470429DA13F9B64EBCA353E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>Section 2231(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6661">20 U.S.C. 6661(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7898DB61B0C047CCA55C1C177807148F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74D7B174F2AC4ADCAA9E346B2868768E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB87985D7612547A2A3917E83784FEE24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08FB7B37B0834C50B8E53BFAC8EFB9AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history</quote> after <quote>traditional American history</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C88450AAD0A42F8884F1A8CECDF8D08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presidential and congressional academies for american history and civics</header><text>Section 2232 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6662">20 U.S.C. 6662</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB0044A042C444DAB2218C8CBC12723A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC763F136547E4272B46713CA6856F81E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H83E49950632A43729EF6362E05FEF5D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HB3099E0FE23A45648C27B807366E1D07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFD73A04F160C4847BA567DF99BADDAE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="H28D7C50F181D420FB50E18757131E5D8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>teachers of American history</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3410149347654B4EADF09A5ABA6246E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>subjects of American history</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H75641FAB99F04E99B43690ECBC00A258"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35F74400F7754ADBAC83CDD992358A47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2DCF809F13F40C3B278ABB416A8690F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>, and with the Smithsonian Institution’s Asian Pacific American Center to provide programs and resources for educators and students</quote> after <quote>National Parks</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBF8BCFB6D8041D1832FAAA175D053FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF40BEBAFB7CB40ADBE826CDE21571EA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>including Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H043DD15371544166A30220FF4C501C52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E66A432024A44ABBE8960EAC0A56853"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C100806D6D84FA4B87E0A1A0E2E7AB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National activities</header><text>Section 2233 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6663">20 U.S.C. 6663</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2FF83419B4FF4E8F854D78187FC038F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7359892FA87840C0B5A847CF0745BC1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H29C65B849A6F4F6C96798F03739B4FE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC8DA8A1083842DE838F57A207614A2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by inserting <quote>which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history,</quote> after <quote>American history,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H50AA390FE4F74989B4B210354A0499AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National assessment of educational progress</header><text>Section 303(b)(2)(D) of the National Assessment of Educational Progress Authorization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9622">20 U.S.C. 9622(b)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(which shall include Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history)</quote> after <quote>history</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

