<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25A00-5XN-T5-D7V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1678 IS: Securing America's Ports of Entry Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1678</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on
                    Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To increase the number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers and
            support staff and to require reports that identify staffing, infrastructure, and
 equipment needed to enhance security at ports of entry.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id1c62c810-e4bb-4159-8c26-6fb900758838" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing America's Ports of Entry Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idbb2dd530-4909-4334-ac00-75c691c37189" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel</header><subsection id="id4df99342-cbb5-45e6-8a44-8b7a61da4b15" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to appropriations, the Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall hire, train, and assign 1,000 new U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers above the current attrition level during every fiscal year until the total number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers equals and sustains the requirements identified each year in the Workload Staffing Model.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3f65242d-21c0-45f6-aab6-d76ffec7eb27" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support staff</header><text>The Commissioner is authorized to hire, train, and assign support staff, including technicians and Enterprise Services mission support, to perform non-law enforcement administrative functions to support the new U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers hired pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id03ba56a5-bd72-4d84-8e01-8a9d776e1b87" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Traffic forecasts</header><text>In calculating the number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers needed at each port of entry through the Workload Staffing Model, the Commissioner shall—</text><paragraph id="id6561590f-71da-45eb-bd66-d57534a8e93f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>rely on data collected regarding the inspections and other activities conducted at each such port of entry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e6c8c13-4def-431f-94b7-2b0113c06446" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider volume from seasonal surges, other projected changes in commercial and passenger volumes, the most current commercial forecasts, and other relevant information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06accbfb-7301-4d43-8b35-129f12dee29d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider historical volume and forecasts prior to the COVID–19 pandemic and the impact on international travel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96d258ede3e74d09bbbb520d1a143bb6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>incorporate personnel requirements for increasing the rate of outbound inspection operations at land ports of entry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0f98f687-ec14-4bc6-9ee9-7e9af48b2a5e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commissioner does not hire the 1,000 additional U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers authorized under subsection (a) during fiscal year 2026, or during any subsequent fiscal year in which the hiring requirements set forth in the Workload Staffing Model have not been achieved, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="id68cb8789-51e2-4b07-8bb3-64a6e9d00d21" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a review of U.S. Customs and Border Protection hiring practices to determine the reasons that such requirements were not achieved and other issues related to hiring by U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id57cbdf4ed84f4563a29a11c0cf09d2cc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes the results of the review conducted pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc5ea9ab5-9e00-4e31-9585-d5e10d31a4e6" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ports of entry infrastructure enhancement report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that identifies—</text><paragraph id="id00eab1e8-42fe-4cb1-9009-84aa1e9a113f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>infrastructure improvements at ports of entry that would enhance the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers to interdict opioids and other drugs that are being illegally transported into the United States, including a description of circumstances at specific ports of entry that prevent the deployment of technology used at other ports of entry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26515d44-556a-4b26-bd53-dbdc854a7418" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>detection equipment that would improve the ability of such officers to identify opioids, including precursors and derivatives, that are being illegally transported into the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ef973b4-a15e-4285-b169-ab685ccaf3a6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>safety equipment that would protect such officers from accidental exposure to such drugs or other dangers associated with the inspection of potential drug traffickers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id580c6e7e-9c35-403e-8c1f-7ad2981f90ae" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="idc08b7622-4f6a-41ef-b538-0a3f5179f16a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary duty assignments</header><paragraph id="ida10f9fc657b74fe98501e64c0bb1f0d2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2e0f279d7534d4db94d408a100ac769" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaef241214d2d4868b67d7f57c7ca867f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15853994fe4e4b2a8f27417c4e7914a2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d2939f7dc0844749b0f5aad513c92e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3308b540da0e42e490248155f3d89711" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c0b17f0e7114ef7969990f3b2dd6d7c" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</committee-name></text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51a82731-5bd0-4d25-8e49-e09061e388a5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quarterly report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall submit a quarterly report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes, with respect to the reporting period—</text><subparagraph id="id734b556e-f206-45b8-b4c1-70d887d5e56d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of temporary duty assignments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf71f17e7-beff-4bb4-8884-5a27f5525d37" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers required for each temporary duty assignment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65f968b3-f516-477f-a1c5-ff4fdaeff7f9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ports of entry from which such officers were reassigned;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79005b00-7847-4caf-ac55-66e12663ce7f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ports of entry to which such officers were reassigned;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cc3198b-2b91-4ccf-b52c-314b38e815c5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the ports of entry at which reimbursable service agreements have been entered into that may be affected by temporary duty assignments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd999a61c-565c-4ddc-8e55-23b4844fbcdb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the duration of each temporary duty assignment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c220c5b-2455-4d8a-8244-64d58d8e6fa3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the cost of each temporary duty assignment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7537987fce44afaa424a46345bbdde8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the extent to which the temporary duty assignments within the reporting period were in support of the other U.S. Customs and Border Protection activities or operations along the southern border of the United States, including the specific costs associated with such temporary duty assignments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7763217f-fad3-4e13-acea-882bc8ae4349" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 10 days before redeploying employees from 1 port of entry to another, absent emergency circumstances—</text><subparagraph id="id98564f3c-ea0b-4b80-949a-c25f430ebff4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commissioner shall notify the director of the port of entry from which employees will be reassigned of the intended redeployments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc921b5d0-adbf-4a5b-868f-bcb684458a1a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the port director shall notify impacted facilities (including airports, seaports, and land ports) of the intended redeployments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id383ef9dc-5a3f-466d-be2c-ef25536c7fa5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Staff briefing</header><text>The Commissioner shall brief all affected U.S. Customs and Border Protection employees regarding plans to mitigate vulnerabilities created by any planned staffing reductions at ports of entry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1e1fb87c-56d6-4b7f-a62a-8168a4282353" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports on U.S. Customs and Border Protection agreements</header><text>Section 907(a) of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4451">19 U.S.C. 4451(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idae34afe7-3401-4570-9004-afaaed428bfb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and an assessment</quote> and all that follows and inserting a period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idabf53c15-57aa-4d0a-b32b-628919286319" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (12) as paragraphs (5) through (13), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ab55c50-e1e9-49d5-93aa-3cea173e6e5f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96273a63-8113-4ca2-91cc-c4c3bddcf57c" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id26abe9fb-620c-4ae5-adfe-2c74c7014d63" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the factors that were considered before entering into the agreement, including an assessment of how the agreement provides economic benefits and security benefits (if applicable) at the port of entry to which the agreement relates.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f666bcf-bf77-4571-9240-12e6f8509cd5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as redesignated, by inserting <quote>, including the locations of such services and the total hours of reimbursable services under the agreement, if any</quote> after <quote>the report</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc9cb468f-8e94-46a0-a94c-b6956be3de08" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual workload staffing model report</header><text>As part of the Annual Report on Staffing required under section 411(g)(5)(A) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211(g)(5)(A)</external-xref>), the Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall include—</text><paragraph id="id80f8ed1d-cdb9-4b84-ba4f-58fb260b25ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information concerning the progress made toward meeting the U.S. Customs and Border Protection officer and support staff hiring targets set forth in section 2, while accounting for attrition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73724612-a143-494b-aedb-085b273bb325" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an update to the information provided in the Resource Optimization at the Ports of Entry report, which was submitted to Congress on September 12, 2017, pursuant to the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2017 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58001dad-0704-41af-ae2c-554a2eb0180f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of the information included in the reports required under subsection (a) and section 907(a) of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015, as amended by subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


