<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1EAB8A0AA10942AFB8BFC239D66B8FF1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1145 IH: Nobody Elected Elon Musk Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1145</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the special Government employee managing the Department of Government Efficiency shall be liable for any claims against the Federal Government related to Department activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0EB5518B3B7F49258EEE355D911BA898" style="OLC"><section id="H24069C9369794E0199AAAB4D029BA083" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nobody Elected Elon Musk Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H289DCCB0411F490FA8151117CE5EF952"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment of claims against Federal Government related to Department of Government Efficiency activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the special Government employee (as that term is defined in section 202(a) of title 18, United States Code) managing or otherwise in charge of the Department of Government Efficiency (or any successor thereof) within the Executive Office of the President shall be liable for any claim against the Federal Government relating to activities of the Department, including claims brought as a result of violation of Federal labor laws, data privacy laws, threats to national or domestic security, Federal appropriations laws, or any other statutes. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

