<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFFFF334C10B34628BD8360C153581628" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2931 IH: Save SBA from Sanctuary Cities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2931</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to relocate certain offices of the Small Business Administration in sanctuary jurisdictions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A0F2AD835FF49B39724968E07376D70" style="OLC"><section id="H96F8E55B699249FDB492EDDABA89F80C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save SBA from Sanctuary Cities Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H5D6176519ECA42319AB098E258ED0C92"><enum>2.</enum><header>Relocation of certain offices in sanctuary jurisdictions</header><subsection id="H149EBEBEF462419C81056B4525659AA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall relocate each covered office located in a sanctuary jurisdiction in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8CCBD76FF3F24690A8D9E9A4BEDE840C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a covered office only if, prior to ordering the relocation of such covered office under such subsection, the Administrator makes a determination that such covered office is located in a sanctuary jurisdiction and makes such determination publicly available.</text></subsection><subsection id="H20534EB08F114A259C16A3C5A78B942C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relocation requirement</header><text>When relocating a covered office under this section, the Administrator shall relocate such covered office to a location that—</text><paragraph id="H9E4C245D4C9A40A291C2A31DD1218AC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not in a sanctuary jurisdiction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5146C8F49E3D4053B7C0A1E83AB4986D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the State in which such covered office is located prior to such relocation is not a sanctuary jurisdiction, is in such State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H287AE8497B2B4B44933E3EB79A85672D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Suspension of operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period the Administrator is relocating a covered office under this section that is located in a State that is a sanctuary jurisdiction, such covered office shall cease the operations of such office in such State.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3EC63A344E784A119E97AF6C12A61D1B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relocation deadline</header><paragraph id="H3D4515DD135D42B8A9B31D230815899E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later 60 days after the Administrator makes publicly available a determination under subsection (b) with respect to a covered office, the Administrator shall relocate such covered office in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12400CA8F3114A0AB3AD9AB4F0ED9EEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><subparagraph id="H6C1BA98CC8DA434B9E6917405FE24824"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a covered office described in paragraph (1) is not relocated in accordance with subsection (c) prior to the expiration of the 60-day period applicable to such relocation under such paragraph—</text><clause id="H6C52A6BEB40C483883A51ED5E39B08A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later 5 days after the expiration of such 60-day period, the head of such covered office shall submit to the Administrator a written explanation of why such covered office was not relocated prior to expiration of such 60-day period; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A0917259F4740908648FD4352B46BC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the day after expiration of such 60-day period and ending on the date on which such covered office is relocated to a location that is not in a sanctuary jurisdiction—</text><subclause id="HC270E9686BA84899818A52386E67664F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such covered office shall cease operations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBDDDF091419A41C18493C2A45617E0A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each employee of the Administration whose duty station was at such covered office shall be assigned to a duty station at another covered office that is located in the same State and not in a sanctuary jurisdiction or, if no other covered office is located in the same State and not in a sanctuary jurisdiction, any other covered office that is not located in a sanctuary jurisdiction.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3486900231D045A1A40AE14ED41889EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Administrator shall immediately remove the head of a covered office required to submit a written explanation under subparagraph (A)(i) if—</text><clause id="HDA15B279013F4B158A621CA730AE7DEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such head does not submit such a written explanation in accordance with such subparagraph; or</text></clause><clause id="H19F3A787354C485DACD8430688202A09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator determines that the reasons provided in the written explanation submitted by such head under such subparagraph for the relocation of such covered office not being completed prior to the expiration of the 60-day period described in paragraph (1) with respect to such covered office are insufficient.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H775D2FBD3E374FA69BF0FB9111EBECF1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>New office limitation</header><text>The Administrator may not establish a covered office in sanctuary jurisdiction.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BA9C1262FD94550A01FA27A47A40559"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H14B2A7F0E6974D6E8ED9AFEBBE56F8D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B0D3044F804C878C8048D7C8A38E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA44F666B10C74F14BF37DD88FD77C3DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered office</header><text>The term <term>covered office</term> means a regional, district, or local office the Administration, other than the headquarters of the Administration, or any other component of the Administration fully funded by funds appropriated by Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCA6A1544DF74CC8A8045D64D889B3E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sanctuary jurisdiction</header><subparagraph id="HDEA12BF976E7416B9722488C1786AE02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subparagraph (B), the term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State that has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any government entity or official from—</text><clause id="H94F30B567BB84160B0594E268F82165E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sending, receiving, maintaining, or exchanging with any Federal, State, or local government entity information regarding the citizenship or immigration status (lawful or unlawful) of any individual; or</text></clause><clause id="HD01BE6B08AB847A398389B3C01A442CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>complying with a request lawfully made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer for, or notify about the release of, an individual.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8E8497F20C740A79A0912A00D221FC7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or political subdivision of a State shall not be deemed a sanctuary jurisdiction based solely on its having a policy whereby its officials will not share information regarding, or comply with a request made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer regarding, an individual who comes forward as a victim or a witness to a criminal offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

