<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0045CEAF40394ACA9C216DC9BD0342BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3262 IH: Nurses for Under-Resourced Schools Everywhere Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make demonstration grants to eligible local educational agencies or consortia of eligible local educational agencies for the purpose of increasing the numbers of school nurses in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8973F591D3714B318003800B87AB3405" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB56353CB0093436FBAC8D2E093581470" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nurses for Under-Resourced Schools Everywhere Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NURSE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB3DF59ACD24D40BE8A636B9A35051172"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H32E9E286DF634547946876B9504168F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Association of School Nurses identifies schools as primary locations to address student health issues. Since a school nurse is the health care provider that many students see on the most regular basis, it is the position of National Association of School Nurses that a professional registered school nurse be present in every school all day, every day.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0CB5C6D59754E07A05C95CC1C23C8B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The American Academy of Pediatrics has recognized the crucial role that school nurses play in children’s health and has called for having a full-time school nurse every day and in every school building.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD5D36D0E5B6849E7B4A856A1C3569B6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The school nurse functions as the leader and coordinator of the school health services team, including by carrying out chronic disease management and health promotion as well as facilitating access to a medical home for each child and supporting academic achievement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAD23891858649B59BB2BBD92E1EB6C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With over 25 percent of students managing chronic conditions such as asthma, diabetes, and epilepsy, the presence of a school nurse ensures these children can thrive in a safe and supportive environment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A5660D3E36441789D651797A3B75E83"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A 2024 Morning Consult public-opinion poll conducted to understand the public perception of school nursing found that 87 percent of adults in the United States have a favorable view of school nurses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26B3E10EEAB44991B6F1C4EF7089F36B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to data from the National Association of School Nurses, one-third of schools do not have a school nurse.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H854F6C86C85E4E54B1C60577C0186A87"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Federation of Teachers has called for a nurse in every school, as nurses are frontline workers that address an array of health needs and their presence in a school can help to improve student learning.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D2C951CEE0744BCA02B4910ABCC129E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">School nurses promote wellness and disease prevention to improve health outcomes for our Nation’s children. In addition, school nurses perform early intervention services such as periodic assessments for vision, hearing, and dental problems, in an effort to remove barriers to learning.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBA0867A1B52422FB00BCC412246AFFB"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Association of School Nurses has reported that medication administration to students is one of the most common health-related activities performed in school. As more chronically ill and medically unstable children enter the school system each year, the medical factors that promote and support their academic success increase, including the need for medications that enhance overall health or stabilize chronic conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20DC77F941A04D7BB90ADF2C4CEBD8C5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the American Academy of Pediatrics, students today face increased social and emotional issues, which enhance the need for preventive services and interventions for acute and chronic health issues. School nurses are actively engaged members of school-based mental health teams and spend nearly 32 percent of their time providing mental health services, including universal and targeted interventions, screenings to identify early warning signs and provide referrals to medical providers, and crisis planning.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEE219DE229448D0A516A43A9A1284CC"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Communicable and infectious diseases account for millions of school days lost each year. Data illustrates that when students have access to a registered nurse in school, immunization rates increase.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H90DD3E8F77A642AD9F576F2AC5F09F3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increasing the number of school nurses</header> <subsection id="HE508798E44564558969A8DDE5A1AE9E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H16D95A846ACC4BFF9D98B651F10BA925"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given to the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73AC4975AB0A41D2A987DBD8F8F2DD41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acuity</header><text>The term <term>acuity</term>, when used with respect to a level, means the level of a patient’s sickness, such as a chronic condition, which influences the need for nursing care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2AFE21F91854B04A46DEE0091378204"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0812F6CB7DC4FF3821D4A3E7F5F9C70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency in which not less than 20 percent of the children are eligible to participate in the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FD3402559D54733B3D86CB3209B1DC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium of local educational agencies described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9459C065DD37491D998E6AB450A5BF34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State educational agency in consortium with local educational agencies described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FFDAA6F4F074B1D850B1FC0AB2387D4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>high-need local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency described in paragraph (3)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB76706ACCBB148E3927BAA6774C86F51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that serves not fewer than 15,000 children who are eligible to participate in the program described in such paragraph; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE48FB58F28243CAAB668D33A105ABE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which not less than 40 percent of the children served by the agency are eligible to participate in the program described in such paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EE1C13098D84D9ABFF3C4E983FDA612"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nurse</header><text>The term <term>nurse</term> means a registered nurse, as defined under State law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D5F24FE46254B4ABE7B44F8FEA51816"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DC7EFE40D2C4148891738C5AAA2600D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Workload</header><text>The term <term>workload</term>, when used with respect to a nurse, means the amount of time the nurse takes to provide care and complete the other tasks for which the nurse is responsible.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF955EC6AA03E404888CE0FF7AF5EFCF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration grant program authorized</header> 
<paragraph id="HFCEBBD5C4084467D9CD958D9CA3C3341"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary of Education shall award demonstration grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to pay the Federal share of the costs of increasing the number of school nurses in the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entity, which may include hiring a school nurse to serve schools in multiple school districts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D56E7125D30451B8FE8FB356194866B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>S<enum-in-header>EA</enum-in-header>s</header><text>In the case of an eligible entity described in subsection (a)(3)(C) that receives a grant under paragraph (1), such entity shall use amounts received under the grant to award subgrants to the local educational agencies that are members of the entity, and reserve not more than 10 percent of such grant funds to support statewide activities to meet a variety of health needs, which may include hiring a nurse to provide training and technical assistance to schools statewide that meet the criteria established in subsection (d)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24E1742E8D324B628620743598B0B1AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header> 
<paragraph id="HD6BB97ACA706467C9FD3A16361C43F60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC90D155165F4430A4B71A83389EA698"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include information with respect to the current (as of the date of application) number of school nurses, student health acuity levels, and workload of school nurses in each of the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAC693ECBE9243D6B428D82D7AA8B85B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to each application submitted by an eligible entity that—</text> <paragraph id="H6348EF3C8F9B4ACB88791BB4F26DB44E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a high-need local educational agency, a consortium composed of high-need local education agencies, or a State educational agency in consortium with high-need local education agencies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H373622C5D2EB40CB8EFC8A4C39BA05C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates—</text> <subparagraph id="H65DE25474CDE43D1859FA175DB460CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the greatest need for new or additional nursing services among students in the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the agency or consortium; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FFD23DECABB4923A66A34B4621DA484"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the eligible entity does not have a school nurse in any of the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the local educational agency or the consortium-member local educational agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEC82C8FAC7644384B16C161652A4C3D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal share; non-Federal share</header> <paragraph id="H249C46E72AAC4B638FCCE46FBAD253B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of a grant under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEE35B057BFD8459687BD55148C0F0579"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not exceed 75 percent for each year of the grant; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAC805FC8658488A8482311E82862DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a multiyear grant, shall decrease for each succeeding year of the grant, in order to ensure the continuity of the increased hiring level of school nurses using State or local sources of funding following the conclusion of the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41F284C0A7244402BA8FFDCECEB1ECEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header><text>The non-Federal share of a grant under this section may be in cash or in-kind, and may be provided from State resources, local resources, contributions from private organizations, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A6C38055C0E40C2BE42D8F66A31727F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive or reduce the non-Federal share of an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section if the eligible entity demonstrates an economic hardship.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B0D990EE2A14461BA297A1FB8C747CD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which a grant is first made to a local educational agency under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the demonstration grant program carried out under this section, including an evaluation of—</text> <paragraph id="HF0A6AD2CE87946CB99CBCC1BD68A0165"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the program in increasing the number of school nurses; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D5C89DF36BA41B39808B26D7E5AF4AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact of any resulting enhanced health of students on learning, such as academic achievement, attendance, and classroom time.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8F83705EC298439CB3C34950BE42A290"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

