<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0495B7490BE4C8A8D11636DD7D4B7B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4230 IH: the Appropriations Compliance and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4230</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require certain executive branch employees to complete annual training on appropriations law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CA29A77791142A69EE5174F9293116A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBA25D8CE673F47FB87CBFBC362FCBEAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>the Appropriations Compliance and Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7DFDC43F63B84F73ADCDF8A3CC6DA507"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory appropriations law training</header> 
<subsection id="H39E6A241A2F247DEAD231844E0208D86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/41">Chapter 41</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/4105">section 4105</external-xref> the following new section (and conforming the table of contents at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HCD4EBF063361445F98E14CA0CA63B2F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H6EE38711DBE445F08176E08376CA316A"><enum>4106.</enum><header>Mandatory appropriations law training</header> <subsection id="HF569E219347F4237B773F2B79B8B0613"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training</header> <paragraph id="H9B8B858E46F84EE08FF5C5AD219DB236"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of each agency shall require any employee occupying a covered position at the agency to complete an annual training course on appropriations law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H167C9A452E5A4E979ACDC2232981459A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>With respect to any employee occupying a covered position on the date of the enactment of this section, such training shall be completed not later than 1 year after such date and annually thereafter. With respect to any individual appointed to a covered position after such date of enactment, such training shall be completed not later than 60 days after such appointment and annually thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF183E1FBDF8444EBA905C9AD256D5B08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Course requirements</header> <paragraph id="HCD122916C8D34BD4BEF6AD2413029EB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out the requirements of this section, the head of each agency shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC850824A911148EB8BB286DECD8D036D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the appropriations law training course offered by the Government Accountability Office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40A3F45499B74B18AB0F7CC16135690A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish an appropriations law training course within the agency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H630119C5FF6B4DA5A29D8BDED13F5241"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use an appropriations law training course offered by any other agency or contractor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA69E638CCAF74A8495F62E52FA921DE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the head of an agency establishes a training course under paragraph (1)(B) or uses a training course offered by an agency or contractor under paragraph (1)(C), such course may not be implemented or used without prior approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Comptroller General. Any such course shall at a minimum provide training on the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H029D74A63D364D83A2D33921AD4CA881"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The constitutional and statutory framework governing the obligation and expenditure of appropriated funds, including the role of Congress and its power of the purse, the role of the Office of Management and Budget, and the role of executive agencies in the appropriations process;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15930719B3C0402AA24A8AB5379409A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1301 of title 31 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Purpose Statute</quote>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D4F46B77B0342FBB191F94C3AFBDC70"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 1341, 1342, and 1511 through 1519 of title 31 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Antideficiency Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B52B5AC784742379A316DD62E58687F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bona fide needs rule, including section 1502 of title 31.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BACDEF6013C4F4EBB6E8390D6B4E7BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (parts A and B of title X of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AB92EEC717A42B4A804F6799A3773DE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of the direction provided in the current fiscal year’s appropriation Act and accompanying report or explanatory statement (if any) relevant to the employing agency.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0443E8AB31F49EB951F919A2BFB766D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>All possible penalties an employee may be subject to for violating appropriations law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD644D9BD013B4660BC5F5E7F7F981842"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other relevant statutory or regulatory provisions concerning the proper use of appropriated funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A7559D0BE514D86AE4CF5D66CBE9AD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall submit an annual report to the Office of Management and Budget listing each employee who has completed such training. The head shall make a permanent notation in the employee's official personnel record file each time such employee completes such training.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBD4FDA0ED6124917AD1D3571E93D5D97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header> <paragraph id="H52A4852344164A47BEAFC2320787E0B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an employee fails to complete the required training under this section, after 45 days of noncompliance—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBF53C9CBFA2C460C9CEA1864B55E639A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employee—</text> <clause id="HF0848CB6CE6D4B65972003F8E5478D72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be suspended from supervisory authority over budget execution or financial decision making, including obligation of funds; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC05A33335FA34379BF94CF8E0D7C08BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not, nowithstanding any other provision of law, receive any performance bonus or increase in basic rate of pay; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53E1E46720344E66BA6F1B0915180F83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the head of the agency shall place a notation of such noncompliance in the employee’s official personnel record file.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF84CD97A7034E2DB0BCBB98F843E1A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional penalties</header><text>If an employee remains in noncompliance after 60 days, such employee shall be suspended from accessing any agency information technology systems and computer networks, including email and financial management systems, until the employee completes the required training under this section.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H31C26BDC4DC74B36A8CEDE3AF35930D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency accountability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall be responsible for ensuring each employee occupying a covered position is in compliance with this section. Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the head of each agency shall publish, on the agency’s public website, statistics regarding compliance by such employees with the training required by this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7201F38674E14FFF8EEC7893F875AB21"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of covered position</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered position</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HDBA0607C78974900B1F5E9A50AD0D727"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any position within the executive branch of the Government that is classified at or above grade 11 of the General Schedule (or equivalent);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8C55CC922AD4254B0885CA485A8DCCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any political position (as that term is defined in section 4(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/136">Public Law 114–136</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32F1A0CF760C414F8680ED77242C1857"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any Senior Executive Service position (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE15C632DF8EC45259D2B78E0E449F5BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> 
<paragraph id="HE3979DBD963147338E13652CF0D638A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, in consultation with the Comptroller General, shall issue implementation guidance and maintain a list of approved providers of training required by section 4106 of title 5, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5571104329C48FE8A0CB6EEA931DAC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency compliance plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each executive branch agency shall submit to the Office of Management and Budget a plan for implementing the training required by such section 4106.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

