<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25260-CVG-42-G9K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 144 IS: Recognizing the heritage, culture, and contributions of Latinas in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 144</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the heritage, culture, and contributions of Latinas in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States celebrates National Women’s History Month every March to recognize and honor the achievements of women throughout the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 31,000,000 Latinas living in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, approximately 1 in 6 women in the United States is a Latina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas have helped shape the history of the United States since its inception;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas contribute to the society of the United States through working in many industries, including business, education, science and technology, medicine, engineering, mathematics, literature and the arts, the military, agriculture, hospitality, and public service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas come from diverse cultures across North America, Central America, South America, and the Caribbean, and Afro-Latinas face disparities in recognition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas are dedicated public servants, holding posts at the highest levels of the Federal Government, including the Supreme Court of the United States, cabinet-level positions, the Senate, and the House of Representatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 45,710 Latinas serving in the Armed Forces and the first Latina to become a general in the Marine Corps reached that rank in 2006;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas are breaking the glass ceiling in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, with the first Latina to travel into space doing so during a 9-day Space Shuttle Discovery mission in 1993;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas contributed $1,300,000,000 to the United States gross domestic product in 2021;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latina activists have led the fight for civil rights, including labor rights, LGBTQ rights, women’s rights, and racial equality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas, like Hollywood icon Raquel Welch, have created award-winning art;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas are recipients of Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, and Tony awards, including Rita Moreno, who earned all 4 awards between 1961 and 1977;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latina singers and songwriters, such as Selena, Celia Cruz, Shakira, Gloria Estefan, and Linda Ronstadt, have made lasting and significant contributions to music throughout the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas serve in the medical profession and the first female and first Hispanic Surgeon General was appointed in 1990;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas serve as journalists reporting vital news and information to the public;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas are world-class athletes, representing the United States in the Olympics and other international competitions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latinas working full-time, year-round are paid just 58 cents for every dollar paid to White, non-Hispanic men, and over a 40-year career, a Latina with a professional degree could lose more than $2,900,000 in wages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the face of societal obstacles, including unequal pay, disparities in education, health care needs, and civil rights struggles, Latinas continue to break through and thrive;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States should continue to invest in the future of Latinas to address the barriers they face; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by 2060, the population of Latinas in the United States is projected to be 48,834,000: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id873e745bbe2e4351906bff18566338d8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates and honors the successes of Latinas and the contributions they have made and continue to make to the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f2aa97304044faa9e02914ae2dbfa50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the changes that are still to be made to ensure that Latinas can realize their full potential as equal members of society. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

