<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H76FD40F17CD74B9189059AEEC33FAEC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5696 IH: Strengthening Tribal Real Estate Authority and Modernizing Land for Indigenous Nation Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve Tribal self-governance by streamlining appraisals for on-reservation trust land acquisitions by Indian Tribes with self-governance realty programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7DAA26F3F95E4BD69B683125E09A29CA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD96EDBE21FB34F9E989F3B6668F42AA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Tribal Real Estate Authority and Modernizing Land for Indigenous Nation Expansion Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STREAMLINE ACT</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFDB1DE54545A49BD88E8C4DCCFB50A3E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory revision to part 151 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations</header> <subsection id="H61C3BAC109F843EF9FE927AEE568122C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFF9F2689D83A46C0A0AA3C476F6F5DA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ISDEAA</header><text>The term <term>ISDEAA</term> means the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE51A4F18766148EFA36ED07EAF505E0C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Self-governance realty program</header><text>The term <term>self-governance realty program</term> means a program operated by an Indian Tribe under a compact or funding agreement pursuant to title I or title IV of ISDEAA that includes real estate services and valuation functions recognized by the Office of Tribal Sovereignty of the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15DEDB4B2CA6470E92EAD43F92D6C339"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning of the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1148C0C3640A4AD595E0572450C1CBCC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF04291D1319440F9E649544B9BEBF28" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribal appraisal</header><text>The term <term>Tribal appraisal</term> means a valuation prepared for an Indian Tribe by personnel or contractors operating under the Indian Tribe’s ISDEAA title I contract or ISDEAA title IV compact or funding agreement in conformance with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6D9A3174009470BA27C5E647248CBC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise part 151 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to land acquisitions), to provide that the Secretary shall accept a Tribal appraisal or valuation in lieu of a Federal appraisal with respect to an Indian Tribe if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEF3780B018C54E0491538A027BABE107"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Indian Tribe is party to an ISDEAA title I of contract or ISDEAA title IV compact or funding agreement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD04FAAF7A56842279AEBB56AE5B5C8E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Indian Tribe has assumed responsibility for realty or land management functions under such contract, compact, or funding agreement, including the authority to conduct appraisals or valuations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA7B55BFD306459E9665B21A97879FD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the land to be acquired is located within the exterior boundaries of the reservation of the Indian Tribe, or contiguous to lands held in trust for the Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4DDE054D7F9D447F8A5FCCE2C8C5BB49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appraisal acceptance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise part 151 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that, for acquisitions within a reservation or contiguous to trust lands of an Indian Tribe, the Secretary shall accept a Tribal appraisal in lieu of an appraisal procured or reviewed by the Appraisal and Valuation Services Office, if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4BE46A883472468BA31A33ECBCFDBD37" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Indian Tribe is party to an ISDEAA title I of contract or ISDEAA title IV compact or funding agreement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3346171746E347CE9E128F11C5D61775"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the contract, compact, or funding agreement includes real estate services and valuation authority; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96AF14B3CEF140BE8F536E9B91D1EC00"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appraisal conforms to the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCDC324920A654CFB951D23DB2687A18F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Indian Trust Asset Reform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section limits Indian Tribes from using the authorities available to Indian Tribes under section 305 of the Indian Trust Asset Reform Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5635">25 U.S.C. 5635</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD245B3BE9ED94A9083673338825DB474"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fiduciary and trust duty satisfied</header><text>Acceptance by the Secretary of a Tribal appraisal that meets the requirements of subsection (b) shall be deemed in compliance with the Secretary’s fiduciary and trust responsibility with respect to valuation for such acquisition.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0B6D3BB38DDD4002B4E191A14B1FE6B5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ministerial role</header><text>In the case of the acceptance of Tribal appraisal pursuant to subsection (b), the role of the Department of the Interior shall be limited to ministerial confirmation of receipt and recordation of the Tribal certification.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4034454AF2C84407971384F980C9D2E6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Policy manuals</header><text>The Secretary shall conform relevant Department of the Interior manuals, including the Appraisal and Valuation Services Office guidance and the Fee-to-Trust Handbook (52 IAM 12–H), to the requirements of subsection (b).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H83B77D691CB6450A871664499576F05E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendment to Indian Land Consolidation Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 219 of the Indian Land Consolidation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2218">25 U.S.C. 2218</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H95841DDE59864A5CBBF2C74576F3BE54" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HAD3EFB1070C2438FBA250E09DED56C33">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Tribal appraisals under self-Governance realty programs</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H13BFCA94EED143A3ABCF31B4894578BC"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>shall not require an appraisal prepared by or reviewed by the Department of the Interior for a conveyance or acquisition of trust or restricted land by an Indian tribe, if—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H85540BCA47D54C1CA47F4D6586E9AEB3" commented="no">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the tribe is a party to a self-governance compact or contract under title I or title IV of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAD5D33FA67CC453284038510EA082F17">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the tribe has assumed responsibility for realty or land management functions under such compact or contract, including the authority to conduct appraisals or valuations;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5A070A2EBCEF414F951642CFC1075DFC">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the land is located within the exterior boundaries of the tribe’s reservation, or contiguous to lands already held in trust for the tribe; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H62D6A3EA37F746F69A08EC9DC616E3B4">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appraisal conforms to Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6B9F51B3FC214D39AA08EDCFA3DF016E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>if the criteria described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) are met, shall accept appraisals or valuations conducted under the tribe’s compacted program as sufficient to establish fair market value.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H7849008F8EE04AEE90C7218EBEA387E1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transparency and evaluation</header> 
<subsection id="H26EA4C7D5C9D4D1E92ADA6E3BC275FEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The Secretary shall track and publish processing times for fee-to-trust acquisitions using Tribal appraisals versus Department of the Interior appraisals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCFF3C9CC4A844D669973CC7075DDF84B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall evaluate the implementation of this Act and any effects on processing time, quality, and litigation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90E8B8CEA5CA4563B0B25DB9ED50614A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on NEPA or title review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters requirements for environmental compliance, title evidence, or notice under part 151 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

