<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25122-792-5Y-XDW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S863 IS: Genomic Data Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide consumers with the right to delete their genomic data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Genomic Data Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac3f969cce144f9e99d592fcbfb8dfec"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer rights regarding privacy of genomic data</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id947cfa5d5cdf4f7daf5fae08a2bfa421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaed5b7879784377849625daaa68d1db"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consumer controls</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4e2595911af42d79c43e2042f67f71e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall provide a simple and effective mechanism to allow a consumer to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7b48e395cfe4f66a888424ddfc7da06"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access the genomic data of the consumer; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac1e41e5cfe04441be7b67539ff4181c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (4)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb76deb49f1b4c7f8dd61a2ecebac4ed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">delete the account of the consumer, including any genomic data associated with such account; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa1e5b5c741742d2a6b0765887fc2145"><enum>(II)</enum><text>request the destruction of any biological sample of the consumer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56e7ec7dbdeb4f1d90a95824b8d8a370"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required mechanism</header><text>The direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall make available to a consumer the mechanism described in subparagraph (A) through the primary means by which the company communicates with the consumer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcabcd83bf762412fb28e3680b1de58af"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2a472c56031497f97db9f486c06c372"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consumer controls and use of deidentified genomic data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall make available, in a clear and conspicuous, not misleading, and easy-to-read manner a notice that—</text><clause id="idadba552323d64a54a338c58eb452b507"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides a detailed and accurate representation of the rights set forth in clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="id9fbbf775ad0e4305b736597f01fea657"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>discloses that the deidentified genomic data of a consumer may be shared or disclosed to conduct medical or scientific research, consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05745436c9334e41b952bc9336cc0fa9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purchase of company</header><text>In the event that a direct-to-consumer genomic testing company is purchased or otherwise acquired by another entity, the direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall send to each consumer, not fewer than 30 days prior to the date on which the purchase or acquisition is complete, a notice that includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc4e56944d4b486a8c9e937dbb270a0a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the identity of the entity purchasing or otherwise acquiring the company; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dea06b1ed234747b36440f0f0935a4d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a detailed and accurate representation of the how a consumer can exercise the rights set forth in clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) under the new ownership.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7abeeb4e3d0474fa3e093ebd5b9cb34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Processing of deletion or destruction requests</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cea383795d247059b1c614d4103064c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a consumer's request to delete the genomic data or to destroy the biological sample of the consumer, a direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id896f9bbb3e52464088b49ba75304eb28"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fulfill such request not later than 30 days after the date on which the consumer makes such request; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5864785eb05d439889e7fd2b620cef3e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the consumer of such deletion or destruction not later than 30 days after the deletion or destruction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98deca5212614cf6a1d29c232e79d4a5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Outstanding requests during purchase of company</header><text>In the event that a direct-to-consumer genomic testing company is purchased or otherwise acquired by another entity while a consumer's request to delete the genomic data or to destroy the biological sample of the consumer is outstanding—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36172fd3db394cfc8182cf685a8f7814"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity that is purchasing or otherwise acquiring the company shall comply with the requirements described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf93e5e056b4445eaf9814e51bfecf00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the 30-day period to fulfill such request shall begin on the date on which the consumer makes such request to the direct-to-consumer genomic testing company.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc67131a852ce4c88a0cd0c0e28196c87"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>A direct-to-consumer genomic testing company shall not permit a consumer to exercise a right described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) if the company determines that the exercise of the right would require the deletion of information—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id831d0f5d4b7645909152184fe3955b3f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to a warrant, lawfully executed subpoena, or other court order; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcaff64f901984bb6a4a8103ead7fe29f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the company is required to retain in order to comply with any other applicable legal or regulatory requirement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb140cee3dd0e4994b62b4f123445142f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="id7848db482e4b4d5298a9352e33a968d4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35e52655e72e4a2587758fb49cdd16c1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="idca3f580a1dbc447f8feca80a1d3848e1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id439b14dc5ab64d76a2190bd633871f4b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13985461b0864027a331eea6ed08ba44"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dac2b1b6a45400e909d77f5aa2b5333"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission may promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id951aca043a764e8e88e5bca5cab377a0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id41d7d0cb62814be7acdabc300a9456e8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological sample</header><text>The term <term>biological sample</term> means any material part of the human, discharge therefrom, or derivative thereof, such as tissue, blood, urine, or saliva, known to contain deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided021ffed84243a295a23a946b0ec7c8"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7a87dab2899416180809b2ea3d59591"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consumer</header><text>The term <term>consumer</term> means an individual who provides a biological sample to a direct-to-consumer genomic testing company.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22e63903df154ea587d9f4b5258cedf8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deidentified genomic data</header><text>The term <term>deidentified genomic data</term> means data that cannot be used to infer information about, or otherwise be linked to, a particular individual, provided that the business that possesses the information does all of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id414dc2f9a12047638dfad3f7cc00a738"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Takes reasonable measures to ensure that the information cannot be associated with a particular individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4575359fa714df0896a2a3cbd526b5e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Publicly commits to maintain and use the information only in deidentified form and not to attempt to reidentify the information, except that the business may attempt to reidentify the information solely for the purpose of determining whether its deidentification processes satisfy the requirements of this subparagraph, provided that the business does not use or disclose any information reidentified in this process and destroys the reidentified information upon completion of that assessment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee73d77b6397419dbc3908ceb8abf223"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Contractually obligates any recipients of the information to take reasonable measures to ensure that the information cannot be associated with a particular individual and to commit to maintaining and using the information only in deidentified form and not to reidentify the information. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id119407cb2ae348d9bcaf78f4128234eb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Direct-to-consumer genomic testing company</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id086fd86573a0459898d93d027769e43f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>direct-to-consumer genomic testing company</term> means a person that does any of the following:</text><clause id="idf0962a80972043c6a55ad692fdc3a180"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Manufactures or develops genomic testing products or services for sale directly to consumers.</text></clause><clause id="id547c44a53eed44d9bcc48f5ba51c7b91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Analyzes or interprets genomic data obtained from a consumer.</text></clause><clause id="idc1fdf5be09b946128841df79459d3bd6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Collects, uses, maintains, or discloses genomic data collected or derived from a direct-to-consumer genomic testing product or service.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6de31f2e9aa49d58507abc8fc918b4c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Purchases or acquires genomic data from a direct-to-consumer genomic testing company.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id332d8738b1c548e6b17e90c4ef9afca6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion for health care professionals</header><text>The term <term>direct-to-consumer genomic testing company</term> shall not include a health care professional (as defined in section 225 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/234">42 U.S.C. 234</external-xref>)) that performs an action described in subparagraph (A) for purposes of diagnosis or treatment of a medical condition. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8324cf0998c4364a33b0a078729b0ec"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Genomic data</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5648dd005b504b9bafc638c463d52c3a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>genomic data</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d104a230215493aa29c829c4356fa4a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any data, regardless of its format or whether the data has been deidentified, that results from the analysis of a biological sample from a consumer and concerns genomic material; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2dd48808fcb42f99c31e3742d8df624"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce693cad7e834265841d909f5b008023"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deoxyribonucleic acids (DNA), ribonucleic acids (RNA), genes, chromosomes, alleles, genomes, alterations or modifications to DNA or RNA, and single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c7dc0aea9c645f39b3146cba88ebe00"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uninterpreted data that results from the analysis of the biological sample; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf68b37e65e914caa83e7e29bf09f17f3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any information extrapolated, derived, or inferred therefrom.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cabf5292c6d4defbfb1139630b44475"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion of deidentified genomic data</header><text>The term <term>genomic data</term> shall not include the deidentified genomic data of a consumer to the extent that such data is used to conduct medical or scientific research, consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id367d888f8403492690ca0b8007f9c9e0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Genomic testing product or service</header><text>The term <term>genomic testing product or service</term> means any testing product or service that analyzes or interprets the genomic data or biological sample of a consumer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70d0d6b33fff48308d3b6ab76530219c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to Federal and State laws</header><paragraph id="id2bdab48c39264c55a92232d653d7515c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal law preservation</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to limit any other provision of Federal law, except as specifically provided in this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96af7849835d41ff9bc2c52c6d67dbde"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law preservation</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to preempt, displace, or supplant any State law, except to the extent that a provision of State law conflicts with a provision of this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, and then only to the extent of the conflict.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

