<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25266-9C9-HN-XR9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S754 IS: Farm and Food Cybersecurity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to periodically assess cybersecurity threats to, and vulnerabilities in, the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector and to provide recommendations to enhance their security and resilience, to require the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct an annual cross-sector simulation exercise relating to a food-related emergency or disruption, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H851C8EC4057C4C89926EB2832F29793D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HCFB1C4BEFD49469D8BD9C5DA7A18737E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farm and Food Cybersecurity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0B6107E64D9D4402A6E26DABBDBE9767"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE77A55B79C504CEE9431D11AD435CFC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector</header><text>The term <term>agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H5FC91862C3EF474497D93A6885C893D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity relating to the production, processing, distribution, storage, transportation, consumption, or disposal of agricultural or food products; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2E4272914814B67A4581CF01F6CB88B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any entity involved in an activity described in subparagraph (A), including a farmer, rancher, processor, manufacturer, distributor, retailer, consumer, and regulator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H257E949C16A44B729796C79DC781ACF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cybersecurity threat; defensive measure; incident; security vulnerability</header><text>The terms <term>cybersecurity threat</term>, <term>defensive measure</term>, <term>incident</term>, and <term>security vulnerability</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2200 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/650">6 U.S.C. 650</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4BFDCD6A1D34AF486A2CD371E3AB494"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2B970A222654FFBB05DCC223B59F88E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sector-specific <enum-in-header>ISAC</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <term>sector-specific ISAC</term> means the Food and Agriculture-Information Sharing and Analysis Center.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H652849C2479245FD83CEB2982F546791"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessment of cybersecurity threats and security vulnerabilities in the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector</header><subsection id="HF8CF99977FDC40038A0CAAA288425696"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Risk assessment</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall conduct a risk assessment, on a biennial basis, on the cybersecurity threats to, and security vulnerabilities in, the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector, including— </text><paragraph id="H02BAF590A5BB4C3E827778B3112C7A8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the nature and extent of cyberattacks and incidents that affect the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63D0A25246D4DF199A47A52AA2FA12F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential impacts of a cyberattack or incident on the safety, security, and availability of food products, as well as on the economy, public health, and national security of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E49CE77C9F4A0B8342DE372FA17061"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the current capability and readiness of the Federal Government, State and local governments, and private sector entities to prevent, detect, mitigate, respond to, and recover from cyberattacks and incidents described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A20232EE48A403DB6A2E7D61935F986"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the existing policies, standards, guidelines, best practices, and initiatives applicable to the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector to enhance defensive measures in that sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B46871BED7F4F0FB46B3B0626E7D9BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the gaps, challenges, barriers, or opportunities for improving defensive measures in the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF0F8193DA34AF6BC28F258C4410161"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for Federal legislative or administrative actions to address the cybersecurity threats to, and security vulnerabilities in, the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector, including intrusive, duplicative, or conflicting regulatory requirements that may divert attention and resources from operational risk management to a compliance regime that impedes security efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF0B4A29566624A26A864AE4263991294"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private sector participation</header><text>In conducting a risk assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with appropriate entities in the private sector, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H688A96B493534CE9A568B0FB76A55137"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sector-specific ISAC; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF8E988D4D5C5427E81755197609B9967"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate sector coordinating council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDD1A559CD104C1D837A24B3696E6FCB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report on each risk assessment conducted under subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph id="H9F155C41687742C69B5A918BF3A0F383"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3AD716C944C4B0287DBFB2824970A21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H687DC205A2E4448B88558BD9EC44C201"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H807130E87FEC4A2E9E0BDF6C0FD5898E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H15CA40FBAC0D4DD09267DF0C24097EEF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Food security and cyber resilience simulation exercise</header><subsection id="HA4977EA3EB50455EA55EE1B947BAE8C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct, over a 5-year period, an annual cross-sector crisis simulation exercise relating to a food-related emergency or disruption (referred to in this section as an <quote>exercise</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA20E0F3D1CB14EA584E49B8BA19FE2F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of each exercise are—</text><paragraph id="H66E7881FB3A447FF922446D6AB8C930B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assess the preparedness and response capabilities of Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments and private sector entities in the event of a food-related emergency or disruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6389637252884C9F846D7B3BC7070A3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify and address gaps and vulnerabilities in the food supply chain and critical infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1883687A0F1E4989BACC9CC465BDBEEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enhance coordination and information sharing among stakeholders involved in food production, processing, distribution, and consumption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D10683D65D84E73A37A6F0A9D0E34AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of existing policies, programs, and resources relating to food security and resilience;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11E729F0EFBB4F95B6795E352A71540F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to develop and disseminate best practices and recommendations for improving food security and resilience; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A46328BA9E84D03B82F6F23CEF9DC33"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to identify key stakeholders and categories that were missing from the exercise to ensure the inclusion of those stakeholders and categories in future exercises.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB231A93E3D8412A93C9D9BB3AFB50DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Design</header><text>Each exercise shall—</text><paragraph id="H8A2E6069586047C5851168192DBCF808"><enum>(1)</enum><text>involve a realistic and plausible scenario that simulates a food-related emergency or disruption affecting multiple sectors and jurisdictions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E0D290B2CFE45D7B0345FCB8294D65F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate input from experts and stakeholders from various disciplines and sectors, including agriculture, public health, nutrition, emergency management, transportation, energy, water, communications, related equipment suppliers and manufacturers, and cybersecurity, including related academia and private sector information security researchers and practitioners, including the sector-specific ISAC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD300920FAFB946E3BEB55F3ACEEA9822"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use a variety of methods and tools, such as tabletop exercises, workshops, seminars, games, drills, or full-scale exercises; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7EDAA5AC5A4A53B63D1A158206C3C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include participants from Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments and private sector entities, including the sector-specific ISAC and appropriate sector coordinating councils, that have roles and responsibilities relating to food security and resilience.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB2A456F6B7849638D7D8D81656DFE05"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private sector participation</header><text>In conducting an exercise, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate entities in the private sector, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H58017AACCE324739AD448AD4C01929FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sector-specific ISAC; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDE1BDBD9549642059F1DFD024F74E580"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate sector coordinating councils.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0654C5AA75AA4BDC8716411846ACC068"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Feedback; report</header><text>After each exercise, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of the Federal agencies described in subsection (a), shall—</text><paragraph id="H76E7EC5DC5FE4CC6B1872FCB9E6AD800"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide feedback to, and an evaluation of, the participants in that exercise on their performance and outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4BD3841D5154977AAA7EAA2B791ABAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>produce, and submit to Congress, a report that summarizes, with respect to that exercise, the findings of that exercise, lessons learned from that exercise, and recommendations to enhance the cybersecurity and resilience of the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8FE46B80D144ABAA436B4B49B78C723"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

