<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD5E4BD291FE044A8939B4CB40EC3261A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1065 IH: Protect Our Letter Carriers Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1065</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate the implementation of security measures undertaken by the United States Postal Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0CD008EE69134AE09A2A623A38B4C7E4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3D73EE32FFAC47C681F420F2152BADDF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Our Letter Carriers Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBBD01D17BC124AFC82049976A6D41B4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H400341DD4E6F45808E70ADA13388F047"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States Postal Service letter carriers must be protected from acts of violence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0501426E1834FBF87B6D27C21195730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Attorney General should vigorously prosecute any case of assault against a postal employee.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H3AC4A9D95E6E4E1BADF6D3DCAEC56B03"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funds to upgrade collection boxes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,400,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to the United States Postal Service to carry out, as determined by the United States Postal Service—</text> <paragraph id="H34F37CD9E49440DEAB6F8AFA5B71BF86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the installation of high security collection boxes; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FDF58BB14D949F9954F40019DB85F5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the replacement of older versions of the universal mailbox key, also known as the arrow key, with electronic versions.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC505C40CA75B49A6804526563384A68D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordination of prosecution of offenses against the United States Postal Service</header> <subsection id="H17EFE518562B41EF8941896E589EDE70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 542 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H0D6D44C84AF241FDAB66AC2782AF53A3" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HD91B43BC7ACF4F25BC3E7DA16CB1DA81"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall, in consultation with the United States attorney for the district, appoint in each judicial district an assistant United States attorney with principal responsibility in the district to coordinate and supervise the investigation and prosecution of alleged offenses committed—</text> <paragraph id="H6D8E3969F3FD45878BCFD83EE9DD571F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in violation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 18;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3C4F6B346B4464BB50B1EE3502D0AFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in violation of sections 2115, 2116, or 2117 of title 18; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H162D734477434E0392028CC65A2A34C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>against a carrier or person entrusted with the mail and having custody thereof, in violation of section 111 of title 18.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H870913FB3D8F413BAE3820F806B6CDEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for compliance</header><text>The Attorney General shall comply with section 542(c) of title 28, United States Code, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4568B4BB44B5426AA83039E82FE22618"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sentencing guidelines with respect to robbery against a postal employee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than May 1 following the first year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Sentencing Commission shall amend the sentencing guidelines and policy statements promulgated under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, to provide that the assault or robbery of a postal employee, including conduct committed during the immediate flight after the commission of such an assault or robbery if the conduct creates a substantial risk of serious bodily injury, shall be treated in the same manner as the assault of a law enforcement officer.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

