<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBA9B1D65A9544EA3923959A51C4D09D0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5317 IH: Community Bank Deposit Access Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to ensure that certain custodial deposits of well capitalized insured depository institutions are not considered to be funds obtained by or through deposit brokers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H19475E31A14F4B33AB97BBB9C8D8B67D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H619683F2B2924845A68E1D90C781B630" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Bank Deposit Access Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBA6837912BBA49318B1EEC73D3B3C1A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limited exception for custodial deposits</header> <subsection id="HF9F33EB4FB284CD18524C54A1684E33B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 29 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831f">12 U.S.C. 1831f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46A43B3267CC4FB0AAD9ADF2E691E2C8"> 
<subsection id="HCF496311822A483BB561C772CB5E2A99"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Limited exception for custodial deposits</header> 
<paragraph id="H6484559C57D14FA0AA7318A609E22016"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Custodial deposits of an eligible institution shall not be considered to be funds obtained, directly or indirectly, by or through a deposit broker to the extent that the total amount of such custodial deposits does not exceed an amount equal to 20 percent of the total liabilities of the eligible institution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECE8F51B51B345108ACAC88DD1CECF7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBFDB3FDD5E4B429CB843C1FA1E2A5BAD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Custodial deposit</header><text>The term <term>custodial deposit</term> means a deposit that would otherwise be considered to be obtained, directly or indirectly, by or through a deposit broker, if the deposit is deposited at 1 or more insured depository institutions, for the purpose of providing or maintaining deposit insurance for the benefit of a third party, by or through any of the following, each acting in a formal custodial or fiduciary capacity for the benefit of a third party:</text> <clause id="HB1C030432909410C834FAA84A11D57D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An insured depository institution serving as agent, trustee, or custodian.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H17D232739F114C1197366D0882728127"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A trust entity controlled by an insured depository institution serving as agent, trustee, or custodian.</text></clause> <clause id="HD49BEB3D4C464B1CB56B631208CCC070"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A State-chartered trust company serving as agent, trustee, or custodian.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE074E189D75B44A3A1A8C5D6672FFE4D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A plan administrator or investment advisor, acting in a formal custodial or fiduciary capacity for the benefit of a plan, as defined in section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA3F3EA32BB64CFFB2FECE6B118E01F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an insured depository institution that accepts custodial deposits, that were not deposited at the insured depository institution in return for fees paid by the insured depository institution pursuant to an agreement with a third party, if the insured depository institution—</text> 
<clause id="H7311BD546BBB4EFFBB72197E932CFEDF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has less than $10,000,000,000 in total assets as reported on the consolidated report of condition and income as reported quarterly to the appropriate Federal banking agency;</text> </clause> <clause id="H6A325CD53B674D11A0712EE8925EE4D9"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDD4B5CFC35214FAEA5325FF362987992"><enum>(I)</enum><text>when most recently examined under section 10(d) was found to have a composite condition of outstanding or good; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3AC6E0E4A2504347A0F3CF4E894B5B6E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is well capitalized; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HAD666C45F35649A2B1A2C9BE690DEEE3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has obtained a waiver pursuant to subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41E3580337AA4D049EE56A1C535BCAD7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Plan administrator</header><text>The term <term>plan administrator</term> has the meaning given the term <term>administrator</term> in section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FA43B0764AF47B99172333496AD5A29"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Well capitalized</header><text>The term <term>well capitalized</term> has the meaning given the term in section 38(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H768DEE0A8FD34594B2E42C950CF1215E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interest rate restriction</header><text>Section 29 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831f">12 U.S.C. 1831f</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90AE976CA19146DB9B0CD1675744089A"> <subsection id="HE6684221126845C59423E96AC420F5AA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restriction on interest rate paid</header> <paragraph id="HDA91F9B4CE4D4530B2B211C03FAAC6A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H314C65844BE0442DB4F6AAA0829D2599"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms <term>custodial deposit</term>, <term>eligible institution</term>, and <term>well capitalized</term> have the meanings given those terms in subsection (j); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1258F8A09454DAD80402AFCABABC70D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>covered insured depository institution</term> means an insured depository institution that—</text> 
<clause id="H5B2A73FDC21F4C66A93816AE03D3D1A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under subsection (c) or (d), accepts funds obtained, directly or indirectly, by or through a deposit broker; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA2B2E8102779411A9641E6A23045D426"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>while acting as an eligible institution under subsection (j), accepts custodial deposits while not well capitalized.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H369820DBE9004ADB9C253A06EE28C63B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A covered insured depository institution may not pay a rate of interest on funds that, under subsection (c) or (d), are obtained, directly or indirectly, by or through a deposit broker or on custodial deposits that are accepted while not well capitalized that, at the time the funds or custodial deposits are accepted, significantly exceeds the limit set forth in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EAAF7F401974DF8942E048E24F6564C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit on interest rates</header><text>The limit on the rate of interest referred to in paragraph (2) shall be not greater than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F788EC8D8D240ED958C6531D9E43286"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate paid on deposits of similar maturity in the normal market area of the covered insured depository institution for deposits accepted in the normal market area of the covered insured depository institution; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BB1A0AEB38A4C05AD7A86CD9E29F17A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the national rate paid on deposits of comparable maturity, as established by the Corporation, for deposits accepted outside the normal market area of the covered insured depository institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

