<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC0593C79B6544BC93FD72A88F97F0D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5600 IH: Streamlining Powerlines Essential to Electric Demand and Reliability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5600</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act to streamline the siting of certain transmission facilities in the national interest.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50FDA1D3F2DB4B1882804171914A90B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3310F090846E41C787784AEB8B684941" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Powerlines Essential to Electric Demand and Reliability Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPEED and Reliability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0AB1D91EBEB54B74AF1035D89A815810" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transmission permitting</header> <subsection id="H9BDA4873FF47470ABFF7C641828A0E50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 216 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3D6A1ABF08614259B6DEB1B16BE21BF8" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HCCB885472FFE4284A1B84CFE2E3F751C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7C66C9CE42624AEDB41B5557EFF303CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89F5D84B863B4531A7B4032B2AFF18EC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ERO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ERO</term> has the meaning given such term in section 215(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E65AD6814D94479A30034A5A671C6C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Improved reliability</header><text>The term <term>improved reliability</term> means that, on balance, considering each of the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (D), reliability is improved in a material manner that benefits customers through at least one of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB3304666C6D54982A598D41ADBF4CE52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Facilitating compliance with a mandatory standard for reliability approved by the Commission under section 215.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B231AB68F834088AF8C39811066A4CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A reduction in expected unserved energy, loss of load hours, or loss of load probability (as defined by the ERO).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29A8E675BDA4492E8A4844CB58A9E92C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Facilitating compliance with a tariff requirement or process for resource adequacy on file with the Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEEE007EF53E43F29D67AFEF1A56C6DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other similar material improvement, including a reduction in correlated outage risk, such as achieved through increased geographic or resource diversification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF69D7F97E3284C79836853C94914F085"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Landowner input</header><text>The term <term>landowner input</term> means input received—</text> <subparagraph id="H8FEB94EA8DC94F1D902869C67BDFCF2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the Commission;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CE2B3C27E9F45929212DA80D2C333A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from affected landowners, such as farmers and ranchers, in the path of the proposed construction or modification of an electric transmission facility; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H369BD7D582344A36AB449771E5A5C5A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pursuant to notification provided to, and consultation with, those affected landowners, farmers, and ranchers by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D8B3365F2CE448EB11BB87D1FC4DEA7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBFA9E88BBAFA470186AB00E25D208A94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction permit</header><text>Section 216(b) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H561BF206085E4CF6ADAB9402F6F36945"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Except</quote> and all that follows through <quote>finds that</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsections (d)(1) and (i), the Commission shall, after notice and an opportunity for hearing, including a public comment period of at least 60 days, issue one or more permits for the construction or modification of electric transmission facilities necessary in the national interest if the Commission finds that</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E1070D595244ABE851725ABED886C22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B10329242764C788E7EE61820CF3EC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by inserting <quote>or modification</quote> after <quote>siting</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA7276C5308347F29B82F5D7BF51B07A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<clause id="H9952E8C1E2A64C7E88190DB273DBD36C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>or modification</quote> after <quote>siting</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7E5B788641984B88BED8C2F014C52D8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>the later of</quote> in the matter preceding subclause (I) and all that follows through the semicolon at the end of subclause (II) and inserting <quote>the date on which the application was filed with the State commission or other entity;</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H119C884FBEA34C77B4001A2BD2496F72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) through (6) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H43C88B89FECA453FB5E9913FDF07E0AA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HDB6F5949FE944AB8A1C07C30BCB2AC22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the proposed facilities will be used for the transmission of electric energy in interstate (including transmission from the outer Continental Shelf to a State) or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0703D88345E5469FB846079353A03CDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the proposed construction or modification is consistent with the public interest;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FB1B726171F461CB5071D1C04ADAEFC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the proposed construction or modification will significantly reduce transmission congestion in interstate commerce, protect or benefit consumers, and provide improved reliability;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8690EA53F3B84D70850F64D4E23453AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the proposed construction or modification is consistent with sound national energy policy and will enhance energy independence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB221727F43AC4AAA872A833FA92AEFEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the electric transmission facilities are capable of transmitting electric energy at a voltage of not less than 100 kilovolts or, in the case of facilities that include advanced transmission conductors (including superconductors), as defined by the Commission, voltages determined to be appropriate by the Commission; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54A8F0F429A14E0C89EAA4E960F37DEA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the proposed modification (including reconductoring) will maximize, to the extent reasonable and economical, the transmission capabilities of existing towers, structures, or rights-of-way.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC648AFF14884A1E9D449B7A691874F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State siting and consultation</header><text>Section 216 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7D57068FD62348D4A70F8B77C757855E" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HDF357D037B1845FCB05A2369511D9D50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State siting and consultation</header> 
<paragraph id="H1793F411141847649833ECC12E9FF58D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preservation of state siting authority</header><text>The Commission shall have no authority to issue a permit under subsection (b) for the construction or modification of an electric transmission facility within a State except as provided in paragraph (1) of that subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA06E47A2C4AA44CEB9486B1919B5E694"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In any proceeding before the Commission under subsection (b), the Commission shall afford each State in which a transmission facility covered by the permit is or will be located, each affected Federal agency and Indian Tribe, private property owners, and other interested persons, a reasonable opportunity to present their views and recommendations with respect to the need for and impact of a facility covered by the permit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AB744E036FD45978D0388699DC42524"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Landowner input</header><text>In authorizing the construction or modification of an electric transmission facility under subsection (b), the Commission shall take into account landowner input.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H97275B4C48DC43C0982C5A67412B797C"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Rights-of-Way</header> <text>Section 216(e)(3) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p(e)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>shall conform</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>shall be in accordance with rule 71.1 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H84AE93C9538E4F2389A68048ACA570FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cost allocation</header> 
<paragraph id="H1C3593C15F98450D8428CDE01CE4941F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 216 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAAEBFD516D3A4071B2BF489796B04D9C" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H582E9EF279E744DD98194C8AE5FA7AD8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cost allocation</header> <paragraph id="H6903C8E480E6477EA31EE4E76DCB91D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transmission tariffs</header><text>For the purposes of this section, any transmitting utility that owns, controls, or operates electric transmission facilities that the Commission finds to be consistent with the findings under paragraphs (2) through (6) and, if applicable, (7) of subsection (b) shall file a tariff or tariff revision with the Commission pursuant to section 205 and the regulations of the Commission allocating the costs of the new or modified transmission facilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A8219771C20483DB9E9EC0278BACF6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmission benefits</header><text>The Commission shall require that tariffs or tariff revisions filed under this subsection are just and reasonable and allocate the costs of providing service to customers that benefit, in accordance with the cost-causation principle, including through—</text> <subparagraph id="H3EBFF99B1B6B4A749EAEC471986216CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improved reliability;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H186B04B813924195A422361B8F4DD661"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced congestion;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B46D0B989F44B6ABEE02E57CA1E3235"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduced power losses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H360E779081A042CFB71EE77C3792A395"><enum>(D)</enum><text>greater carrying capacity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66EAE192BA074D6E84B93561B5A4B6AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reduced operating reserve requirements; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1616AEEBAEE4C45973D4D58E49A6A10"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improved access to lower cost generation that achieves reductions in the cost of delivered power.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13C7EE4F80504D8590DF21C38742F408"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ratepayer protection</header><text>Customers that receive no benefit, or benefits that are trivial in relation to the costs sought to be allocated, from electric transmission facilities constructed or modified under this section shall not be involuntarily allocated any of the costs of those transmission facilities, provided, however, that nothing in this section shall prevent a transmitting utility from recovering such costs through voluntary agreement with its customers.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30B06D1CA7124A68BEDCA73267747244"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>If the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission finds that the considerations under paragraphs (2) through (6) and, if applicable, (7) of subsection (b) of section 216 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (b)) are met, nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to exclude transmission facilities located on the outer Continental Shelf from being eligible for cost allocation established under subsection (f)(1) of that section (as amended by paragraph (1)).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H60789B7AA2284DEC9A7E2B286327D460"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Coordination of Federal authorizations for transmission facilities</header> <text>Section 216(h) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H7D34CA100669409C9FF8F5A718AAB3F9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting the following:</text>
          <quoted-block id="H6CC7AE39697D4DBFAB4FE14D7491F67B" style="OLC"
            display-inline="yes-display-inline">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">, except that—</text> <subparagraph id="H26516F8FCB074355A57C97460B867841"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the Commission shall act as the lead agency in the case of facilities permitted under subsection (b); and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC063AB5BCAB547B497B80D65B133C625">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Department of the Interior shall act as the lead agency in the case of facilities located on a lease, easement, or right-of-way granted by the Secretary of the Interior under section 8(p)(1)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(p)(1)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE32202D4E4434EE38E1F5A7AED0B6D61">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in each of paragraphs (3), (4)(B), (4)(C), (5)(B), (6)(A), (7)(A), (7)(B)(i), (8)(A)(i), and (9), by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>lead agency</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H50C8B8E9417546018CFDB6537EFEE28C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>As head of the lead agency, the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The lead agency</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6FC7EED3D26A4272A89AF0BBF5E12423">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (5)(A), by striking <quote>As lead agency head, the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The lead agency</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFF61B2CDEEA841CBB32A5672F642ED74">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (7)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF5F78C562EB40C6BB6890DB91B69822"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>18 months after the date of enactment of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>18 months after the date of enactment of the SPEED and Reliability Act of 2025</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H833B2A0ACE4743CCBA76F708F4CA9BE8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>1 year after the date of enactment of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>18 months after the date of enactment of the SPEED and Reliability Act of 2025</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H11AFF5CD838940A0A127A48B6044CFE4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Interstate compacts</header><text>Section 216(i) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H25805B0D427A467C9F89D7E763B413FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>, including facilities in national interest electric transmission corridors</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H832E4919B9154AC9B07B3F7386D8B002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6270E1942D81410A8EB36F67D6F3D1B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF40DFDE76B9A49BDB21D53B03880711A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5D0FF9D2B214FF3BE92FCC16E63E192"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in disagreement</quote> in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) and all that follows through <quote>(A) the</quote> in subparagraph (A) and inserting <quote>unable to reach an agreement on an application seeking approval by the</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C737D69EE80485FBE759C7C93077C89"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Transmission infrastructure investment</header><text>Section 219(b)(4) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824s">16 U.S.C. 824s(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7CDDCDC153594F00B96FC8CEFD6B41A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFCFE86620AD4963B397A9A322295D41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H594E586ED654488E95FDCCAE3BF5EBDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC6BBDD5A12B345B4BD0AA77CCA43252F" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H8AC8AD5C948543BBB6B2931082819F6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all prudently incurred costs associated with payments to jurisdictions impacted by electric transmission facilities developed pursuant to section 216.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H388BD7F45D0A498FA032795D5ED7626C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Section 216 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (k) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H497AA14C9C7744619253316E2BFCD9CA" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HBA8A7980F5CE4153AAF7A711E614A5EA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header> 
<paragraph id="HBCF2DB72DB524CDCBDFE26AAA67E6CF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ercot</header><text>This section shall not apply within the area referred to in section 212(k)(2)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H676704B4582D42B39A4A870E607B8E40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other utilities</header> <subparagraph id="H95687C0FA9144AFB81E956D5D6A65C2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the Commission shall have jurisdiction over all transmitting utilities, including transmitting utilities described in section 201(f), but excluding any ERCOT utility (as defined in section 212(k)(2)(B)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27C59703C0074962877D2AF97F223D9A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Being subject to Commission jurisdiction for the purposes of this section shall not make an entity described in section 201(f) a public utility for the purposes of section 201(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4CF8AB33CF48412C955CC95170A9EAF6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HAB652EB9C1734876B18150482FB8D0DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 50151(b) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/169">Public Law 117–169</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18715">42 U.S.C. 18715(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>designated by the Secretary to be necessary in the national interest under section 216(a) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824p">16 U.S.C. 824p(a)</external-xref>)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28317173D08043F0AA83CB0B4B16D0C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1222 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16421">42 U.S.C. 16421</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C305F6564924C56A5F39C4DDF47475B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in subsection (a)(1)(A), by striking <quote>is located in a national interest electric transmission corridor designated under section 216(a) of the Federal Power Act and</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF1A6FB9D63A483CBE3EFCD2C2337166"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A), by striking <quote>is located in an area designated under section 216(a) of the Federal Power Act and</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E1EFA2A48314439BB2387F0BAC62864"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 40106(h)(1)(A) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18713">42 U.S.C. 18713(h)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(A) is located in</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(B) is necessary</quote> in subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>is necessary</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H825662DFE5CB436D8EEA11FA9F132947"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Minimizing regulatory burden</header><text>Except as explicitly provided, no new rule or rule making (as such terms are defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) shall be required of any agency in order to implement this section or any amendment made by this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HE71E4C0C0CEB4BF6829D40B6732A3C57"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section or an amendment made by this section grants authority to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/791a">16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.</external-xref>) over sales of electric energy at retail or the local distribution of electricity.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

