<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MAR25126-6D4-7L-MWP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SCON 17 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that any public rendition of “The Star-Spangled Banner” should be performed as written by Francis Scott Key, in English.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. CON. RES. 17</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that any public rendition of <quote>The Star-Spangled Banner</quote> should be performed as written by Francis Scott Key, in English.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>The Star-Spangled Banner</quote>, written by Francis Scott Key in 1814, was designated as the national anthem of the United States by Congress in 1931;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the lyrics of <quote>The Star-Spangled Banner</quote>, as originally composed in English, reflect the historical and cultural significance of the resilience and unity of the United States during a time of national challenge;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the English-language text of the anthem, as written by Francis Scott Key, serves as a unifying symbol of the heritage and patriotism of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preserving the original English lyrics in public performances honors the historical context and intent of the anthem as a representation of the values and identity of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas maintaining the integrity of the anthem’s original language fosters a shared understanding and respect for its meaning among all people of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That—</text><paragraph id="HBCC4F0E2A89C4867B0D9B185556F5B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any public rendition of <quote>The Star-Spangled Banner</quote> should be performed as written by Francis Scott Key, in the English language, to preserve the historical and cultural integrity of the national anthem and maintain its unifying significance for the people of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF625CD24B22471DA129B6976DC66209"><enum>(2)</enum><text>performers and organizers of public events are encouraged to honor the tradition of presenting <quote>The Star-Spangled Banner</quote> in its original English form, as a tribute to its historical and patriotic importance.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

