<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H236287C62E624BBC829155AB582C6C34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1716 RH: Taiwan Conflict Deterrence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 35</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1716</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–48, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 27, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To deter Chinese aggression towards Taiwan by requiring the Secretary of the Treasury to publish a report on financial institutions and accounts connected to senior officials of the People’s Republic of China, to restrict financial services for certain immediate family of such officials, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H973295AA3DC64CE6B6DA3836A418E0F5"><section id="H35990C6442AA44A58626CF8D13389551" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Conflict Deterrence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDC3A9B215AC045DEA750617B7A5538A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on financial institutions and accounts connected to certain Chinese government officials</header><subsection id="H3D91711482E94ABCAAE5A2A6BFB67708"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Financial institutions report</header><paragraph id="H1530B60CCF7D404AA507AE541486D9C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date that the President, pursuant to section 3(c) of the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3302">22 U.S.C. 3302(c)</external-xref>), informs the Congress of a threat resulting from actions of the People’s Republic of China and any danger to the interests of the United States arising therefrom, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the appropriate Members of Congress containing the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2771BC3679C741918E95485DC553AA73"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each of at least 10 natural persons described under subsection (b), at least 1 of whom is a natural person listed under paragraph (1) of such subsection (b) and at least 1 of whom is a natural person listed under paragraph (2) of such subsection (b), the estimated total funds that are held in financial institutions and are under direct or indirect control by such natural person and a description of such funds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFA103C1F0474E44835D0CDF80A83BC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of any financial institutions that—</text><clause id="HE7BE7B9403FA49A29494E77D6BCECFBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintain an account in connection with significant funds described in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause id="H13E88B3BF4084FA38A17F33927B9A565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise provide significant financial services to a natural person covered by the report.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7A714D5EE1641FEA9969B61BBC25B4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after submitting a report described under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury, or a designee of the Secretary, shall provide to the appropriate Members of Congress an unclassified or classified briefing (as determined appropriate by the Secretary) on the funds covered by the report, including a description of how the funds were acquired, and any illicit or corrupt means employed to acquire or use the funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93B8EBEF39AC4FEEB4AFF53FE973FB30"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The requirements described under paragraph (1) may not be applied with respect to a natural person or a financial institution, as the case may be, if the President determines:</text><subparagraph id="HD4403F91E78D485BBFED6C53BB2365CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The funds described under paragraph (1)(A) were primarily acquired through legal and noncorrupt means.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24266E06E1D4348A93D4F302E056873"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The natural person has agreed to provide significant cooperation to the United States for an important national security purpose with respect to China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EEA20418C4E48F6B97B9651E66607C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A financial institution has agreed to—</text><clause id="H4316BC5D50CF4730B4EB8F3AF81B3833"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no longer maintain an account described under paragraph (1)(B)(i);</text></clause><clause id="H6F7131F4C9D4433792A6637547ADB14A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no longer provide significant financial services to a natural person covered by the report; or</text></clause><clause id="HDA3ED7EF97D04920A86570CAF8323CD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide significant cooperation to the United States for an important national security purpose with respect to China.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3BF5F3F402448D0BF70E74FD1084B16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive any requirement described under paragraph (1) with respect to a natural person or a financial institution upon reporting to the appropriate Members of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="HCD6D9D7206AF44AB967B88FB2B16AD75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the waiver would substantially promote the objective of ending the threat described under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF10B120106AD4001B61EB198024F7712"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the threat described under paragraph (1) is no longer present; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2985E8635CD43239D9A75164616FA21"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the waiver is essential to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B3EF5B7C1E34EB48348913D91FF6C71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Natural persons described</header><text>The natural persons described in this subsection are persons who, at the time of a report, are the following:</text><paragraph id="H954D7B35A5A14EDDA5AFD4E492B20A0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A member of the Politburo Standing Committee of the Chinese Communist Party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCDA49D4C015481E868E07CEF2B6F32B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A member of the Politburo of the Chinese Communist Party that is not described under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43E7DC16173642DA84B47629C94B891F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A member of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party that—</text><subparagraph id="HAD8197C0B75643D0AE2BA7E3A147F71A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is none of the foregoing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H193BCB7D0F4E4137AD6A0582A8215FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>performs any official duty that directly or indirectly affects Taiwan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF94557BB34740F29BF730DCE08B0DAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of reports; public availability</header><paragraph id="HE85326AA06124331A38B55A204902D05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text>The reports required under paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H250CF613EED24968BAE229D90B4147A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make the unclassified portion of the report required under subsection (a)(1) available to the public on the website and social media accounts of the Department of the Treasury—</text><subparagraph id="H2B5563EB407A4E1381BFB55D1F7B09E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in English, Chinese, and any other language that the Secretary finds appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76E9F6A2F2B64B57A2101161C9F344D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in precompressed, easily downloadable versions that are made available in all appropriate formats.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBAD8384BCBE843B19009BB8E5D314A17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on financial services for certain immediate family</header><subsection id="H0A892E9AB3E3473BB175FCBEF3071D0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall prohibit a United States financial institution, and any person owned or controlled by a United States financial institution, from engaging in a significant transaction with—</text><paragraph id="H19E7B7BFC13E47AB947A65735189D6CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a natural person covered by a report made under section 2(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H241ED042BD0D446DBF0964D604241359"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the immediate family of a person described under paragraph (1), if the Secretary finds that such immediate family benefits from funds described in the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D020185491C49D2A8984BE9CBA79F85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H2E20E57129904639A904936244FD5FC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activity of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C14204097D346B7BD0C6D240328AD3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the application of subsection (a) with respect to a person upon reporting to the appropriate Members of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="HAFDB2881E96543189F6A9B4E5BD48774"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the waiver would substantially promote the objective of ending the threat described under section 2(a)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H376E0D7E541649038DC4F7140DC1AC8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the threat described under section 2(a)(1) is no longer present; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6144DB7261E4D968F91AD5916A154BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the waiver is essential to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74AD991D90B047F6B18E1E1C1136A8A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text>The reports required under paragraph (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A41807078E7414EA49F875997E14A02"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><subparagraph id="H02F1456E85094F5BB4723400EBC22069"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing or requiring any sanction with respect to the importation of any good.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797E6E7366EE44378AC63CE386AFED3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DED2C9110CC4B7EBADA73B208262CCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="H2503097634AE429DA55679B39B7BDBE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section. Not later than 60 days after issuing a license pursuant to this section, the President shall submit a copy of the license to the appropriate Members of Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H584B3554737D410AB6A9832BCE2ADD0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section 206.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6A4D8480E6D4FD6B449B847CACD35CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall have no force or effect on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HF84B2DA94C564CDD971123A987F50A46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the date that the President reports to the appropriate Members of Congress that the threat described under section 2(a)(1) is no longer present; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H073CB40762A4478395B661DC71EDD34A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 25 years after the date that the Secretary of the Treasury submits the final report required under section 2(a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCB382C7DFD984A44B775FF23300081C0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H542CFC725A9E48E4892828F75D1D6F26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate Members of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Members of Congress</term> means the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate, the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H763F1ECEBA3445A89D560E7118BAB1A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means a United States financial institution or a foreign financial institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD5691E5BA92424792453F56CACD0287"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning given that term in section 561.308 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2305E0FCBD65457A86647AA3E7D23B3B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The term <term>funds</term> has the meaning given to such term by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H605B1A05B92A4865AC2766A2094CFA9F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Immediate family</header><text>The term <term>immediate family</term> of any natural person means the following (whether by the full or half blood or by adoption):</text><subparagraph id="H372325EE2B274EF69D5E788C92529668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such person’s spouse, father, mother, children, brothers, sisters, and grandchildren.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H936FD8E83CEE4982B08769D73DADDFE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The father, mother, brothers, and sisters of such person’s spouse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB019E14CCFDA4C499BC059A071F26DA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The spouse of a child, brother, or sister of such person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F6C1BB071F14CAAB9C2F1A912F17C91"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States financial institution</header><text>The term <term>United States financial institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>U.S. financial institution</term> under section 561.309 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

