<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6B3C0D4CAB44C7EB1D55B6EAC501E29" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 483 IH: Recognizing the 250th birthday of the United States Army.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 250th birthday of the United States Army.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 1775, the Second Continental Congress, representing the citizens and patriots of the Thirteen American Colonies, authorized the establishment of the Continental Army;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the collective expression of the pursuit of personal freedom that created the United States Army also led to the adoption of the Declaration of Independence and the realization of the fundamental principles and values of the United States in the Constitution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the past 250 years, the Army's central mission has been to fight and win the wars of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 190 campaign streamers carried on the United States Army flag are a testament to the valor, commitment, and professionalism of the brave soldiers who have served <quote>to build the Nation's might</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the battles of Yorktown, Gettysburg, Cantigny, Normandy, the Bulge, Okinawa, Inchon, la Drang, 73 Easting, Fallujah, and Kamdesh are but a few of the notable battles soldiers of the United States Army have fought with extraordinary courage and distinction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>loyalty, duty, respect, selfless service, honor, integrity, and personal courage</quote> are the values by which the United States soldier lives and serves;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Army of today is the world's most capable and lethal ground force that <quote>always places the mission first</quote> and <quote>will never accept defeat</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Army Forces are <quote>ready to deploy, engage, and destroy the enemies of the United States of America in close combat</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas no matter what the cause, location, or magnitude of future conflicts, the United States can rely on its Army to produce well-trained, well-led, and highly motivated soldiers to carry out the missions entrusted to them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Army’s motto, as carried on its flag is <quote>This We’ll Defend.</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, whatever the mission, the United States turns to its Army for decisive victories as <quote>the guardians of freedom and the American way of life</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6434123B32974CB2B13B0A0B6A4BF83E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0E9490F2299041B5B84FFDDF9D7C7457"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives, recognizing the historic significance of the 250th anniversary of the United States Army—</text><paragraph id="H421977BCE4C744D4A7F734390D7E6369"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses the appreciation of the people of the United States to the Army and the soldiers who have served in it with dedication for 250 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E69860E05B540AE88A79FA956877F20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the valor, commitment, and professionalism that United States soldiers have displayed throughout the history of the Army; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA5800C186B741EAAA969A23F6456322" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to observe that anniversary with honorific programs, ceremonies, and activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

