<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54882954A2874CF1BCE7F1B9FCBAF794" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1280 IH: Decentralizing and Reorganizing Agency Infrastructure Nation-wide To Harness Efficient Services, Workforce Administration, and Management Practices Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1280</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the head of each Executive agency to relocate 30 percent of the employees assigned to the headquarters of the Executive agency to duty stations outside the Washington metropolitan area, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D0C8A8E5B5E4B448AD50FD898CCCB5E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H08ECDCD1D0294F69A438A29CCFF262E0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Decentralizing and Reorganizing Agency Infrastructure Nation-wide To Harness Efficient Services, Workforce Administration, and Management Practices Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DRAIN THE SWAMP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0AF30228B2C749C7812321088E586842"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H5741BBBA75CA42EA81F153DCC0445908"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Budget justification materials</header><text>The term <term>budget justification materials</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3(b)(2)(A) of the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE232B22EAB0448B390C04462D818431F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term>— </text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FA218F2D894DE88CE753AD18042AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given that term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E9E6B7DE920493C89B9D94B160717CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an individual who—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D9C2525CB3747A48ACF29D786E606FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the event of a lapse in appropriations, would be an excepted employee and exempt from the limitation on voluntary services under section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, because the duties of the position in which the individual is serving are performing mission-essential functions of the Executive agency employing the individual that are necessary for purposes of defending the United States against imminent threats; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CDF98D0468E495DAC0F16B414B784B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is serving in a position within—</text>
<subclause id="HEB9431F3228040E087D64AE4E0ED0217"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Executive Office of the President; or </text></subclause> <subclause id="H9ED748941FC74389A74630B0A85CCE9F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a component, the mission of which is related to national security, of—</text>
<item id="H3F435D387E40405284EB15E8D670557F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Department of Defense, including—</text> <subitem id="H43D0F5A8F7834310967172E438C17C4B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the Defense Intelligence Agency;</text></subitem>
<subitem id="H8E8D16F8DAE94EC0AF15BCE92334F21D"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the National Security Agency; and</text></subitem> <subitem id="H98FD09D49F2B4B689F875DCDB9EC05C2"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency;</text></subitem></item>
<item id="H44CA6A3CD5C64A85AAA4442624E42190"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text></item> <item id="H64A812F65FE94E80A9CD2F2EFB307C39"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></item>
<item id="H0BE8FA33C6B2496889B38B80205E028B"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; or</text></item> <item id="H488F64A8C4AD4581BA573EC1480C7879"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the Central Intelligence Agency.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H73D50CEE44114FD484E9B6D60DD0F984"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>Executive agency</term> means an agency, as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, that is in the executive branch of the Government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC81FCE0F0A354EE89CBDCD7CAA5A3BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Headquarters employee of an Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>headquarters employee of an Executive agency</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H742A005EF0F247C98BC064A31D1A5C84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of an Executive agency whose permanent duty station is at the headquarters of the Executive agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF30FF1666D5349959619FFA75C307D99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employee of an Executive agency—</text>
<clause id="H2D7A07DDE9B347D18072500287CE213E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who teleworks on a full-time basis; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1D6A7B10253B4F81820FD04F90E3ECE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whose rate of pay is calculated based on the Washington metropolitan area rate of pay.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C41D45F84E1475CAABFCD390407D8F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Headquarters of the Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>headquarters of the Executive agency</term>, with respect to an Executive agency, means the building serving as the principal managerial and administrative center of the Executive agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D340100A9134BDA934E165523691C19"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pay locality</header><text>The term <term>pay locality</term> has the meaning given that term in section 5302 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9FF20FF11F8F4EC89063CDA20077216A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rural</header><text>The term <term>rural</term> means any area that is not designated as an urban area, based on the most recent data available from the Bureau of the Census.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C9D466C527E457089DFE7E026D9CB9D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Telework</header><text>The term <term>telework</term> has the meaning given that term in section 6501 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96310CE0D54641EF82AC88BDBFF235D9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Telework on a full-time basis</header><text>The term <term>telework on a full-time basis</term> means that an employee is authorized to telework for 100 percent of the work days of the employee per pay period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAA83A6583A3438BA6E521CECBA57A75"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Washington metropolitan area</header><text>The term <term>Washington metropolitan area</term> means the geographic area to which the Washington metropolitan area rate of pay applies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3DE7D35A54D480EB003FF8F94A0C6B8"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Washington metropolitan area rate of pay</header><text>The term <term>Washington metropolitan area rate of pay</term> means the rate of pay in effect for the pay locality designated as <quote>Washington-Baltimore-Arlington, DC–MD–VA–WV–PA</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE204325459CA4E34893CD39F895F0B16"><enum>3.</enum><header>Relocation of employees</header> <subsection id="HF76A9F283D254ED4937DDD4C520436F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, and not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Executive agency shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H0F8E039AEFF24DE9BAFFCC78A66E8E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>change the permanent duty station of not less than 30 percent of the headquarters employees of the Executive agency, as of the date of enactment of this Act, to be at an office of the Executive agency at a location outside the Washington metropolitan area, which shall be at locations throughout the regions of the Executive agency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B6F932844FD472280EF3E06908A65E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each employee of the Executive agency whose permanent duty station is changed under paragraph (1), ensure that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEF31840C2A9A4A688A4AC29FDD8E3C6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of pay of the employee is calculated based on the pay locality for the permanent duty station of the employee; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE82ECB29118B4922AF4138E762883B3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employee is not authorized to telework on a full-time basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HADF077AED8894854AC0F70BB20E760CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of new duty stations</header><text>The head of each Executive agency shall, in determining the permanent duty stations of headquarters employees of the Executive agency under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H8113F974C5464CB5A12413EF1B68F75B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote geographic diversity, including consideration of rural markets; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52C422ECBFCD42E7A338579BD4EF7114"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure adequate staffing throughout the regions of the Executive agency, to promote in-person customer service.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H70A31515BBDB486C9EB8A35E24F3904C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of employees eligible for a change in duty station</header> <paragraph id="HAB7FAE830CDB4EC8AA17C0D75811F563"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the head of each Executive agency shall include each headquarters employee of the Executive agency as eligible for a change in permanent duty station under subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4DF575F69834A14BE5975D160CE7C11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A headquarters employee of an Executive agency who is a qualified individual who receives an accommodation to telework on a full-time basis as a reasonable accommodation under title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12111">42 U.S.C. 12111 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE825217E7E04FC9A678475356C3985F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be determined to be eligible for a change in permanent duty station under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3CD20141494467DA97AFD5EF591804C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be counted as a headquarters employee of the Executive agency for purposes of complying with subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3429906305E140DF9C4AA367D3774A7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of determination of eligibility</header><text>Not later than the day before the date on which the head of an Executive agency submits the report required under subsection (d), the head of the Executive agency shall notify each headquarters employee of the Executive agency who the head of the Executive agency determines is eligible for a change in permanent duty station under subsection (a) of that determination.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC7EA69EC868E433295A03E536C9A83F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Executive agency shall submit to each committee of the Senate or the House of Representatives with jurisdiction of 1 or more programs, projects, or activities of the Executive agency a report that provides—</text> <paragraph id="HA268F10EF77A4194806FDEF0697D3448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of headquarters employees of the Executive agency, as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE8E014B3C734F868D5451428579FCC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of headquarters employees of the Executive agency identified as eligible for a change in permanent duty station, in accordance with subsection (c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H848D09F68F9B4F5DBE888B2DC32693D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of headquarters employees of the Executive agency whose permanent duty station will be changed to be at an office of the Executive agency at a location outside the Washington metropolitan area under subsection (a);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC1D9E7834D474C6BBD8931082A00CC4C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of headquarters employees of the Executive agency subject to an exception under subsection (c)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11AA02A319864E03A654D9457B88F73C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the plan of the head of the Executive agency to implement subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H905DD95CAD474A5BA088035002291CAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
<paragraph id="H8778EE5028E4450EB1E16D5471979CFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not earlier than 60 days, and not later than 90 days, after the date on which the head of an Executive agency submits the report required under subsection (d), the head of the Executive agency shall notify each headquarters employee of the Executive agency whose permanent duty station will be changed to be at an office of the Executive agency located outside the Washington metropolitan area under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H00E29F384C384E62BEEAFCB5E80A7C94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that, effective 90 days after the date of the notification—</text>
<clause id="H8CE6249D754E4BC5B29FF99EDED999B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the permanent duty station of the employee shall be changed;</text></clause> <clause id="HCF5927B4012048EFB1E8E9CF971B081A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rate of pay of the employee shall be calculated based on the pay locality for such permanent duty station; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3FF17A778714470E8DF26FA3D22E57AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the employee shall not be authorized to telework on a full-time basis; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CB0215DCD314597BE627277029033A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of the location of such permanent duty station.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA68BD4F7A5DA454BB898269B82A53402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full-time teleworkers remaining in the washington metropolitan area</header>
<subparagraph id="HAA6AB5A8C25C48ABB498B8C724DA7083"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any employee described in subparagraph (B), effective on the date that is 180 days after the date on which the head of the Executive agency employing the employee submits the report required under subsection (d), the employee shall not be authorized to telework on a full-time basis.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB521C5A3CD1D4C7CADD81C4A11B890F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employees covered</header><text>An employee described in this subparagraph is a headquarters employee of an Executive agency—</text>
<clause id="H467028D3529149918C75807A0CD6E7CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who teleworks on a full-time basis, as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text></clause> <clause id="HF35BA8E5C6384C5D81A03497A4C73CD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is not subject to an exception under subsection (c)(2); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H26011375ED1D4EB893D34901981F2E91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whose permanent duty station is not changed to be an office of the Executive agency at a location outside the Washington metropolitan area under subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4576328BE37F41D3A66F58F005A3BE31"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reduction in headquarters office space</header> <subsection id="H47715B4E13E248B98D165F1CA2ABD3EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H60003308BD564110ABDC2D706E7940AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue a memorandum directing that the amount of real property serving as the headquarters of an Executive agency that is owned or leased by the Federal Government be reduced by not less than 30 percent; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3B0FCD6888F455BBF485A088CD7B336"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in identifying property to be sold or for which a lease is to be terminated or not renewed, prioritize—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6882CFE655AB45FDA35530C9ADB27051"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the disposal of buildings; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H407748D7023B46BFB761C88256785DCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>co-locating the headquarters of Executive agencies in as few locations as practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2AEB615030224F0894F2804DEE54222E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>If the head of an Executive agency is directed to reduce office space under the memorandum issued under subsection (a), the head of the Executive agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7D869A6A550543438E8116EF7FE75A29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>begin reducing office space in accordance with the memorandum not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H092DE6FB478E41C493FC2E0737043A9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complete the reduction of office space in accordance with the memorandum not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB52D9220FA5941DEB9C75C4F654CFCB0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Information included in budget justification materials provided to congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of each Executive agency shall include in the first budget justification materials of the Executive agency submitted after the date of enactment of this Act, and the budget justification materials of the Executive agency for each fiscal year thereafter—</text>
<paragraph id="HF1BABD5862E3450387679BB7F809FEB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of headquarters employees of the Executive agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE58BC2B8D3A14820AA9EACFDDF4BE47A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of employees of the Executive agency assigned to a permanent duty station in—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4C4F4FE2DD984CC0A676E0C3ADA55FA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a field office of the Executive agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H828694A228364375955484DFBADCF75A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a district office of the Executive agency; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89614BFCB4D6494580EBE4DB6ACAF77B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a regional office of the Executive agency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0ACEA597FDB24E1E9D42269EED31D4A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of employees of the Executive agency who telework on a full-time basis; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E3C137A177844A78C4FDC001DAD55AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of employees of the Executive agency who are a qualified individual who receives an accommodation to telework on a full-time basis as a reasonable accommodation under title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12111">42 U.S.C. 12111 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D64533326174D0BBA50E7D1CA315637"><enum>6.</enum><header>No relocation incentives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If, pursuant to this Act, the official worksite (as defined in section 531.605 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations) of an employee changes from the residence of the employee to the headquarters of the Executive agency of the employee, notwithstanding any other provision of law, no such employee shall be paid any relocation incentive.</text></section>
<section id="H72C43364104745E99FD6C5B4E6A87197"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> <section id="H86774AF0722248DC901EBC46B639C302"><enum>8.</enum><header>Supersession</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall supersede any other provision of law and any provision of a collective bargaining agreement or master labor agreement.</text></section>
<section id="HEC8737F78A9646D1B5775FBB2CAA4B41"><enum>9.</enum><header>No private cause of action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to establish a private cause of action, equitable or otherwise, to challenge any selection, change, or decision made, or action taken, under this Act. </text></section> </legis-body></bill>

