<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25885-HM7-WS-347"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1749 IS: No United States Recognition of Russian Sovereignty Over Crimea or Any Other Forcibly Seized Ukrainian Territory</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1749</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit United States Government recognition of the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over Crimea, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No United States Recognition of Russian Sovereignty Over Crimea or Any Other Forcibly Seized Ukrainian Territory</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf61b224f80d74ea4961345239825639a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against United States recognition of the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over Crimea</header><subsection id="id80abe6c3e3074eba9086315c7bb75471"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States not to recognize the Government of the Russian Federation's claim of sovereignty over Crimea or any other forcibly seized Ukrainian territory, including any related airspace or territorial waters.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9ce8b2cc9bb6454b957b9377e5255f33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>In accordance with subsection (a), no Federal department or agency may take any action, extend any nonhumanitarian assistance, or spend any funds that implies recognition of the Government of the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over Crimea or any other forcibly seized Ukrainian territory, unless any such claim is formally recognized by the democratically elected Government of Ukraine. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

