<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDD2FE79B82A4F73B15B1853ED844A0A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3092 IH: Electrodiagnostic Medicine Patient Protection and Fraud Elimination Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3092</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for additional requirements with respect to electrodiagnostic services under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF0FB7876390408496592E5FF8B90582" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H07538B5BFBE44B649890DDC6B86E8762" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electrodiagnostic Medicine Patient Protection and Fraud Elimination Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H721B9057B2C44BE0BCE3D6DF88C2861E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional requirements for electrodiagnostic services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4060F5C9D5B048028160D7BCAEEED0B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H7CEA9E12B511461A82D8FC239B3A6BE5"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Payment for electrodiagnostic services</header> 
<paragraph id="HED8E538D8EE44847A8884C4D3EA63C3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No payment may be made under this part for electrodiagnostic services described in paragraph (2) furnished on or after a date determined appropriate by the Secretary that is not earlier than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection and not later than 4 years after such date of enactment that are not furnished at a qualified facility. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to such services furnished for interoperative neuromonitoring.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03EFDEF9A966479BB747212DD6952ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electrodiagnostic services</header><text>The services described in this paragraph are the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04F48E2539C043819BB2B6A648FBEC7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Nerve conduction studies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B3B003E6D174F0FBF8A93B24151E2E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Needle electromyography tests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87FAF92494BC4DAFA677A69F8643D26F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>qualified facility</quote> means a facility accredited by an organization specified by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AEDF16C0D014D10AD820CE3E93EDED4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Accreditation organizations</header> <subparagraph id="HEA3AD37EB9794674B97C325885F16D1F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall specify accrediting organizations, in consultation with the advisory committee described in paragraph (5), for purposes determining whether a facility is a qualified facility. The Secretary may specify an organization pursuant to the preceding sentence only if such organization requires, as a condition of accreditation of a facility by such organization, that such facility meet the requirements described in subparagraph (B). In making such specification, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="HB9D0C1736AF0440EB6D81DDAC42F0329"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that the number of accrediting organizations so specified is adequate to facilitate the accreditation of facilities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1DA297A430C2436D986B2F4CCFD82529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prioritize such specification of accrediting organizations that are widely recognized by both public and private entities as having experience in the accreditation of such facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H359522B3D23C4409AAEEAAD355654809"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Facility requirements</header><text>The requirements described in this subparagraph are, with respect to a facility and electrodiagnostic services furnished at such facility, the following:</text> <clause id="H5901A3B25EA44F9F8F310B81F58440BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility establishes and maintains a quality assurance and control program to ensure the reliability, safety, and accuracy of such service.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H604AD42B2D4C4370B144769B09D7ECA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility ensures that such service is conducted using a device capable of performing both nerve conduction studies that record amplitude and latency and needle electromyography tests capable of real-time waveform display and analysis.</text></clause> <clause id="HBAC3C4644D734170BD2A7BE323C1F753"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that such service is a needle electromyography test, the facility ensures that the individual furnishing such test has completed not less than 3 months of training in performing and interpreting electrodiagnostic studies during a residency or fellowship program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education or the Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada, or by an individual described in section 410.32(b)(2)(iv) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HED9AFF6C170A4DA8AAD097E50062270E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The facility ensures that the results are interpreted on-site and at the time of the procedure—</text> <subclause id="HAF9501F40A58428BB61559E46DCD61D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a needle electromyography test, by the individual who performed such test; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2008C5C8345748ECA9771726995CFC82"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a nerve conduction study, by the individual who performed or supervised such study.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5607875E18A34337A5CA204F4CF6E827"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other requirement determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H747DE83765DC49A8A59C6488D30BD3E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall finalize regulations that outline—</text> <clause id="H937DD824D677429898B280E7F8D1B3A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the process by which an accrediting organization may be specified under subparagraph (A);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEAEE1B5E03734F3E8DB52D14FD246916"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the duration and the minimum time period between reviews for reaccreditation an organization so specified must provide for with respect to an accreditation of a facility made by such organization;</text></clause> <clause id="H3B19315F3F9D4A94BBB46B2F08E8D0DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the process by which the Secretary may withdraw approval of an accrediting organization so specified if the Secretary determines that such organization no longer requires, as a condition of accreditation of a facility by such organization, that such facility meet the requirements described in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1ECB8E81DF5548CBB72CBF7B2736EAD2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the effect such a withdrawal will have on facilities accredited by such organization as of the date of such withdrawal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EE2BE8FB9B442828F5C9AE048AA2092"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header> <subparagraph id="H5A1B6D976E7242F78977D09EA6BAF5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>National Electrodiagnostic Services Advisory Committee</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>committee</quote>) for purposes of carrying out the duties specified in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27CB6C4FB0CD47A7BCF38660D67802F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the committee are the following:</text> <clause id="H763F0443AC504F08A49AAEDF400E31FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>To provide to the Secretary recommendations with respect to requirements that may be determined appropriate by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (4)(B)(v), including any proposed additions to such requirements or modifications of such requirements. In developing such recommendations, the committee shall prioritize—</text> 
<subclause id="HFB17B1F24E6B44459AA7DE76B12B8ABF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reducing unnecessary treatments and surgeries;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD8926A8CDF3E411AAF63F39DB78BF5C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>decreasing the need for retesting of individuals;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDB5DA4F413104554ACA029FE0F544A99"><enum>(III)</enum><text>enhancing the reliability of diagnoses and promoting positive health outcomes for individuals;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEB2956422A4E409E87EB752F40E98D3C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>addressing emerging waste, fraud, and abuse schemes; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCFB989B8990041668E011B2CBA04CC69"><enum>(V)</enum><text>otherwise improving the quality of care for individuals.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H36F87BCA9AB54388B5A912A15762109C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To provide to the Secretary recommendations regarding the regulations described in paragraph (4)(C).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5CA2E1C90A0E444397E2FC2CF793D17C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To provide to the Secretary recommendations with respect to whether accrediting organizations seeking to be specified pursuant to paragraph (4)(A) should be so specified.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF9AAD884D164DF6A2B1B09A7C0F598D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The committee shall be composed of not fewer than 9 and not more than 11 individuals selected by the Secretary. Such individuals shall not be officers or employees of the Federal Government and shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H2FE9D7E4118C465CA0AED5B017000AC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least one physician with experience in furnishing electrodiagnostic services described in paragraph (2) in a lab accredited by an organization determined appropriate by the Secretary;</text></clause> <clause id="HCFBD13C00294430B90E7F0EE3C37BFD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one physical therapist that is certified in clinical electrophysiology by an organization determined appropriate by the Secretary;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEC6D8188F79E4C81A83988A3EE323C00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other health care practitioners;</text></clause> <clause id="HBCE145E02ED6423884D11E0C24996840"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one patient representing an affected community; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1FE27301E25C430CA23E75DC75F50313"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other individuals determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FB52B61E9294C3AA49BE4B5BCEC49D2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The committee shall convene not less than twice each year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

