<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5E45476170DB4432A555F2F9213B7553" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1469 RH: National Senior Investor Initiative Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 94</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1469</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–124]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 21, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create an interdivisional taskforce at the Securities and Exchange Commission for senior investors.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H1CBCA558411C4DDE843ED1B1101BC1FA"><section id="H3FA26C4F8BBA4055BDEA74D6E107FA8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Senior Investor Initiative Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Senior Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0522068D597341EB89FBFF36C1505390"><enum>2.</enum><header>Senior Investor Taskforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78d">15 U.S.C. 78d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C8F138C7C9E4BDF915D279AC312561E" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><subsection id="H0023D5ED2DDC49B4B46B15166E81699F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Senior Investor Taskforce</header><paragraph id="H1299D699445A430F8025048641D4385D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Commission the Senior Investor Taskforce (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Taskforce</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H64856113856F4861BB09488F049A5B3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director of the Taskforce</header><text>The head of the Taskforce shall be the Director, who shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H313AB3E0E91540038D01F6739C60B79C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report directly to the Chairman; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD55130CF859A444ABAE979C466BF4B0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be appointed by the Chairman, in consultation with the Commission, from among individuals—</text><clause id="H34D5513472574CDF86B761A3F023CCA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>currently employed by the Commission or from outside of the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="H28CC7E350188442EAD27F5E156F2BC0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>having experience in advocating for the interests of senior investors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF39C1D1A42AC469881A9376938166BA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staffing</header><text>The Chairman shall ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="HD38FF2E2442B43868AFE4F95A1020317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Taskforce is staffed sufficiently to carry out fully the requirements of this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DE1BFDA56BE4F2CBACD22891F6E82B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such staff shall include individuals from the Division of Enforcement, Office of Compliance Inspections and Examinations, and Office of Investor Education and Advocacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A6831234E0D459FB5BF34DE7C5398BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No compensation for members of Taskforce</header><text>All members of the Taskforce appointed under paragraph (2) or (3) shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their services as officers or employees of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8089289E844CE7ADAD782454B331C5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minimizing duplication of efforts</header><text>In organizing and staffing the Taskforce, the Chairman shall take such actions as may be necessary to minimize the duplication of efforts within the divisions and offices described under paragraph (3)(B) and any other divisions, offices, or taskforces of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5274A9E7EEB64F00A97A3ED29C074CBB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Functions of the Taskforce</header><text>The Taskforce shall—</text><subparagraph id="HBF670C2C9864402E99B2D5988CF9E6E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify challenges that senior investors encounter, including problems associated with financial exploitation and cognitive decline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FDB5FF9A1C44A2CA1FB046426FAA325"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify areas in which senior investors would benefit from changes in the regulations of the Commission or the rules of self-regulatory organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FFC852543A246E587FB19E3C7E5BACF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate, as appropriate, with other offices within the Commission, other taskforces that may be established within the Commission, self-regulatory organizations, and the Elder Justice Coordinating Council; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C6A792E36784DF3AC1A15919D3E4674"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consult, as appropriate, with State securities and law enforcement authorities, State insurance regulators, and other Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE73EA6C2857424CB5763C3D1EFD6862"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Taskforce, in coordination, as appropriate, with the Office of the Investor Advocate and self-regulatory organizations, and in consultation, as appropriate, with State securities and law enforcement authorities, State insurance regulators, and Federal agencies, shall issue a report every 2 years to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, the first of which shall not be issued until after the report described in section 3 of the National Senior Investor Initiative Act of 2025 has been issued and considered by the Taskforce, containing—</text><subparagraph id="H5D160B4DA1FA414CBE1F61618187FF95"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriate statistical information and full and substantive analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FAC2FF2A46F4AC9B853EAD67FDDCA88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of recent trends and innovations that have impacted the investment landscape for senior investors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D121EBFEAFC496F959D8195434CACBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of regulatory initiatives that have concentrated on senior investors and industry practices related to senior investors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE9DA0E6485E4CF99CD5B4AB827331B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">key observations, best practices, and areas needing improvement, involving senior investors identified during examinations, enforcement actions, and investor education outreach;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4393463CDD764EF0A30FA935F82DC2D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the most serious issues encountered by senior investors, including issues involving financial products and services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA249DBFCEFFD4DB8A863824F3271A79D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an analysis with regard to existing policies and procedures of brokers, dealers, investment advisers, and other market participants related to senior investors and senior investor-related topics and whether these policies and procedures need to be further developed or refined;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D79DE538E514E3B9C5FE3F02CBB3277"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for such changes to the regulations, guidance, and orders of the Commission and self-regulatory organizations and such legislative actions as may be appropriate to resolve problems encountered by senior investors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8662810245B54D84B8163D6467392102"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other information, as determined appropriate by the Director of the Taskforce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4179938552A42E19036D89324D50CE9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Request for reports</header><text>The Taskforce shall make any report issued under paragraph (7) available to a Member of Congress who requests such a report. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A70B8649A0B4124AD5C359AFB4CB1AF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Taskforce shall terminate after the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F9B948A4DA4A30A02B6FB23A99C2BE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Senior investor defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>senior investor</term> means an investor over the age of 65.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7032A1F3A32B44448419837A505C4868"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Use of existing funds</header><text>The Commission shall use existing funds to carry out this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H45AB52722093451783C50A5F3D34955C"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO study</header><subsection id="H3DDD24509B604527A90BCA2DEB47DF42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress and the Senior Investor Taskforce the results of a study of financial exploitation of senior citizens.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8F4741EF80C74A74867198B1CAA202E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include information with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HDFC33510881E4C2FA204EF720DFDABEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>economic costs of the financial exploitation of senior citizens—</text><subparagraph id="H6A001A711D354C4F88AB448DB34D2F8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>associated with losses by victims that were incurred as a result of the financial exploitation of senior citizens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H095FF06379B24E6F9283CCC15BC732FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incurred by State and Federal agencies, law enforcement and investigatory agencies, public benefit programs, public health programs, and other public programs as a result of the financial exploitation of senior citizens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA46486A9EDB472083DD52515BDB9C05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incurred by the private sector as a result of the financial exploitation of senior citizens; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1BE0256EC974E37AD04F1806DDD94AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other relevant costs that—</text><clause id="HA89BBF3994204C1BA9C2CDD50FE71219"><enum>(i)</enum><text>result from the financial exploitation of senior citizens; and</text></clause><clause id="H47EF069371F049D6A14C9840BD14D2E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Comptroller General determines are necessary and appropriate to include in order to provide Congress and the public with a full and accurate understanding of the economic costs resulting from the financial exploitation of senior citizens in the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H870D94778A854CB49081AC83CEF25287"><enum>(2)</enum><text>frequency of senior financial exploitation and correlated or contributing factors—</text><subparagraph id="H79FAA61159CB43E1A5CD513096A5F025"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about percentage of senior citizens financially exploited each year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB24F647F413744328F562C007846E1D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information about factors contributing to increased risk of exploitation, including such factors as race, social isolation, income, net worth, religion, region, occupation, education, home-ownership, illness, and loss of spouse; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42DFA1184F2A4BF6A2D49B6097B7C4DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>policy responses and reporting of senior financial exploitation—</text><subparagraph id="H59AAFAC4F89E42A8BA75EE4C7459F992"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the degree to which financial exploitation of senior citizens unreported to authorities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB85ED3F990B401BB9BC8DCB1208105E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reasons that financial exploitation may be unreported to authorities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E9EAD8A6B1C41E984FFCFE0937A08C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent that suspected elder financial exploitation is currently being reported—</text><clause id="HADB426408775495F9D96EBF01452902F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information regarding which Federal, State, and local agencies are receiving reports, including adult protective services, law enforcement, industry, regulators, and professional licensing boards;</text></clause><clause id="HA7E3FB60CCE24C93B18A621A56CCACA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information regarding what information is being collected by such agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="H18C9362E6B9240C2A45A56B5EDC7C068"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information regarding the actions that are taken by such agencies upon receipt of the report and any limits on the agencies’ ability to prevent exploitation, such as jurisdictional limits, a lack of expertise, resource challenges, or limiting criteria with regard to the types of victims they are permitted to serve;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31B5948941A24E6089C99BFE1C2452BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an analysis of gaps that may exist in empowering Federal, State, and local agencies to prevent senior exploitation or respond effectively to suspected senior financial exploitation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8377D5B64CDF4B9E88AD2A6DE75716C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an analysis of the legal hurdles that prevent Federal, State, and local agencies from effectively partnering with each other and private professionals to effectively respond to senior financial exploitation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE66F0E13524B4E068C9B61EF937764DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Senior citizen defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In section, the term <term>senior citizen</term> means an individual over the age of 65.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

