<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25G38-R8K-H4-W79">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2606 IS: To require the Commander of United States Cyber Command to complete development of a roadmap for industry collaboration on artificial intelligence-enabled cyber capabilities for cyberspace operations of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2606</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Commander of United States Cyber Command to complete
            development of a roadmap for industry collaboration on artificial intelligence-enabled
            cyber capabilities for cyberspace operations of the Department of Defense, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="id6af9b4f8ee534e7287a8a129037e8bec" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>United States Cyber Command artificial intelligence industry collaboration
                roadmap</header>
            <subsection id="idb48f6f141c834e20aa31a0dfdd9e3a2c">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Roadmap required</header>
 <text>Not later than August 1, 2026, the Commander of United States Cyber Command shall, in coordination with the Chief Digital and Artificial Intelligence Officer of the Department of Defense, the Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, and the Director of the Defense Innovation Unit, complete development of a roadmap for industry collaboration on artificial intelligence-enabled cyber capabilities for cyberspace operations of the Department of Defense.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id5ab54bc7803644a0900162f9e83fe35c">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Purpose</header>
 <text>The roadmap developed under subsection (a) shall establish a framework for coordination between the private sector and the Department of Defense to integrate state-of-the-art artificial intelligence capabilities into offensive and defensive cyberspace operations through—</text>
                <paragraph id="id4df159a734f64e6a96ba5cdc845f603e">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>convening United States commercial artificial intelligence developers, cybersecurity experts, and relevant Federal Government offices; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id771a05d8a51c4690bc748e89c1208070">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>facilitating information exchange on artificial intelligence technology and capabilities for cyber operations.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id85614aeb0e3648e2b32c94090c57b23f">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Elements</header>
 <text>The roadmap developed under subsection (a) shall address the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbd65e523026494cb363ea7b6a33493b"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Courses of action and selected approach on various alternatives to manage and execute collaborative research and development partnerships with industry.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf91279615975419fb540ca3162b7070c">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Collaborative development lines of effort for artificial intelligence-enabled cyber capabilities and associated near-term use cases.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idb5b937c0ca0d458db48cb056e7ebb4bb">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Strategy and methodology for industry engagement and commercial collaboration, including—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id889292a1ffa6488dba5a21e33a27e86f">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>contractual mechanisms for industry collaboration on cyber tools and capabilities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id6ad562122aaf4a37ac923e01be4e2361">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>security clearance requirements, goals, and resource needs for industry partners; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id5d7c4218647840e98dac2b878e7dbd61">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>evaluation of existing contract and collaboration authorities and identification of required policy changes or new authorities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0dd00fd9992a48758fcc1a2e194fbc1f">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Implementation objectives, milestones, and status of relevant pilot programs.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id802de2f831e844eb982f6a6497d1b114">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Technology transition mechanisms from development to operational use.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7563c586ad4946f0ba5ccc399769654b">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Infrastructure requirements and associated costs.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id0543a7310d304f9086024a2b0c6d8447"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text>Assessment of organizational structure options, including establishment of a new center or integration within existing organizations.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id3b0bd555be734b36833e927ef54d0771">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Congressional briefings</header>
                <paragraph id="id39267c14d5e44a3486913bfd6de421b4">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Initial briefing</header>
 <text>Not later than November 1, 2026, the Commander of United States Cyber Command shall provide the congressional defense committees a briefing on the roadmap developed under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id078de76b7a374e7588fae3cea5dc8418">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Annual updates</header>
 <text>During the period beginning on the date on which the President submits to Congress a budget for fiscal year 2028 pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and ending on December 31, 2030, the Commander shall, not less frequently than once each year, provide the congressional defense committees a briefing on the status of industry collaboration activities carried out in accordance with the roadmap developed under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

