<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H88FD92FE5CEA48628196B7A389E78417" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 530 EH: ACES Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 530</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To provide for a study by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine on the prevalence and mortality of cancer among individuals who served as active duty aircrew in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H31BCDF0C11A7491F861CD85F7FB2B0CB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H65A51D9B2B0B41C0B833C0FDCBEDF13A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ACES Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H9170E1603EA4459285E0A2FB2FD07765"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Academies study on prevalence and mortality of cancer among individuals who served as active duty aircrew in the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="H98B0CA5BDF7F4AFA92EDDA7FE3EF1A55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreement</header> <paragraph id="H294315D64E8544678ECA98EDCD67C8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (in this section referred to as the <quote>National Academies</quote>), under which the National Academies shall conduct a study on the prevalence and mortality of cancers among covered individuals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H539A16B8152C4EC3A3870E6D1BC3D578"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDD8366532C624712AA5CEA5BD19DFB50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Date</header><text>The Secretary shall finalize the agreement under paragraph (1) by not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary enters negotiations with the National Academies with respect to such agreement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08C0C86C477C4F909D66FF1EEDB8E00C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report; briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to satisfy the requirement under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="HF5D12C033D7A44598359D730BA26A12C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text> <subclause id="HE884C806E214406A95DFBEE4C4E6C6C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an explanation of the reasons the Secretary failed to satisfy such requirement; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H71A6802C2CBB45C082FE81806FDFF414"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an estimate of the date on which the Secretary will finalize the agreement under paragraph (1); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H565332BDF1B54FD0946875A51E70E40E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 60 days after the date on which the Secretary failed to satisfy such requirement, provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing on the progress of the Secretary toward finalizing such agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33B7E05AF9AA4003898F2FC24D1AECB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEBC79A38C4564D95915E523526F121EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify exposures associated with military occupations of covered individuals, including relating to chemicals, compounds, agents, and other phenomena;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A7DFC1CC75247C79653732904926A1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the literature to determine associations between exposures referred to in paragraph (1) and the incidence or prevalence of overall cancer morbidity, overall cancer mortality, and increased incidence or prevalence of—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E32337DE253484EBB97F45182010AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>brain cancer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF2D62B2D71F42E3BC50B4638507EB34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>colon and rectal cancers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CE31ABE7EF34E28B0B56D3805773869"><enum>(C)</enum><text>kidney cancer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7A6D525B60D4B2585B2C53698E95951"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lung cancer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1994C1048B4439F8A42993759BA466D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>melanoma skin cancer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB70CDEC842914B3CB95D074B962A7785"><enum>(F)</enum><text>non-Hodgkin lymphoma;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H12FEFDB47EE447398ED12BA42653BC27"><enum>(G)</enum><text>pancreatic cancer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H481DFBED88FF4654B33604F2A14D6725"><enum>(H)</enum><text>prostate cancer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC5C2C39524549CE96170A97ACA18F31"><enum>(I)</enum><text>testiscular cancer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8ED9890E34F7437EA34FDA6C71589879"><enum>(J)</enum><text>thyroid cancer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB95F20E3B1141FD8BFF6B940088E7E9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>urinary bladder cancer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3A0807D0C124A169BE69FBC9041A3C5"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other cancers as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the National Academies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C6788C4CACB4507ABE3BD7263FBDC70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determine, to the extent possible, the prevalence of and mortality from the cancers specified in paragraph (2) among covered individuals by using available sources of data, which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B6D737DBC084643BEA9F824F21ED6B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health care and other administrative databases of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the individual Services, respectively;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F9817D9EEFE48CB9699F02C7404B27B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the national death index maintained by the National Center for Health Statistics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B7EEE6E4D5C4EE29CC4A5921CCA615E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the study conducted under section 750 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3716).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5E6D080DE6FB4B9291E4177D7FFE5C07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>At the conclusion of the study required under subsection (a), the National Academies shall submit to the Secretary and to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the results of the study described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6018B7F68EA94C41AB08CE03E58BC1C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered individual defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an individual who served on active duty in the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps as an aircrew member of a fixed-wing aircraft, including as a pilot, navigator, weapons systems operator, aircraft system operator, or any other crew member who regularly flew in a fixed-wing aircraft.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3E128E4F38C74A79BB5A8BD5E136E5AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2031</quote>. </text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250505" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 5, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


