<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25535-GJT-3F-5MX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2169 IS: Rural Hospital Cybersecurity Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2169</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250625" legis-day="20250624">June 25 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the development of a comprehensive rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idc55e2826-302a-4aee-8ebf-b6b56173ff39" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Hospital Cybersecurity Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id96ca5cd9-6fc1-438d-8726-86e8fa2b9a00" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id609ef308-560a-473d-b159-d60f00d678d6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7314629fb3254a08af7123f6bbaf77a6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfda783a9-c12b-413f-936c-f5a428eb4df5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbfb3b76f-a91b-40cb-a3d7-2087c2b8e63f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a0bf72131e74fa5b8ec0ebfe82edfcb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geographic division</header><text>The term <term>geographic division</term> means a geographic division that is among the 9 geographic divisions determined by the Bureau of the Census.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcec0fe62-945d-4c6a-8527-b4ede005f721" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rural hospital</header><text>The term <term>rural hospital</term> means a healthcare facility that—</text><subparagraph id="ida85a5bae-0429-4c97-a41d-2c2d83c84a7b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located in a non-urbanized area, as determined by the Bureau of the Census; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3050bef-2c03-4d55-b8e5-3554f9742814" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides inpatient and outpatient healthcare services, including primary care, emergency care, and diagnostic services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28bf6767-9677-413a-bf5d-aba540e56120" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id900f4747-53ea-4de3-9656-6104f03019d7" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy</header><subsection id="id3fb0d037-1e16-4596-aad0-afd38d516c4a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a comprehensive rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy to address the growing need for skilled cybersecurity professionals in rural hospitals.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4fa3d6d8-9000-4382-931c-443e6f69311e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37acff3e-cce2-482e-90da-dffaec9fc0b8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may consult with the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Labor, and any other appropriate head of an agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id128beff8-2eb2-46fc-a25f-90a8d47bb9c5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Providers</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with not fewer than 2 representatives of rural healthcare providers from each geographic division in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5826d31b-3a8c-44e4-86c6-6ab690468d9e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy developed under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, consider the following components:</text><paragraph id="id8d0d415b-7462-4f3d-9382-ea1013db435b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Partnerships between rural hospitals, non-rural healthcare systems, educational institutions, private sector entities, and nonprofit organizations to develop, promote, and expand the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce, including through education and training programs tailored to the needs of rural hospitals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78c9b7b2-f3ab-40b9-a9b0-c48c88de1ce1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The development of a cybersecurity curriculum and teaching resources that focus on teaching technical skills and abilities related to cybersecurity in rural hospitals for use in community colleges, vocational schools, and other educational institutions located in rural areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97d3cee7c6904ca6a5f80fd2a2c24a52" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida70ac52206954e5e8509236ba0ad8bbf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cybersecurity workforce challenges that are specific to rural hospitals, as well as challenges that are relative to hospitals generally; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92907a2493c942638705dea56f9d2ffa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">common practices to mitigate both sets of challenges described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9afd8be1-9c19-4c34-9ae2-2a8f7ff6955c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for legislation, rulemaking, or guidance to implement the components of the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf7fc4cdf-ce9a-4cdb-95a8-c333196986d0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the first full fiscal year ends following the date on which the Secretary transmits the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy developed under subsection (a), and not later than 60 days after the date on which each fiscal year thereafter ends, the Secretary shall provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress that includes, at a minimum, information relating to—</text><paragraph id="ida15bc277-3a87-42f6-a15e-20f0b446de35" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>updates to the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy, as appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc06b4c88-0436-4e23-98d1-2df9cbe98e74" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any programs or initiatives established pursuant to the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy, as well as the number of individuals trained or educated through such programs or initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida889c598-08ca-4cbd-9bb7-7da4464c90b5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>additional recommendations for legislation, rulemaking, or guidance to implement the components of the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d4b04bf-b677-4404-b2a0-2e14c8301364" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the rural hospital cybersecurity workforce development strategy in addressing the need for skilled cybersecurity professionals in rural hospitals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1ad56750-dde1-4dbc-9e55-8daeba3d7179" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Instructional materials for rural hospitals</header><subsection id="id550dd841-679a-411a-a4b1-a5916a4abb66" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall make available instructional materials for rural hospitals that can be used to train staff on fundamental cybersecurity efforts.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1afee50a-5736-47b9-b096-0b548efb4eff" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="idcee7aceb-f7a2-4adf-89e1-eebe0d4a79a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with appropriate heads of agencies, experts in cybersecurity education, and rural healthcare experts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc59f8f7-fe3e-4502-aa8d-227a23f39aa4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify existing cybersecurity instructional materials that can be adapted for use in rural hospitals and create new materials as needed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8641dbf5-5d76-4c95-9f48-894857c4556b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct an awareness campaign to promote the materials available to rural hospitals developed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb100a33a4a9244d5a71b03f8966f02a5" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

