<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2E3793AFBCF436AB9B30C37FC95629B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4522 IH: Neutralizing Unfair Chinese Export Subsidies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4522</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for working with allies to seek increased compliance by China with certain OECD export credit standards.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H852EA6B4195B4B18A42BA81977B9D983" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB0BD90AA4E4444019E988E27283A74DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Neutralizing Unfair Chinese Export Subsidies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H969C1C7BE19E4D3887FC2CB6ACBE1BF8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Working with allies to ensure China’s compliance with OECD standards</header> <subsection id="H452EBD365778420693BD81D4F935D028"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a detailed strategy and timeline with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDD7F8941C78F4B348537A0F37DAC7F92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthening United States advocacy and cooperation with appropriate allies and partners to seek to ensure substantial compliance by China with the financial terms and conditions of the OECD Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A8CF573A1834D268E0931CA28A4CBDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the goal described in section 11(a)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93D165F6E8B74345A6E92E69E1DF6F48" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International negotiations on export subsidies</header> 
<paragraph id="HA0450FB9F100417397F7A5C74DB69088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 11(a)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a-5">12 U.S.C. 635a–5(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with the possible goal of eliminating, before the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of the Export-Import Bank Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2015,</quote> and inserting <quote>with the goal of eliminating, before the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Neutralizing Unfair Chinese Export Subsidies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6ABDB52D4744F67B4FB1E49535C036A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Section 11(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a-5">12 U.S.C. 635a–5(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2019</quote> and inserting <quote>2029</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA67559D785C34168B53C36EA4E08C14B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conduct of negotiations</header><text>Section 11 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a-5">12 U.S.C. 635a–5</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA483BDD333A46789B4DECB68FDDDAEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in each of subsections (a) and (d), by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the United States Trade Representative,</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H363762F9B5EF40B89D208FF7AB28EADA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, and endeavor to hold not less frequently than twice per year,</quote> before <quote>negotiations</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECECE8B5E31E45BBA91175B64B7C269E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in each of subsections (b), (c), and (e), by striking <quote>President</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of the Treasury</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D9308DBF1A64F26A7F4E4CE8B1D4C35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>, and endeavor to hold such negotiations not less frequently than twice per year</quote> before the period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7369318F8C3E40869617565FF2149BB8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exchange rate governance and International Monetary Fund</header> <subsection id="HAB82605C57F14A9190198FC37241729C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In applying criteria to determine whether the People’s Republic of China has manipulated the rate of exchange between its currency and the United States dollar, the Secretary of the Treasury—</text> 
<paragraph id="H50E33F47CE4F48A280C3F66787988411"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take into account—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9A2E25D241A4451BB5B03A63E8A7090"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compliance by the People’s Republic of China with its obligations under Article VIII of the Articles of Agreement of the International Monetary Fund;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1EF29885FC764A5A853DE9EB7C78DBB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transparency of exchange rate management by the People’s Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA93B985A7A9142B9B141DFA9B7FD1264"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant support by the government of the People’s Republic of China to particular economic sectors that prevents effective balance of payments adjustments; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BC09E7265ED4A32BD3BF944D3DB4E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may carry out the determination regardless of any global current account surplus of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA942A8D79789429EA747F20959D91FAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Opposition to IMF quota increase</header><text>During the one-year period following a determination by the Secretary of the Treasury that the People’s Republic of China has manipulated the rate of exchange between its currency and the United States dollar, the Secretary shall instruct the United States Governor of the International Monetary Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any proposal to increase the quota of the People’s Republic of China in the Fund, other than consent to an amendment to the Articles of Agreement of the Fund that has been authorized by law.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

