<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25408-LX9-1H-6YS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 233 ATS: Commending and congratulating the University of Florida men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Men’s Basketball Championship. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending and congratulating the University of Florida men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Men’s Basketball Championship. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Monday, April 7, 2025, the University of Florida men’s basketball team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Florida Gators</quote>) won the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Men’s Basketball Championship with a 65–63 win over the University of Houston Cougars; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this is the Florida Gators' third national championship and first under Coach Todd Golden, who is in his fourth season coaching the team;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Coach Golden is the eighth youngest coach to win the NCAA Men’s Basketball National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Walter Clayton, Jr. was named the Most Outstanding Player of the NCAA tournament, averaging 22.5 points and going a perfect 11-of-11 from the free throw line in the Final Four;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Will Richard led the Florida Gators with 18 points and 8 rebounds during the championship game, propelling the team to victory; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the University of Florida is the only NCAA Division I school to hold 3 national titles in men’s basketball (2006, 2007, 2025) and football (1996, 2006, 2008) and is the only NCAA Division I school to win a national title in basketball and football in the same year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida380399dfa2f4814a772dc92ba1ccc9c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the University of Florida men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Men’s Basketball Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id67f42c4d1b9041c8bd2d497783ea5624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the fans, students, and faculty of the University of Florida; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13e4c8c3b57d44918e83008a859babe0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id491dbfa13bed4e429d1b003a24435fd1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Dr. W. Kent Fuchs, interim president of the University of Florida;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad92936b7a5e451493b162980f50877f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Scott Stricklin, director of athletics at the University of Florida; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5f563be931a44bc9faf2f6674c4224e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Todd Golden, head coach of the University of Florida men’s basketball team.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

