<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC404C693B3864B67A90CFAB79E6E09D0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 8 IH: Reaffirming the House of Representatives’s commitment to ensuring secure elections throughout the United States by recognizing that the presentation of valid photograph identification is a fundamental component of secure elections.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 8</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Reaffirming the House of Representatives’s commitment to ensuring secure elections throughout the United States by recognizing that the presentation of valid photograph identification is a fundamental component of secure elections.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas elections allow United States citizens to empower their fellow citizens to be their voice in the constitutional republic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the operation of free and fair elections is vital to Americans’ trust in government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas countries that hold elections without very basic security measures eventually lose the support of their people and erode faith in elections and the rule of law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas absentee voting systems and voting by mail systems that lack photograph verification are less secure than in-person voting with photograph verification;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States citizens are required by law to present valid photograph identification to prove identity for a wide array of other interactions with government, including applications for taxpayer-funded food stamps, welfare, Social Security, and Medicaid;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States citizens are required by law to present valid photograph identification to prove identity for a wide array of interactions with private institutions, including to open a bank account, rent or buy a house, apply for a mortgage, buy, rent, or operate a motor vehicle, board an airplane, get married, purchase firearms, buy a cell phone, apply for fishing and hunting licenses, pick up prescription medication, and many other functions; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States citizens possess no greater commodity than the franchise, and understand that protection of the security of voting and elections is crucial for the maintenance of the Republic and its way of life: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2A881171FBE542D484C8155D36296097"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9C48DE1181544519B7DB35077D9D6287"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H6F4F8A33CB7C4B26A54B27F4699F444B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms and reiterates its commitment to ensuring secure elections throughout the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27A16FFB08B4143AEE46EA0885EE3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that the presentation of valid photograph identification is a fundamental component of secure elections throughout the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

