<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0FF56A6B1F70484EA21B7A23B389B947" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1203 IH: Stop Victimizers and Offenders from Yielding Explicit Unconsented Recordings Surreptitiously Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1203</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to expand the scope of the prohibition against video voyeurism.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95212F003C934FB8BE9F5588D767FF8E" style="OLC"><section id="HC74C38317C1E443186911E4AFDAD24A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Victimizers and Offenders from Yielding Explicit Unconsented Recordings Surreptitiously Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>Stop VOYEURS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7F688711788841D9B31FDB3FF5469C33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanded prohibition against video voyeurism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1801 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6A0903B6EA574B8298E7B2CCD6B315A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HA153B954763A4CA2B9DB0F2860C64816"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States,</quote> and inserting <quote>, in a circumstance described in subsection (d),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06D070EED46347CCB0461FF5C30D4A61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>imprisoned not more than one year</quote> and inserting <quote>imprisoned not more than 5 years</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C5012FA8D254702952F9B4AB7B46E51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H668868CCC2AB4C2F864A60B40D82693C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HADE7811241CD467E9CCD573F90078C94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Circumstance described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text><paragraph id="H5315ED0BD4304366BE5E62C9A7106E7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the offender or victim traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC48DFD6FC214A96A6BCE80408E62FDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the offender used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA7B23CEA7D49D1AC7639E7D2E0D3B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54282F3E74474D739D3C98684CCA36BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the offender transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C879B9F53964B0CBB29EF0277901437"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any equipment, item, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFADF1E5669E54C54BC88344D0A87C478"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B00B16BB4F4D36BA7EC2D7D128471C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

