<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7945697FAC0E4411991B38D1F265A3EF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4510 IH: Healing Partnerships for Survivors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4510</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act to authorize grants to strengthen relationships between health and wellness providers or systems (including for behavioral health) and community-based sexual assault programs to support survivors of sexual assault across the lifespan of the survivor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA84B65C393F34104B3FDF9D95B768F2C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H69F6BF616DD044EFBC543B5B2F459AF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healing Partnerships for Survivors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3C6ADD2512934F22A54F8D6A65356874"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for strengthening relationships between health and wellness providers or systems, behavioral health programs, disability programs, and other service provider or community-based sexual assault programs to support survivors of sexual assault</header> <subsection id="HBE21CD8F30C04151AC1AAF4E0F480973"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Family Violence Prevention and Services Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10401">42 U.S.C. 10401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A1CAF5995F24D5B93558C30BDBB7748"> 
<section id="HB0B9408CE9884CCA914D9AE1E8944EE9"><enum>315.</enum><header>Grants for strengthening public health systems of support for survivors of sexual assault</header> 
<subsection id="H33CBE06773A84670AAFEBA1369505B33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H285E867EDFAE443581B69275DA2A751D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated under section 303(d) to carry out this section, the Secretary, acting through the Office of Family Violence Prevention and Services, may award grants to eligible entities to develop, implement, and improve systems of support and service provision through partnerships with health and wellness providers or systems, behavioral health programs, disability programs, or other service provider or community-based sexual assault programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3363A782844844148AE0593940A5C02E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD931C1EE3A12463A940B55F236541032"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an entity shall be—</text> 
<clause id="HF5DFD72A26814B6F9F1335C531148212"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State sexual assault coalition, a territorial sexual assault coalition, or a tribal coalition;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF41FC8C2B8C04590B7964EF957B584D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit community-based sexual assault program, including such a program that is a rape crisis center, culturally specific organization, or community-based organization, with a history of demonstrated work with survivors of sexual assault; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC97E376463974873A10B493231840C9F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an Indian tribe or tribal organization.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11AB38B5640049D29CE261E647270BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="H92F329AD2B23425691CE630E050E61B7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sexual assault; State sexual assault coalition; tribal coalition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>sexual assault</quote>, <term>State sexual assault coalition</term>, and <quote>tribal coalition</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="H343162D162114B02A6C14CFC6F4FF053"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Territorial sexual assault coalition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>territorial sexual assault coalition</quote> means a program addressing sexual violence that is—</text> 
<subclause id="HF6855C0118464242AB1074E318AF759B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an established nonprofit, nongovernmental territorial coalition addressing sexual assault within the territory; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H24A77964659F4D95B41A9CFDECEF87FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a nongovernmental organization with a demonstrated history of addressing sexual assault within the territory that proposes to incorporate as a nonprofit, nongovernmental territorial coalition.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BB66786F6624CE4B7D5D394F7E0AFE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1785B452963D4046A12391301E2EB30F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <subparagraph id="HA337082A87D941BDB0E835EAB2340140"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under paragraph (1) shall, directly or through subgrants or contracts, develop and implement a program for developing partnerships with health and wellness providers or systems, behavioral health programs, disability programs, or other service providers or community-based sexual assault programs to develop trauma-informed, culturally relevant partnerships, training, responses, services, and policies to address and improve the comprehensive response to the health and well-being of survivors of sexual assault across the lifespan of the survivor, including adult survivors of childhood sexual abuse, regardless of age.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC0FD69BBB5C4899B5373B825C9D2EEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program developed and implemented under subparagraph (A) may engage in the following:</text> <clause id="HCBF8766195CD4744879BC5828FF3A231"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The provision of services, including prevention, screening, linkages to care, and treatment, including therapy, support groups, holistic healing services, somatic approaches, substance-use services and supports, temporary housing assistance, and personal advocacy through case management, and information and referral services.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA35882A4A2844377882DA8C9F3059C87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Support for an adult survivor of childhood sexual abuse or sexual assault while the survivor receives health care or substance-use treatment services, including recovery and harm reduction support.</text></clause> <clause id="HB03B529D9EB6471D9E0C38A0D383BFF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The provision of training for staff and partners associated with delivering services described in clause (i).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5CDE114F97E44F2BB7AF87B084E97999"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The provision of a trauma-informed and culturally relevant or specific health and wellness modality for a survivor of sexual assault.</text></clause> <clause id="HC3E4E1D8B5EB4B4286198419449D5194"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Such other activities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43657A27BF7945E7891CEA4D40486272"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports and evaluations</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary, at such time as shall be reasonably required by the Secretary, a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H46BB60CE00E94078835C0BCA230688C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the activities that have been carried out with such grant funds;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9563B0B66D7741B6BCF9412D932ECDF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an evaluation of the impact and effectiveness of such activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3271544E4C144377A893E5015E5F592F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides such additional information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF7CF2DA58394FB88941818922CBE1BA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under paragraph (1) shall ensure that each program developed or implemented with such grant protects victim privacy, confidentiality, and safety in compliance with applicable confidentiality, privacy, and nondisclosure requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E1CB189096640458DC29532DDAC22F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance and training</header> <paragraph id="H93E83E7259774B11A413DF7DDD229521"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 303(d) for any fiscal year to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award not more than 10 percent of the funds available for the fiscal year to 2 or more eligible entities for the provision of training and technical assistance to grantees and potential grantees under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3DF1892B8A4468F86A3F1E5C3295ABB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC5CD64AC269E449E91CAACC92762C508"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall—</text> <clause id="HF9F65C553CBD455E8BD8104C765A46CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be a private, nonprofit organization that focuses primarily on issues related to sexual assault;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1D08088F508845BDA1150D9E4DC58B4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in an application for a grant under paragraph (1), provide documentation to the Secretary demonstrating experience working directly on issues related to sexual assault;</text></clause> <clause id="H71AAFE12BCDD4F599C10BDB681E71E98"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demonstrate to the Secretary in such application, the strong support of sexual assault service programs, including through letters of support, from around the United States for the entity’s demonstrated history in providing training and technical assistance on issues related to sexual assault.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB862A49B5C874F0FAD20E58ADFFFA4AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Demonstrated expertise</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), at least one of the eligible entities applying for the grant shall have—</text> <clause id="H48A4A7456E17423BB2B66FF08D811D56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a demonstrated expertise primarily working with culturally specific communities; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4956596411DD49A5825C78A5FBE6456F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a demonstrated expertise in addressing, and a primary purpose to address, the development and provision of culturally specific services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3EA9733CBE94542A95360C5BD185B6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required uses of funds</header><text>An eligible entity awarded a grant under paragraph (1) shall use the grant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H02B9645E1D9344ACB20F187F559A0FED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide training and technical assistance to entities receiving grants under subsection (a)(1) for the implementation of programs funded under such subsection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CA3201CE40644448589FABC6CB4C7C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conduct evaluations of the programs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96FF2BE60771406C8D03CCCD29BACBA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to identify and disseminate best practices that emerge from the programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CF3D0647C8745B48ADB33235C4441C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to carry out any other activity determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69A4FB6810C14706B2CD3AA3BF1D1DE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal administration</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 303(e) for any fiscal year, not more than $5,000,000 for such fiscal year may be used by the Secretary for evaluation, monitoring, and other administrative expenses.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C933CE96024435DA3206F63A76BE214"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of sexual assault</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>sexual assault</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF930EE54624F47C8A29C09079B144307"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 304 of the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10404">42 U.S.C. 10404(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6701B29019D44AE4A02CD98436A922FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and dating violence</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>dating violence, and sexual assault</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5719B0027B61441F9E04882BA19B7E06"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or dating violence</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>dating violence, or sexual assault</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7A0DE9DC9D9A4CCB83BC0C0FBCACBD49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 303 of the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10403">42 U.S.C. 10403</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A03EE57E50D475B8D1C55477728A0E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78198C93F9774B029F1A20B4D0952AD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD29C4215D1B24574B52524F36B8A8C30"> 
<subsection id="HCB71931DDA5A4BA9B70ABDB294B7F35D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants for strengthening public health systems of support for survivors of sexual assault</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 315 $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

