<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H936269A70C204116A5FDBF0B113A4289" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4883 IH: Local Gun Violence Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4883</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and maintain a local gun violence prevention laws database, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8957A480ED8F48A5BDE820F36A3C13A2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7EE84065FE84DC7BF47316E47295A1D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Gun Violence Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB70824D033D549F783828AF3FA7F6083"><enum>2.</enum><header>Local gun violence prevention laws database</header> <subsection id="H7F58992B498046EBA6D11450EBA3A12E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish and maintain a database in which units of State and local government (including cities, towns, counties, and special district governments) enter into such database information on—</text>
<paragraph id="HF63EDEA065A54D40BC547248EF74B798"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the laws and ordinances such units of government have enacted to reduce gun violence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC9637115FA14FCCA65098BB7CFD31A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how successful such laws and ordinances have been in reducing gun violence in the relevant jurisdictions.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H197F50EF60314B0298A8274321AAC866"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The information included by a State or local government in the database established under subsection (a) with respect to a law or ordinance referred to in such subsection shall include the following information:</text> <paragraph id="HA24D5476FFCA4AC29E55DC0DF0D96699"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information about the size of the unit of government involved.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADF107AEEAD9452EBA8AE12E90EB6363"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date on which the law or ordinance was enacted.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13E26289CC5844F2AF9999E226F7CAA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date on which the law or ordinance took effect.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAD35C184207C43AEBE15F2132B449C91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Data on the rates of gun violence and gun deaths in the unit of government both before and after the law or ordinance took effect.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H573F1D44C47440B4B02904A6294C222C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The database established under subsection (a) shall be searchable by any State or local unit of government.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4D65DBABCADB4CB999BE7D23E3B4E2E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach to State and local governments to increase awareness of the database under subsection (a) and to encourage such governments to use such database.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H569AEC173E8F4A08BF3F9C7DFA08C3DE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report specifying, with respect to the database established under subsection (a)—</text>
<paragraph id="H96D04C1192DB4DBAA2F45CFBAE141AF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how many submissions to such database have been received;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AB809C777634EFB90E98EA93A92B3FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>what common topics are identified in such submissions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD91642910FBE47E0AC7BA8AD5D9A4E3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>which laws or ordinances the reports contained in such submissions indicate have been successful; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1C6EE56F82B4114A970DFB3B3C3E81A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any geographic areas within the United States that have high or low participation in the database.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC473FFD1FEC945E1B3DE39F0FE272D08"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="HD783684B9A7B4657AA05D97E40A3172E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,500,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF424AE475A9B42A4B7C15E41126721AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

